<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The makings of &#34;Islamic Science&#34;</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-08-28_the-makings-of-islamic-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-08-28_the-makings-of-islamic-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/08/28/the-makings-of-islamic-science/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“In the time of the Hellenes and during the early days of the empire of&#xA;the Rum the sciences were honoured and enjoyed universal respect. From&#xA;an already solid and grandiose foundation, they were raised to greater&#xA;heights every day, until the Christian religion made its appearance&#xA;among the Rum; this was a fatal blow to the edifice of learning; its&#xA;traces disappeared and its pathways were effaced”&lt;br&gt;&#xA;-Abu al-Hasan Ali ibn al-Husayn al-Masudi, the scientist from Baghdad,&#xA;who lived in the 900s of the CE.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hekate</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-08-16_hekate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-08-16_hekate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/08/16/hekate/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/1600/hekate.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/320/hekate.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/320/hekate.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another point I shall consider is the role of the great goddess Hekate&#xA;in Neoplatonic thought. Hekate in Neoplatonism plays a strikingly&#xA;parallel role to mAyA in uttaramImAMsaand prakR^iti in sAMkhya. She is&#xA;described in the Chaldaean oracles to have emerged from the “primary&#xA;entity/being” (the Neoplatonic equivalent of puruSha or brahman) and&#xA;separates the two “fires”- the “purely intellectual fire” that belongs&#xA;to the primary entity/being and the material fire from which the cosmos&#xA;arises. She separated the two fires in the form of a membrane (again&#xA;parallel to the mAyA of uttaramImAMsa). The universe is seen as her&#xA;emanation. In iconography she is seen as three-headed and the mistress&#xA;of the 3 paths and may be compared to the goddess tripurA of shrIvidyA.&#xA;An old orphic hymn to her is of considerable interest (the original&#xA;Greek text is provided along with an adaptation of the translation by&#xA;Adam Forrest; we note a few words in the Greek text for comparison with&#xA;saMskR^itaM)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some considerations on Neoplatonism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-08-16_some-considerations-on-neoplatonism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-08-16_some-considerations-on-neoplatonism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/08/16/some-considerations-on-neoplatonism/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have always believed, since I was probably 11 years old, that it was&#xA;important to study Neoplatonic thought and ritual. This is particularly&#xA;important because it was one of the sister systems of our own, and was&#xA;the only world philosophy with a reasonably comparable depth and scope.&#xA;Importantly, as we are the only surviving heathens in the world with an&#xA;unbroken link to our ancient traditions firstly of the shruti and then&#xA;of the Agama-s, we alone, are in the unique position to study&#xA;Neoplatonism from an insider’s perspective, which is entirely lacking&#xA;for the western students of Graeco-Roman thought. We need to look at&#xA;history and philosophy NeoPlatonism from various angles: 1) How did it&#xA;originate; how did the connections to ancient Greek and Hindu thought&#xA;develop in Eurasia? 2) What does the end of Neoplatonism tell us about&#xA;the dangers of Abrahamistic monotheism to modern Hindus? 3) What do the&#xA;relationships between Neoplatonism and Hindu thought mean? 4) What is&#xA;the common theme realized from Neoplatonism and Hindu thought in terms&#xA;of their unifying role that transcended linguistic and regional&#xA;differences?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arya influence</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/MT_lekhAH/Arya-influence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/MT_lekhAH/Arya-influence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1599462903228248064.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My theory is that it is now clear Greek, Albanian and Armenian come staight from Yamnaya/Catacomb migrations (Y-DNA R-Z2103 clades + Southern Arc). Aryans couldn’t have interacted with Helladic period Proto Greeks, but what about the Greek like tribes who stayed on the Steppes?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I currently see the matter as being somewhat complicated. There is definitely a clear ancestral component going back to early IE &amp;amp; earlier I-An. However, the case might be made for specific Greek-Aryan parallels in linguistic&amp;amp; philological terms. When viewed probabilistically (Bayesian if you like), this builds up quite a bit; e.g., lu&lt;del&gt;N/la&lt;/del&gt;N formations, word for arrow eis:iShu; liT usage in epic language; geometric formulation of altars, certain specific epic motifs&amp;hellip; making some kind of specific link between Gr &amp;amp; Aryan more probable than the alternative.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Augustus - virgil</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/MT_lekhAH/augustus_virgil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/MT_lekhAH/augustus_virgil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The magnification of Caesar Augustus by Virgil in the Aeneid:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;..&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And here, here is the man, the promised one you know of —&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Caesar Augustus, son of a god, destined to rule&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Where Saturn ruled of old in Latium, and there&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Bring back the age of gold: his empire shall expand &lt;br&gt;&#xA;Past Garamants and Indians to a land beyond the zodiac&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And the sun&amp;rsquo;s yearly path, where Atlas the sky-bearer pivots&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The wheeling heavens, embossed with fiery stars, on his shoulder.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Himera battles</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/MT_lekhAH/himera-battles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/MT_lekhAH/himera-battles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1577109711727403008.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.2205272119&#34;&gt;https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.2205272119&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Archaeogenetics &amp;amp; other methods contribute to the understanding of the battles of Himera between Carthaginian &amp;amp; the Greeks. The 1st battle was won by the Greeks. The second under the lesser known 1st Hannibal decimated the Greeks for good. Hannibal then made a human sacrifice of 3000 yavana-s &amp;amp; enslaved all their women. Probably some victims of his gruesome sacrifice were among those whose genomes were sequenced by the authors. At least 2 individual seem to be fighters from the steppes with East Asian admixture, like shaka-s One of them has a potential Mongolic mito haplogroup leaving no doubt that these were likely shaka-s who had mixed with groups on the eastern steppe. It is also notable that there were Baltic groups in the war &amp;ndash; I wonder if these were actually the famous Thracian peltasts who were mobilized by the Greeks, rather than actually hailing from the Baltic region.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
