<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aniketa kushAgraH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/aniketa-kushAgraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/aniketa-kushAgraH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://samalochan.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/image-modified-300x300.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://samalochan.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/image-modified-300x300.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;बिहार में जन्मे कुशाग्र अनिकेत न्यू यॉर्क, अमेरिका में अर्थशास्त्र और प्रबंधन-विशेषज्ञ के रूप में कार्यरत हैं। कुशाग्र ने अर्थशास्त्र, गणित, और सांख्यिकी में स्नातक की शिक्षा न्यू यॉर्क के कॉर्नेल विश्वविद्यालय से पूरी की, जहाँ उन्हें विश्वविद्यालय के सर्वोच्च अकादमीय सम्मान से पुरस्कृत किया गया। तत्पश्चात् वे कोलंबिया विश्वविद्यालय से प्रबंधन-शास्त्र (MBA) में सर्वोच्च सम्मान से उत्तीर्ण हुए।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;कुशाग्र तीन भाषाओं (अंग्रेज़ी, हिंदी, एवं संस्कृत) में अपने गद्य और पद्य लेखन के लिए भारत और सयुंक्त-राज्य में अनेक पुरस्कारों से सम्मानित हो चुके हैं। उन्होंने नित्यानंद मिश्र के सह-लेखन में Krishna-Niti: Timeless Strategic Wisdom (२०२४) नाम की चर्चित पुस्तक लिखी है। सम्प्रति वे भारतीय शिलालेखीय साहित्य पर शोध कर रहे हैं।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ka337@cornell.edu&#34;&gt;ka337@cornell.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cults</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/cults/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/cults/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;solar&#34;&gt;Solar&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;~Kayasthas and the cult of Sun worship ~&#xA;In Bhinmal Stone inscription of Udaysimhadeva VS 1306, we find reference to two sons of Thakkura Udaysimha of Mathur subcaste.The two brothers donated to treasure of Jagatswamin, Surya Divinity of Bhinmal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The same diety has been referred to as Kuldevta of Narapati ,kayastha minister of Hammira of Ranthambore in inscriptions of Hammira era.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mathurs like other major subcastes of kayasthas trace their descent from Lord Chitragupta.&#xA;Vishnudharmottara purana describes Lord Chitragupta dressed in Udichyavesa on right side of Yama.This iconography resembles companion of Surya, Pingala.Udichyavesa is associated with form of Surya worship introduced by Iranian Magis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>gahaDavAla</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/gahaDavAla/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/gahaDavAla/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1861378362750779688.html#google_vignette&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thread by @historiakayasth&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;🧵 Kayasthas in the Gahadavala realm: An epigraphical survey&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Roughly 100 epigraphical records are known from the times of the Gahadavalas, from 11th to 12th centuries CE. Most of these are copper plate land grants to Brahmins. Unfortunately, there is a paucity of large stone inscriptions the likes of which were issued by other dynasties of the times, viz Chandelas, Kalachuris, Paramaras etc. Thus, it is hard to deduce the exact social conditions and the administrative setup of this dynasty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hero memorials</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/hero-memorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/hero-memorials/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kAyastha grants</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/kAyastha-grants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/kAyastha-grants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/historiakayasth/status/1864694429145288758&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;grants&#34;&gt;Grants&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This brings us to the point that Kayasthas were also the benefactor of these grants themselves. For instance, members of the family of Suhadadeva enjoyed multiple village-grants for several generations beginning with his ancestor Thakur Jajuka in the 10th century. Grants to these families were in lieu of military and bureaucratic services. Such hereditary land grants were also given to Kayastha families by other dynasties too. We will document major families of such grants in separate  threads.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kAyastha records</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/kAyastha-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/kAyastha-records/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/historiakayasth/status/1805533793316753800&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Ajaygarh fort inscription from Panna, MP, circa 11th century CE records the grant of a village and the authority of the famous Kalanjar fort to a Srivastava Kayastha named Maheswara by Kirttivarman Chandela. Maheswara belonged to a long line of Srivastavas who served as administrators and warriors in the Chandela kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of his ancestors was Thakur Jajuka Srivastava, a warrior who was the contemporary of Ganda Chandela in the 10th cen. The 7th verse of this inscription records that Jajuka ushered in the Golden Age by establishing &amp;lsquo;मानवाचारविधि&amp;rsquo; ie the Laws of Manu in the Chandela realm. Thakur Jajuka wasn&amp;rsquo;t just an ordinary warrior. He also had impressive scholarly credentials. In another inscription from Ajayagarh he is mentioned as having mastered &amp;ldquo;विद्याचतुर्दश&amp;rdquo; or the 14 sciences, viz, the 4 Vedas, 6 Vedangas, Nyaya, Mimansa, Dharmashastra and the Puranas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kAyastha Scholarship</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/kAyastha-scholarship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/kAyastha-scholarship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1851879556107637110.html#google_vignette&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sanskrit-poets&#34;&gt;Sanskrit poets&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Medieval Kayasthas were ardent scholars of Sanskrit. Thus, they feature prominently as composers of Sanskrit eulogies. We shall document some Kayastha poets of high calibre in this thread.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Mandsaur stone slab Inscription of the Naigama family, who served as hereditary viceroys to Aulikaras in the 6th century CE, mention a member of their family named &amp;lsquo;Bhagavaddoṣa&amp;rsquo; who was a skilled poet of Sanskrit and Prakrit. The verse 17 of this Inscription suggests that he was perhaps one of the most renowned poets of his time, so much so that other poets used to sing his praises in their own poems. The Naigamas are today known as Nigams and constitute one of the 12 subcastes of northern Kayasthas. 2/n&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mAthur</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/mAthur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/mAthur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mathur Kayasthas&lt;br&gt;&#xA;-Footprints from Kushan to Paramars-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mathur Kayasthas likely derive their surname from geographical location of Mathura.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Early Kayasthas of Mathura were an elite group is indicated by the fact that they donated sculptures during Kushana period.Yasa wife of a kayastha is said to have donated this sculpture .&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;manoratha&#34;&gt;Manoratha&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After mention of Yasa of Kushana Period,we find mention of Mathur Kayasthas in Gwalior inscription of King Bhuvanpala 1103AD. The inscription speaks of Manoratha who was a gentleman and followed the three fold way of life.He was brilliant at arithmetic and his calibre was such that even Brihaspati couldn&amp;rsquo;t praise him enough. He was confidante of the King and had total control over exchequer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matrimony cases</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/matrimony-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/matrimony-cases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Elites have practiced intermarriage as a part of diplomatic alliance for long. Royal courtiers too were a part of such alliances.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;naigamas&#34;&gt;naigamas&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Naigama family served the Aulikaras of Malwa as &amp;ldquo;Rajasthaniyas&amp;rdquo; or viceroys for several generations between 4th to 6th centuries. They are known from several epigraphical records from southern Rajasthan and Malwa during this period.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The stone slab inscription below, from Mandsaur dated to the early 6th century, gives a detailed account of this family and their association with the powerful Aulikaras who defeated the Hunas. 1/n The issuer of this inscription was one Naigama named Nirdosh. The main object of this inscription was to boast about the family&amp;rsquo;s credentials. Verse 14 of mentions that one member of a preceding generation of this family, Ravikirtti, married a lady named &amp;ldquo;Bhānuguptā.&amp;rdquo; 2/n John Faithful Fleet, the epigraphist who initially translated this inscription, identified this Bhānuguptā as a member of the imperial Gupta family. Furthermore, in the next verse, the same inscription refers to Aulikaras as &amp;ldquo;bāndhava&amp;rdquo; referring to the kinship between Naigamas and the Aulikaras. However, this kinship could not have been due to a common origin as this record very clearly says that&amp;hellip; Sashthidatta, the progenitor of this Naigama family and a wealthy man came into the shelter of the Aulikaras, this he was not a member of this family. Thus, scholars believe that this kinship was not due to a common origin, but a result of intermarriage as was the norm back then.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revenue admin role</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/revenue-admin-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/revenue-admin-role/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;🧵 Kayasthas in the revenue department: An in depth survey of early mediaeval land grants&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a class of record-keepers, Kayasthas were primarily associated with revenue department of early-medieaval kingdoms in North-India. Both literary and epigraphical evidence, particularly copper plate grants, suggest that members of this group occupied all rungs of the revenue administration in those times and were also the benefactors thereof.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this thread we will study, how not only Kayasthas shaped and managed the revenue administration, but also how their own social identity was shaped by the system. In early mediaeval records, an officer of the revenue department was generally known as the अक्षपटलिक (Akshapatalika). Copper plate land-grants suggest that there were different grades of this post. The highest being महा-अक्षपटलिक the general superintendent of revenue records of the state. In many medieval kingdoms, this post was monopolised by members of the Kayastha caste.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>shrIvastava</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/shrIvastava/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/kAyastha/articles/shrIvastava/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1867913149460164971.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;etymology&#34;&gt;Etymology&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the etymology of the Kayastha subcaste Srivastava:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Srivastavas are today counted among the Chitraguptavanshi Kayasthas of northern India, found across several Hindi speaking states and Nepal. There are several popular derivations of this surname. But in this thread we will try to understand the etymology of this name using epigraphical records.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The clan name of Srivastava is found in several inscriptions of early-medieaval north central India as writers, officials and ministers of various kingdoms. The original spelling of the name was श्री-वास्तव्य (Śrī-vāstavya) with श्री as a prefix- which is sometimes absent in old records of this clan. Three epigraphical records by different families of this clan give us a derivation of this name which we shall discuss here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
