<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;01 LIFE on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;01 LIFE on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Discovering the World of the Pirahãs</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/01_Discovering_the_World_of_th/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/01_Discovering_the_World_of_th/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;t was a bright Brazilian morning on December 10, 1977, and we were waiting to take off in a six-passenger plane provided by my missionary agency, the Summer Institute of Linguistics (SIL). The pilot, Dwayne Neal, put the aircraft through its preflight inspection. He walked around the plane and checked to see how well the load was balanced. He checked for external signs of damage. He drew a small vial from the fuel tank to check for water in the fuel. He tested the action of the propeller. This is a routine that has become as normal to me now as brushing my teeth before going to work, but then it was my first time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 The Amazon</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/02_The_Amazon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/02_The_Amazon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O&lt;/strong&gt;nce you have made your peace with the Amazon, a Pirahã village is a relaxing place. The first step toward this peace is for you to learn to ignore, even enjoy, the heat. That is not as hard as it might sound. The human body, when clothed properly, can handle the 90 to 110F temperatures well, especially since the jungle provides plenty of shade and, in the case of the Pirahãs, the Maici River, which is always cool, wet, and relaxing. The humidity is harder to accept, though. Perspiration—that otherwise effective tool for lowering body temperature via evaporation in temperate climates—produces little more than athlete’s foot and crotch rot in the Amazon, unless your skin, like the Pirahãs’, is weather-beaten and usually dry because you rarely perspire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 The Cost of Discipleship</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/03_The_Cost_of_Discipleship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/03_The_Cost_of_Discipleship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;W&lt;/strong&gt;e went as disciples of Christ to the Pirahãs. And the Bible warns disciples that service is fraught with dangers. So we began to discover. One late afternoon Keren began to complain that the Pirahãs were making her tense. She was frying the meat from an anteater that Kóhoi had killed. She was surrounded as usual by about a dozen Pirahãs, curious about our cooking and eating habits (and hungry for some anteater steak). She asked me to walk with her on our airstrip. The airstrip was like our personal park. It didn’t just serve as a landing site for the plane, it gave us a place to walk, to jog, and to escape the village once in a while.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Sometimes You Make Mistakes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/04_Sometimes_You_Make_Mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/04_Sometimes_You_Make_Mistakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt; realized when Keren and Shannon were near death with malaria that there were important things about the Pirahãs that I was not understanding or successfully appreciating. I was hurt that the Pirahãs didn’t show more empathy for me and my situation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It didn’t occur to me then, caught up as I was in my own crisis, that the Pirahãs went through what I was now agonizing over on a regular basis. And their lot was worse than mine. Every Pirahã has seen a close family member die. They have seen and touched the bodies of their deceased loved ones and have buried them in the forest near their home. They had no medical doctor or hospital to turn to for help in most cases. When someone gets too ill to work among the Pirahãs, no matter how easily the disease might be treatable by Western medicine, there is a significant chance that the person will die. And the neighbors and family do not bring casseroles to a Pirahã funeral. If your mother dies, if your child dies, if your husband dies—you still have to hunt, fish, and gather food. No one will do this for you. Life gives death no quarter. No Pirahã can borrow a motorboat to take his family for help. And no one is likely to offer a Pirahã family help if they do appear in the nearest town looking for assistance. But neither would most Pirahãs accept help from a stranger.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 Material Culture and the Absence of Ritual</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/05_Material_Culture_and_the_Ab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/05_Material_Culture_and_the_Ab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;F&lt;/strong&gt;rom the time I first met the Pirahãs I wanted to understand their culture better. I thought I would begin simple, with their material culture, rather than, say, with their beliefs and moral values. Since the majority of their time in the village was spent in their huts, I wanted to see one built. I got my chance one day when Xaikáibí decided to build a new hut. The hut he was building is the more substantial of two types of hut that the Pirahãs make, called &lt;em&gt;kaíi-ií&lt;/em&gt; (daughter-thing).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 Families and Community</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/06_Families_and_Community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/06_Families_and_Community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P&lt;/strong&gt;irahãs laugh about everything. They laugh at their own misfortune: when someone’s hut blows over in a rainstorm, the occupants laugh more loudly than anyone. They laugh when they catch a lot of fish. They laugh when they catch no fish. They laugh when they’re full and they laugh when they’re hungry. When they’re sober, they are never demanding or rude. Since my first night among them I have been impressed with their patience, their happiness, and their kindness. This pervasive happiness is hard to explain, though I believe that the Pirahãs are so confident and secure in their ability to handle anything that their environment throws at them that they can enjoy whatever comes their way. This is not at all because their lives are easy, but because they are good at what they do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 Nature and the Immediacy of Experience</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/07_Nature_and_the_Immediacy_of/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/07_Nature_and_the_Immediacy_of/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T&lt;/strong&gt;he Pirahãs’ relationship to nature is fundamental to understanding them. Understanding this relationship is as important to gaining a full picture of their values and overall culture as understanding their material culture and their sense of community. As I began to study how the Pirahãs relate to nature in more detail, I discovered that concepts and words for the environment help to define their perspective on how nature fits together and how it is related to human beings. Two terms, &lt;em&gt;bigí&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;xoí,&lt;/em&gt; are telling in this regard and help us comprehend the Pirahã worldview.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 A Teenager Named Túkaaga: Murder and Society</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/08_A_Teenager_Named_Tkaaga_M/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/08_A_Teenager_Named_Tkaaga_M/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;J&lt;/strong&gt;oaquim, like the other residents of the Apurinã Indian settlement of Ponto Sete on the Maici, had arisen early and gone about his tasks—tending his jungle garden and small manioc field, looking for signs of game for a possible evening hunting trip, and fishing in the clear Maici water upriver from his home. Like others at “Sete,” Joaquim was broader and stronger-looking than the Pirahãs. His Tupi and Apurinã lineage endowed him with a muscularity that contrasted with the Pirahãs’ intense leanness. With broad, strong feet from a lifetime without shoes, his powerful toes could grip the path securely, giving him greater stability than Westerners in expensive hiking footwear. He was a shy man, very quiet, about thirty years old, who smiled frequently, but always held his hand to his mouth when he did so in order to hide his missing front teeth. He purloined cups (plastic, nonbreakable cups are a favorite and hard-to-come-by item) from me from time to time when he thought I would not notice. He laughed at the Pirahãs as inferior. But he was after all a man who had faced the same hardships and environment as they, accumulating much more materially than they have—a fact that, while irrelevant to the Pirahãs, was clearly important to him. But he and the others at Ponto Sete believed that they and the Pirahãs were good friends. The Apurinãs at Sete always treated the Pirahãs well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 Land to Live Free</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/09_Land_to_Live_Free/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/09_Land_to_Live_Free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T&lt;/strong&gt;he most common challenges the Pirahãs face are disease and incursions into their land by people from other parts of the world—especially divers, fishermen, and hunters from a variety of countries, including Brazil. Japanese sport fishermen and Brazilian commercial fishing boats on the Marmelos have been a frequent sight, the visitors paying the Pirahãs in sugarcane rum, cloth, manioc meal, and even relatively expensive trade items, like canoes, to help them locate fish, through a caboclo intermediary. They also suffer ill effects from trade with caboclos, who usually only give them sugarcane rum in exchange for food and jungle products. Rather than cause offense and risk a dangerous encounter with any of these outsiders, the Pirahãs will often give them all the food that they have to placate them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Caboclos: Vignettes of Amazonian Brazilian Life</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/10_Caboclos_Vignettes_of_Amaz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/01_LIFE/10_Caboclos_Vignettes_of_Amaz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;aboclos are by and large descendants of Amazonian indigenous peoples who now speak only Portuguese, are integrated into the regional economy, and consider themselves Brazilians rather than members of a tribe. The Pirahãs call caboclos &lt;em&gt;xaoói-gíi&lt;/em&gt; (authentic foreigners; the suffix &lt;em&gt;-gíi&lt;/em&gt; means “authentic” or “real”). Americans and other foreigners, including Brazilians from the city, are simply *xaoóì.*The Pirahãs relate better to the caboclos because they see them more often and because they and the caboclos share the same environment and many of the same skills of hunting, fishing, canoeing, and knowledge of the jungle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
