<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Tipu Sultan - VOD on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Tipu Sultan - VOD on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00  PREFACE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/00_pre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/00_pre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PREFACE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Secularism &lt;em&gt;per se&lt;/em&gt; is a doctrine which arose in the modem West as a&#xA;revolt against the dosed creed of Christianity. Its battle-cry was that&#xA;the State should be freed from the stranglehold of the Church, and the&#xA;citizen should be left to his own individual choice in matters of&#xA;belief. And it met with great success in every Western democracy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Had India borrowed this doctrine from the modem West, it would have&#xA;meant a rejection of the dosed creeds of Islam and Christianity, and a&#xA;promotion of the Sanatana Dharma family of faiths which have been&#xA;naturally secularist in the modern Western sense. But what happened&#xA;actually was that Secularism in India became the greatest protector of&#xA;closed creeds which had come here in the company of foreign invaders,&#xA;and kept tormenting the national society for several centuries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01  1         THE SWORD OF TIPU SULTAN Making darkness by closing one&#39;s eyes </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/01_ch01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/01_ch01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1&lt;br&gt;&#xA;THE SWORD OF TIPU SULTAN&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Making darkness by closing one&amp;rsquo;s eyes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;V.M. KORATH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Former Editor of &lt;em&gt;Mathrubhoomi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Historical novels are usually an admixture of historical facts and&#xA;imagination. As such they are not expected to truthfully portray all the&#xA;historical events. However, authors of historical novels have the moral&#xA;responsibility to present historical facts without blatant distortions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Bhagwan Gidwani, the author of the controversial novel, &lt;em&gt;The Sword&#xA;of Tipu Sultan&lt;/em&gt;, does not seem to be bound by any such ethical&#xA;obligations; he does not have any qualms even to deliberately falsify&#xA;historical facts. Therefore, a tele-serial based on such a novel also&#xA;cannot be otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02  2         RELIGIOUS INTOLERANCE OF TIPU SULTAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/02_ch02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/02_ch02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2&lt;br&gt;&#xA;RELIGIOUS INTOLERANCE OF TIPU SULTAN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LATE P.C.N. RAJA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tipu Sultan had, ruled his kingdom only for sixteen-and-a-half years,&#xA;from December 7, 1782 to May 4, 1799. The territory of Malabar was under&#xA;his effective control only for a short period of eight years. If he had&#xA;not secured the assistance of the wily Purnaiyya, there would not have&#xA;been so many Muhammadans in the states of Kerala and Karnataka. Hindus&#xA;also would not have become less prosperous, and fewer in number.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03  3         TIPU&#39;S OWN TESTIMONY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/03_ch03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/03_ch03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;3&lt;br&gt;&#xA;TIPU&amp;rsquo;S OWN TESTIMONY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C. NANDAGOPAL MENON&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(The writer is convenor of Bombay Malayalee Samajam)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you love me, should you not put up with my weakness sometimes?&amp;rdquo; -&#xA;Tipu Sultan is purported to have asked Mir Sadik who was one of his&#xA;ministers. This is a remark invented by Bhagwan S. Gidwani in his&#xA;controversial novel, &lt;em&gt;The Sword of Tipu Sultan&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Across-section of the new generation of historians and novelists is of&#xA;the opinion that all the available documents and history books on Tipu&#xA;Sultan originate from the British and, therefore, they cannot be relied&#xA;upon, the ostensible policy of the British being to &amp;lsquo;divide and rule&amp;rsquo;.&#xA;Pointing to the correspondence between Shrimad Paramahamsa&#xA;Parivrajakacharya Shri Sankaracharya of Sringeri Mutt and Tipu Sultan&#xA;during 1791-92 and 1798, they argue that Tipu was an apostle of&#xA;secularism and as such respected Hindu religious heads and places of&#xA;worship. Tipu is also identified as among the first nationalists who&#xA;fought against the British to liberate the country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04  4         TIPU SULTAN: AS KNOWN IN KERALA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/04_ch04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/04_ch04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;4&lt;br&gt;&#xA;TIPU SULTAN: AS KNOWN IN KERALA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;RAVI VARMA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of late there has been a concerted attempt to distort and falsify&#xA;recorded Indian history, very often even by painting dark periods of&#xA;Indian history as glorious and progressive, to suit the selfish and&#xA;perverted interests of the ruling clique. One of these attempts relates&#xA;to the life and deeds of Tipu Sultan of Mysore. Most of his active life&#xA;as Sultan of Mysore was spent in Kerala, waging wars of territorial&#xA;annexation and Islamic conversions. Therefore, the true character of&#xA;Tipu Sultan can be best judged from his activities in Kerala. The&#xA;following is an earnest attempt to present Tipu Sultan as known from the&#xA;available records of Kerala history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05  APPENDIX 1         MAPPILAS OF MALABAR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/05_appe01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/05_appe01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APPENDIX 1&lt;br&gt;&#xA;MAPPILAS OF MALABAR&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It would be worthwhile to have some broad idea of the character of&#xA;Mappilas who became notorious after the invasion of Kerala by Hyder Ali&#xA;and Tipu Sultan. The following notes are based on the documented history&#xA;of the period contained in. the &lt;em&gt;Malabar Manual&lt;/em&gt; of William Logan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2. The Mappilas had not dared to disobey their Hindu Rajas before the&#xA;advent of Mysore Sultans with their Islamic brutalities in Kerala. But&#xA;having joined hands with Hyder Ali and Tipu Sultan, they assisted them&#xA;in all their Islamic atrocities against the Hindu population. Since the&#xA;whole of Malabar was divided into a number of independent&#xA;principalities, the Mysore Sultans who had a huge army and powerful&#xA;field-guns, had no difficulty in subjugating the tiny kingdoms one by&#xA;one. The Mysore army was defeated only when it attacked Travancore which&#xA;by then was a big state, and had acquired superior field-guns and a&#xA;trained army&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06  APPENDIX 2         NEDUMKOTTA: TRAVANCORE DEFENCE FORTIFICATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/06_appe02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/06_appe02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APPENDIX 2&lt;br&gt;&#xA;NEDUMKOTTA: TRAVANCORE DEFENCE FORTIFICATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Nedumkotta was a defence fortification constructed along the&#xA;northern borders of the erstwhile Travancore State. It passed through&#xA;the territories of the then Cochin State.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Nedumkotta was built primarily to resist the invasion under Hyder&#xA;Ali Khan against Travancore State. It was raised mainly with clay and&#xA;mud, and reinforced with stones, laterite and granite at strategic&#xA;places. It started from the Krishan Kotta on the west coast, above&#xA;Kodungallur, and stretched upto the Annamalai Hills on the Western&#xA;Ghats. It was about 48 km long, twenty feet wide and twelve feet high.&#xA;Its alignment was along the Periyar river on the west coast upto&#xA;Chalakudy from where it went along the Chalakudy river upto the&#xA;Annamalai Hills in the east. There were underground cells to store&#xA;gunpowder and other war materials, special chambers for soldiers to&#xA;live, and look-outs and mounted field-guns all along the fortification.&#xA;Besides, on the north side of the fortification, ditches were dug twenty&#xA;feet wide and sixteen feet deep, and filled with thorny plants,&#xA;poisonous snakes, and hidden weapons. On the south side as well as on&#xA;the top of the fortification, wide roads were laid for the convenience&#xA;of military movements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08  5         SCANDALOUS TELE-SERIAL ON TIPU SULTAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/08_ch05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/08_ch05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;5&lt;br&gt;&#xA;SCANDALOUS TELE-SERIAL ON TIPU SULTAN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PRAKASH CHANDRA ASDHIR&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Should a serial on Tipu be telecast?&amp;rdquo; - this question deserves the&#xA;attention of every Hindu.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The points made out by a progressive Muslim, Asghar Ali Engineer, in&#xA;support of the telecast of the serial, &amp;lsquo;The Sword of Tipu Sultan&amp;quot;, are&#xA;really very interesting. He bluntly states, &amp;ldquo;The Sword of Tipu Sultan&#xA;may be a historical novel, and the story may be somewhat different from&#xA;actual history. After all, the author is at liberty to portray the&#xA;characters as he wishes and tell his story in any fashion - to depict&#xA;the central figure (Tipu) in a positive or romantic or negative light.&#xA;And in this case, if the writer, Bhagwan Gidwani, has chosen to ignore&#xA;or underplay some of the more unpleasant aspects of the ruler and the&#xA;regime, he is well within his rights as a writer of fiction to do so. He&#xA;cannot be condemned even if he has restricted his research to buttress&#xA;his view of Tipu.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09  6         TIPU SULTAN: A FANATIC MUSLIM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/09_ch06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/09_ch06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;6&lt;br&gt;&#xA;TIPU SULTAN: A FANATIC MUSLIM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;RAVI VARMA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Union Government&amp;rsquo;s decision to ban the book on Prophet Mohammad&#xA;entitled &lt;em&gt;The Satanic Verses&lt;/em&gt;, by an internationally renowned Muslim&#xA;scholar, Mr. Salman Rushdie, has been described as a shameful surrender&#xA;to the minority lobby of fanatic Muslim leaders like Shahabuddin,&#xA;Sulaiman Sait and Imam Bukhari. Similarly, the internationally acclaimed&#xA;film on Jesus Christ titled &lt;em&gt;Last Temptation of Jesus Christ&lt;/em&gt; has been&#xA;banned in India so that the religious feelings of the tiny though&#xA;powerful Christian community may not be hurt. But what about the&#xA;religious sentiments of seventy crore Hindus in India? Neither the&#xA;socialist and secularist Union Government nor the secularist political&#xA;parties of different hues show any respect for Hindu sentiments. Why?&#xA;Because they do not mind hurting the religious feelings of seventy crore&#xA;Hindus in India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10  7         TIPU SULTAN AND DOORDARSHAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/10_ch07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/10_ch07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;7&lt;br&gt;&#xA;TIPU SULTAN AND DOORDARSHAN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;K. GOVINDAN KUTTY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was Bhagwan Gidwani&amp;rsquo;s obvious intention to extol Tipu Sultan when he&#xA;wrote what he called a &amp;ldquo;historical novel&amp;rdquo; - &lt;em&gt;The Sword of Tipu Sultan&lt;/em&gt;.&#xA;Sanjay Khan&amp;rsquo;s approach to the subject could not have been different when&#xA;he embarked on his controversial tele-film project based on Mr.&#xA;Gidwani&amp;rsquo;s book. Whether their adulation of Tipu is consistent with facts&#xA;of history is what an expert panel set up by the Ministry of information&#xA;and Broadcasting is supposed to determine. But Doordarshan&amp;rsquo;s predicament&#xA;is that it may still not be able to telecast &amp;lsquo;The Sword of Tipu Sultan&amp;rsquo;&#xA;without intensifying Hindu resentment in Kerala where considerable&#xA;sections of people regard the &amp;ldquo;Tiger of Mysore&amp;rdquo; as an inveterate&#xA;tormentor, and a symbol of religious bigotry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11  8         THE TELE-SERIAL ON TIPU SULTAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/11_ch08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/11_ch08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;8&lt;br&gt;&#xA;THE TELE-SERIAL ON TIPU SULTAN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;P. PARAMESWARAN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In normal course, Doordarshan should have full freedom to telecast any&#xA;serial which is not against the interest of the general public. But&#xA;here, the problem is not a novel. It is the distorted presentation of&#xA;historical events and historical personalities. In the process of&#xA;projecting certain people in glorifying terms, an attempt is also being&#xA;made to deliberately defame certain other people. When it is mixed with&#xA;a dose of religious fanaticism, it becomes dangerous. It could lead to&#xA;religious conflicts. Is it not better to avoid such personalities?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12  9         A LETTER TO SHRI P. UPENDRA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/12_ch09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/12_ch09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;9&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A LETTER TO SHRI P. UPENDRA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DR. P.C.C. RAJA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Shri P. Upendra,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Hon&amp;rsquo;ble Minister for Information &amp;amp; Broadcasting,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Government of India,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sir,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am a member of the Zamorin&amp;rsquo;s family, Calicut. As you are perhaps&#xA;aware, the Zamorin of Calicut was the ruler of Calicut before the advent&#xA;of the British. I am a retired Headmaster of the Zamorin&amp;rsquo;s High School,&#xA;Calicut. At present I am a practising Homeopathic physician. I am aged&#xA;79 years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13  10         HIGHLIGHT OF AGITATION AGAINST THE TIPU SULTAN SERIAL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/13_ch10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/13_ch10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;10&lt;br&gt;&#xA;HIGHLIGHT OF AGITATION AGAINST THE TIPU SULTAN SERIAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.N. JOG&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Three years back, one news item which appeared on the pages of many&#xA;dailies attracted my attention. The news item was about a big&#xA;studio-fire in Bangalore, where shooting of Shri Sanjay Khan&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;tele-serial, &amp;ldquo;The Sword of Tipu Sultan&amp;rdquo; was in progress. Scores of young&#xA;artistes died and many others were injured in the studio-fire. While&#xA;going through the press report, I was amazed to read that &amp;ldquo;in this TV&#xA;serial Tipu Sultan is being depicted as a great warrior and secular&#xA;benevolent ruler&amp;rdquo;. Tipu Sultan who forcibly converted thousands of&#xA;Hindus and Christians to Islam, hanged to death hundreds of innocent&#xA;women and children, and destroyed and looted scores of temples and&#xA;churches in Malabar, Cochin, Coorg, Dindigal, Mangalore and Coimbatore,&#xA;a secular, fair-minded ruler! Hypocrisy also must have some limit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14  11         HISTORY OF LEGAL BATTLE AGAINST THE T.V. SERIAL - The Sword of Tipu Sultan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/14_ch11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/14_ch11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;11&lt;br&gt;&#xA;HISTORY OF LEGAL BATTLE AGAINST THE T.V. SERIAL - The Sword of Tipu&#xA;Sultan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Madhavrao D. Pathak, Advocate&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The legal fight against the shameful and motivated attempt of&#xA;Doordarshan and the Government of India to project the usurper king of&#xA;Mysore, Tipu Sultan, as a national hero, was a long, expensive and&#xA;frustrating ordeal. According to authentic and documented history of the&#xA;period, Tipu Sultan had hanged to death and sold as slaves a large&#xA;number of innocent men, women, and children; looted and destroyed and&#xA;burnt down hundreds of Hindu temples and Christian churches; and&#xA;circumcised and converted to Muhammadanism thousands of Hindus and&#xA;Christians in Mangalore, Coorg, Coimbatore, Dindigal, and Kerala. He had&#xA;made territorial concessions to the French whose help he sought to fight&#xA;the British. He had also sent emissaries to Islamic countries -&#xA;Afghanistan, Iran, and Turky - inviting them to conquer the whole of&#xA;North India for the glory and spread of Islam. But the Doordarshan&#xA;serial on Tipu Sultan, based on a novel entitled &lt;em&gt;The Sword of Tipu&#xA;Sultan&lt;/em&gt; by Bhagwan Gidwani, was full of deliberate distortion,&#xA;fabrication, and suppression of recorded facts of history with the&#xA;object of glorifying a villain as a national hero, a benevolent ruler,&#xA;and a paragon of all virtues.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2. The Petitioners objected to and protested against Doordarshan&#xA;misusing the official media network to telecast a controversial serial&#xA;full of lies, distortions and white-washed stories about a historical&#xA;figure who was hated all over South India for his heinous crimes and&#xA;cruelties in the service of Islam. This was bound to mislead the&#xA;gullible general public into believing that a treacherous and cruel&#xA;Islamic bigot was a renowned national hero - travesty of truth which is&#xA;against the very spirit and purpose for which the Doordarshan was set&#xA;up. It was for these reasons that the Petitioners requested the Bombay&#xA;High Court (later the Supreme Court also) to restrain the Government of&#xA;India and Doordarshan from telecasting the Tipu Serial based on the&#xA;dubious novel of Bhagwan Gidwani. They asked the Court to direct the&#xA;Doordarshan to project the character of Tipu Sultan based on his real&#xA;life known from the recorded history of South India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15  APPENDIX         IN THE HIGH COURT OF JUDICATURE AT BOMBAY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/15_appe03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/tipu/15_appe03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APPENDIX&lt;br&gt;&#xA;IN THE HIGH COURT OF JUDICATURE AT BOMBAY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Writ Petition No. 5435 of 1989&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dr. Ravindra Ramdas.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mr. Ravi Varma.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mr. R.G. Menon.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mr. P.C.C. Raja.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;. Petitioners&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VERSUS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. The Secretary,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;hellip;.Union of India, Information and Broadcasting Department, New&#xA;Delhi.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;2. Director&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;hellip;.Doordarshan, New Delhi.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;3. Mr. Sanjay Khan.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;4. Union of India,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;hellip;.New Delhi.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;5. Mr. P. Upendra,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;hellip;.Hon&amp;rsquo;ble Minister for Information and Broadcasting Department, New&#xA;Delhi.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;6. Mr. K.R. Malkani,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;hellip;.Deen Dayal Research Institute, New Delhi - 110 019&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
