<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;jnana-yoga on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;jnana-yoga on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>055 THE NECESSITY OF RELIGION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/055_the_necessity_of_religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/055_the_necessity_of_religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-necessity-of-religion&#34;&gt;THE NECESSITY OF RELIGION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in London&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of all the forces that have worked and are still working to mould the&#xA;destinies of the human race, none, certainly, is more potent than that,&#xA;the manifestation of which we call religion. All social organisations&#xA;have as a background, somewhere, the workings of that peculiar force,&#xA;and the greatest cohesive impulse ever brought into play amongst human&#xA;units has been derived from this power. It is obvious to all of us that&#xA;in very many cases the bonds of religion have proved stronger than the&#xA;bonds of race, or climate, or even of descent. It is a well-known fact&#xA;that persons worshipping the same God, believing in the same religion,&#xA;have stood by each other, with much greater strength and constancy, than&#xA;people of merely the same descent, or even brothers. Various attempts&#xA;have been made to trace the beginnings of religion. In all the ancient&#xA;religions which have come down to us at the present day, we find one&#xA;claim made — that they are all supernatural, that their genesis is not,&#xA;as it were, in the human brain, but that they have originated somewhere&#xA;outside of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>056 THE REAL NATURE OF MAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/056_the_real_nature_of_man/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/056_the_real_nature_of_man/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER II&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-real-nature-of-man&#34;&gt;THE REAL NATURE OF MAN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in London&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Great is the tenacity with which man clings to the senses. Yet, however&#xA;substantial he may think the external world in which he lives and moves,&#xA;there comes a time in the lives of individuals and of races when,&#xA;involuntarily, they ask, &amp;ldquo;Is this real?&amp;rdquo; To the person who never finds a&#xA;moment to question the credentials of his senses, whose every moment is&#xA;occupied with some sort of sense-enjoyment — even to him death comes,&#xA;and he also is compelled to ask, &amp;ldquo;Is this real?&amp;rdquo; Religion begins with&#xA;this question and ends with its answer. Even in the remote past, where&#xA;recorded history cannot help us, in the mysterious light of mythology,&#xA;back in the dim twilight of civilisation, we find the same question was&#xA;asked, &amp;ldquo;What becomes of this? What is real?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>057 MAYA AND ILLUSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/057_maya_and_illusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/057_maya_and_illusion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER III&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;maya-and-illusion&#34;&gt;MAYA AND ILLUSION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in London&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Almost all of you have heard of the word Māyā. Generally it is used,&#xA;though incorrectly, to denote illusion, or delusion, or some such thing.&#xA;But the theory of Maya forms one of the pillars upon which the Vedanta&#xA;rests; it is, therefore, necessary that it should be properly&#xA;understood. I ask a little patience of you, for there is a great danger&#xA;of its being misunderstood. The oldest idea of Maya that we find in&#xA;Vedic literature is the sense of delusion; but then the real theory had&#xA;not been reached. We find such passages as, &amp;ldquo;Indra through his Maya&#xA;assumed various forms.&amp;rdquo; Here it is true the word Maya means something&#xA;like magic, and we find various other passages, always taking the same&#xA;meaning. The word Maya then dropped out of sight altogether. But in the&#xA;meantime the idea was developing. Later, the question was raised: &amp;ldquo;Why&#xA;can&amp;rsquo;t we know this secret of the universe?&amp;rdquo; And the answer given was&#xA;very significant: &amp;ldquo;Because we talk in vain, and because we are satisfied&#xA;with the things of the senses, and because we are running after desires;&#xA;therefore, we, as it were, cover the Reality with a mist.&amp;rdquo; Here the word&#xA;Maya is not used at all, but we get the idea that the cause of our&#xA;ignorance is a kind of mist that has come between us and the Truth. Much&#xA;later on, in one of the latest Upanishads, we find the word Maya&#xA;reappearing, but this time, a transformation has taken place in it, and&#xA;a mass of new meaning has attached itself to the word. Theories had been&#xA;propounded and repeated, others had been taken up, until at last the&#xA;idea of Maya became fixed. We read in the Shvetāshvatara Upanishad,&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Know nature to be Maya and the Ruler of this Maya is the Lord Himself.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Coming to our philosophers, we find that this word Maya has been&#xA;manipulated in various fashions, until we come to the great&#xA;Shankarāchārya. The theory of Maya was manipulated a little by the&#xA;Buddhists too, but in the hands of the Buddhists it became very much&#xA;like what is called Idealism, and that is the meaning that is now&#xA;generally given to the word Maya. When the Hindu says the world is Maya,&#xA;at once people get the idea that the world is an illusion. This&#xA;interpretation has some basis, as coming through the Buddhistic&#xA;philosophers, because there was one section of philosophers who did not&#xA;believe in the external world at all. But the Maya of the Vedanta, in&#xA;its last developed form, is neither Idealism nor Realism, nor is it a&#xA;theory. It is a simple statement of facts — what we are and what we see&#xA;around us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>058 MAYA AND THE EVOLUTION OF THE CONCEPTION OF GOD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/058_maya_and_the_evolution_of_the_conception_of_god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/058_maya_and_the_evolution_of_the_conception_of_god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER IV&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;maya-and-the-evolution-of-the-conception-of-god&#34;&gt;MAYA AND THE EVOLUTION OF THE CONCEPTION OF GOD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in London, 20th October 1896&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have seen how the idea of Māyā, which forms, as it were, one of the&#xA;basic doctrines of the Advaita Vedanta, is, in its germs, found even in&#xA;the Samhitās, and that in reality all the ideas which are developed in&#xA;the Upanishads are to be found already in the Samhitas in some form or&#xA;other. Most of you are by this time familiar with the idea of Maya, and&#xA;know that it is sometimes erroneously explained as illusion, so that&#xA;when the universe is said to be Maya, that also has to be explained as&#xA;being illusion. The translation of the word is neither happy nor&#xA;correct. Maya is not a theory; it is simply a statement of facts about&#xA;the universe as it exists, and to understand Maya we must go back to the&#xA;Samhitas and begin with the conception in the germ.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>059 MAYA AND FREEDOM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/059_maya_and_freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/059_maya_and_freedom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER V&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;maya-and-freedom&#34;&gt;MAYA AND FREEDOM&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in London, 22nd October 1896&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Trailing clouds of glory we come,&amp;rdquo; says the poet. Not all of us come as&#xA;trailing clouds of glory however; some of us come as trailing black&#xA;fogs; there can be no question about that. But every one of us comes&#xA;into this world to fight, as on a battlefield. We come here weeping to&#xA;fight our way, as well as we can, and to make a path for ourselves&#xA;through this infinite ocean of life; forward we go, having long ages&#xA;behind us and an immense expanse beyond. So on we go, till death comes&#xA;and takes us off the field — victorious or defeated, we do not know. And&#xA;this is Māyā.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>060 THE ABSOLUTE AND MANIFESTATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/060_the_absolute_and_manifestation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/060_the_absolute_and_manifestation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER VI&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-absolute-and-manifestation&#34;&gt;THE ABSOLUTE AND MANIFESTATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in London, 1896&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The one question that is most difficult to grasp in understanding the&#xA;Advaita philosophy, and the one question that will be asked again and&#xA;again and that will always remain is: How has the Infinite, the&#xA;Absolute, become the finite? I will now take up this question, and, in&#xA;order to illustrate it, I will use a figure. Here is the Absolute (&lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt;),&#xA;and this is the universe (&lt;em&gt;b&lt;/em&gt;). The Absolute has  &lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;chart.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;chart.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;become&#xA;the universe. By this is not only meant the material world, but the&#xA;mental world, the spiritual world — heavens and earths, and in fact,&#xA;everything that exists. Mind is the name of a change, and body the name&#xA;of another change, and so on, and all these changes compose our&#xA;universe. This Absolute (&lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt;) has become the universe (&lt;em&gt;b&lt;/em&gt;) by coming&#xA;through time, space, and causation (&lt;em&gt;c&lt;/em&gt;). This is the central idea of&#xA;Advaita. Time, space, and causation are like the glass through which the&#xA;Absolute is seen, and when It is seen on the lower side, It appears as&#xA;the universe. Now we at once gather from this that in the Absolute there&#xA;is neither time, space, nor causation. The idea of time cannot be there,&#xA;seeing that there is no mind, no thought. The idea of space cannot be&#xA;there, seeing that there is no external change. What you call motion and&#xA;causation cannot exist where there is only One. We have to understand&#xA;this, and impress it on our minds, that what we call causation begins&#xA;after, if we may be permitted to say so, the degeneration of the&#xA;Absolute into the phenomenal, and not before; that our will, our desire&#xA;and all these things always come &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; that. I think Schopenhauer&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;philosophy makes a mistake in its interpretation of Vedanta, for it&#xA;seeks to make the will everything. Schopenhauer makes the will stand in&#xA;the place of the Absolute. But the absolute cannot be presented as will,&#xA;for will is something changeable and phenomenal, and over the line,&#xA;drawn above time, space, and causation, there is no change, no motion;&#xA;it is only below the line that external motion and internal motion,&#xA;called thought begin. There can be no will on the other side, and will&#xA;therefore, cannot be the cause of this universe. Coming nearer, we see&#xA;in our own bodies that will is not the cause of every movement. I move&#xA;this chair; my will is the cause of this movement, and this will becomes&#xA;manifested as muscular motion at the other end. But the same power that&#xA;moves the chair is moving the heart, the lungs, and so on, but not&#xA;through will. Given that the power is the same, it only becomes will&#xA;when it rises to the plane of consciousness, and to call it will before&#xA;it has risen to this plane is a misnomer. This makes a good deal of&#xA;confusion in Schopenhauer&amp;rsquo;s philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>061 GOD IN EVERYTHING</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/061_god_in_everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/061_god_in_everything/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER VII&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;god-in-everything&#34;&gt;GOD IN EVERYTHING&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in London, 27th October 1896&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have seen how the greater portion of our life must of necessity be&#xA;filled with evils, however we may resist, and that this mass of evil is&#xA;practically almost infinite for us. We have been struggling to remedy&#xA;this since the beginning of time, yet everything remains very much the&#xA;same. The more we discover remedies, the more we find ourselves beset by&#xA;subtler evils. We have also seen that all religions propose a God, as&#xA;the one way of escaping these difficulties. All religions tell us that&#xA;if you take the world as it is, as most practical people would advise us&#xA;to do in this age, then nothing would be left to us but evil. They&#xA;further assert that there is something beyond this world. This life in&#xA;the five senses, life in the material world, is not all; it is only a&#xA;small portion, and merely superficial. Behind and beyond is the Infinite&#xA;in which there is no more evil. Some people call It God, some Allah,&#xA;some Jehovah, Jove, and so on. The Vedantin calls It Brahman.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>062 REALISATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/062_realisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/062_realisation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER VIII&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;realisation&#34;&gt;REALISATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in London, 29th October 1896&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I will read to you from one of the Upanishads. It is called the Katha&#xA;Upanishad. Some of you, perhaps, have read the translation by Sir Edwin&#xA;Arnold, called the Secret of Death. In our last [i.e. a previous]&#xA;lecture we saw how the inquiry which started with the origin of the&#xA;world, and the creation of the universe, failed to obtain a satisfactory&#xA;answer from without, and how it then turned inwards. This book&#xA;psychologically takes up that suggestion, questioning into the internal&#xA;nature of man. It was first asked who created the external world, and&#xA;how it came into being. Now the question is: What is that in man; which&#xA;makes him live and move, and what becomes of that when he dies? The&#xA;first philosophers studied the material substance, and tried to reach&#xA;the ultimate through that. At the best, they found a personal governor&#xA;of the universe, a human being immensely magnified, but yet to all&#xA;intents and purposes a human being. But that could not be the whole of&#xA;truth; at best, it could be only partial truth. We see this universe as&#xA;human beings, and our God is our human explanation of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>063 UNITY IN DIVERSITY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/063_unity_in_diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/063_unity_in_diversity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER IX&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;unity-in-diversity&#34;&gt;UNITY IN DIVERSITY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in London, 3rd November 1896&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Self-existent One projected the senses outwards and, therefore, a&#xA;man looks outward, not within himself. A certain wise one, desiring&#xA;immortality, with inverted senses, perceived the Self within.&amp;rdquo; As I have&#xA;already said, the first inquiry that we find in the Vedas was concerning&#xA;outward things, and then a new idea came that the reality of things is&#xA;not to be found in the external world; not by looking outwards, but by&#xA;turning the eyes, as it is literally expressed, inwards. And the word&#xA;used for the Soul is very significant: it is He who has gone inward, the&#xA;innermost reality of our being, the heart centre, the core, from which,&#xA;as it were, everything comes out; the central sun of which the mind, the&#xA;body, the sense-organs, and everything else we have are but rays going&#xA;outwards. &amp;ldquo;Men of childish intellect, ignorant persons, run after&#xA;desires which are external, and enter the trap of far-reaching death,&#xA;but the wise, understanding immortality, never seek for the Eternal in&#xA;this life of finite things.&amp;rdquo; The same idea is here made clear that in&#xA;this external world, which is full of finite things, it is impossible to&#xA;see and find the Infinite. The Infinite must be sought in that alone&#xA;which is infinite, and the only thing infinite about us is that which is&#xA;within us, our own soul. Neither the body, nor the mind, not even our&#xA;thoughts, nor the world we see around us, are infinite. The Seer, He to&#xA;whom they all belong, the Soul of man, He who is awake in the internal&#xA;man, alone is infinite, and to seek for the Infinite Cause of this whole&#xA;universe we must go there. In the Infinite Soul alone we can find it.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;What is here is there too, and what is there is here also. He who sees&#xA;the manifold goes from death to death.&amp;rdquo; We have seen how at first there&#xA;was the desire to go to heaven. When these ancient Aryans became&#xA;dissatisfied with the world around them, they naturally thought that&#xA;after death they would go to some place where there would be all&#xA;happiness without any misery; these places they multiplied and called&#xA;Svargas — the word may be translated as heavens — where there would be&#xA;joy for ever, the body would become perfect, and also the mind, and&#xA;there they would live with their forefathers. But as soon as philosophy&#xA;came, men found that this was impossible and absurd. The very idea of an&#xA;infinite in place would be a contradiction in terms, as a place must&#xA;begin and continue in time. Therefore they had to give up that idea.&#xA;They found out that the gods who lived in these heavens had once been&#xA;human beings on earth, who through their good works had become gods, and&#xA;the godhoods, as they call them, were different states, different&#xA;positions; none of the gods spoken of in the Vedas are permanent&#xA;individuals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>064 THE FREEDOM OF THE SOUL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/064_the_freedom_of_the_soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/064_the_freedom_of_the_soul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER X&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-freedom-of-the-soul&#34;&gt;THE FREEDOM OF THE SOUL&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in London, 5th November 1896&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Katha Upanishad, which we have been studying, was written much later&#xA;than that to which we now turn — the Chhāndogya. The language is more&#xA;modern, and the thought more organised. In the older Upanishads the&#xA;language is very archaic, like that of the hymn portion of the Vedas,&#xA;and one has to wade sometimes through quite a mass of unnecessary things&#xA;to get at the essential doctrines. The ritualistic literature about&#xA;which I told you which forms the second division of the Vedas, has left&#xA;a good deal of its mark upon this old Upanishad, so that more than half&#xA;of it is still ritualistic. There is, however, one great gain in&#xA;studying the very old Upanishads. You trace, as it were, the historical&#xA;growth of spiritual ideas. In the more recent Upanishads, the spiritual&#xA;ideas have been collected and brought into one place; as in the Bhagavad&#xA;Gitā, for instance, which we may, perhaps, look upon as the last of the&#xA;Upanishads, you do not find any inkling of these ritualistic ideas. The&#xA;Gita is like a bouquet composed of the beautiful flowers of spiritual&#xA;truths collected from the Upanishads. But in the Gita you cannot study&#xA;the rise of the spiritual ideas, you cannot trace them to their source.&#xA;To do that, as has been pointed out by many, you must study the Vedas.&#xA;The great idea of holiness that has been attached to these books has&#xA;preserved them, more than any other book in the world, from mutilation.&#xA;In them, thoughts at their highest and at their lowest have all been&#xA;preserved, the essential and the non-essential, the most ennobling&#xA;teachings and the simplest matters of detail stand side by side; for&#xA;nobody has dared to touch them. Commentators came and tried to smooth&#xA;them down and to bring out wonderful new ideas from the old things; they&#xA;tried to find spiritual ideas in even the most ordinary statements, but&#xA;the texts remained, and as such, they are the most wonderful historical&#xA;study. We all know that in the scriptures of every religion changes were&#xA;made to suit the growing spirituality of later times; one word was&#xA;changed here and another put in there, and so on. This, probably, has&#xA;not been done with the Vedic literature, or if ever done, it is almost&#xA;imperceptible. So we have this great advantage, we are able to study&#xA;thoughts in their original significance, to note how they developed, how&#xA;from materialistic ideas finer and finer spiritual ideas are evolved,&#xA;until they attained their greatest height in the Vedanta. Descriptions&#xA;of some of the old manners and customs are also there, but they do not&#xA;appear much in the Upanishads. The language used is peculiar, terse,&#xA;mnemonic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>065 THE COSMOS: THE MACROCOSM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/065_the_macrocosm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/065_the_macrocosm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER XI&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-cosmos-the-macrocosm&#34;&gt;THE COSMOS: THE MACROCOSM&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in New York, 19th January 1896&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The flowers that we see all around us are beautiful, beautiful is the&#xA;rising of the morning sun, beautiful are the variegated hues of nature.&#xA;The whole universe is beautiful, and man has been enjoying it since his&#xA;appearance on earth. Sublime and awe-inspiring are the mountains; the&#xA;gigantic rushing rivers rolling towards the sea, the trackless deserts,&#xA;the infinite ocean, the starry heavens — all these are awe-inspiring,&#xA;sublime, and beautiful indeed. The whole mass of existence which we call&#xA;nature has been acting on the human mind since time immemorial. It has&#xA;been acting on the thought of man, and as its reaction has come out the&#xA;question: What are these, whence are they? As far back as the time of&#xA;the oldest portion of that most ancient human composition, the Vedas, we&#xA;find the same question asked: &amp;ldquo;Whence is this? When there was neither&#xA;aught nor naught, and darkness was hidden in darkness, who projected&#xA;this universe? How? Who knows the secret?&amp;rdquo; And the question has come&#xA;down to us at the present time. Millions of attempts have been made to&#xA;answer it, yet millions of times it will have to be answered again. It&#xA;is not that each answer was a failure; every answer to this question&#xA;contained a part of truth, and this truth gathers strength as time rolls&#xA;on. I will try to present before you the outline of the answer that I&#xA;have gathered from the ancient philosophers of India; in harmony with&#xA;modern knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>066 THE COSMOS: THE MICROCOSM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/066_the_microcosm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/066_the_microcosm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER XI&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-cosmos-the-microcosm&#34;&gt;THE COSMOS: THE MICROCOSM&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in New York, 26th January 1896&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The human mind naturally wants to get outside, to peer out of the body,&#xA;as it were, through the channels of the organs. The eye must see, the&#xA;ear must hear, the senses must sense the external world — and naturally&#xA;the beauties and sublimities of nature captivate the attention of man&#xA;first. The first questions that arose in the human soul were about the&#xA;external world. The solution of the mystery was asked of the sky, of the&#xA;stars, of the heavenly bodies, of the earth, of the rivers, of the&#xA;mountains, of the ocean; and in all ancient religions we find traces of&#xA;how the groping human mind at first caught at everything external. There&#xA;was a river-god, a sky-god, a cloud-god, a rain-god; everything&#xA;external, all of which we now call the powers of nature, became&#xA;metamorphosed, transfigured, into wills, into gods, into heavenly&#xA;messengers. As the question went deeper and deeper, these external&#xA;manifestations failed to satisfy the human mind, and finally the energy&#xA;turned inward, and the question was asked of man&amp;rsquo;s own soul. From the&#xA;macrocosm the question was reflected back to the microcosm; from the&#xA;external world the question was reflected to the internal. From&#xA;analysing the external nature, man is led to analyse the internal; this&#xA;questioning of the internal man comes with a higher state of&#xA;civilisation, with a deeper insight into nature, with a higher state of&#xA;growth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>067 IMMORTALITY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/067_immortality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/067_immortality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER XII&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;immortality&#34;&gt;IMMORTALITY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in America&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What question has been asked a greater number of times, what idea has&#xA;led men more to search the universe for an answer, what question is&#xA;nearer and dearer to the human heart, what question is more inseparably&#xA;connected with our existence, than this one, the immortality of the&#xA;human soul? It has been the theme of poets and sages, of priests and&#xA;prophets; kings on the throne have discussed it, beggars in the street&#xA;have dreamt of it. The best of humanity have approached it, and the&#xA;worst of men have hoped for it. The interest in the theme has not died&#xA;yet, nor will it die so long as human nature exists. Various answers&#xA;have been presented to the world by various minds. Thousands, again, in&#xA;every period of history have given up the discussion, and yet the&#xA;question remains fresh as ever. Often in the turmoil and struggle of our&#xA;lives we seem to forget it, but suddenly some one dies — one, perhaps,&#xA;whom we loved, one near and dear to our hearts is snatched away from us&#xA;— and the struggle, the din and turmoil of the world around us, cease&#xA;for a moment, and the soul asks the old questions &amp;ldquo;What after this?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;What becomes of the soul?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>068 THE ATMAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/068_the_atman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/068_the_atman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER XIII&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-atman&#34;&gt;THE ATMAN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in America&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many of you have read Max Müller&amp;rsquo;s celebrated book, &lt;em&gt;Three Lectures on&#xA;the Vedanta Philosophy&lt;/em&gt;, and some of you may, perhaps, have read, in&#xA;German, Professor Deussen&amp;rsquo;s book on the same philosophy. In what is&#xA;being written and taught in the West about the religious thought of&#xA;India, one school of Indian thought is principally represented, that&#xA;which is called Advaitism, the monistic side of Indian religion; and&#xA;sometimes it is thought that all the teachings of the Vedas are&#xA;comprised in that one system of philosophy. There are, however, various&#xA;phases of Indian thought; and, perhaps, this non-dualistic form is in&#xA;the minority as compared with the other phases. From the most ancient&#xA;times there have been various sects of thought in India, and as there&#xA;never was a formulated or recognised church or any body of men to&#xA;designate the doctrines which should be believed by each school, people&#xA;were very free to choose their own form, make their own philosophy and&#xA;establish their own sects. We, therefore, find that from the most&#xA;ancient times India was full of religious sects. At the present time, I&#xA;do not know how many hundreds of sects we have in India, and several&#xA;fresh ones are coming into existence every year. It seems that the&#xA;religious activity of that nation is simply inexhaustible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>069 THE ATMAN: ITS BONDAGE AND FREEDOM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/069_the_atman_its_bondage_and_freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/069_the_atman_its_bondage_and_freedom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER XIV&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-atman-its-bondage-and-freedom&#34;&gt;THE ATMAN: ITS BONDAGE AND FREEDOM&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in America&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to the Advaita philosophy, there is only one thing real in the&#xA;universe, which it calls Brahman; everything else is unreal, manifested&#xA;and manufactured out of Brahman by the power of Māyā. To reach back to&#xA;that Brahman is our goal. We are, each one of us, that Brahman, that&#xA;Reality, plus this Maya. If we can get rid of this Maya or ignorance,&#xA;then we become what we really are. According to this philosophy, each&#xA;man consists of three parts — the body, the internal organ or the mind,&#xA;and behind that, what is called the Âtman, the Self. The body is the&#xA;external coating and the mind is the internal coating of the Atman who&#xA;is the real perceiver, the real enjoyer, the being in the body who is&#xA;working the body by means of the internal organ or the mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>070 THE REAL AND THE APPARENT MAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/070_the_real_and_the_apparent_man/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/jnana-yoga/070_the_real_and_the_apparent_man/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER XV&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-real-and-the-apparent-man&#34;&gt;THE REAL AND THE APPARENT MAN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in New York&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here we stand, and our eyes look forward sometimes miles ahead. Man has&#xA;been doing that since he began to think. He is always looking forward,&#xA;looking ahead. He wants to know where he goes even after the dissolution&#xA;of his body. Various theories have been propounded, system after system&#xA;has been brought forward to suggest explanations. Some have been&#xA;rejected, while others have been accepted, and thus it will go on, so&#xA;long as man is here, so long as man thinks. There is some truth in each&#xA;of these systems. There is a good deal of what is not truth in all of&#xA;them. I shall try to place before you the sum and substance, the result,&#xA;of the inquiries in this line that have been made in India. I shall try&#xA;to harmonise the various thoughts on the subject, as they have come up&#xA;from time to time among Indian philosophers. I shall try to harmonise&#xA;the psychologists and the metaphysicians, and, if possible, I shall&#xA;harmonise them with modern scientific thinkers also.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
