<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;writings prose on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;writings prose on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>194 IS THE SOUL IMMORTAL?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/194_is_the_soul_immortal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/194_is_the_soul_immortal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-the-soul-immortal&#34;&gt;IS THE SOUL IMMORTAL?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(The Swamiji&amp;rsquo;s contribution to the discussion of this question, carried&#xA;on in the pages of &lt;em&gt;The New York Morning Advertiser&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;None has power to destroy the unchangeable.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; — Bhagavad-Gitā.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the great Sanskrit epic, the Mahābhārata, the story is told how the&#xA;hero, Yudhishthira, when asked by Dharma to tell what was the most&#xA;wonderful thing in the world, replied, that it was the persistent belief&#xA;of man kind in their own deathlessness in spite of their witnessing&#xA;death everywhere around them almost every moment of their lives. And, in&#xA;fact, this is the most stupendous wonder in human life. In spite of all&#xA;arguments to the contrary urged in different times by different schools,&#xA;in spite of the inability of reason to penetrate the veil of mystery&#xA;which will ever hang between the sensuous and the supersensuous worlds,&#xA;man is thoroughly persuaded that he cannot die.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>195 REINCARNATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/195_reincarnation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/195_reincarnation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reincarnation&#34;&gt;REINCARNATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Contributed to the &lt;em&gt;Metaphysical Magazine&lt;/em&gt;, New York, March, 1895)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Both you and I have passed through many births; you know them not, I&#xA;know them all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; — Bhagavad-Gitā&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of the many riddles that have perplexed the intellect of man in all&#xA;climes and times, the most intricate is himself. Of the myriad mysteries&#xA;that have called forth his energies to struggle for solution from the&#xA;very dawn of history, the most mysterious is his own nature. It is at&#xA;once the most insoluble enigma and the problem of all problems. As the&#xA;starting-point and the repository of all we know and feel and do, there&#xA;never has been, nor will be, a time when man&amp;rsquo;s own nature will cease to&#xA;demand his best and foremost attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>196 ON DR. PAUL DEUSSEN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/196_on_dr_paul_deussen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/196_on_dr_paul_deussen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-dr-paul-deussen&#34;&gt;ON DR. PAUL DEUSSEN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Written for the &lt;em&gt;Brahmavādin&lt;/em&gt;, 1896.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More than a decade has passed since a young German student, one of eight&#xA;children of a not very well-to-do clergyman, heard on a certain day&#xA;Professor Lassen lecturing on a language and literature new — very new&#xA;even at that time — to European scholars, namely, Sanskrit. The lectures&#xA;were of course free; for even now it is impossible for any one in any&#xA;European University to make a living by teaching Sanskrit, unless indeed&#xA;the University backs him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>197 ON PROFESSOR MAX MÜLLER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/197_on_professor_max_muller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/197_on_professor_max_muller/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-professor-max-müller&#34;&gt;ON PROFESSOR MAX MÜLLER&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Written for the &lt;em&gt;Brahmāvadin&lt;/em&gt;, from London, June 6, 1896.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Though the ideal of work of our &lt;em&gt;Brahmavādin&lt;/em&gt; should always be&#xA;&amp;ldquo;कर्मण्येवाधिकारस्ते मा फलेषु कदाचन — To work thou hast the right, but&#xA;never to the fruits thereof&amp;rdquo;, yet no sincere worker passes out of the&#xA;field of activity without making himself known and catching at least a&#xA;few rays of light.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The beginning of our work has been splendid, and the steady earnestness&#xA;shown by our friends is beyond all praise. Sincerity of conviction and&#xA;purity of motive will surely gain the day; and even a small minority,&#xA;armed with these, is surely destined to prevail against all odds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>198 SKETCH OF THE LIFE OF PAVHARI BABA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/198_sketch_of_the_life_of_pavhari_baba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/198_sketch_of_the_life_of_pavhari_baba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;sketch-of-the-life-of-pavhari-baba&#34;&gt;SKETCH OF THE LIFE OF PAVHARI BABA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To help the suffering world was the gigantic task to which the Buddha&#xA;gave prominence, brushing aside for the time being almost all other&#xA;phases of religion; yet he had to spend years in self-searching to&#xA;realise the great truth of the utter hollowness of clinging to a selfish&#xA;individuality. A more unselfish and untiring worker is beyond our most&#xA;sanguine imagination: yet who had harder struggles to realise the&#xA;meaning of things than he? It holds good in all times that the greater&#xA;the work, the more must have been the power of realisation behind.&#xA;Working out the details of an already laid out masterly plan may not&#xA;require much concentrated thought to back it, but the great impulses are&#xA;only transformed great concentrations. The theory alone perhaps is&#xA;sufficient for small exertions, but the push that creates the ripple is&#xA;very different from the impulsion that raises the wave, and yet the&#xA;ripple is only the embodiment of a bit of the power that generates the&#xA;wave.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>199 ARYANS AND TAMILIANS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/199_aryans_and_tamilians/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/199_aryans_and_tamilians/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;aryans-and-tamilians&#34;&gt;ARYANS AND TAMILIANS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A veritable ethnological museum! Possibly, the half-ape skeleton of the&#xA;recently discovered Sumatra link will be found on search here, too. The&#xA;Dolmens are not wanting. Flint implements can be dug out almost&#xA;anywhere. The lake-dwellers — at least the river-dwellers — must have&#xA;been abundant at one time. The cave-men and leaf-wearers still persist.&#xA;The primitive hunters living in forests are in evidence in various parts&#xA;of the country. Then there are the more historical varieties — the&#xA;Negrito-Kolarian, the Dravidian, and the Aryan. To these have been added&#xA;from time to time dashes of nearly all the known races, and a great many&#xA;yet unknown — various breeds of Mongoloids, Mongols, Tartars, and the&#xA;so-called Aryans of the philologists. Well, here are the Persian, the&#xA;Greek, the Yunchi, the Hun, the Chin, the Scythian, and many more,&#xA;melted and fused, the Jews, Parsees, Arabs, Mongols, down to the&#xA;descendants of the Vikings and the lords of the German forests, yet&#xA;undigested — an ocean of humanity, composed of these race-waves&#xA;seething, boiling, struggling, constantly changing form, rising to the&#xA;surface, and spreading, and swallowing little ones, again subsiding —&#xA;this is the history of India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>200 THE SOCIAL CONFERENCE ADDRESS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/200_the_social_conference_address/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/200_the_social_conference_address/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-social-conference-address&#34;&gt;THE SOCIAL CONFERENCE ADDRESS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;God created the native, God created the European, but somebody else&#xA;created the mixed breed&amp;rdquo; — we heard a horribly blasphemous Englishman&#xA;say.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before us lies the inaugural address of Mr. Justice Ranade, voicing the&#xA;reformatory zeal of the Indian Social Conference. In it there is a huge&#xA;array of instances of inter-caste marriages of yore, a good leaf about&#xA;the liberal spirit of the ancient Kshatriyas, good sober advice to&#xA;students, all expressed with an earnestness of goodwill and gentleness&#xA;of language that is truly admirable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>201 INDIA&#39;S MESSAGE TO THE WORLD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/201_indias_message_to_the_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/201_indias_message_to_the_world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;indias-message-to-the-world&#34;&gt;INDIA&amp;rsquo;S MESSAGE TO THE WORLD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following notes were discovered among Swami Vivekananda&amp;rsquo;s papers. He&#xA;intended to write a book and jotted down forty-two points as a syllabus&#xA;for the work, but only a few points were dealt with as an introduction&#xA;by him and the work was left unfinished. We give the manuscript as&#xA;found.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SYLLABUS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. Bold has been my message to the people of the West. Bolder to those&#xA;at home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>202 STRAY REMARKS ON THEOSOPHY </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/202_stray_remarks_on_theosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/202_stray_remarks_on_theosophy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;stray-remarks-on-theosophy&#34;&gt;STRAY REMARKS ON THEOSOPHY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Found among Swami Vivekananda&amp;rsquo;s papers.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Theosophists are having a jubilee time of it this year, and several&#xA;press-notices are before us of their goings and doings for the last&#xA;twenty-five years.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nobody has a right now to say that the Hindus are not liberal to a&#xA;fault. A coterie of young Hindus has been found to welcome even this&#xA;graft of American Spiritualism, with its panoply of taps and raps and&#xA;hitting back and forth with Mahātmic pellets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>203 REPLY TO THE ADDRESS OF THE MAHARAJA OF KHETRI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/203_reply_to_the_maharaja_of_khetri/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/203_reply_to_the_maharaja_of_khetri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chronology &lt;a href=&#34;../../volume_7/epistles_third_series/29_dear.htm&#34;&gt;»&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply-to-the-address-of-the-maharaja-of-khetri&#34;&gt;REPLY TO THE ADDRESS OF THE MAHARAJA OF KHETRI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;INDIA — THE LAND OF RELIGION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the residence of the Swamiji in America, the following Address&#xA;from the Maharaja of Khetri (Rajputana), dated March 4th, 1895, was&#xA;received by him:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My dear Swamiji,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the head of this Durbar (a formal stately assemblage) held today for&#xA;this special purpose, I have much pleasure in conveying to you, in my&#xA;own name and that of my subjects, the heartfelt thanks of this State for&#xA;your worthy representation of Hinduism at the Parliament of Religions,&#xA;held at Chicago, in America.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>204 REPLY TO THE MADRAS ADDRESS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/204_reply_to_the_madras_address/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/204_reply_to_the_madras_address/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply-to-the-madras-address&#34;&gt;REPLY TO THE MADRAS ADDRESS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(When the success of the Swami in America became well known in India,&#xA;several meetings were held and addresses of thanks and congratulations&#xA;were forwarded to him. The first reply which he wrote was that to the&#xA;Address of the Hindus of Madras.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FRIENDS, FELLOW-COUNTRYMEN AND CO-RELIGIONISTS OF MADRAS,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is most gratifying to me to find that my insignificant service to the&#xA;cause of our religion has been acceptable to you, not because it is as a&#xA;personal appreciation of me and my work in a foreign and distant land,&#xA;but as a sure sign that, though whirlwind after whirlwind of foreign&#xA;invasion has passed over the devoted head of India, though centuries of&#xA;neglect on our part and contempt on the part of our conquerors have&#xA;visibly dimmed the glories of ancient Âryāvarta, though many a stately&#xA;column on which it rested, many a beautiful arch, and many a marvellous&#xA;corner have been washed away by the inundations that deluged the land&#xA;for centuries — the centre is all sound, the keystone is unimpaired. The&#xA;spiritual foundation upon which the marvellous monument of glory to God&#xA;and charity to all beings has been reared stands unshaken, strong as&#xA;ever. Your generous appreciation of Him whose message to India and to&#xA;the whole world, I, the most unworthy of His servants, had the privilege&#xA;to bear shows your innate spiritual instinct which saw in Him and His&#xA;message the first murmurs of that tidal wave of spirituality which is&#xA;destined at no distant future to break upon India in all its&#xA;irresistible powers, carrying away in its omnipotent flood all that is&#xA;weak and defective, and raising the Hindu race to the platform it is&#xA;destined to occupy in the providence of God, crowned with more glory&#xA;than it ever had even in the past, the reward of centuries of silent&#xA;suffering, and fulfilling its mission amongst the races of the world —&#xA;the evolution of spiritual humanity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>205 A MESSAGE OF SYMPATHY TO A FRIEND</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/205_a_message_of_sympathy_to_a_friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/205_a_message_of_sympathy_to_a_friend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chronology &lt;a href=&#34;../../volume_6/epistles_second_series/039_mother.htm&#34;&gt;»&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-message-of-sympathy-to-a-friend&#34;&gt;A MESSAGE OF SYMPATHY TO A FRIEND&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Written from Bombay on 23rd May, 1893 to D. R. Balaji Rao who just had&#xA;a severe domestic affliction.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Naked came I out of my mother&amp;rsquo;s womb, and naked shall I return thither;&#xA;the Lord gave and the Lord hath taken away; blessed be the name of the&#xA;Lord.&amp;rdquo; Thus said the old Jewish saint when suffering the greatest&#xA;calamities that could befall man, and he erred not. Herein lies the&#xA;whole secret of Existence. Waves may roll over the surface and tempest&#xA;rage, but deep down there is the stratum of infinite calmness, infinite&#xA;peace, and infinite bliss. &amp;ldquo;Blessed are they that mourn, for they shall&#xA;be comforted.&amp;rdquo; And why? Because it is during these moments of&#xA;visitations when the heart is wrung by hands which never stop for the&#xA;father&amp;rsquo;s cries or the mother&amp;rsquo;s wail, when under the load of sorrow,&#xA;dejection, and despair, the world seems to be cut off from under our&#xA;feet, and when the whole horizon seems to be nothing but an impenetrable&#xA;sheet of misery and utter despair — that the internal eyes open, light&#xA;flashes all of a sudden, the dream vanishes, and intuitively we come&#xA;face to face with the grandest mystery in nature — Existence. Yes, then&#xA;it is — when the load would be sufficient to sink a lot of frail vessels&#xA;— that the man of genius, of strength, the hero, sees that infinite,&#xA;absolute, ever-blissful Existence &lt;em&gt;per se&lt;/em&gt;, that infinite being who is&#xA;called and worshipped under different names in different climes. Then it&#xA;is, the shackles that bind the soul down to this hole of misery break,&#xA;as it were, for a time, and unfettered it rises and rises until it&#xA;reaches the throne of the Lord, &amp;ldquo;Where the wicked cease from troubling&#xA;and the weary are at rest&amp;rdquo;. Cease not, brother, to send up petitions day&#xA;and night, cease not to say day and night — THY WILL BE DONE.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>206 WHAT WE BELIEVE IN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/206_what_we_believe_in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/206_what_we_believe_in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Addressee &lt;a href=&#34;../../volume_5/epistles_first_series/015_kidi.htm&#34;&gt;»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-believe-in&#34;&gt;WHAT WE BELIEVE IN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Written to &amp;ldquo;Kidi&amp;rdquo; on March 3, 1894, from Chicago.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I agree with you so far that faith is a wonderful insight and that it&#xA;alone can save; but there is the danger in it of breeding fanaticism and&#xA;barring further progress.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jnāna is all right; but there is the danger of its becoming dry&#xA;intellectualism. Love is great and noble; but it may die away in&#xA;meaningless sentimentalism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>207 OUR DUTY TO THE MASSES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/207_our_duty_to_the_masses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/207_our_duty_to_the_masses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-duty-to-the-masses&#34;&gt;OUR DUTY TO THE MASSES&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Written from Chicago to H. H. the Maharaja of Mysore on June 23, 1894.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shri Nārāyana bless you and yours. Through your Highness&amp;rsquo; kind help it&#xA;has been possible for me to come to this country. Since then I have&#xA;become well known here, and the hospitable people of this country have&#xA;supplied all my wants. It is a wonderful country, and this is a&#xA;wonderful nation in many respects. No other nation applies so much&#xA;machinery in their everyday work as do the people of this country.&#xA;Everything is machine. Then again, they are only one-twentieth of the&#xA;whole population of the world. Yet they have fully one-sixth of all the&#xA;wealth of the world. There is no limit to their wealth and luxuries. Yet&#xA;everything here is so dear. The wages of labour are the highest in the&#xA;world; yet the fight between labour and capital is constant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>208 REPLY TO THE CALCUTTA ADDRESS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/208_reply_to_the_calcutta_address/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/208_reply_to_the_calcutta_address/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply-to-the-calcutta-address&#34;&gt;REPLY TO THE CALCUTTA ADDRESS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Written from New York on Nov. 18, 1894, to Raja Pyari Mohan Mukherji,&#xA;President of the public meeting held on Sept. 5, 1894 at the Calcutta&#xA;Town Hall in appreciation of Swami Vivekananda&amp;rsquo;s work in the West.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am in receipt of the resolutions that were passed at the recent Town&#xA;Hall meeting in Calcutta and the kind words my fellow-citizens sent over&#xA;to me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>209 TO MY BRAVE BOYS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/209_to_my_brave_boys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/209_to_my_brave_boys/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-my-brave-boys&#34;&gt;TO MY BRAVE BOYS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Written to Alasinga Perumal from New York on 19th November, 1894.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Push on with the organization. Nothing else is necessary but these —&#xA;&lt;em&gt;love, sincerity, and patience&lt;/em&gt;. What is life but growth, i.e.&#xA;expansion, i.e. love? Therefore all love is life, it is the only law of&#xA;life; all selfishness is death, and this is true here or hereafter. It&#xA;is life to do good, it is death not to do good to others. Ninety per&#xA;cent of human brutes you see are dead, are ghosts — for none lives, my&#xA;boys, but he who loves. Feel, my children, feel; feel for the poor, the&#xA;ignorant, the downtrodden; feel till the heart stops and the brain reels&#xA;and you think you will go mad — then pour the soul out at the feet of&#xA;the Lord, and then will come power, help, and indomitable energy.&#xA;Struggle, struggle, was my motto for the last ten years. Struggle, still&#xA;say I. When it was all dark, I used to say, struggle; when light is&#xA;breaking in, I still say, struggle. Be not afraid, my children. Look not&#xA;up in that attitude of fear towards that infinite starry vault as if it&#xA;would crush you. Wait! In a few hours more, the whole of it will be&#xA;under your feet. Wait, money does not pay, nor name; fame does not pay,&#xA;nor learning. It is love that pays; it is character that cleaves its way&#xA;through adamantine walls of difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>210 A PLAN OF WORK FOR INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/210_a_plan_of_work_for_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/210_a_plan_of_work_for_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-plan-of-work-for-india&#34;&gt;A PLAN OF WORK FOR INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Written to Justice Sir Subrahmanya Iyer from Chicago, 3rd Jan., 1895.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is with a heart full of love, gratitude, and trust that I take up my&#xA;pen to write to you. Let me tell you first, that you are one of the few&#xA;men that I have met in my life who are thorough in their convictions.&#xA;You have a whole-souled possession of a wonderful combination of feeling&#xA;and knowledge, and withal a practical ability to bring ideas into&#xA;realised forms. Above all, you are sincere, and as such I confide to you&#xA;some of my ideas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>211 FUNDAMENTALS OF RELIGION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/211_fundamentals_of_religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/writings_prose/211_fundamentals_of_religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;fundamentals-of-religion&#34;&gt;FUNDAMENTALS OF RELIGION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This incomplete article was found in the papers of Miss S. E. Waldo.&#xA;The heading is inserted by us — &lt;em&gt;Publisher&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My mind can best grasp the religions of the world, ancient or modern,&#xA;dead or living, through this fourfold division:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. Symbology — The employment of various external aids to preserve and&#xA;develop the religious faculty of man.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2. History — The philosophy of each religion as illustrated in the&#xA;lives of divine or human teachers acknowledged by each religion. This&#xA;includes mythology; for what is mythology to one race, or period, is or&#xA;was history to other races or periods. Even in cases of human teachers,&#xA;much of their history is taken as mythology by successive generations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
