<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Demographic miracle 2025</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/demographic-miracle-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/demographic-miracle-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1885685628479684769.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thread by @HeTows on Thread Reader App – Thread Reader App&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know what the explanation of the &amp;ldquo;Israeli demographic miracle&amp;rdquo; is, but I know this: its only truly miraculous component is one of the seemingly least impressive ones. Namely, secular Jewish TFR, which isn&amp;rsquo;t sky-high but merely hovers around replacement level.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Israel&amp;rsquo;s high fertility (a TFR close to 3, completely unique in the developed world) is often discussed in vague, general terms, linking the phenomenon to religion, nationalism, and &amp;ldquo;siege mentality&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s often ignored that Israel is an archipalego of several different tribes. Most of these &amp;ldquo;tribes&amp;rdquo; have fertility levels that are completely unremarkable when compared to similar groups in other countries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fakhrizadeh kill</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/fakhrizadeh-kill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/fakhrizadeh-kill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/Schandillia/status/1836444524144668803&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[THE FORGOTTEN MASTERSTROKE]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1/25&#xA;Wires, electronics, explosives, and other wares were smuggled into Iran over the course of a year. Covertly. One small piece at a time. All meant for in situ assembly. When finally put together, the contraption weighed nearly a ton. At its heart was a Belgian-made FN MAG machine gun.&#xA;Image&#xA;2/25&#xA;As should be an easy guess, this was in preparation for an assassination. The year was 2020. Target? A high-profile IRGC asset, big enough to enjoy the highest levels of State protection. You likely guessed Qasem Soleimani, the commander of the Quds Force, but you’re wrong.&#xA;3/25&#xA;This was someone else, just as important to the Islamic regime, if not more, but remarkably under popular radar. Soleimani was taken in January, on foreign soil. This one would meet his fate in November.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel as a client state</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/israel-client-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/israel-client-state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rattibha.com/thread/1504159435190505474?lang=en&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Israel 🇮🇱 is Client state of US/West, with more Sovereignty and Slightly independent foreign policy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll also look at the reasons for slightly more Sovereignty- Many people told me that Israel is Sovereign country, Well lemme tell ya that it&amp;rsquo;s not. It&amp;rsquo;s pure client state of US/West and there is no harm accepting this truth. A client state is a state which is subservient to powerful state or dependent politically, economically, and Militarily on bigger power. There are many names to this term like Vassal state, satellite state, dominion state etc. Depending on situations we use different names.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Midanite &amp; canaanite - YHWH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/midanite_canaanite_yhwh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/midanite_canaanite_yhwh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/KeniteYahwism&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;rechabite&#34;&gt;Rechabite&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Rechabites were a small religious sect that lived during the time of Jeremiah (Jeremiah 35). They were descended from the Kenites according to the book of Chronicles (1 Chronicles 2:55). They were Yahwists who lived in tents, did not practice agriculture and abstained from alcohol. They rejected the culture of Canaan especially the worship of Baal. Their strictness may have been a reaction to the policies of Ahab (his support of Baal worship).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
