<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Sword</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-09-16_the-sword/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-09-16_the-sword/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/09/16/the-sword/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;nakula the 4th pANDava asked the kuru grandsire on his arrowy death bed&#xA;about the origin of the sword. nakula said that he believed that the&#xA;sword was a superior weapon and even if one lost his bow or horse or&#xA;chariot one could still defend himself against mace and spear wielders&#xA;if one were a good swordsman.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;bhIshma replied that he was excited beyond words by that question and&#xA;began to utter a narrative.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hindu Armies: the forgotten struggle against the Moslems</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-04-19_hindu-armies-the-forgotten-struggle-against-the-mo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-04-19_hindu-armies-the-forgotten-struggle-against-the-mo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/04/19/hindu-armies-the-forgotten-struggle-against-the-moslems/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Indian text books written by secular historians, have often highlighted the fact that the Hindu armies crumbled like fresh cookies against the armies of the Moslems, and the Moslems more or less easily occupied India. What they fail to tell us is the valor of the Hindus in their spirited struggle against the Moslems. We need to repeatedly remember these great unsung heroes of the Hindu struggle. Our culture is still alive today because of the brave sacrifices of these great Hindu fighters who placed themselves in the path of the murderous Moslem warriors. Often the only option to death on the battle field was death by gory torture or forcible conversion to Islam. The saddest tragedy of this is that many modern Hindus simply do not want to remember and learn from the sacrifices of these predecessors of theirs because of the evil of secularism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bow-making in Hindu lore</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/MT_lekhAH/2003-08-20_bow-making-in-hindu-lore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/MT_lekhAH/2003-08-20_bow-making-in-hindu-lore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/08/20/bow-making-in-hindu-lore/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The making of the bow is discussed in dhanurveda.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It states that a bow should have 3 material: iron, horn and wood and&#xA;should be 4 cubits in length. The Bow string is supposed to be made of&#xA;bamboo fiber, hide or bark fiber. The middle part is recommended to have&#xA;grip for the hand. The shape should be that of the “eye brows of a&#xA;beautiful damsel” . A good bow is supposed to be made of a composite of&#xA;horn, metal and wood. The good horns for a bow were said to be those of&#xA;the buffalo, the rohisha deer and the recommended trees for the wood are&#xA;the sAl, chandana, cane, dhavala or kakubha.. The tips of the bow termed&#xA;Artni were made from horn reinforced with iron. The body was made with a&#xA;combination of wood and horn or iron and horn. Additionally, Hindus also&#xA;made an all iron or all bronze bow. From the hymns of the atharva veda&#xA;one may infer that a composite bow was being refered to. So it is likely&#xA;that the composite bow goes back to the early Aryan period. Thus the&#xA;composite bow is unlikely to have been introduced to India by the hUnas,&#xA;chInas, mlecchas or pahAlavans. The all metal bow could be perpetually&#xA;kept strung and used a ready weapon for assault like a pistol. The&#xA;Hindus also appear to have wielded the bow with a thumb ring and used a&#xA;leather guard to protect agains the bow string abrading the hand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Hindu contribution: the war elephant</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/MT_lekhAH/2003-08-19_a-hindu-contribution-the-war-elephant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/MT_lekhAH/2003-08-19_a-hindu-contribution-the-war-elephant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/08/19/a-hindu-contribution-the-war-elephant/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It has often been stated that many of the martial failures of Hindus has&#xA;been due to the use of ponderous and slothful elephants in war. However,&#xA;the Indians seem to have persisted with elephants until very recently.&#xA;They first started using elephants right at the dawn of their&#xA;civilization in the Indus period. What is the truth behind the&#xA;elephant’s utility?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;“bhagadatta on his elephant, supratika, showering arrows on his foes,&#xA;looked like the resplendent Sun scattering his rays on the earth… Like a&#xA;cowherd driving his cattle in the forest, bhagadatta charged on his&#xA;elephant repeatedly smiting the pANDava host. Like the cawing of&#xA;confused crows when assailed by hawks and a loud noise was heard amidst&#xA;the pANDava troops who fled away in great speed. That prince of&#xA;elephants urged on by bhagadatta, with his a~Nkusha, looked like a&#xA;winged mount of yore. It filled the pANDu host with the fear sailing&#xA;merchants feel at the sight of the swelling ocean. The elephants,&#xA;chariot warriors, cavalrymen, flying in fear made an awful din that&#xA;filled heaven, earth and the cardinal points. Mounted on that foremost&#xA;elephant, rAja bhagadatta of pragjyotisha (Assam), pierced the hostile&#xA;army like the fierce asura virochana entered the deva battle-array in&#xA;the days of yore. In fear the people felt that one had multiplied into&#xA;many and was coursing all over their ranks.— Mbh. droNa parvA 24″&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Thus did the king bhagadatta, an ally of duryodhana pierce the pANDava&#xA;host on the 12th day of the great bhArata war, wreaking much havoc,&#xA;before he was slain by arjuna.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
