<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Rjrashva on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Rjrashva on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Carrying-capacity &amp; colonization</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/carrying-capacity_colonization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/carrying-capacity_colonization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Rjrasva comment&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Edo Japan land was maxxed to direct food production which is why it could feed 30 million. If they used draft animals they 1st had to feed the oxen. This is why draft animals &amp;amp; wheeled transport slowly disappeared in Edo era though they were more frequent earlier.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;30 million seems to be the natural pre industrial carrying capacity of Kyushu + Honshu + Shikoku because it hit that by mid 1700&amp;rsquo;s iirc &amp;amp; for the next century. The population barely grew due to famines like Tenmei (1782-1788) or limiting family size through abortion &amp;amp; infanticide due to poverty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contra sugar for copper</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/contra_sugar_for_copper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/contra_sugar_for_copper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kudo Heisuke&amp;rsquo;s daughter.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;From Hitori Kangae by Tadano Makuzu, 1818&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is lamentable about our country&amp;rsquo;s shallow ways is that people feel that they are knowledgeable simply if they read Chinese and Japanese books and study long-established things. No one talks about the need to reflect on the situation of the country as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thinking about why this should be so, I concluded that, rich in material goods and with abundant pleasures available, people fritter away their time in amusements.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Or else, as people work at this and try to correct that, the years pass,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and even if they come up with some ideas in their old age,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;there is no one with whom to discuss them,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;so in the end their ideas come to naught.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diet</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/diet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nonveg that people had in early Meiji &amp;amp; Edo era in interiors away from waterbodies (like Lake Biwa) was rice grasshoppers (a serious pest) &amp;amp; wasps (still eaten in rural Gifu). Seafood for interiors had to wait till transport &amp;amp; refrigeration advances.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edo east japan depopulation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/edo-east-japan-depopulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/edo-east-japan-depopulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Rjrasva (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Edo era, Eastern Japan had low TFR(or more accurately infant survival) rates due to infanticide&amp;amp; abortion. Depop was serious so by late Edo there was pregnancy surveillance, subsidies, &amp;amp; immigration (from domains without this issue)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Which is y it makes me laugh when people just project current trends linearly abt some &amp;ldquo;human or Japanese or Korean extinction&amp;rdquo; while confusing correlation with causation &amp;amp;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;underlying all this is the assumption that industrial civ will last forever because as Julian Simon taught us: &amp;ldquo;there may well be other suns elsewhere&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; human ingenuity will help turn copper into lead or as most people believe: there is infinite coal, oil, gas, copper on earth because why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t there be?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finite-resource-awareness</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/finite-resource-awareness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/finite-resource-awareness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even in early 1600&amp;rsquo;s Japanese thinkers understood  difference between what could be created (sugar, silk) vs finite resources that could only be extracted (Copper, Silver etc).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This led them to differentiate between essentials (salt) vs luxuries (sugar). Policy was to curb imports of luxuries like silk&amp;amp; sugar while figuring out how to produce them in Japan so that precious Japanese metal would stop enriching foreigners (especially the Xtians/West). A central concern in the rise of kokueki 国益(national interest) thought in 1700&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insect eating</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/insect-eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/insect-eating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the Taisho period, people ate more than 50 types of insects! ? Tracing the history of insect eating in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The grasshopper dish is called いなごの佃煮 (inago no tsukudani) &amp;amp; still consumed in areas like Nagano (where wasps are also eaten).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If people ate Wagyu beef in Edo period, then total pop would have been way &amp;lt; 30 mill&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/cu31924032481974/page/178/mode/1up?view=theater&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;RELATION OF MEAT ANIMALS TO DENSITY OF POPULATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Japan probably presents the most extreme example of a people who maintain a high civilization with few animals. With the exception of the northern island of Hokkaido, the whole country has a population of from 400 to 500 people per square mile; and the rough and steep country permits only a sixth of the land to be cultivated.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Room for pasture does not exist, because of a &amp;ldquo;dense growth of bamboo grass wholly unfit for food and impossible to eradicate.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The effect of this absence of pasture and pressure of population in limiting the production of domestic animals is marked.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Not firing</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/not-firing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/not-firing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;loyalty-and-treachery&#34;&gt;Loyalty and treachery&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Right after we formed our American company, we needed a lot of people in a hurry to establish our sales organization because business got very good very fast. Some of our new employees were good and some, we realized later, we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have hired. We had trouble with one man and I was exasperated and constantly worried about him. Finally, I discussed his case with my American colleagues. &amp;ldquo;What can we do with this guy?&amp;rdquo; I asked one day. They all looked at me as though I was slowwitted. &amp;ldquo;Why, fire him, of course,&amp;rdquo; they said. I was stunned by the idea. I had never fired anybody, and even in this case it had never crossed my mind. But to solve a problem by firing the man was the American system. It seemed so clear and straightforward and logical. I began to think America is a manager&amp;rsquo;s paradise; you can do anything you want to do. Then a few months later I saw the other side of the coin. I was stunned by the idea. I had never fired anybody, and even in this case it had never crossed my mind. But to solve a problem by firing the man was the American system&amp;hellip; Then a few months later I saw the other side of the coin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Succession</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/succession/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/succession/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why Are so Many of the World&amp;rsquo;s Oldest Businesses in Japan? Example, Kyoto - Kiyomizu Rokubey: Tradition and Vision in Ceramics Kyoto&amp;rsquo;s leading potteries, was established 245 years ago. Led by the current Rokubey, the 8th generation to take the name.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;family-continuity&#34;&gt;Family continuity&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Ishikawa, Japan, for a great many people things are very different. Japan is a great country for tradition anyway, but Ishikawa is home to a disproportionately high number of people who have great stacks of ancestors peering over their shoulders. Sake makers, kimono dyers, ryokan owners, potters, confectioners &amp;hellip; Hundreds of years of expertise and expectation bear down on them - they carry a name and a trade that must live on through them, just as it has done since the Edo period.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sugar tax - save copper</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/sugar-tax_save-copper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/rjrasva/sugar-tax_save-copper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kudo Heisuke&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sugar, too, should be monopolized.105 Sugar, as Heisuke explained, being simply a luxury that the lower ranks should not enjoy as much as they did, should be regulated, because sugar was traded for copper, and the more sugar the people consumed, the more precious copper left the country.106 The lower ranks did not trouble to think about it, but the government ought to:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our precious copper leaves the country so that the lower ranks can eat sugar. They do not give a second thought to the fact that 1,000,000 kin of copper leave our country annually for sugar&amp;hellip;. Yet, while the sugar import should not be stopped, it should be controlled tightly by a monopoly (za). Thereby the lower ranks would not consume sugar, or fancy it, so much.107&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
