<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is our race?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-12-23_what-is-our-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-12-23_what-is-our-race/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/12/23/what-is-our-race/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Americans are particularly interested in knowing about a person’s race,&#xA;just as we might be curious about a person’s varNa or jAti. In any&#xA;paper-work, be it of small or big importance, the American officialdom&#xA;demands to known your race. Indians living in the mlechCha-desha often&#xA;have a profound difficulty with this matter because despite comprising a&#xA;1/6 th of humanity they do not have a race to describe them. The common&#xA;categories imposed by the Americans are white, black, Native American,&#xA;Asian, and “Pacific Islanders”. Of these the first 4 can be called valid&#xA;races, whereas the 5th is too vague and would qualify as a race if they&#xA;had monophyletic Melanasians and Papuans and their closest sister groups&#xA;as the only valid members of that category. It is often frustrating that&#xA;an Indian just does not have a choice. Today a paper was published by&#xA;Rosenberg et al in the free wannabe tabloid studying the Indian&#xA;populations using a sample of Indians living in the US. The conclusions&#xA;are not unexpected but worth reiterating nevertheless:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indo-Aryans: Movement of their culture, languages and genes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-12_indo-aryans-movement-of-their-culture-languages-and-genes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-12_indo-aryans-movement-of-their-culture-languages-and-genes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/07/12/indo-aryans-movement-of-their-culture-languages-and-genes/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Indo-Aryans have heavily influenced the world by way to the movements of&#xA;their genes, languages and culture. Let us compare some of these&#xA;movements to understand their dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The invasion of the Indian sub-continent: After breaking away from&#xA;the Balto-Slavic with which they are unified by the synapomorphies such&#xA;as the Satem state and the classical RUKI rule the Indo-Iranian stem&#xA;developed a distinctive culture for a period in the Eurasian grassland&#xA;and its northern border zones. At some point, most likely between&#xA;3500-1200 BCE they entered the India sub-continent and came to dominate&#xA;much of it, converting the entire area to Indo-Aryan speaking and a&#xA;culturally Indo-Aryan zone. This parallels the later invasion of Iran by&#xA;their cousins the Iranians and the conversion of that region to an&#xA;Iranian speaking zone. In these newly occupied zones in the&#xA;sub-continent and Iran they established Arya-varta or AiryAna vaejo —&#xA;the land of the Aryas, which became epitomes of the two branches of&#xA;Aryan civilization. Genetically the Indo-Aryans left a huge impact on&#xA;the Indian population with anywhere between 80-20% genetic contribution&#xA;to the non-tribal caste populations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2) The Middle East (1600-1200 BCE): As we saw in the earlier essay the&#xA;Indo-Aryan influence in the middle east was mainly as a superstratum or&#xA;in the form of loan words in Hurrian and Hittite. They clearly entered&#xA;the Middle east well before the Iranians and mainly introduced&#xA;equestrian, and personal names amongst the elite. However, their&#xA;cultural influence was seen in Egypt and the Middle East though their&#xA;formal religion was only mildly present.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indo-Aryans of the Middle East</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-11_indo-aryans-of-the-middle-east/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-11_indo-aryans-of-the-middle-east/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/07/11/indo-aryans-of-the-middle-east/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Indo-Aryans of the second millenium Middle East have been a topic of&#xA;continuing interest highlighted beginning with the works of Johannes&#xA;Friedrich in 1929. Subsequently, Mironov and PE Dumont have also&#xA;expanded upon this subject. These studies are of key importance to the&#xA;Aryan problem, which may be briefly described as the question of time&#xA;and place of origin of the Indo-Aryan languages of India and its&#xA;speakers. In my opinion the traces of Indo-Aryan in the Middle East are&#xA;indisputable; however, it is clear that only words and no complete&#xA;Indo-Aryan language surives in these regions.The chief traces of IA in&#xA;the Middle-East are the famous horse training manual of Kikkuli the&#xA;Mitannian in the land of the Hittites, the Hittite-Mitanni treaty, and&#xA;various texts from Syria, Nuzi and Mitanni documents. From the&#xA;Indo-Aryan names of the royalty and the presence in the specialized&#xA;horse-training manual it is suggestive that the Indo-Aryan population&#xA;was relatively restricted to a mobile equestrian elite. The words&#xA;appears to be a superstrate on the Hurrian (an old Asiatic language of&#xA;possible Caucasian affinities) the language of the original people of&#xA;Syria and the main consitituents of the Mitanni Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rathva tribe: surprising survival of Vedic traits</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-07-16_rathva-tribe-surprising-survival-of-vedic-traits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-07-16_rathva-tribe-surprising-survival-of-vedic-traits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/07/16/rathva-tribe-surprising-survival-of-vedic-traits/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Rathvas are a peculiar tribe in Gujarat whose art was studied by Jyotirindra Jain. Most tribes of India preserve certain aboriginal traits that have are often interlaced with Indo-Aryan tendencies. Most commonly the rudra cult of the the Indo-Aryans and its various ramifications has been used as a conduit for the assimilation of aboriginal tribes. Hence, the most frequent Indo-Aryan elements are associated with the worship of rudra and his entourage, and syncretization of local goddess into the pan-Indo-Aryan transfunctional goddess cult. This could have in the early stages involved the vrAtyas and para-Vedic Indo-Aryans, who often existed at the periphery of the orthodox Vedic Indo-Aryan world and often had special rites to the god rudra mahadeva. We see very few pristine vedic elements in these assimilated tribes of India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Masi Reddi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/2003-09-01_masi-reddi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/2003-09-01_masi-reddi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/09/01/masi-reddi/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Masi Reddi and his wife Nilamama lived in the eastern ghats selling wood&#xA;with their 6 sons. They invoked mahAdeva, who appeared in their house in&#xA;the form of a jangama. He gave Nilamma some ashes and said they would&#xA;become rich when another son was born. This son was Undala Padmanna.&#xA;Soon they became prosperous by acquiring agriculture. However Padmanna&#xA;never did any work. So his brothers decided to kill him. They asked him&#xA;to burn a termite hill hoping that a cobra that lived in it would emerge&#xA;and bite him. He did so an instead a herd of black bleating sheep&#xA;emerged. He was frightened by them, but rudra appeared and asked him to&#xA;rear them and live by their milk. rudra taught how to milk the sheep and&#xA;boil their milk. He then sent him to a distant place where rAkshas lived&#xA;and obtain fire from there. The rAkshas had captured and chained a&#xA;ravishingly beautiful fair-skinned brAhmaNa girl. Though of collyrium&#xA;complexion Undala Padmanna seduced the brAhmaNa girl and managed to&#xA;release her. As they were running away the rAkshas started chasing them.&#xA;The brahmin girl asked the Reddi to run ahead to attract the rAkshas&#xA;attention. As they chased him, she made her escape and used a Sanskrit&#xA;spell to turn the Reddi into a &lt;em&gt;Varanus&lt;/em&gt; lizard. The rAkshas were&#xA;confused and returned. She then made him back into a man and they&#xA;returned to their flock with the fire. He married her giving her a&#xA;woollen bracelet. Then he married a tribal woman of his own ethnicity&#xA;and gave her a cotton bracelet. The descendents of the brahmin woman&#xA;founded a higher semi-sanskritized caste amidst the herders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kasar Gavlis</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/2003-08-30_kasar-gavlis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/2003-08-30_kasar-gavlis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/08/30/kasar-gavlis/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Near Baramati lived a band of Kasar Gavlis, who sold their curds and&#xA;milk in brass pots. One day they were visited by viShUchikA. They all&#xA;died as a result. The vacuum was filled by a roving band of Maharatta&#xA;tribals called the Bhosles. The Bhosles also took to breeding the&#xA;gavlis’ cattle and trading milk and curd. They then were called the&#xA;Gavlis. The original gavlis worshiped a horned buffalo deity called&#xA;mhasobA. The incoming Bhosles too started worshiping mhasobA there&#xA;after. Dotting the whole Pune district and its surrounding are buffalo&#xA;breeding settlements and associated mhasobA shrines. Also seen are&#xA;shrines of vAghobA, khandobA, dhulobA, jyotibA, mhaskobA, birobA and&#xA;various AyIs or female deities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A brief summary of the state of early Indian history</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/2003-07-20_a-brief-summary-of-the-state-of-early-indian-histo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/2003-07-20_a-brief-summary-of-the-state-of-early-indian-histo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/07/20/a-brief-summary-of-the-state-of-early-indian-history/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a moment let us set archaeology aside and examine what textual evidence is available for the dates in early Hindu history.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Generally people accept the following relative chronology:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Early/middle layers of the R^igveda, parts of the atharva veda.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Latest R^igveda, core atharva veda, core yajur veda&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Events of the rAmAyaNa&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;vedAnga jyotiSha, core events of mahAbhArata, late vedic material&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;systematization of vedic saMhitas, shrauta rituals, janamejaya’s conquest of takshashila&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;first purANas composed, end of vedic composition&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;brahminical sutra literature begins&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;pANini, kaNAda&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;buddha&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Other assumptions that generally may be accepted:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aryanized tamils</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/Aryanized-tamils/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/Aryanized-tamils/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/i/lists/934873690050740224&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IMO, despite the high-volume claims of Dravidianists and Dravidologists, in the earliest of the tamiL texts you already find a fullfledged Hindu system more or less the same as that practiced in more northern locales of the subcontinent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, its transmission in the south was via two vehicles. There were the vaidika pArpAn-s/antaNar-s (v1) who bore the Sanskrit tradition and a more folk transmission, which like in other contact zones of the Indosphere used translation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>grAma-pura shift</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/grAma-pura-shift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/grAma-pura-shift/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;grama-to-nagara-shift&#34;&gt;grAma to nagara shift&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1540190371992453120&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I should remark that a philological examination of Sanskrit tradition will show that the grAma (village/encampment) was an ideal only the remote Indo-Aryan past &amp;ndash; the time of the shruti. Since the 2nd urbanization the center of cultured H life has always been the city. The ways of the paura in the nagara were seen as epitome of high culture &amp;amp; lot of new norms are centered on the paura householder, perhaps a shift from the older gRhamedhin in more rural settings. This shift begins in the latest layer of the veda where we see the emergence of an Aryan neologism &amp;ndash; nagara which went on to supplant the old pUr to a degree. Thus, I think even a wanderer V1 like the great rAjashekhara might have seen the rural gRhamedhin as a bit of an anachronism.+++(4)+++&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iShTakA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/iShTakA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/iShTakA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Word iShTaka &amp;amp; its homologs need some discussion. First, it is attested in Iranic e.g. Avestan iShtya &amp;amp; zemo-iStva, zemo=earth -&amp;gt;SKT: jmA; hence, earthen-brick. It is seen in some Dravidian languages in form close to the prAkR^ita one (iTTa-) &amp;amp; the Thai language of Kra-Dai family. Hence, it can be reasoned that it is a widely travelled word that moved along with this technology.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, given that Dravidian forms resemble prAkR^ita we can posit a transfer from IA-&amp;gt;Dr. Similarly a prAkR^itic form was likely carried to Thailand via trade from India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toilets</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/toilets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/articles/MT_lekhAH/toilets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Excellent. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if the twt sparking was just ignorance or kutarka. Whatever the case, even if we drop the whole Harappan thing for a moment there is evidence from the historical period for urban residential drainage. e.g. mauryan drains in pATaliputra; shu&lt;del&gt;Nga drain at Atrajinkhera; shu&lt;/del&gt;Nga to gupta drains in Mathura; septic tank at mathurA; there have been several reports in the Indian archaeological literature.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moreover the smR^iti-s say that voiding malamUtrau should be done in silence in secluded spots with many negative qualifiers. It was hardly like  a place where people chatted at leisure. May be that happened in ancient Rome. The ASI report this a gupta age toilet fitting from a &amp;ldquo;monastery&amp;rdquo; so it would be internal not open.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
