<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;calcutta quran petition on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;calcutta quran petition on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 PREFACE TO THIRD EDITION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/01_pref1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/01_pref1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PREFACE TO THIRD EDITION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first two editions of this book were published in quick succession - July 1986 and July 1987 - because it was received with great interest and appreciation by the Hindu intelligentsia at large, in this country and abroad.  But the present (third) edition has been delayed inordinately in spite of persistent demand after the second edition went out of print in 1988.  A reprint of the second edition was not brought out because I wanted to include in a new edition the copious materials which I had collected in the meanwhile from orthodox collections of Hadis and which I thought worth presenting to the readers.  But that was not to be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 PREFACE TO SECOND EDITION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/02_pref2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/02_pref2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PREFACE TO SECOND EDITION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Soon after the first edition of this book was published in July 1986, a significant judgment on some &lt;em&gt;Ayats&lt;/em&gt; of the Quran was pronounced by Z.S. Lohat, metropolitan magistrate of Delhi.  As most of these &lt;em&gt;Ayats&lt;/em&gt; and others of a similar sort figure in the Calcutta Quran Petition of Chandmal Chopra, we thought it relevant to reproduce the impugned poster in which the &lt;em&gt;Ayats&lt;/em&gt; were cited.  Operative portion of the judgment is also being reproduced in order to give a glimpse of the arguments for and against.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 CHAPTER 1 A GOVERNMENT IN PANIC</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/03_chi1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/03_chi1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A GOVERNMENT IN PANIC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Muslims in India have often sought shelter under Sections 153A and 295A of the Indian Penal Code (I.P.C.) for preventing every public discussion of their creed in general and of their prophet in particular.[^1] Quite a few publications which examine critically the sayings and doings of the Prophet or other idolized personalities of Islam, have been proscribed under Section 95 of the Criminal Procedure Code (Cr.P.C.) as a result of pressure exerted by vociferous, very often violent Muslim protests.  Little did they suspect that the same provisions of the law could be invoked for seeking a ban on their holy book, the Quran.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 CHAPTER 2 THE JUDGMENT MISSES THE MAIN POINT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/04_chi2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/04_chi2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE JUDGMENT MISSES THE MAIN POINT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is not for laymen like us to discuss the correctness or otherwise of a High Court judgment.  It should better be left to those who are conversant with the law and can enter into the intricacies of interpretation and logical construction.  For all we know, it is perhaps impossible to impugn a book under the existing law, if it is assumed at the very outset that the book is a sacred scripture cherished as such by a certain community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 CHAPTER 3 ENTIRE QURAN IS A MANUAL ON JIHAD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/05_chi3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/05_chi3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENTIRE QURAN IS A MANUAL ON &lt;em&gt;JIHAD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now we can take up the third observation in Justice Basak’s judgement, namely, that “This book [The Quran] is not prejudicial to maintenance of religious harmony”, and that “Because of the Koran no public tranquility has been disturbed upto now and there is no reason to apprehend any likelihood of such disturbance in future”.  He has gone further and chosen to repeat the etymological exercise which we find in most of the books written by apologists of Islam in modem times.  We are informed by Justice Basak that the word “&lt;em&gt;Muslim&lt;/em&gt;” has been formed from the word “&lt;em&gt;IslAm&lt;/em&gt;” which in turn derives from “&lt;em&gt;as-salam&lt;/em&gt;”, meaning peace.  The mission of Islam, we are assured by him, is the establishment of peace, and a Muslim is he who works wholeheartedly for this fulfilment.  The argument is clever but not consistent either with what is advocated by the scriptures of Islam or with what we find in the recorded history of this creed spread over more than fourteen hundred years.  Human history has known several movements which have used words to mean exactly the opposite of what those words stand for in common parlance.  Christianity, Communism and Nazism abound in such doublespeak.  So also Islam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 CHAPTER 4 THE PROPHET SETS THE PATTERN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/06_chi4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/06_chi4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER 4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE PROPHET SETS THE PATTERN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prophecy about the Prophet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[A Jew from Syria had migrated to Medina some years before Muhammad proclaimed his prophethood in 610 CE.]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Later when he knew that he was about to die he said, “O Jews, what do you think made me leave a land of bread and wine to come to a land of hardship and hunger?” When we [the Jews] said that we could not think why, he said that he had come to this country expecting to see the emergence of a prophet whose time was at hand.  This was the town where he would migrate and he was hoping that he would be sent so that he could follow him.  “His time has come,” he said, “and don’t let anyone get to him before you, O Jews; &lt;em&gt;for he will be sent to shed blood and to take captive the women and children of those who oppose him.  Let not that keep you back from him&lt;/em&gt;.”[^1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 CHAPTER 5 THE ORTHODOX EXPOSITION OF JIHAD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/07_chi5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/07_chi5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER 5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE ORTHODOX EXPOSITION OF &lt;em&gt;JIHAD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imam Abu Hanifa, the eighth-century systematizer of Muslim law, is held in the highest regard by Muslims all over the world.  He is also the most important authority for Muslims in India, a majority of whom subscribe to his school (&lt;em&gt;mazhab&lt;/em&gt;).  And the most outstanding treatise of his school is the &lt;em&gt;HidAyah&lt;/em&gt; compiled by Shaykh Burhan-ud-din Ali who flourished in the 12th century (CE).  The Shaykh claims to have studied all earlier commentaries on the Quran and the Hadis belonging to the schools of MAlik, ShAfii and Hanbal, besides that of Hanifa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 CHAPTER 6 JIHAD IN INDIA’S HISTORY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/08_chi6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/08_chi6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER 6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;JIHAD&lt;/em&gt; IN INDIA’S HISTORY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The principles of &lt;em&gt;jihAd&lt;/em&gt; elaborated in countless compendia composed by Islamic scholars, have been generalized from concrete practices of the Prophet, and confirmed by Allah through “revelations” in the Quran.  In turn, these principles have guided all swordsmen of Islam throughout these fourteen countries and in many lands.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;India has had a prolonged experience of &lt;em&gt;jihAd&lt;/em&gt; from the day when the first Muslim army stepped into Sindh in 712 CE and won its first victories after suffering a number of defeats for 78 years.  Lands in Seistan, Khurasan, Transoxiana and Afghanistan where Hindu religion and culture had flourished for long, had been subjected to &lt;em&gt;jihAd&lt;/em&gt; in earlier years.  We are citing some of the prominent &lt;em&gt;jihAds&lt;/em&gt; waged in India by the most famous &lt;em&gt;mujAhids&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 CHAPTER 7 DOCTRINE OF THE ISLAMIC STATE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/09_chi7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/09_chi7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER 7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DOCTRINE OF THE ISLAMIC STATE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The doctrine of &lt;em&gt;jihAd&lt;/em&gt;, which is the whole of the Quran, deals primarily with the performance of the militarized Muslim Ummah till the time an “infidel land” is conquered and Muslim hold is consolidated over it by terrorising its people through slaughter and pillage.  The operations of the same military machine after the conquest are dealt with by another department of Islamic theology - doctrine of the Islamic state.  A very clear exposition of this doctrine is provided by Professor Jadunath Sarkar who had spent a life-time in studying the theology and history of Islam.  We reproduce below what he stated in 1928.  Once again we have replaced the word “God” by the word “Allah”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 CHAPTER 8 MUSLIM UMMAH IS A MILITARY MACHINE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/10_chi8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/10_chi8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER 8&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MUSLIM &lt;em&gt;UMMAH&lt;/em&gt; IS A MILITARY MACHINE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The teeming tomes on orthodox Islamic theology devote plenty of space to non-warlike subjects, such as faith, purification, prayers, alms, fasting, pilgrimage, marriage, divorce, business transactions, inheritance, gifts, bequests, vows, oaths, crime, punishment, government, hunting, food, drink, dress, decoration, greetings, magic, poetry, visions, dreams, virtue, last day, repentance, etc.  But the rules laid down for every Muslim, everywhere and at all times, are the same.  In the final analysis this uniform pattern of belief and behaviour erases the individual in man and turns him into a member of a close-knit collective, the &lt;em&gt;Ummah&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 CHAPTER 9 THE PETITION HAS SERVED A GREAT PURPOSE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/11_chi9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/11_chi9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER 9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE PETITION HAS SERVED A GREAT PURPOSE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By filing the Writ Petition for a ban on the Quran, Chandmal Chopra has invited attention to a subject which Hindus have neglected for long and at great cost to themselves.  They have yet to examine critically the claim of the Quran as a sacred scripture and of Islam as a religion.  If Hindus now take up this study in all seriousness and educate themselves about the character of Islam, the Petition will have served its purpose.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 CHAPTER 10 A CLOSE LOOK AT ALLAH OF THE QURAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/12_chi10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/12_chi10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A CLOSE LOOK AT ALLAH OF THE QURAN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The one name which Muslims hate and fear most is that of Chengiz Khan.&#xA;He is a spectre which has haunted Muslim historians for centuries.  He swept like a tornado over the then most powerful and extensive Islamic empire of Khwarazm.  In a short span of five years (1219-1224 CE), he slaughtered millions of Muslims, forced many others including women and children into slavery, and razed to the ground quite a few of the most populous and prosperous cities of the Muslim world at that time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 (1) HIMANGSHU KISHORE’S LETTER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/13_chii1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/13_chii1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(1)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HIMANGSHU KISHORE’S LETTER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Himangshu Kishore Chakraborty, M.A., (Cal.),&lt;br&gt;&#xA;12/A/4, Pashupati Bhattacharya Road,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Behala,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Calcutta - 34.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dated 20th July, 1984.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The Secretary,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Department of Home,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Government of West Bengal,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Writers’ Building,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Calcutta - 1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dear Sir,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sub: Request for proscription of ‘Koran’.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you may be aware, the Islamic religious book, Koran, also spelt as ‘Qur’an’, said to be a collection of revelations made through the angel Gabriel by the almighty Allah to the Prophet Muhammad, containing numerous sayings, repeated in the book over and over again, which on grounds of religion promote disharmony, feeling of enmity, hatred and ill-will between different religious communities and incite people to commit violence and disturb public tranquility, and though most of the events which had occasioned those sayings have now lost all historical significance, the book is still published in the unabridged form, with persistence, and clearly with the deliberate and malicious intention of outraging or insulting other religions and the religious feelings of other communities in India which is apparent from the fact that all the publishers of the book know very well that the various sayings of the book are offensive in this sense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 (2) HIMANGSHU KISHORE’S REMINDER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/14_chii2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/14_chii2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(2)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HIMANGSHU KISHORE’S REMINDER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Himangshu Kishore Chakraborty, M.A.,(Cal.),&lt;br&gt;&#xA;12/A/4, Pashupati Bhattacharya Road,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Behala,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Calcutta - 34.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;14th August, 1984.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The Secretary,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Department of Home,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Government of West Bengal, Writers’ Building,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Calcutta - 1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dear Sir,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sub: Request for proscription of ‘Koran’.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please refer to my letter dated 20th July, 1984, (delivered in your office on the same date) in which I had made a request for forfeiture of the Islamic book, Koran, for the reason that it contains numerous sayings of Prophet Muhammad which on ground of religion promote disharmony, feeling of enmity, hatred and ill-will between different religious communities; incite people to commit violence and disturb public tranquility and outrage or insult other religions and the religious feelings of other communities in India, which render the book liable to be forfeited to the Government in terms of Section 95 of the Code of Criminal Procedure, 1973, read with Sections 153A and 295A of the Indian Penal Code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 (3) NOTICE FROM CHANDMAL CHOPRA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/15_chii3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/15_chii3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(3)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTICE FROM CHANDMAL CHOPRA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;C.M. Chopra.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;25, Burtolla Street,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Calcutta - 7.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;16th March, 1985.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The Secretary,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Department of Home,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Government of West Bengal,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Writers’ Building,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Calcutta - 1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dear Sir,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sub: The Islamic book - Koran - forfeiture of - request for&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In terms of Section 95 Cr.  P.C. read with Sections 153A and 295A I.P.C. every copy of a book is liable to be forfeited to the Government if the book contains words or sayings which promote, on ground of religion, disharmony, enmity, hatred or ill-will between different religious communities or which outrage the religious feelings of any class of citizens of India or insult the religion or religious beliefs of that class of people.  This is so whether the book is classic or epic, religious or temporal, old or new.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 (4) THE WRIT APPLICATION   MATTER NO. 227 OF 1985 IN THE HIGH COURT AT CALCUTTA. Constitution Writ Jurisdiction. (ORIGINAL SIDE)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/16_chii4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/16_chii4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(4)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE WRIT APPLICATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MATTER NO. 227 OF 1985&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;IN THE HIGH COURT AT CALCUTTA.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Constitution Writ Jurisdiction.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(ORIGINAL SIDE)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the Matter of&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An application Under Article 226 of the Constitution of India and Writs, directions and orders thereunder.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;AND&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the Matter of&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Section 95 of the Code of Criminal&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Procedure, 1973.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;AND&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the Matter of&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sections 153A and 295A Indian Penal&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;AND&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the Matter of&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 (5) AFFIDAVIT IN OPPOSITION Government of West Bengal Office of the Advocate-on-Record, 5, K.S. Ray Road, (2nd floor) Calcutta - 1</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/17_chii5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/17_chii5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(5)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFFIDAVIT IN OPPOSITION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Government of West Bengal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Office of the Advocate-on-Record,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;5, K.S. Ray Road, (2nd floor)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Calcutta - 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No. AGR/985/85.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dated the 29th April 1985.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From:  Shri R.C. Deb,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Advocate-on-Record, West Bengal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To: Shri Chandmal Chopra,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;25, Burtolla Street,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Calcutta - 7.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matter No. 297 of 1985&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Chandmal Chopra &amp;amp; Anr.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;-vs-&lt;br&gt;&#xA;State of West Bengal&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dear Sir,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enclosed please find a copy of the affidavit in opposition to be filed on behalf of the respondent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 (6) THE JUDGEMENT BIMAL CHANDRA BASAK May 17 85. Chandmal Chopra &amp; Anr. Versus State of West Bengal</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/18_chii6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/18_chii6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(6)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE JUDGEMENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BIMAL CHANDRA BASAK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 17          85.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Chandmal Chopra &amp;amp; Anr.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Versus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;State of West Bengal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Court: I have heard and disposed of this application on the 13th of May 1985 when I indicated that I shall give my reasons later.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2. This is an application under Article 226 of the Constitution of India praying for a Writ of Mandamus directing the State of West Bengal to declare each copy of the Koran, whether in the original Arabic or in its translation in any of the languages, as forfeited to the Government.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 (7) THE REVIEW APPLICATION MATTER NO. 297 OF 1985 IN THE HIGH COURT AT CALCUTTA Constitutional Writ Jurisdiction (ORIGINAL SIDE)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/19_chii7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/19_chii7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(7)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE REVIEW APPLICATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MATTER NO. 297 OF 1985&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;IN THE HIGH COURT AT CALCUTTA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Constitutional Writ Jurisdiction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(ORIGINAL SIDE)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the Matter of an application for condonation of delay in the submission of the review application.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the matter of&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chandmal Chopra &amp;amp; Anr.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;- Applicant.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Versus&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The State of West Bengal&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;- Respondent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. The Hon’ble Mr. Satish Chandra, the Chief Justice and His Companion Justices of the said High Court.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 (8) REVIEW APPLICATION DISMISSED MATTER NO. 297 OF 1985 Constitutional Writ (ORIGINAL SIDE) </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/20_chii8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/20_chii8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(8)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REVIEW APPLICATION DISMISSED&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MATTER NO. 297 OF 1985&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Constitutional Writ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(ORIGINAL SIDE)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BIMAL CHANDRA BASAK&lt;br&gt;&#xA;June 21 85.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Chandmal Chopra &amp;amp; Anr.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;-Vs-&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The State of West Bengal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two papers were moved before me.  One is an application for condonation of delay in the submission of the review application and another is stated to be an application for review of my Judgment dated 17th May, 1985, but which is actually a memorandum of review.  By the said Judgment I have dismissed the Writ petition directed against Koran in limine.  Thereafter these two “applications” have been filed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 BIBLIOGRAPHY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/21_bib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/calcutta_quran_petition/21_bib/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BIBLIOGRAPHY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Comprehensive History of India&lt;/em&gt;, Volume Fifth, &lt;em&gt;The Saltanat&lt;/em&gt;, edited&#xA;by Mohammad Habib and K.A. Nizami, New Delhi, 1970, First Reprint, 1982.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Akbar-NAma&lt;/em&gt; of Abul Fazl, translated into English by H. Beveridge,&#xA;Volume I and II Bound in One, New Delhi reprint, 1993.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Babur-NAma&lt;/em&gt; of Zahiruddin Babur, translated into English by A.S.&#xA;Beveridge, New Delhi reprint, 1979.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Elliot and Dowson, &lt;em&gt;History of India as told by its own Historians&lt;/em&gt;, New Delhi reprint, 1990, Volume I, II, III, IV, V, VI, VIII.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
