<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;indian muslims on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;indian muslims on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Indian Muslims Prologue</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/01_pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/01_pro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indian Muslims&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prologue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are books on Indian Muslims like M. Mujeeb’s &lt;em&gt;The Indian Muslims&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;(George Allen &amp;amp; Unwin, London, 1967) and Ram Gopal’s &lt;em&gt;Indian Muslims&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;(Asia Publishing House, Bombay, 1959).  There are journals, Articles,&#xA;and “Letters to the Editor” on Indian Muslims or Muslim Indians.  But&#xA;who are these Indian Muslims?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;M. Mujeeb answers: “whoever they may be, and wherever they may be in&#xA;India, the Indian Muslims take themselves for granted” (p.9). It is&#xA;indeed not necessary to attempt a meticulous definition of Indian&#xA;Muslims because they are so keen on asserting their identity that one&#xA;cannot mistake them wherever they may be.  Mujeeb further adds: “It is&#xA;the author’s firm belief that the Indian Muslims have, in their religion&#xA;of Islam, and in the true representatives of the moral and spiritual&#xA;values of Islam the most reliable standards of judgement, and they need&#xA;not look elsewhere to discover how high or low they stand” (P.24).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Chapter 1 Early Muslims</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/02_ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/02_ch1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Early Muslims&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No integrated contemporary account exists to say how Islam spread in&#xA;India.  Medieval chroniclers very graphically describe the achievements&#xA;of Muslim invaders, conquerors, monarchs, governors, rulers of&#xA;independent Muslims kingdoms, and even officials, in effecting&#xA;conversions.  Muslim hagiological works, some reliable others not so&#xA;reliable, too report on addition to Muslim population through&#xA;conversions.  But the actual numbers who embraced Islam year after year&#xA;and decade after decade are not known.  Some Muslims no doubt came from&#xA;abroad as conquerors and soldiers.  Some scholars and religious men also&#xA;arrived either in the train of conquerors or at the invitation of Indian&#xA;sultans or as refugees.  Arabs, Abyssinians, Egyptians, Persians and&#xA;Transoxionians, all find mention as having come to India to seek refuge&#xA;or fortune.  But the majority of Muslims are converts from Hinduism.&#xA;One has, therefore, to collect facts and figures contained in stray&#xA;references of medieval writers, especially Persian chroniclers, to make&#xA;a conversion-cum-immigration survey to be able to estimate the growth of&#xA;Muslim population.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Chapter 2 Rise of Muslims under the Sultanate</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/03_ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/03_ch2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Rise of Muslims under the Sultanate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Muslim population in India grew with the expansion of Turkish rule in&#xA;Hindustan.  Its rise was due mainly to the immigration of Muslims from&#xA;abroad and conversion of Hindus to Islam.  There were Muslim losses&#xA;also, in wars, famines, and through reconversions, and there was the&#xA;growth of Muslim numbers through natural procreation in years and&#xA;decades.  We study all these processes, to begin with between C.E. 1200&#xA;and 1400.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Chapter 3 Proselytization in Provincial Muslim Kingdoms</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/04_ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/04_ch3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Proselytization in Provincial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Muslim Kingdoms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A year before the dawn of the fifteenth century, Timur had claimed to&#xA;have invaded Hindustan to destroy its infidels and idolators.&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;¹&lt;/a&gt;  In&#xA;the year 1400 India was predominantly Hindu; Muslims comprised less than&#xA;2 per cent of the population.  The country south of the Krishna River&#xA;right up to Cape Camorin formed the Vijayanagar empire and it was&#xA;Hindu.  On the west coast, the strip between Goa in the south to Chaul&#xA;and (future) Bombay in the north was in the hands of independent Hindu&#xA;rulers.  In the Bahmani kingdom conversions and immigration were&#xA;swelling Muslim numbers.  But the whole of Central India with Rajasthan&#xA;to the west and Gondwana to the east was Hindu.  East U.P., Bihar and&#xA;Orissa were also Hindu.  Only in Baluchistan, portion of the Punjab west&#xA;of the River Ravi, Sind and Bengal there were good number of Muslims,&#xA;but there too the Hindus were in majority.  In the heart of the&#xA;Sultanate - the eastern Punjab, Delhi and its outlying regions, and&#xA;western U.P. - Gujarat, and Malwa, Muslim numbers were rising but were&#xA;not yet large.  Timur might have made his declaration merely as a&#xA;champion of Islam, and yet he was not wrong in his assessment of the&#xA;Hindu population of India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 Chapter 3 Proselytization in Provincial Muslim Kingdoms</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/05_ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/05_ch3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Proselytization in Provincial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Muslim Kingdoms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A year before the dawn of the fifteenth century, Timur had claimed to&#xA;have invaded Hindustan to destroy its infidels and idolators.&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;¹&lt;/a&gt;  In&#xA;the year 1400 India was predominantly Hindu; Muslims comprised less than&#xA;2 per cent of the population.  The country south of the Krishna River&#xA;right up to Cape Camorin formed the Vijayanagar empire and it was&#xA;Hindu.  On the west coast, the strip between Goa in the south to Chaul&#xA;and (future) Bombay in the north was in the hands of independent Hindu&#xA;rulers.  In the Bahmani kingdom conversions and immigration were&#xA;swelling Muslim numbers.  But the whole of Central India with Rajasthan&#xA;to the west and Gondwana to the east was Hindu.  East U.P., Bihar and&#xA;Orissa were also Hindu.  Only in Baluchistan, portion of the Punjab west&#xA;of the River Ravi, Sind and Bengal there were good number of Muslims,&#xA;but there too the Hindus were in majority.  In the heart of the&#xA;Sultanate - the eastern Punjab, Delhi and its outlying regions, and&#xA;western U.P. - Gujarat, and Malwa, Muslim numbers were rising but were&#xA;not yet large.  Timur might have made his declaration merely as a&#xA;champion of Islam, and yet he was not wrong in his assessment of the&#xA;Hindu population of India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 Chapter 4 Growth under the Mughals</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/06_ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/06_ch4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Growth under the Mughals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By the time Akbar the Great (1556-1605) embarked upon the policy of&#xA;reuniting these kingdom under his imperial banner, Muslim population was&#xA;rising all over the country.  Still, despite all the exertion of the&#xA;Muslims at proselytization, Hindu resistance to it was also admirably&#xA;effective.  Sind and Punjab no doubt had a sizeable Muslim&#xA;population.  But at the beginning of the sixteenth century, northern&#xA;Sind (north of the River Indus) had, according to Portuguese accounts, a&#xA;local Hindu as its ruler or governor.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;)  In Gujarat, Malwa, and&#xA;Khandesh Muslims were growing in numbers ever since Alauddin Khalji had&#xA;conquered these kingdoms, but mostly in the cities and seaports.  In the&#xA;interior the Hindus predominated.  However, the notices of some&#xA;foreigners show that Muslim population in Gujarat had risen&#xA;considerably.  The people of Cambay were both Moors and Hindus, wrote&#xA;Barbosa^(&lt;a href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;) and according to the impression of Pires, the Hindus&#xA;had been reduced to “almost the third part of the&#xA;kingdom.”^(&lt;a href=&#34;#3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;)  On the Malabar coast, according to Portuguese&#xA;estimates, the Muslims comprised about twenty percent of the&#xA;population.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;)  The Bahmani kingdom had a large number of Muslims&#xA;which went on growing with time.  In Ahmadnagar, Bijapur, Golkunda,&#xA;Bidar, and Berar, the successor kingdoms of Bahmani, large number of&#xA;foreign Muslims swelled the ranks of the indigenous.  Writing on April,&#xA;7, 1561, C. Rodrigues remarks that in Bijapur “the Moors are as&#xA;innumerable as insects.”^(&lt;a href=&#34;#5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;)  Another region to which this epithet&#xA;could be applied was Bengal.  Even so the Muslims were not in a majority&#xA;even in these parts.  In the Vijayanagar empire there were a few Muslim&#xA;contingents of soldiers and some Muslim citizens, but south of the river&#xA;Krishna the Muslim numbers were microscopic.  In the rest of the country&#xA;Hindu population predominated.  The Haryana, Delhi, Agra, and western&#xA;U.P. regions formed the nucleus, first of the Sultanate of Delhi and&#xA;then of the Mughal Empire.  It was no enemy territory where warfare for&#xA;conquest would have brought converts; its revenues in kind fed the&#xA;capital cities of Delhi and Agra; and its aggressive Zamindars were left&#xA;in restrained peace.  Consequently this region remained largely Hindu.&#xA;Here the small minority of Muslims was introduced as a result of early&#xA;Turkish victories and Muslim immigrants were added largely under the&#xA;Saiyyads and Lodis.  Rajputana was Hindu; Muslims there were in&#xA;insignificant numbers, because there Muslim rule could never get a&#xA;foothold.  Indeed when Father Pinheiro and his caravan were going from&#xA;Cambay to Akbar’s court at Lahore through Ahmedabad, Patan and&#xA;Rajasthan,^(&lt;a href=&#34;#6&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;) in the course of the journey they passed through&#xA;numerous large cities which were devastated, “especially the mosques&#xA;therein.”^(&lt;a href=&#34;#7&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;)  In the east, according to Fitch, Banaras was a&#xA;great city peopled exclusively by Hindus.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#8&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;)  He also says that&#xA;the inhabitants of Kuch Bihar were entirely Hindu.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#9&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;)  The vast&#xA;majority of the population of Orissa too was Hindu; and Muslim were very&#xA;few.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#10&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;)  Similar was the case with Gondwana and Central India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 Chapter 5 Factors Contributing to the Growth of Muslim Population</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/07_ch5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/07_ch5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Factors Contributing to the Growth of Muslim Population&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A study of the preceding pages clearly shows that the rise in Muslim&#xA;population was due mainly to conversions of Hindus to Islam.  It also&#xA;needs no reiteration that “it was part of the state policy to establish&#xA;Islam as the religion of the whole land”.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;)  It would again be a&#xA;truism to say that “Islam is essentially a missionary religion” and&#xA;every Muslim is a propagandist of his faith; and as they settled in&#xA;India, they must have entered upon proselytizing efforts.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;)&#xA;Thus Muslim rulers, nobles, Mashaikh, Maulvis, traders and merchants&#xA;were all in one way or the other Muslim missionaries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 Chapter 6 Factors which Checked Islamization of India</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/08_ch6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/08_ch6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Factors which Checked Islamization of India&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, if the components of growth of Muslim population were many, Muslim&#xA;losses comparatively few, and fecundity among them high, the problem&#xA;that needs investigation is why Muslims have remained a minority in this&#xA;country and why India, unlike many other countries in the medieval&#xA;period, could not be completely converted to Islam.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vastness of the Country&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The vastness of the country and its natural and political division into&#xA;regions and kingdoms made the task of its complete subjugation and&#xA;conversion extremely difficult.  In fact throughout the medieval period&#xA;at no time was the whole of India under direct Muslim rule.  Even in the&#xA;regions where Muslim rule was firmly established it was thought&#xA;expedient to leave the countryside alone.  Victories provided the Muslim&#xA;ruling class the luxuries of the city cultured life, and their interest&#xA;in rural areas remained confined merely to the collection of land&#xA;revenue.  In the words of Kingsley Davis, “although there were mass&#xA;conversions, the country was too vast, the invaders too few, and the&#xA;volume of immigration too small to change the social complex… India,&#xA;therefore, never became a Muslim nation, but remained simply a Hindu&#xA;country in which Muslims were numerous”.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;)  Henry Blochmann puts&#xA;it more explicitly.  He writes: “The invaders were few and the country&#xA;was too large and too populous.  The waves of immigration from Turan&#xA;were few and far between, and deposited on Indian soil adventurers,&#xA;warriors, and learned men, rather than artisans and colonists.  Hence&#xA;the Muhammadans depended upon the Hindoos for labour of every kind, from&#xA;architecture down to agriculture and the supply of servants.  Many&#xA;branches they had to learn from the Hindoos, as, for example, the&#xA;cultivation of indigeneous produce, irrigation, coinage, medicine, the&#xA;building of houses, and weaving of stuffs suitable for the climate, the&#xA;management of elephants, and so forth.”^(&lt;a href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 Epilogue</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/09_epi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/09_epi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Epilogue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We began by noting that the sword of Islam was blunted in India.  Islam&#xA;had spread in Arabia, Syria, Egypt, Iran, Iraq, North Africa and even&#xA;parts of Europe with a bang.  Within a hundred years of the death of the&#xA;Prophet this spectacular success had been achieved through the&#xA;instrument of &lt;em&gt;Jihad&lt;/em&gt;.  It appeared as if there was no stopping the&#xA;Islamic avalanche on the Globe, both to the east and the west of the&#xA;land of its birth - Arabia.  But contrary to all hopes and expectations,&#xA;Islam received a check in a most unexpected quarter - Hindustan, a&#xA;country believed to be divided by caste, tom by dissensions and&#xA;indifferent to conventionality in religious faith.  Persistent efforts&#xA;were made to Islamize India but to no avail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Bibliography</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/10_bib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/10_bib/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bibliography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contemporary Sources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abul Fazl, Allami, &lt;em&gt;Ain-i-Akbari&lt;/em&gt;, 3 vols. Vol. I translated by H.&#xA;Blocmann and ed. by D.C. Phillot, Asiatic Society of Bengal (Calcutta,&#xA;1939); Vol. II trs. by H.S. Jarret and annotated by Jadunath Sarkar,&#xA;A.S.B. (Calcutta, 1959); Vol.  III, Jarret and Sarkar (Calcutta, 1948).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Akbar Namah&lt;/em&gt;.  Bib.  Ind.  Text, 3 vols.  English trs. by H. Beveridge&#xA;(Calcutta, 1948).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abdul Hamid Lahori, &lt;em&gt;Badshahnamah&lt;/em&gt;, Bib. Ind., 2 vols. (Calcutta,&#xA;1898).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Chapter 6 Factors which Checked Islamization of India</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/11_ch6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/indian_muslims/11_ch6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Factors which Checked Islamization of India&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, if the components of growth of Muslim population were many, Muslim&#xA;losses comparatively few, and fecundity among them high, the problem&#xA;that needs investigation is why Muslims have remained a minority in this&#xA;country and why India, unlike many other countries in the medieval&#xA;period, could not be completely converted to Islam.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vastness of the Country&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The vastness of the country and its natural and political division into&#xA;regions and kingdoms made the task of its complete subjugation and&#xA;conversion extremely difficult.  In fact throughout the medieval period&#xA;at no time was the whole of India under direct Muslim rule.  Even in the&#xA;regions where Muslim rule was firmly established it was thought&#xA;expedient to leave the countryside alone.  Victories provided the Muslim&#xA;ruling class the luxuries of the city cultured life, and their interest&#xA;in rural areas remained confined merely to the collection of land&#xA;revenue.  In the words of Kingsley Davis, “although there were mass&#xA;conversions, the country was too vast, the invaders too few, and the&#xA;volume of immigration too small to change the social complex… India,&#xA;therefore, never became a Muslim nation, but remained simply a Hindu&#xA;country in which Muslims were numerous”.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;)  Henry Blochmann puts&#xA;it more explicitly.  He writes: “The invaders were few and the country&#xA;was too large and too populous.  The waves of immigration from Turan&#xA;were few and far between, and deposited on Indian soil adventurers,&#xA;warriors, and learned men, rather than artisans and colonists.  Hence&#xA;the Muhammadans depended upon the Hindoos for labour of every kind, from&#xA;architecture down to agriculture and the supply of servants.  Many&#xA;branches they had to learn from the Hindoos, as, for example, the&#xA;cultivation of indigeneous produce, irrigation, coinage, medicine, the&#xA;building of houses, and weaving of stuffs suitable for the climate, the&#xA;management of elephants, and so forth.”^(&lt;a href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
