<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/aNDaman/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/aNDaman/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gov ferry tickets</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/aNDaman/articles/gov_ferry_tickets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/aNDaman/articles/gov_ferry_tickets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STARS e-Ticketing Portal has moved to a new url - &lt;a href=&#34;https://dss.andamannicobar.gov.in/eticketing&#34;&gt;https://dss.andamannicobar.gov.in/eticketing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;E-Ticket Booking is allowed from 09:00 am to 04:00 pm IST on all days including Sundays. Can book only 10 days in advance. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;Big difference between islander vs non-islander fares.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Real-time Voyage and PNR status can be viewed from Online Enquiry Service.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In case of voyage cancellation by DSS, the registered passenger/user must cancel the E-Ticket PNR to receive the full refund amount. PNR Cancellation facility is allowed up to 10 days of actual date of sailing. No refund will be provided if the PNR is not cancelled within the defined cancellation period.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Misc tips</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/aNDaman/articles/misc_tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/aNDaman/articles/misc_tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;saumya&#34;&gt;saumya&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cellular jail - book tickets in advance , avoid queues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mahatma Gandhi National Park and Chidiya Tapu are okay. Small places- get to see biodiversity. Kids will like. Relatively less crowded.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Only good thing about Andaman Trip is Havelock Island. It is renamed as Swaraj Dweep now (the havelock island). Radha Nagar and VijayaNagar are best beaches in the country ! Sunsets are a little early so, post lunch , you all can leave for the Radhanagar beach and comeback after you play there until sunset. Havelock is the best part of Andaman trip ! Kids will really have fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RaghUttama on aNDamans</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/aNDaman/articles/raghUttama_on_aNDamans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/aNDaman/articles/raghUttama_on_aNDamans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;videoEmbed&#34;  caption=&#34;Video&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IX6uyd7qtSg&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-and-geography-of-port-blair&#34;&gt;Introduction and Geography of Port Blair&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[00:01]]&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m recording now. So, we lived for one year and to give you an idea, Port Blair is on the west side of the island. Okay. And the ship, usually what it does is it goes through this route and then comes on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[00:28]]&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Just one second. Hold on. All right. Hello. Hello. H good evening sir.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[02:44]]&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sorry, sorry about that. Okay. So the ship actually goes through this channel and then comes to the west. Okay. And this Haddo, this place in Port Blair is the harbor. This is where the harbor is. Okay. And this is the Chatham sawmill, this is one of Asia&amp;rsquo;s largest sawmills, even now. Okay. So a lot of rosewood, Padauk wood—Padauk was originally from Andaman—this is the mill that they used to use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
