<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/plant-growing/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/plant-growing/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chesterton gate disasters</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/plant-growing/articles/chesterton-gate-disasters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/plant-growing/articles/chesterton-gate-disasters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The flip side on &amp;ldquo;inappropriate technology&amp;rdquo; is the famous parable of &amp;ldquo;Chesterton&amp;rsquo;s Fence&amp;rdquo;: if you come across a gate in a field and see no reason why its should be there, do not remove it until you have figured out why it was put there in the first place. Millennia of hard earned handed down tradition and agricultural and ecological knowledge is being lost year after year, every time an old farmer dies without heirs. In many cases we have passed the point of no return: we will have to argue in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lanka buffaloes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/plant-growing/articles/lanka-buffalos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/plant-growing/articles/lanka-buffalos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A story of inappropriate technology: in the 1970s it was decided to modernize the rice farming of Sri Lanka, whose system that had not changed much for 3000 years. The goal was to replace the water buffalo with the modern tractor, but the attempt had disastrous consequences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Buffalos create &amp;ldquo;wallows&amp;rdquo;, pools of muddy water without which they cannot control their temperatures. Always filled with water, these wallows create many eco-services: in the dry season the become a haven for fish that then migrate back to the paddies when these fill with water. The fish is a valuable source of proteins for landless laborers and greatly help control the population of malaria causing mosquitoes who breed in the rice paddies. The vegetation around the wallows are breeding and hunting grounds for snakes and water monitor lizards who prey on rats that eat the rice and the crabs that burrow into the sides of the rice paddies eventually causing them to lose integrity, leading to collapses of entire paddy systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NarsaNNa farm</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/plant-growing/articles/narsaNNa-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/plant-growing/articles/narsaNNa-farm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Aranya Permaculture Resource&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many farmers in India who have land that used to be irrigated can no longer irrigate their land&lt;br&gt;&#xA;because they cannot afford to dig new bore wells to get to the water which has receded.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Other farmers have never been able to irrigate their land and often they cannot feed their families because of low yields.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another issue which is drawing a lot of interest is&lt;br&gt;&#xA;how to increase food production for an increasing population.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;In India there is a tremendous amount of land&lt;br&gt;&#xA;which is not being farmed because of poor soils&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and lack of access to water.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;We submit that with these techniques could be used to farm these lands.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphate</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/plant-growing/articles/phosphate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/plant-growing/articles/phosphate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source - ravilochana&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Phosphate - is mostly sourced from Morocco by the entire world. I don&amp;rsquo;t think we will run out of phosphate by 2100. It is sure to happen by 2200 or so. But we may yet survive till 2100 with current reserves&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
