<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०३ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/03/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०३ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/03/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>khANDavaprastha nirIkShaNaM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/03/2005-03-30_khandavaprastha-nirikshanam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/03/2005-03-30_khandavaprastha-nirikshanam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/03/30/khandavaprastha-nirikshanam/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The critical time for khANDavaprastha had come. We were seeing signs of&#xA;revolt. We deployed the dual saMGNYAnaM and kAmaM. We heavily rely on&#xA;that. It had temporarily veiled the other party. But the true effects we&#xA;will have to wait and see. We also need to spend a few days doing&#xA;tarpaNaM to strI on laukIka matters (I wonder why women are so&#xA;exaggerated in their mundane laukIka interests). Like the wandering yogI&#xA;needing to please the gR^ihastrI or more precisely agastya maitrAvaruNi&#xA;needing to pacify lopAmudra vaidharbhi. The grand dance and drama had to&#xA;be arranged to be played out by the nATI who never learned nATya. To add&#xA;to this enchanting Hayasthanika came with her “grandmother” asking for&#xA;help on “hahahaDakShaDa”. On other occasions I would easily been&#xA;smothered by her great charm and done anything for her but with a more&#xA;important strI on the line Hayasthanika was asked to attend to her own&#xA;business.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Descent to naraka</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/03/2005-03-25_descent-to-naraka/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/03/2005-03-25_descent-to-naraka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/03/25/descent-to-naraka/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We had earlier narrated how we had spent time in svarga with the&#xA;apsaras. From there we descended to the himaparvatas- i.e for warm&#xA;weather souls like us the slopes of the pAshaNDa’s hill. We continued&#xA;sporting there for sometime enjoying the brief bliss of our successes.&#xA;Then our ill fate brought us crashing to a low hollow in plane of&#xA;pR^ithivi. We thought we had hit the nadir of existence when we were&#xA;shaking from our thunderous crash to pR^ithivi. We did not know that the&#xA;narakas lay below. Then the noose of karma having caught us dragged us&#xA;to the lower realms and to our utter shock we lay in naraka. We felt&#xA;like king yuddhiShiThira in his final journey on the path to naraka. How&#xA;is it that we are in naraka? we asked, just as the great king had done.&#xA;Torments were seizing us from all sides. And there we saw our shachiva&#xA;and amAtya also being dragged away to a dark recess of naraka, they were&#xA;yelling and cursing but each one faces his torment in naraka on his own.&#xA;At this point all we could say is that why has our fate taken us to&#xA;naraka? But we found no answers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The pain of the cell phones</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/03/2005-03-25_the-pain-of-the-cell-phones/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/03/2005-03-25_the-pain-of-the-cell-phones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/03/25/the-pain-of-the-cell-phones/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We saw the wonderous charms of Hayastanika fade behind the impenetrable&#xA;veils. We conjured memories of eating the wonderous superhot mango&#xA;pickle on a pleasant spring afternoon and talking of the “pancha-shara&#xA;mulapadhArta” with the wonderful Kappa on the wonderful summer day in&#xA;the high mountains – they were both similar. We were reminded of the&#xA;distant afternoon of the “curtain” where we experienced the pleasures of&#xA;R’s company. Our reverie, as the pleasures of existence, was broken by&#xA;the call from Jx. Everyone was talking about Jx’s wonderful cell phone,&#xA;but Jx insisted it never worked. They then looked at my one cell phone&#xA;which was purchased on last shelf of the last shop in Sadashiv Peth.&#xA;Unlike Jx’s they were not sure if mine would even work. I kept it to my&#xA;ear and went through the routines. It made some wierd noises. At night&#xA;it would ring without reason. We remembered our muni’s words: “It is a&#xA;two fold problem of both purchasing a cell phone for you and selling the&#xA;peculiar camera-cum-phone you have devised”. In the Sadashiv Peth&#xA;operation we had received our current cell phone in barter for the&#xA;peculiar camera-cum-phone we had made. The learned muni, wise beyond his&#xA;years, had warned us that in the desh nobody really wanted peculiar&#xA;devices of that type. pretabuddhI drAviDAchAryaputri had bought that&#xA;c-c-p we had made. On account of her perverse bent she was unable use&#xA;the phone. She wondered why such devices existed in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>navagupta’s abhichAra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/03/2005-03-17_navaguptas-abhichara/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/03/2005-03-17_navaguptas-abhichara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/03/17/navaguptas-abhichara/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;sha~Nkara bhagavatpAda had defeated the famous tantric navagupta of the&#xA;pITha of kAmarUpa in a debate. navagupta unable to come to terms with&#xA;his defeat invoked chAmuNDA with oblations of twigs dipped in menstrual&#xA;blood and the sUtaka fluid. And thus he laid a spell on sha~Nkara. The&#xA;unerring abhichAra of the great goddess had its effect on the Acharya&#xA;and he was afflicted by a terrible sore in his ass. As a result of this&#xA;he was wasting away much to the dismay of his students. When pressed by&#xA;them he revealed that it was a result of navagupta’s incantations. His&#xA;student padmapAda quickly got into action and invoked the most deadly&#xA;spell of nR^isiMha in the form known as the aShTamukha gaNDabheruNDa&#xA;ugranR^isiMha. As result the spell of navagupta was back-hurled and it&#xA;possessed him and killed him. The accounts state that the AchArya had to&#xA;worship kumAra at kumAra parvata to rid himself of the disease. It here&#xA;that he composed the famous poem to the god in the bhuja~Nga meter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The recombination game</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/03/2005-03-12_the-recombination-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/03/2005-03-12_the-recombination-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/03/12/the-recombination-game/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There was always a spirit of competition between me and my father. Same was true of my brother. We felt internally satisfied when we did better than him in some areas of mental and physical ability. Eventually, in the domain of knowledge and science we became superior to him. But there were 3 areas we never measured up to him:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the enormous ability for mental arithmetic calculations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;cricket and&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;that “pAshupata yoga” attitude to life.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is that yoga that has led him to all his successes in life and every other ability of his was merely an incidental matter. He is always secretive of that yoga but definitely consciously confident of it. It is hardly of the flashy kind that so many yogIs may display, and the enormous difficulties he has faced in life have definitely had their mark on him, but his ability to survive has depended on that yoga.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The journey to Kashi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/03/2005-03-10_the-journey-to-kashi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/03/2005-03-10_the-journey-to-kashi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/03/10/the-journey-to-kashi/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the Atman, which merely watches, is poised to cast away its&#xA;sharIra and the old corpses shall lie on the path of no return, as&#xA;though marked by the dance of sharva, we shall narrate those old events&#xA;that we shall probably never get to talk of, once we walk ahead on the&#xA;path. The tale of the yogi prince of Shri Lanka who was offered putrid&#xA;food by the Dakini in the house of pleasure in bhArata came to our mind.&#xA;Also the dyadic fate of yayAti presented itself. After the enjoyment of&#xA;pleasures on earth and svarga one may fall head long from the lokas, as&#xA;the purANas talk of the meteoric crash of an individual who has&#xA;exhausted his puNya.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The wicks of bhairavAnanda</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/03/2005-03-08_the-wicks-of-bhairavananda/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/03/2005-03-08_the-wicks-of-bhairavananda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/03/08/the-wicks-of-bhairavananda/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having worshipped krodhabhairava and offered his arghya to shikhAshekhara, bhairavAnanda obtained the four wicks of atyendrajAla. These wicks he handed over to the 4 seekers of wealth. This tale is all only too well known to all our compatriots.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now there is another one. somAkhya had visited the 3: ishAnashiva, vimalashambhu and ugratANDavadeva. They gave somAkhya the wick of jha~NkArabhairava. somAkhya carrying that wick wandered widely for many years on the hills such as hanumat parvata, pAShaNDa parvata, durgA parvata, umA parvata and vetAla parvata. During these wanderings the only voice he heard was that of a talking goose. Finally after descending from the parvatas and suffering intensely in his travels he was walking along the plains of vimAnasthala when his wick suddenly dropped. somAkhya vigorously dug at the spot and obtained a load of copper. Carrying this copper with difficutly he placed at a shed in his dwelling. Then he visited vimalashambhu and asked what he may do with the copper. vimalashambhu answered: Perform yoga, you may be able make use of the copper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
