<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Byzantium on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/byzantium/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Byzantium on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/byzantium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>al-jAhiz_on_byzantines</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/byzantium/al-jAhiz_on_byzantines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/byzantium/al-jAhiz_on_byzantines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Al Jahiz in the 9th century writes with no holds barred and calls the Byzantines LARPers who are a completely different people from the Ancient Greeks. He says the Ancient Greeks are no more, the Byzantines (Rum) just claim to be their inheritors based on geographical proximity.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Had the common people but known that the Christians and the Byzantines have neither wisdom nor clarity [of mind] nor depth of thought but are simply clever with their hands in wood-turning, carpentry, plastic arts, and weaving of silk brocade, they would have removed them from the ranks of the literati and dropped them from the roster of philosophers and sages - because&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Byzantine failure</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/byzantium/byzantine-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/byzantium/byzantine-failure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Messages on the net.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When were they successful? Apart from Belisarius conquering a chunk of Italy and Maghreb, they never did anything else. Just continuously lost land and stagnated despite having the entirety of Greek science at their disposal for 1000 years. Their brightest moments came in 717 during Siege of Constantinople and in the 6th century. Although even in the 700s they only won defensively. They lost most of their lands to Ummayads.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Byzantine frontiersmen</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/byzantium/byzantine-frontiersmen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/byzantium/byzantine-frontiersmen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1505307874699800576.html&#34;&gt;Anna&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Eastern Roman “Wild West” &amp;amp; the Epic Ballads of Roman Frontiersmen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This was the ERE or the Byzantine Empire in 629 AD ~ The Byzantine-Sassanid wars have concluded. The Siege of Constantinople is won &amp;amp; Emperor Heraclius has restored the true cross to Jerusalem. These futile wars with back &amp;amp; forth land grabs costing immense amounts of money &amp;amp; manpower crippled both empires, a “trench warfare” of sorts. However, the Sassanid Empire completely collapsed to a rising tide: the Arab Muslims. The House of Sassan would flee to Tang China.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constantine System tragedy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/byzantium/constantine-system-tragedy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/byzantium/constantine-system-tragedy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rattibha.com/thread/1516837317209640963?lang=en&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The historiography of Constantine and his dynasty has a sort of mythology about it that he forcefully set the empire on a new path and rejuvenated it, that he was a caudillo who appeared at a time of crisis. But on closer examination a different image comes into focus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you were tasked with describing his dynasty in one word, it would have to be &amp;ldquo;byzantine.&amp;rdquo; In two words, &amp;ldquo;eunuch intrigue.&amp;rdquo; Constantine himself was a very capable man. But a rather un-principled one, and strangely impressionable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
