<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Cochran Gregory on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Cochran Gregory on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zones of Thought</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-03-28_zones-of-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-03-28_zones-of-thought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.wordpress.com/2012/03/28/zones-of-thought/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zones of Thought&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/205.png&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/205.png?w=640&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://westhunt.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/205.png?w=640&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;scientific papers&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;        scientific papers&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most people think that science and math and engineering are found&#xA;everywhere, like soccer, but actually, they are regional practices, more&#xA;like hurling or tossing the caber. In the map, countries are resized&#xA;according to the number of scientific papers they produce. Population&#xA;size plays a role, but average productivity matters more. Note that&#xA;Singapore, with a population of 5 million, looks bigger than Indonesia,&#xA;with 240 million people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A sobering thought</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-03-23_a-sobering-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-03-23_a-sobering-thought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.wordpress.com/2012/03/23/a-sobering-thought/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A sobering thought&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In scuba diving, pressure increases by one atmosphere with each ten&#xA;meters of depth. As pressure increases, people breathing standard air&#xA;mix gradually get silly. This is mainly caused by the increasing&#xA;nitrogen pressure, and is called nitrogen narcosis, or sometimes,&#xA;rapture of the deeps. The effect of nitrogen narcosis is a bit like&#xA;being drunk – closer to sniffing nitrous oxide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The effects are measurable, and sometimes noticeable, at one extra&#xA;atmosphere, ten meters down. As a rough guide, divers sometimes cite&#xA;‘Martini’s Law’, the notion that the effect of nitrogen narcosis is like&#xA;that of an martini for each extra ten meters of depth.+++(4)+++&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If I were a science</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-03-20_if-i-were-a-science-fiction-writer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-03-20_if-i-were-a-science-fiction-writer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.wordpress.com/2012/03/20/if-i-were-a-science-fiction-writer/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I were a science fiction writer&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I sent this to Jerry Pournelle some time ago: here’s a current version&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let us assume that we really could make drugs that increased&#xA;intelligence.+++(4)+++ I’m pretty sure it’s actually possible, and the approach&#xA;that makes it easy is looking at the results of natural selection,&#xA;rather than trying to understand everything about human biochemistry&#xA;from the ground up. Some of the causative mutations in Ashkenazi&#xA;genetic diseases such as Tay-Sachs and Gaucher are good candidates. If I&#xA;were a science fiction writer, I’d wonder where an application of this&#xA;would lead. I can think of a number of possibilities – for some of them,&#xA;the book or short story has already been written.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Object of Emulation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-03-19_the-object-of-emulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-03-19_the-object-of-emulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.wordpress.com/2012/03/19/the-object-of-emulation/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Object of Emulation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By definition, most people are not in the top 1% of intellect, so books&#xA;aimed primarily at that top 1% are never going to be best sellers. The&#xA;question arises, what is the most effective strategy for developing a&#xA;best seller?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thinking of Dan Brown and Malcolm Gladwell, it looks as if&#xA;simply being a person of modest intellect may be an effective strategy&#xA;for writers. I’m not saying that it is the only possible strategy, but&#xA;it may be easier if one never thinks of anything too complicated in the&#xA;first place, rather than having to weigh the level of difficulty of&#xA;every sentence and concept. Probably one would have to be a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;smarter than average to effortlessly simulate normality, particularly in&#xA;real time. It is said that John von Neumann could do this. In much the&#xA;same way, emulating an obsolete computer is fairly easy – for machines&#xA;that are a decade more advanced.+++(5)+++&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Only Game in Town</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-03-12_the-only-game-in-town/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-03-12_the-only-game-in-town/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.wordpress.com/2012/03/12/the-only-game-in-town/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Only Game in Town&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over on Discover gnxp, Victor said “As far as IQ is concerned, I find&#xA;such comparisons meaningless. An IQ test devised by members of some&#xA;African tribe is going to be very different from one devised by Western&#xA;academics. And I can guarantee that most “Caucasians” would not do very&#xA;well on such a test.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I mention this not because it is true or sensible, but rather because it&#xA;is often said. I can hardly count the times that I have seen someone&#xA;make this argument. The person putting it forth usually thinks of it as&#xA;utterly crushing. Another related argument is that there are ‘lots of&#xA;different kinds of intelligence” – so who can say what really matters?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get Smart</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-03-09_get-smart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-03-09_get-smart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.wordpress.com/2012/03/09/get-smart/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Get Smart&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are now at the point where we can realistically expect to see&#xA;interventions that significantly increase human intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;gene-doubling&#34;&gt;Gene doubling&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some approaches build on our real but limited understanding of how the&#xA;brain works. For example, by adding an extra copy of the NR2B gene, the&#xA;Doogie mouse developed better memory. Today there are about 30&#xA;genetically modified mouse strains with improved memory, most making use&#xA;of various tweaks of the same enzyme path influenced by the NR2B gene.+++(4)+++&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plotzing</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-02-05_plotzing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-02-05_plotzing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.wordpress.com/2012/02/05/plotzing/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Plotzing&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was thinking about a series by David Plotz about the Nobel Prize Sperm&#xA;Bank, about ten years ago. It was an amazingly stupid and dishonest&#xA;series – even for Slate. The Repository for Germinal Choice only managed&#xA;to obtain sperm from one Nobelist (William Shockley), and that sample&#xA;didn’t produce a baby. Almost all of the donors were pretty&#xA;high-achievement types, though, and the few kids that Plotz managed to&#xA;contact were ( on average) unusually smart. On the other hand, one can’t&#xA;be sure that they were representative of the 200-odd kids produced by&#xA;this positive-eugenics effort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Increase</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/recent-increase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/recent-increase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The increase in intelligence over the past 10k years (shown in Europeans) explains a lot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why was cultural change so slow in the deep past?  Why was invention so rare? Because people weren&amp;rsquo;t smart enough yet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen anthropology professors claim that all  homo sapiens populations, even hundreds of thousands of years ago,  just had to have the same capabilities as high-performing groups today. Not  the case.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Similar changes probably happened in at least one other population ( East Asians) but not to the same extent, or at all, in others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skin color comparison</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/skin-color-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/intelligence/articles/cochran_gregory/skin-color-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/gcochran99/status/1903941246948704473&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the past several thousand years, alleles that increase intelligence have become more common in Europeans, due to natural selection.  So Europeans today are considerably smarter than their ancestors were 10,000 years ago.  These frequency changes only involved a few hundred alleles at most, a small fraction of the genome.  So they don&amp;rsquo;t have much effect on whole-genome stats like Fst.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FST, or the fixation index, is a measure used in population genetics to quantify the degree of genetic differentiation between populations. It essentially tells us how much genetic variation exists between groups compared to the total variation within and between them. The term comes from Sewall Wright&amp;rsquo;s F-statistics, and FST is a specific case of those metrics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
