<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Akan slave dominance</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/articles/akan-slave-dominance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/articles/akan-slave-dominance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: African Founders: How enslaved people expanded American ideals  - David Fischer&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Summary&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most slaves in New England were Coromantee, from Akan speaking Fante and Asante tribes. They had a strong military tradition which they carried into the New World. They were very militant &amp;amp; led most of the great slave revolts or rebellions. Many fought in the Revolutionary War.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They were far from docile in the twenty-first-century meaning of being easily controlled. Europeans on the coast often observed that Akan-speaking people shared a strong warrior ethic. Males in Fanteland were organized into military companies called asafo, and trained for war with elaborate regalia, rituals, dances, and huge cloth flags that were symbols of their culture and history.&#xA;A very strong warrior tradition existed also among Asante to the north. The scale and violence of warfare increased in the eighteenth century, when a great king, Osei Tutu, founded the Asante empire. Here as elsewhere in other African regions, periods of dynastic warfare increased the flow of captives to slave markets. 66&#xA;These Fante and Asante military traditions were brought to the New World. On West Indian islands where slaves were severely abused, Coromantees earned a reputation as among the most militant and violent of Africans. They led the great Jamaica slave revolt in 1690, founded major Jamaican communities of maroons or escaped slaves by 1739, and organized the Antigua independence movement of 1736. They were at the center of Tacky&amp;rsquo;s War in Jamaica, the Berbice slave war in Guyana in 1763, and Demerara&amp;rsquo;s great slave rebellion of 1823. These events were among the largest and most successful slave risings in the history of the British West Indies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haiti</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/articles/haiti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/articles/haiti/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lumumba murder</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/articles/lumumba-murder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/articles/lumumba-murder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A Patriot Elected Prime minister of an Independent country,killed, dissolved in Acid, Only teeth as a remembrance left&amp;rdquo; authorised by CIA, President of USA &amp;amp; executed by Belgium,all for Uranium,for it&amp;rsquo;s Bombs (Hiroshima &amp;amp; Nagasaki) &amp;amp; then Coup d&amp;rsquo;tetat. Sounds similar?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Patrice Emery Lumumba was born as Elias Okitasombo on July 2, 1925 in Onalua, a village in the Kasai Oriental. After receiving basic education in local school, he settled in Stanleyville (now Kisangani), a city in the northeastern part of the Democratic Republic of the Congo. By 1950s, Patrice Lumumba was squarely involved in Congolese politics. In 1958, he helped create the Mouvement National Congolais (MNC), a pro-independence party in the Congo. MNC was unique among Congolese political parties. It was not organized along ethnic or tribal line.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
