<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/articles/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/articles/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Sanskrit history of the conquest of parNAla-parvata</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-05-19_a-sanskrit-history-of-the-conquest-of-parnala-parvata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-05-19_a-sanskrit-history-of-the-conquest-of-parnala-parvata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/05/19/a-sanskrit-history-of-the-conquest-of-parnala-parvata/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Brahmins do not have it in them to fight” was a common refrain I had&#xA;heard despite being brought up on the tales of the bhR^igu conquests of&#xA;yore- r^ichIka, jamadagni, rAma, agni aurva and all of them. I had&#xA;almost internalized it. But my conversations with PR got me thinking&#xA;about it from different angles till I discovered the truth. My learned&#xA;AchArya had a peculiar regard for PR: he would regularly come to recite&#xA;the R^ig veda when he taught it and would only talk with our AchArya in&#xA;Sanskrit. Otherwise, he spoke with none and had an air of mystery and&#xA;power about him. I had occasionally seen them converse about performing&#xA;a shrauta rite but, they would generally be secretive about it. He had&#xA;some kind of secular job, because I had noted him and pitAshrI talk on&#xA;some technical issues. That was only time he ever used the AnglIka&#xA;bhASha, else he spoke only either in Sanskrit, Maharatti or Tamil&#xA;tongues. He was well-versed in the aShTAdhyAyI and used to cite sutra-s&#xA;and demonstrate them with ease. Once my yajur vedic teacher asked me&#xA;approach him on learning about R^ig in practice with respect to the&#xA;mysterious nyU~nkha and ninarda mode of recitation of mantra-s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Bajirao-I</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-02-28_on-bajirao-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-02-28_on-bajirao-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/02/28/on-bajirao-i/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The muni and me stood on the elevated wall of the plinth of the shanivAr&#xA;palace (Shaniwar palace) on a blazing Indian afternoon about an year&#xA;ago. That was all that was left of the palace built by the famed Peshwa,&#xA;who had raised the Maharattas to their greatest glory. The Peshva was a&#xA;Brahmin of the coastal community different from the interior brahmins of&#xA;Maharashtra. Some have believed that these Brahmins had origins&#xA;elsewhere in North India, but genetically they are not very different&#xA;from other “pa~ncha-draviDa” brahmin groups. However, they were&#xA;probably isolated for long in the coastal zone. His Shaniwar palace is&#xA;now the haunt of vagabonds, so common in the Indian landscape, and a&#xA;truely desolate ruin, that one wonders what has happened to the sense of&#xA;history of the city’s residents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>End of the Maharattas – I</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-05-13_end-of-the-maharattas-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-05-13_end-of-the-maharattas-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/05/13/end-of-the-maharattas-i/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An important lesson is there to be learnt from what happened between&#xA;1795 to 1818 vis-a-vis the Maharattas. Bajirao II handed himself up to&#xA;British protection as he was in conflict with Daulatrao Shinde. Shinde&#xA;was in turn in locked in enemity with Yashvant and Vithoji Holkar and&#xA;the other major Maharatta chiefs like Gaikwad in Gujarat and Bhosle of&#xA;Nagpur. Vithoji Holkar was given to banditry and he began large scale&#xA;thievery and raiding along with his Pendharis north of the Krishna&#xA;river. Vithoji was captured by Bajirao with the help of the British and&#xA;crushed under an elephant in Pune. Yashvant Holkar was enraged by the&#xA;Peshva killing his half brother Vithoji and prepared to attack the&#xA;Peshva. But Daulat Shinde attacked him with his division in North India&#xA;and inflicted heavy damages. Yashvant however escaped and returned to&#xA;take Khandesh and plundered the city of Ahmadnagar and the surroundings&#xA;where he demolished all the palaces of Shinde and burnt the townships.&#xA;Daulat Shinde then sent his forces to attack Yashvant Holkar. Bajirao&#xA;tried to parley with Holkar, but the Konkanasta Brahmin- Maharatta&#xA;rivalry came in the way and the brahmin chief Purandare decided to lead&#xA;the Peshva’s army to attack Holkar. Holkar smashed Purandhare’s troops&#xA;at Baramati and started advancing towards Pune. The Peshva now appealed&#xA;to the Neo-Maharatta Daulat Shinde to aid him. Shinde sent Sadashiv&#xA;Bhaskar, his chief general to aid the Peshva and set out to corner&#xA;Holkar. The Holkar and Shinde armies clashed in the vicinity of Pune in&#xA;fierce fight in which the two Neo-Maharattas exhausted their resources&#xA;in the midst of heavy killing. Bajirao fled from Pune and placed himself&#xA;in British custody at Bassein. Holkar took Pune and place Amritrao, the&#xA;brother of Bajirao, as Peshva. Holkar tried to unite the other Maharatta&#xA;chiefs for a show down with the Britons, but they paid a deaf ear and so&#xA;he left Pune. In 1803 the Britons marched in to Pune and placed Bajirao&#xA;on the gaddi as their puppet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>War in the Konkan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-04-06_war-in-the-konkan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-04-06_war-in-the-konkan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/04/06/war-in-the-konkan/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Very little has been recorded of the valiant freedom struggle in the&#xA;Konkan in the horror years of Indian history. The Konkans on the west&#xA;coast of India had long been the bastion of the Indic civilization that&#xA;withstood external attacks due to the protective influence of the&#xA;Western Ghats. The first major wave of Islamic onslaughts on the region&#xA;was initiated by Alla-ad-din Khalji when he dispatched his ace commander&#xA;Maliq Kaffr to wage Jihad on the ancient dynasty of the Kadambas, who&#xA;were the principal rulers of the Konkans. In 1312, the Army of Islam&#xA;entered the Konkan with a largecavalry force and devastated&#xA;Gopakapattana the capital of the Kadambas. The routed Kadambas fled&#xA;inwards to Chandrapura, an ancient city of great significance in the&#xA;shaiva tAntrika tradition, with their surviving army and defended the&#xA;land against the Islamic assault from this fortified stronghold. In the&#xA;1320s, in course of his invasion of South India Mohammad-ibn-Tughlaq&#xA;made a lateral thrust into the Konkan, after his assault on the Kondana&#xA;fort, Pune, to fructify the aborted Jihad of his predecessor. With over&#xA;80,000 horsemen he invaded Chandrapura, overwhelmed the Kadamba defenses&#xA;and destroyed the city. However, as Tughlaq got engaged in other battles&#xA;and started making preparations for his disastrous invasion of the&#xA;Mongol empire via Tibet, the Kadamba chief Bhima Bhupala initiated the&#xA;war of liberation in the Konkan in 1327. After a several encounters with&#xA;the Islamic garrisons the Kadamba chiefs destroyed them completely,&#xA;liberating much of Konkan region. Soon after that the large-scale Hindu&#xA;revival began in South India under the Harihara and Bukka, and in 1347&#xA;the remaining territory of the Konkan in the province of Malerajya was&#xA;liberated by the assault of Harihara.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mongol-marATha-comparison</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/articles/MT_lekhAH/mongol-marATha-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/articles/MT_lekhAH/mongol-marATha-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1613063733399494657.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A useful exercise in comparative history is to compare the last H empire, that of the marAThA-s, to the Chingizid Mongol empire. While separated in time by several centuries, they had certain similar approaches, problems, and the solutions&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;succession&#34;&gt;Succession&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The issue of succession after the founder was badly handled among the marAThA but better handled among the Mongols - &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2018/08/31/a-brief-overview-of-the-last-campaign-of-chingiz-khan-and-the-issue-of-succession-in-the-mongol-empire/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the later phase the marAThA-s had relatively good run of the kokanastha prime ministers while the chingizids suffered many succession issues. In some ways the struggle of raghunAtha rAv &amp;amp; the main line was paralled by Arik Boke, Qaidu and Dua&amp;rsquo;s struggle as counter-Khans with the main line. All in all the Initial succession issues after the Chatrapati&amp;rsquo;s death set back the marAThA-s much more than anything the Mongols faced till Quibilai.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PAnipaT regression</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/articles/MT_lekhAH/pAnipaT-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/articles/MT_lekhAH/pAnipaT-regression/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1977413008411262991&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;While the H came back in the north under the shinde and the sikh power grew rapidly in the northwestern reaches of the core Indosphere, one could make a case that Panipat-3 left a lasting structural damage that through a long chain of downstream events weakened the marAThA war machine. Barring the effort of the shinde-s, it seems to have made the marAThA-s fall back on time-tested mobile tactics that could yield immediate results but would not hold against a well-disciplined force with strong artillery elements (shinde understood this point well):  the times were changing under their feet as the late 1700s drew to a close. One could compare it to the last Mongol efforts to save the Qing, as the descendants of Chingiz Khan&amp;rsquo;s brother Qasar valiantly led mobile cavalry assaults: they could only go that far in face of disciplined formations with good arti support. In many ways, I think bAjIrav-I was like Chingiz or Subedei reborn for one final time in jambudvIpa before nirvANa. His success in at cusp of the changing times influenced his successors to continue with such tactics after the setback at Panipat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
