<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;perversion of paralance on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/perversion_of_paralance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;perversion of paralance on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/perversion_of_paralance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00 CHAPTER 1 - Something Seriously Wrong Somewhere</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/perversion_of_paralance/00_ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/perversion_of_paralance/00_ch1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1---something-seriously-wrong-somewhere&#34;&gt;CHAPTER 1 - Something Seriously Wrong Somewhere&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was the summer of 1959. I was working as secretary of an organisation of which the late Shri Jayaprakash Narayan was the president. One day an RSS leader walked into my office. I had known him for a number of years. After some small talk, he suggested that I should request J.P. to visit an RSS camp which was being held in New Delhi at that time. J.P. also happened to be in town. I was diffident about the proposition. Having worked with J.P. for more than an year, I had sensed his preferences and prejudices. But I promised to the RSS leader that I would do my best. I broached the subject to J.P. next day, as soon as I found him alone, which was a rare event. J.P. seemed to be stunned as if I had uttered an obscenity. There was an expression of displeasure on his face which made me too feel uncomfortable. He was a gentle person who seldom lost his temper. But now he seemed to be on the verge of exploding. The atmoshphere became tense. For a moment none of us could find words to break the spell of silence. At last J.P. controlled himself and said :&#xA;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do you know what you are talking, and to whom ?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; There was a touch of&#xA;temper in his voice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 CHAPTER 2 - Words Which Defy Dictionaries</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/perversion_of_paralance/01_ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/perversion_of_paralance/01_ch2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-2---words-which-defy-dictionaries&#34;&gt;CHAPTER 2 - Words Which Defy Dictionaries&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As one surveys India&amp;rsquo;s political parlance the first features one notices is that while certain people and parties are described as Leftist, certain others are designated as Righist. Once in a while, political scientists and journalists add nuances to this broad bracketing when they pronounce some splinter group as Left or Right of Centre. But one is left guessing about the location of the Centre itself. It is sometimes suggested that the Centre is constituted by the ruling Congress Party. The Congress Party however, repudiates this description.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 CHAPTER 3 - The Sources Of Leftist Language</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/perversion_of_paralance/02_ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/perversion_of_paralance/02_ch3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-3---the-sources-of-leftist-language&#34;&gt;CHAPTER 3 - The Sources Of Leftist Language&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Leftist professors and publicists claim that their language got formulated in the course of India&amp;rsquo;s fight for freedom from British rule. They also claim that this language was used in the field at various stages of the struggle for freedom. This is a plain and a big lie. The annals of that freedom struggle provide no evidence that this language was used in India&amp;rsquo;s politics till the late thirties of this century. Some prominent words of this language were totally absent from India&amp;rsquo;s political parlance prior to that time. Some other words which we do find in that parlance were used to convey meanings that were entirely different from the meanings they acquired at a later stage. And even when these words became current in their present-day sense their consumption was confined to a small Leftist coterie inside and outside the freedom movement. It was only after the attainment of independence that this parlance spread like a plague, particularly during the period when Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru dominated the Indian political scene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 CHAPTER 4 - The Character of Leftist Language</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/perversion_of_paralance/03_ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/perversion_of_paralance/03_ch4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-4---the-character-of-leftist-language&#34;&gt;CHAPTER 4 - The Character of Leftist Language&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ever since its inauguration in the opening years of this century, the language of Leftism has been the loudest in denouncing this or that imperialism. Quite often, it has imagined or invented an imperialism where none existed. This exercise has helped it to hide the fact that it itself is the latest language of imperialism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imperialism down the ages has evolved and employed a number of languages. The verbiage has varied according to differences of time and clime. But all languages of imperialism have shared certain characteristics in common. The language of Leftism passes this test quite creditably.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 CHAPTER 5 - The History of Leftist Language</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/perversion_of_paralance/04_ch5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/perversion_of_paralance/04_ch5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-5---the-history-of-leftist-language&#34;&gt;CHAPTER 5 - The History of Leftist Language&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Leftist language first came to India as the language of Communist imperialism. Its main spokesman was M.N. Roy. In his &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;India in Transition&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;, published in 1922, he laid down practically all fundamental formulations which, in due course, became the stock-in-trade of India&amp;rsquo;s Leftist parties. The language of these formulations is still the language of Leftism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It will facilitate an understanding of Roy&amp;rsquo;s formulations if we summarise briefly the background of Indian nationalism as it had developed prior to that period. There are certain key words and phrases used by Roy whichg may cause confustion unless they are clarified in advance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 CHAPTER 6 - The Role of Leftist Language</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/perversion_of_paralance/05_ch6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/perversion_of_paralance/05_ch6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-6---the-role-of-leftist-language&#34;&gt;CHAPTER 6 - The Role of Leftist Language&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The language of Communist imperialism continued to lambast the Congress leadership, particularly Mahatma Gandhi for the latter&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;failure to mobilize the toiling masses towards an immediate overthrow of the British rule in India.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; But when the Congress launched a mass movement in March, 1930, the spokesmen of this language kept strictly aloof from it. Instead they published a Draft Plam of Action in December, 1930 characterising the Congress as a &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;class organisation of the capitalists working against the fundamental interests of the toiling masses.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; And they tried to sabotage the freedom struggle by splitting the trade union movement over which they had acquired some hold with the help of finances flowing from the Soviet Union.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 CHAPTER 7 - The Place of Mahatma Gandhi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/perversion_of_paralance/06_ch7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/perversion_of_paralance/06_ch7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-7---the-place-of-mahatma-gandhi&#34;&gt;CHAPTER 7 - The Place of Mahatma Gandhi&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The language of British and Christian imperialism had stood fully exposed for what they were in essence by the time tht Swadeshi Movement swept forward after the Partition of Bengal in 1905. The language of Islamic imperialism had revived but was not resounding enough as yet to ring bells in the minds of national leaders. And the language of Communist imperialism had not yet appeared on the scene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 CHAPTER 8 - Towards A Language of Indian Nationalism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/perversion_of_paralance/07_ch8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/perversion_of_paralance/07_ch8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-8---towards-a-language-of-indian-nationalism&#34;&gt;CHAPTER 8 - Towards A Language of Indian Nationalism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have seen in the foregoing chapters, that India&amp;rsquo;s prevalent political parlance - Right and Left, Reactionary and Progressive Revivalist and Revolutionary, Fascist and Democratic, Communal and Secular, Capitalist and Socialist,, etc. &amp;ndash; is an alien imposition imported mostly from Soviet Russia by a fifth-column of Communist imperialism. We have also seen how this language shares its basic characteristic with the languages of Islamic, Christian and British imperialism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
