<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;gautier ferengi columns on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;gautier ferengi columns on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/00_ch0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/00_ch0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE FERENGI’S COLUMNS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(A Western journalist opening his eyes to the true India)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By François Gautier&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;dedicated: &amp;ldquo;to Sri Sri &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The author wishes to express his gratitude to Sudheendra Kulkarni, one&#xA;time editor of Blitz; to Mr. Narayanan, editor of the Hindustan Times,&#xA;when it was still a versatile newspaper; and to Shekhar Gupta, editor of&#xA;the Indian Express, who stuck by him in spite of a lot of internal&#xA;resistance !&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/01_ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/01_ch1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. AYODHYA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ayodhya marks my political awakening. It is there that for the first&#xA;time I came in contact with this strange phenomenon of Indian politics&#xA;(which repeats itself all over the world): that what appears true, may&#xA;often turn out to be false or is at best a half-truth; and that which&#xA;seems false, or politically not correct, often turns out to be a truth.&#xA;Journalism has to be a &lt;em&gt;first-hand&lt;/em&gt; experience; that is, the&#xA;correspondent should be able to judge what he has been asked to report –&#xA;not through the prism of his atavism, set ideas and prejudices which he&#xA;brings with him - but thanks to an inner intuition towards which he has&#xA;constantly to aspire. Ayodhya is the perfect example of an untruth which&#xA;has been taken as a universal truth by India and the whole world,&#xA;because very few journalists cared to look beyond appearances.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/02_ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/02_ch2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2. KASHMIR : A DEAD-END AND A SOLUTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nothing symbolizes better the absurdity of Partition than Kashmir. Nehru&#xA;and Gandhi’s folly of accepting the division of the country on&#xA;geographical-religion lines has come back to haunt India with a&#xA;vengeance. For, Pakistan, apart from the fact that it was created and&#xA;survives on its hatred of ‘Hindu’ India, has a point: if Nehru accepted&#xA;that Muslim-dominated parts of India go to Pakistan, why not also the&#xA;Valley of Kashmir, which is today in Muslim majority, thanks to decades&#xA;of terror to induce the once strong Hindu community to flee ? Thus,&#xA;Kashmir is a dead-end, because neither India nor Pakistan are going to&#xA;let go, each for obvious reasons. Yet, the state of Kashmir can also be&#xA;the springing-board for a trial run of a Confederation of South Asian&#xA;Sates: there is no other solution for Pakistan and India than reuniting&#xA;the two Kashmirs under a joint authority.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/03_ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/03_ch3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3. THE CHRISTIANS : A MINORITY IN MORAL MAJORITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many of us in the West – at least those born in the forties and early&#xA;fifties – grew-up hearing of the wonderful and ‘saintly’ work done by&#xA;the &amp;ldquo;White&amp;rdquo; missionaries in far away and dangerous (that is jungle and&#xA;snake-infested) countries, where lived &amp;ldquo;Savages&amp;rdquo;, waiting to be&#xA;converted to the civilizing influence of Christianity. The reality which&#xA;I discovered in India was totally different: while there is no doubt&#xA;that Christian missionaries have done a remarkable work in the fields of&#xA;education and health, their prime purpose remains - even today - to&#xA;convert the ‘heathen’ Hindus to the True God – by any means. Christians&#xA;constitute only 3% of the population of India, but they weld an enormous&#xA;moral power, thanks in greater part to many of India’s intelligentsia&#xA;who are educated in Christian schools and taught to look at their own&#xA;culture in a derogatory manner. Nothing illustrates this better than the&#xA;way the Indian Press went berserk after the Staines murder, while&#xA;ignoring the crimes committed against the Hindus for centuries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/04_ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/04_ch4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. THE HINDUS : A MAJORITY IN MORAL MINORITY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here you have a huge majority of 850 million people, part of a culture&#xA;which is thousands of years old. A culture which has proved over the&#xA;ages its infinite tolerance towards other creeds and religions, giving&#xA;refuge to all persecuted minorities in the world, whether Parsis, Syrian&#xA;Christians, Jews, or Tibetans today. Yet Hindu-bashing has become a&#xA;favorite pastime of the Press, both Indian and Foreign – and when you&#xA;find someone such as Murli Manohar Joshi who wants to Indianize Indian&#xA;education, an aspiration which would be found natural in any country, he&#xA;is run down by his own people. Thus one finds that Hindus are&#xA;self-depreciating, tend to lack self-confidence and that they never&#xA;raise their voices in protest against the discrimination which is&#xA;practiced against them. In short, you have a huge physical majority in&#xA;moral minority. Is it because they are cowards ?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/05_ch5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/05_ch5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5. THE INDIAN MEDIA: AN HOSTILE FORCE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Indian journalists must be held responsible in some degree for the slow&#xA;progresses India has made in regaining her self-confidence, shattered by&#xA;centuries of colonization. For Indian journalists are often the worst&#xA;enemies of India and Indian culture, constantly harping at the negative&#xA;sides of India, constantly ignoring the greatness of this country. They&#xA;must also be the biggest Hindu-bashers in a nation where there are&#xA;already so many Hindu bashers (Marxists, Muslims, Christians,&#xA;politicians), having since Independence, made fun in the most belittling&#xA;manner of Hindu culture. Finally, they must also be held to some extent&#xA;responsible for the negative attitude that the western press has had&#xA;since towards India. For towards whom but the Indian journalists will&#xA;the newly arrived correspondent turn to understand this vast and&#xA;difficult continent ?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/06_ch6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/06_ch6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6. THE (UNFRIENDLY) NEIGHBOURS IN ASIA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;India is surrounded mostly by unfriendly neighbors. We see either&#xA;Islamic countries promoting a rabid anti-Hindu policy, such as&#xA;Afghanistan or Pakistan; or small inconsequent nations such as Nepal,&#xA;which owe so much to India, yet often harbor India’s enemies, as shown&#xA;by the Indian Airlines hijack of December 1999. Further East, we find&#xA;Japan, which has a sad hegemonic history, but was one of the most&#xA;vociferous nations against India after Pokhran II&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/07_ch7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/07_ch7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;7. THE WEST AND INDIA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The West, if it does not always show outright hostility to India, often&#xA;displays aggressive ignorance – the United States being the prime&#xA;example – although things are changing thanks to Clinton’s 1999 visit.&#xA;France, a country which had a huge sympathy capital in India, has not&#xA;exploited it because it is obsessed with China. On the friendly side,&#xA;the countries are very few : there is Israel, which shares so much with&#xA;India, yet has been ignored for decades to please the Arabs; or&#xA;non-communist Russia, which is discovering anew that she and India are&#xA;fighting a lonely battle against Muslim fundamentalism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/08_ch8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/08_ch8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;8. EXAMPLES NOT TO FOLLOW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are three countries which offer to India examples not to follow:&#xA;East Timor, Yugoslavia and Tibet. East Timor showed how converted&#xA;Christians provoke secession by alleging &amp;ldquo;persecution&amp;rdquo; and how the West&#xA;has a very short memory. Pundits have predicted for decades the&#xA;balkanisation of India, as it happened in Yugoslavia at the hands of&#xA;Kosovo; so far it has not materialised, but if India allows Kashmir to&#xA;go, who knows what might follow. And finally Tibet, because of it&#xA;isolation and feudalism which it did not care to redress in time, paid&#xA;also the price of its freedom&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09  Back to Contents Pagexa0 xa0 Back to VOI Booksxa0xa0 Back to Home</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/09_ch9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/09_ch9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;9. THE FALSE GODS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Indian mind’s spontaneous tendency is that of &lt;em&gt;bhakti&lt;/em&gt;, of&#xA;worshipping ‘That’ which it feels is above himself. While it is a&#xA;wonderful trait which has brought an innocence and a freshness to the&#xA;Indian psyche, it has been taken advantage in modern times by&#xA;politicians, Christian missionaries and intellectuals. Mother Teresa,&#xA;the Mahatma Gandhi, Rama Rao, or Sonia Gandhi, while they may have been&#xA;outstanding personalities in their own right, have all, consciously or&#xA;unconsciously exploited this innocence, whereas they did not always&#xA;deserved the status of Gods or semi-Gods given to them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/10_ch10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/10_ch10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;10. THE GREAT INDIAN MYTHS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since independence a few Great Indian Myths have done immeasurable harm&#xA;to the country. Yet not only do they survive today, but they are often&#xA;reborn under different avatars. One of these enduring myths concerns&#xA;Ashoka the Great embracing Buddhism, and making it a State religion.&#xA;Another of these other extremely pernicious myths is the Great&#xA;Indo-Chinese friendship, which even the BJP today seems to sometimes&#xA;believe in. The Mahatma Gandhi created the Myth of an inner war in the&#xA;Gita – and not an outer one. On the lower scale, we find the Great&#xA;Cricket Myth, a game of gentlemen, where Indians naturally excel,&#xA;although this myth has taken a bit of battering recently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/11_ch11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/11_ch11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;11. THE ROT OF BOLLYWOOD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is no coincidence that Pakistan, in connivance with Indian Muslims&#xA;and the covert approval of Saudi Arabia, chose Bombay to plant their&#xA;deadly bombs after the destruction of the mosque of Ayodhya. For there&#xA;has always been a strong connection between the Muslims of Bombay, with&#xA;Pakistan and Saudi Arabia, via the film industry (isn’t it, Mr Dilip&#xA;Kumar?). We all know how Indian actors and actresses used to be invited&#xA;at Dawood Ibrahim’s parties and today we have discovered how black&#xA;‘blood’ money is utilized to finance many of Bollywood mega-films. Thus,&#xA;some of these films encourage terrorism and secession in subtle and not&#xA;so subtle ways. We have chosen three such films: Refugee, Mission&#xA;Kashmir and Maachis..&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/12_ch12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/12_ch12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;12. INDIA: EVERYTHING THAT IT SHOULD NOT BE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;India is also the opposite of whatever it should be: so much appears to&#xA;have gone wrong in this country, everything has been perverted. And if&#xA;we had to name the horror that is India, we would say: the VIP culture;&#xA;Delhi an arrogant, superficial and polluted city; tourism where the&#xA;foreigner is a cow to be milked by the Government; there are also much&#xA;more than one billion human beings in India, whatever the Official&#xA;census says; and finally, India might be going towards an ecological&#xA;pralaya –a and nobody in this country gives a damn, certainly not the&#xA;NGO’s who are too busy making money out of India’s poverty.…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/13_ch13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/13_ch13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;13. THE HIDDEN TREASURES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If only India knew the treasure trove hidden in her midst! There is a&#xA;knowledge here, which has been lost to the world; there is a spiritual&#xA;fervor in this country, which is found nowhere in this degree on this&#xA;planet; there is a diversity of cultural and social expression in India,&#xA;which is unique in an increasingly unipolar world. We have chosen four&#xA;stories to illustrate this point: pranayama the science of breathing;&#xA;the astounding festival of Ayappa; kalaripayat, the ancestor of all&#xA;great Asian martial arts; and the jallikatu festival in Madurai. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/14_ch14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/gautier_ferengi_columns/14_ch14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;14. THE RENAISSANCE OF INDIA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is no doubt that under Prime Minister Vajpayee, India had entered&#xA;her Golden Period, her second Renaissance. But will the BJP remain&#xA;faithful to its original aspirations, or will it become &amp;ldquo;Congressized&amp;rdquo;&#xA;as Nostradamus has predicted? Do Indians even know about their own&#xA;civilization and how it influenced the whole world at one time?&#xA;Unfortunately schools and universities&amp;rsquo; curriculums teach a very bland&#xA;and westernized outlook on India and one man, Murali Manohar Joshi, is&#xA;fighting a lonely battle so that Indian children can learn to be proud&#xA;of their own countries. There has to be a Renaissance in all aspects of&#xA;Indian Life, including in science, where once India was a leader, but&#xA;today is just happy copying the West. Finally, will the mother of&#xA;Melting Pots become the India of the Third Millennium?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
