<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;volume 2 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;volume 2 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>051 WORK AND ITS SECRET</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/051_work_and_its_secret/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/051_work_and_its_secret/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-and-its-secret&#34;&gt;WORK AND ITS SECRET&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at Los Angeles, California, January 4, 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the greatest lessons I have learnt in my life is to pay as much&#xA;attention to the means of work as to its end. He was a great man from&#xA;whom I learnt it, and his own life was a practical demonstration of this&#xA;great principle I have been always learning great lessons from that one&#xA;principle, and it appears to me that all the secret of success is there;&#xA;to pay as much attention to the means as to the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>052 THE POWERS OF THE MIND</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/052_the_powers_of_the_mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/052_the_powers_of_the_mind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-powers-of-the-mind&#34;&gt;THE POWERS OF THE MIND&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at Los Angeles, California, January 8, 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All over the world there has been the belief in the supernatural&#xA;throughout the ages. All of us have heard of extraordinary happenings,&#xA;and many of us have had some personal experience of them. I would rather&#xA;introduce the subject by telling you certain facts which have come&#xA;within my own experience. I once heard of a man who, if any one went to&#xA;him with questions in his mind, would answer them immediately; and I was&#xA;also informed that he foretold events. I was curious and went to see him&#xA;with a few friends. We each had something in our minds to ask, and, to&#xA;avoid mistakes, we wrote down our questions and put them in our pockets.&#xA;As soon as the man saw one of us, he repeated our questions and gave the&#xA;answers to them. Then he wrote something on paper, which he folded up,&#xA;asked me to sign on the back, and said, &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t look at it; put it in&#xA;your pocket and keep it there till I ask for it again.&amp;rdquo; And so on to&#xA;each one of us. He next told us about some events that would happen to&#xA;us in the future. Then he said, &amp;ldquo;Now, think of a word or a sentence,&#xA;from any language you like.&amp;rdquo; I thought of a long sentence from Sanskrit,&#xA;a language of which he was entirely ignorant. &amp;ldquo;Now, take out the paper&#xA;from your pocket,&amp;rdquo; he said. The Sanskrit sentence was written there! He&#xA;had written it an hour before with the remark, &amp;ldquo;In confirmation of what&#xA;I have written, this man will think of this sentence.&amp;rdquo; It was correct.&#xA;Another of us who had been given a similar paper which he had signed and&#xA;placed in his pocket, was also asked to think of a sentence. He thought&#xA;of a sentence in Arabic, which it was still less possible for the man to&#xA;know; it was some passage from the Koran. And my friend found this&#xA;written down on the paper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>053 HINTS ON PRACTICAL SPIRITUALITY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/053_hints_on_practical_spirituality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/053_hints_on_practical_spirituality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hints-on-practical-spirituality&#34;&gt;HINTS ON PRACTICAL SPIRITUALITY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at the Home of Truth, Los Angeles, California&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This morning I shall try to present to you some ideas about breathing&#xA;and other exercises. We have been discussing theories so long that now&#xA;it will be well to have a little of the practical. A great many books&#xA;have been written in India upon this subject. Just as your people are&#xA;practical in many things, so it seems our people are practical in this&#xA;line. Five persons in this country will join their heads together and&#xA;say, &amp;ldquo;We will have a joint-stock company&amp;rdquo;, and in five hours it is done;&#xA;in India they could not do it in fifty years; they are so unpractical in&#xA;matters like this. But, mark you, if a man starts a system of&#xA;philosophy, however wild its theory may be, it will have followers. For&#xA;instance, a sect is started to teach that if a man stands on one leg for&#xA;twelve years, day and night, he will get salvation — there will be&#xA;hundreds ready to stand on one leg. All the suffering will be quietly&#xA;borne. There are people who keep their arms upraised for years to gain&#xA;religious merit. I have seen hundreds of them. And, mind you, they are&#xA;not always ignorant fools, but are men who will astonish you with the&#xA;depth and breadth of their intellect. So, you see, the word practical is&#xA;also relative.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>054 BHAKTI OR DEVOTION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/054_bhakti_or_devotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/054_bhakti_or_devotion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;bhakti-or-devotion&#34;&gt;BHAKTI OR DEVOTION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The idea of a Personal God has obtained in almost every religion, except&#xA;a very few. With the exception of the Buddhist and the Jain, perhaps all&#xA;the religions of the world have the idea of a Personal God, and with it&#xA;comes the idea of devotion and worship. The Buddhists and the Jains,&#xA;although they have no Personal God, worship the founders of their&#xA;religions in precisely the same way as others worship a Personal God.&#xA;This idea of devotion and worship to some higher being who can reflect&#xA;back the love to man is universal. In various religions this love and&#xA;devotion is manifested in various degrees, at different stages. The&#xA;lowest stage is that of ritualism, when abstract ideas are almost&#xA;impossible, and are dragged down to the lowest plane, and made concrete.&#xA;Forms come into play, and, along with them, various symbols. Throughout&#xA;the history of the world, we find that man is trying to grasp the&#xA;abstract through thought-forms, or symbols. All the external&#xA;manifestations of religion — bells, music, rituals, books, and images —&#xA;come under that head. Anything that appeals to the senses, anything that&#xA;helps man to form a concrete image of the abstract, is taken hold of,&#xA;and worshipped.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
