<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;vembu-shrIdharaH on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/labor/articles/svembu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;vembu-shrIdharaH on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/labor/articles/svembu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Grassroots capitalism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/labor/articles/svembu/grassroots-capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/labor/articles/svembu/grassroots-capitalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Pleasure of Pursuit- Grassroots capitalism&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sridhar Vembu  | 12 Nov, 2020&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(In 2011, Zoho Corp, a software product company headquartered in Chennai, opened an office in Tenkasi, Tamil Nadu, hoping to train and employ local youth. Last year, Sridhar Vembu, founder and CEO of Zoho, moved from his ranch in Pleasanton, California, to a village in Tenkasi. Vembu spent the lockdown practising what he preaches—grassroots capitalism. He wants to set up R&amp;amp;D and manufacturing projects in rural Tamil Nadu.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hidden potential</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/labor/articles/svembu/hidden-potential/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/labor/articles/svembu/hidden-potential/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I believe the most important economic and social priority for India and other developing nations should be to acquire complex technological know-how. Global inequality is mainly driven by lack of know-how because economic value added primarily goes to those that have it.+++(5)+++ Even within countries, regions with complex technological know-how (such as San Francisco Bay Area or Bengaluru) do vastly better than places such as Stockton/Fresno (not far from SF) and Dharmapuri (not far from Bengaluru). This inequality has become deep and structural.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opportunity vs remuneration</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/labor/articles/svembu/opportunity-vs-remuneration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/labor/articles/svembu/opportunity-vs-remuneration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: https://threader. app/thread/1314485494890196994)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Silicon valley used to have slogans like &amp;ldquo;we code for food&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;ramen profitability&amp;rdquo; - all before the Fed bubble era when billion dollar Series QE funding rounds became common. It may surprise people that Google only raised ~$25 million VC in total and that was common then.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That old silicon valley experience is very relevant today for rural and small town India. We have to roll up our sleeves and invent our way out of poverty and achieve &amp;ldquo;idli profitability&amp;rdquo; quickly. That&amp;rsquo;s the path to rapid capital development and durable prosperity. The raw material is our youth that longs for an opportunity, the vast latent talent pool of India.  The key initial investment is skill development, in a setting of real world projects as opposed to conventional college education. That is the idea behind &amp;ldquo;we code for food&amp;rdquo;. If you are a passionate and ambitious young entrepreneur, rural and small town India beckons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Village skills</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/labor/articles/svembu/village-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/labor/articles/svembu/village-skills/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1254925341786877952&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1254925341786877952&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When what we produce in a village does not get much value in exchange, our income is low.+++(5)+++ To raise income, we have to produce more valuable goods or services. We could also have people with higher productivity and income move in locally and spend some extra income locally. That second idea does not get enough attention. Yet it could play a key role in rural regeneration. If I get 10 well paid engineers to be located in a village of 1000 people and they start spending more of their income locally, it makes a meaningful difference quickly.+++(4)+++ Even in the very short term, it is helpful to local incomes. In the longer term, local skills grow and more village children aspire for high skilled jobs and learn the skills. We could rebalance the village economy with just 1% of the population in high skilled jobs. Of course if we can seed 1% by getting high skilled people to move to a village and then invest in training to create skilled jobs for another 1% of a village, the effect is a fairly substantial increase in overall village income, easily 2-3 times, due to all the multipliers. Seeding those 1% high paid jobs in a village is part of my agenda for Zoho. This is how we plan to redirect our jobs. I hope other entrepreneurs try similar ideas. Find a village you love and please don&amp;rsquo;t overcrowd the same place - there are 600K villages in India alone!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
