<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Misc Business on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/misc_businesses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Misc Business on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/misc_businesses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ads</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/misc_businesses/ads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/misc_businesses/ads/</guid>
      <description>Fundamentals The basic problem in advertising is finding the audience who is likely to buy the product/ service (target audience).
Placement and position There may be place for a limited number of advertisements to be displayed in a certain venue. Yet, there may be several advertisers competing for those places. Further they may be interested in gaining favorable placement in the ad-list.
Coupon distribution Consider a seller wanting to advertise inventory to target customers, or wanting to spur business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air travel</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/misc_businesses/air_travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/misc_businesses/air_travel/</guid>
      <description>Factors affecting price Travel date/ day Tickets cost more in certain months.
Tickets tend to cost more on Fridays, saturday, sunday, than on weekdays (especially monday).
Airport demand/ competition Flights from Dallas or houston probably cost less than flights from austin.
Operation costs Some airlines are cheaper than others.
Fuel costs This constitutes a major part of the operating costs.
Airlines which have access to cheaper fuel - either due to a stockpile (Southwest Airlines in 2000-2009), or geographic location (Emirates airlines) can offer lower prices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distribution</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/misc_businesses/distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/misc_businesses/distribution/</guid>
      <description>Retail vs wholesale Retail business focuses on distributing goods to consumers, while making a profit. Wholesalers focus on selling goods in bulk at a lower price to other businesses and distributors. Eg in USA: Sam’s club, costco. In India: Metro.
Price discrimination Different people are willing to pay different prices for the same product, and retailers try to exploit this.
In general, retailers try to distinguish the two types of customers by offering lower prices only to those who participate in some undesirable process which costs extra time and attention- eg: waiting for a certain day to make a purchase, committing to purchase in advance, gathering coupons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food making</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/misc_businesses/food/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/misc_businesses/food/</guid>
      <description>Agriculture Resources Agriculture requires non-saline water, fertile land, seeds, labor. Of these, overall, water is often most scarce.
Artificial production Research is on to produce meat in-vitro.
Demand and supply Past The discovery of agriculture enabled mass, reliable food production. For most of history, we have had a food surplus. When there was a famine in one country, one could rely on imports from another.
Forecast Human population is growing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gambling</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/misc_businesses/gambling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/misc_businesses/gambling/</guid>
      <description>Bet contract 2 outcomes Consider an event E. A bet between two people (A and B) is a contract which says that if E comes to pass (usually by a specified time), person A will pay an amount x to B; otherwise if E doesn’t happen, B will pay y to A.
y is called the bet liability.
Viability of the bet Rational B (who is not risk-averse) will enter the contract if according to his evaluation of a, a__x − (1 − a)y ≥ 0 or $a \geq \frac{y}{x+y}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manufacturing</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/misc_businesses/manufacturing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/misc_businesses/manufacturing/</guid>
      <description>Process design: Productivity and quality How to transform the shop-floor/ assembly process and the procurement/ design process to increase quantity and quality?
Quality/ quantity trade-off When the focus is on quantity, quality often suffers, as workers are provided incentives and punishments which, focusing on quantity, largely ignore quality. Quality control is often postponed to a later stage.
The Toyota process, observing that correcting/ tolerating mistakes can be costly, tries to ensure that they get it right the first time - workers have the ability to stop the assembly-line in order to fix a mistake when they make/ detect it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Payment</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/misc_businesses/payment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/misc_businesses/payment/</guid>
      <description>Credit cards Credit cards are a relatively safe way for lenders to encourage public borrowing while making purchases - that way, they can make a profit.
Stores - possibly getting a commission - often offer credit cards (with attractive terms) under their brand-name to their customers; but they are actually managed by banks.
The necessary infrastructure is managed by one of a handful of companies - like Visa, MasterCard, AmericanExpress etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>