<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Mediterranian on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Mediterranian on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Greco Roman</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/greco-roman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/greco-roman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;greek-waves&#34;&gt;Greek waves&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;One of the causes for the end of the Mycenaean civilization is held to be the invasion of another Greek group the Dorians. In Greek epics these invasions are believed to represent the return of the Heracleidai, he descendents of Herakles who set out to conquer Greece from the other rulers. From the historical view point it is interesting to note that the use of the script declined after the Dorian invasion even though the Dorians were Greek speakers and could have easily adapted the Linear B themselves.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2011/08/03/homers-illiteracy/&#34;&gt;MT11&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harran</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/harran/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/harran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;harran-ian &amp;ldquo;hermesite&amp;rdquo; pagans under the &amp;ldquo;sAbean&amp;rdquo; guise&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;According to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Abu_Yusuf_Absha_al-Qadi&amp;amp;action=edit&amp;amp;redlink=1&#34; title=&#34;Abu Yusuf Absha al-Qadi (page does not exist)&#34;&gt;Abu Yusuf Absha al-Qadi&lt;/a&gt;, Caliph &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Al-Ma%27mun&#34; title=&#34;Al-Ma&#39;mun&#34;&gt;al-Ma&amp;rsquo;mun&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baghdad&#34; title=&#34;Baghdad&#34;&gt;Baghdad&lt;/a&gt; in 830 CE questioned some &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harranian&#34; title=&#34;Harranian&#34;&gt;Harranians&lt;/a&gt; about what protected religion they belonged to. As they were neither Muslim, Christian, Jewish or Magian, the caliph told them they were non-believers. He said they would have to become Muslims, or adherents of one of the other religions recognized by the Qur&amp;rsquo;an by the time he returned from his &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arab%E2%80%93Byzantine_wars&#34; title=&#34;Arab–Byzantine wars&#34;&gt;campaign against the Byzantines&lt;/a&gt; or he would kill them.&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sabians#cite_note-10&#34;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt; The Harranians consulted with a lawyer, who suggested that they find their answer in the Qur&amp;rsquo;an II.59, which said that Sabians were tolerated. It was unknown what the sacred text intended by &amp;ldquo;Sabian&amp;rdquo; and so they took the name.&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sabians#cite_note-11&#34;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt; These newly dubbed Harranian Sabians acknowledged &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hermes_Trismegistus&#34; title=&#34;Hermes Trismegistus&#34;&gt;Hermes Trismegistus&lt;/a&gt; as their prophet and the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hermetica&#34; title=&#34;Hermetica&#34;&gt;Hermetica&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; as their sacred text, being a group of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hermeticism&#34; title=&#34;Hermeticism&#34;&gt;Hermeticists&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sabians&#34;&gt;W&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;“Although many have been subjugated to error by means of torture, our fathers by the hand of god have endured and spoken valiantly, and this blessed city [Harran] has never been defiled with the error of Nazareth [Isaism]. And we are the heirs, and transmitters to our heirs of paganism, which is honoured gloriously in this world. Lucky is he who beareth the burden with a sure hope for the sake of paganism.” - Thabit ibn Kurra / Qurra. [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/08/28/the-makings-of-islamic-science/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;So in reality the so called “Islamic Science” was a venture of the pagan Neo-Platonists fleeing the terror of Isaism, and many of the early “Islamic intellectuals” like T ibn Kurra were by their own admission Hellenistic pagans. In 529 AD the Hellenistic philosophers fleeing persecution by the Isaistic ruler Justinian fled to the Iranian king Khusrau Anushirwan, who granted them a safe haven. After he defeated the Christians, he imposed a clause in the peace treaty with Justinian that he must allow the religious freedom of the pagans in the Byzantine empire. Harran as a border town received considerable protection from the Iranian rulers and the Hellenistic pagans could develop their religion and science. While Islam destroyed the Iranian empire, it failed to impose itself on the pagans of Harran. It was from here that they spread out and seeded the Arabic world with their highly developed science and philosophy.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/08/28/the-makings-of-islamic-science/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;However, over time Islamic attitudes hardened. We see this even Al Biruni who is considered by many a moderate Islamic scientist. He sees the similarity between Neo-Platonism and the Hindu dharma, but sees both as errors.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/08/28/the-makings-of-islamic-science/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hero</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/heros/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/heros/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cleisthenes, who ended Athenian tribal fighting by assigning everyone to ten units of ten - paving the way for the city&amp;rsquo;s rise.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Arminius, prince of Germanic Cherusci tribe, brought up as a hostage in Rome, dispatched to Germainic conquest, but secretly plotted with German tribes to secure their liberation, leading to ambush and destruction of three Roman legions in the Teutoburg Forest and several other battles against retaliatory Roman campaigns, ultimately murdered by jealous German noble .&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vercingetorix, the chieftain who managed to unite the Gauls in resisting Roman conquest - and nearly won - but too late.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cleopatra, beloved of her father, co-ruler of Egypt, she of much intelligence (knower of many languages such as Greek, Egyptian, Hebrew, Latin, Ethiopian ..), daring and confidence, lover of Kaiser Julius and Marcus Antonius, parent of their children, who tried much to raise her line to Mediterranian domination but failed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Several Roman leaders - see &lt;a href=&#34;../sqpr/&#34;&gt;SPQR page&lt;/a&gt; for details:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kaiser Julius&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kaiser (Caeser) Augustus Octavian.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kaiser Julian the apostate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Porphyry, the Greek, author of the brilliant “Against the Christians”, who was beaten up by a Christian mob in Caesarea, Palestine. [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2013/02/10/the-end-of-the-heathens/&#34;&gt;M&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Proclus (Πρόκλος), the mathematician, and the last RShi of the yavana-s, who &lt;a href=&#34;http://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2013/02/10/the-end-of-the-heathens&#34;&gt;preserved&lt;/a&gt; for some time the statue of Athena uprooted in 435 CE by the edict of the rascal Theodosius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Martyrs such as Porphyry (author of &amp;ldquo;Against the Christians&amp;rdquo;), Hypatia - who were murdered by Christians.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S.P.Q.R</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/spqr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/spqr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;cause-of-rise&#34;&gt;Cause of rise&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why did Rome expand from a small city state to an empire which spanned 3 continents?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;military-ambition-inculcation&#34;&gt;Military ambition inculcation&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the Roman republic, every notable person seeking greater power and reputation had to gain military victories. This meant that positive ambition was never in short supply. Political advancement (highly competitive) being heavily tied to military triumphs; led to stronger will to repeatedly keep up the wars.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;highly-involved-elites&#34;&gt;Highly involved elites&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unlike the selfish elites of the later periods, the aristocracy of the Republic did not spare its blood or treasure in the service of the com interest. When 50,000 Romans, a staggering one fifth of Rome&amp;rsquo;s totalm power, perished in the battle of Cannae, as mentioned previously th senate lost almost one third of its membership. This suggests that the senatorial aristocracy was more likely to be killed in wars than the averao citizen. Add this to the peculiarly Roman practice of &amp;ldquo;devotion,&amp;rdquo; which was always performed by a member of noble lineage, and it is easy to conclude that generally Roman aristocrats led the commoners in battle, and were the first to die.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
