<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Vanga on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/vanga/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Vanga on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/vanga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bengal vaiShNavas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/vanga/bengal-vaiShNavas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/vanga/bengal-vaiShNavas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/dli.bengal.10689.12643&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Dacca (Dhaka) was especially famous for its temple and Hindu festivals. To Vaishnavas. Dacca was second “Vrindavan”. A small city like Dacca contained as many as 700 Vaishnava Temples, along with many “Kali Temples” and some Gurudwaras. Some of these temples were established during the days of the Pathans and Mughals. A large number of these temples have been destroyed., defiled or looted during the February riots. Some 26 important temples, including well know Tokani Pal’s temple, Madan Gopalji, Hayagaribaji, Shamrajji, Gopinathji, Kalachandji, Balaramji and other temples were still under Muslim occupation. People of East Bengal as of Dacca are overwhelmingly Vaishnavas. They could pursue their religious life, various Vaishnava rituals, ceremonies and festivals, unhindered even during the days of Pathan and Mughals rules. But tree years of Pakistan have made them so much terrorized, that while migrating to the Indian Union they have taken away with them 90 p.c. Of their “Vigrahas” and deities. Innumerable Hindu temples are still lying empty and vacant in the city of Dhaka.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>bIrAngana-documentary</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/vanga/bIrAngana-documentary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/vanga/bIrAngana-documentary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.daily-sun.com/printversion/details/376038/Rising-Silence-:-Thinking-Beyond-The-Numbers&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rising Silence : Thinking Beyond The Numbers&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Rajib Kanti Roy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Historically, rape of women during the war is seen as a ‘by-product of war’. Women, who are considered as carriers of culture and their bodies as symbols of the nation to be defended by men, are especially vulnerable during the battle where their very identities as women come under threat. Through this common tactic rape has been used as a means of humiliating the enemy and breaking their spirit. It has also been used as a form of genetic imperialism as the forcible impregnation can undermine national, political and cultural solidarity, changing the next generation’s identity and confusing their loyalties. Pakistan Army knew these factors very well. Thus they had adopted rape as one of their prime strategies while combating against our brave freedom fighters in 1971 and consequently during the Liberation War around 2,00,000 to 4,00,000 innocent women were raped by the occupation forces and their associates either in the army concentration camps or in their own houses. After the war when these women came back home, most of them had to undergo a terrible situation. Albeit the new country recognised such rape victims publicly as Birangona or war heroine, many of them had committed suicide after losing their dignity and hope of life. A very few families had accepted them after aborting child. They kept everything secret and married off their daughters. Being excluded from their families and abandoned by the society rest of these unfortunate women had begun a lone battle to survive. Since then whenever people speak about them, they only mention their numbers. Over the years their contributions were unnoticed, agonies were overlooked and stories were unheard. British-Bangladeshi director Leesa Gazi has shed light on their dormant ache with a view to breaking this long quietness and featured the untold stories of Birangona women in her documentary film ‘Rising Silence’.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GAza comparison</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/vanga/gAza-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/vanga/gAza-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/kausikgy/status/2004212209652846618&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let us take Gaza as a unit of injustice and judge Hindus of Bangladesh by that standard.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. How much land was taken away under the Bangladeshi state from the Hindus?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is approximately 29 times the area of Gaza.[1]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B. How many Hindus migrated out or perished from Bangladesh in the last five decades?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is more than 160 times that of Gazan claimed to have perished from Israeli attacks. [2]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kAlA-pahA.D</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/vanga/kAlA-pahAD/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/vanga/kAlA-pahAD/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rattibha.com/thread/1555209526520950786?lang=en&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Separating facts from fiction in Kalapahad episode.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There have been various myths surrounding Kalapahad, the infamous general of Afghan sultan of Bengal who desecrated Jagannath temple of Puri. These fictional accounts are so numorous and deeply ingrained in the minds of the masses that it is almost impossible to remove it. This is a small attempt to use primary sources and discuss his origin and also discuss how the story of him being a hindu renegade became mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Muslim-genesis</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/vanga/muslim-genesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/vanga/muslim-genesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threads-web.vercel.app/threads/1104092106707140610&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bengali Muslims make up the 2nd largest Muslim community in the world after Arabs at around 190-200M. 90% in East Bengal, 27% in West Bengal, 27% in Assam, 8.5% in Tripura and small proportions elsewhere. Bengali Muslims represent ~70% of the total Bengali community (Up from 55% during 1947). Hindus make up the remaining ~30% with Buddhists at 0.2% and Christians at 0.4% rounding up at miniscule proportions of the Bengali population.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
