<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;1 Setting the stage on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/1_setting_the_stage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;1 Setting the stage on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/1_setting_the_stage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Exponential Growth</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/1_setting_the_stage/1_Exponential_Growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/1_setting_the_stage/1_Exponential_Growth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Humans have amazing strengths, but also significant weaknesses. Chief among them, perhaps, is our collective difficulty in grasping the mathematical consequences of exponential growth.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This is an ironic state, given that our economic and political goals are often geared explicitly to support continued growth. The degree to which an expectation and desire for continued growth is woven into our society makes it important to examine the phenomenon carefully, so that we might avoid building upon a shaky foundation. In this chapter, we explore the general nature of exponential growth, in order to understand the impossibility of its long-term continuance by way of exposing various absurd consequences that uninterrupted growth prescribes. The upshot&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is that our societal framework eventually must face a mandatory departure from the current modela piece of knowledge we should all lodge into the backs of our minds. Subsequent chapters will address applications to economic and population growth-including more realistic logistic growth curves, then pivot toward nailing down limits imposed by our finite planet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Economic Growth Limits</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/1_setting_the_stage/2_Economic_Growth_Limits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/1_setting_the_stage/2_Economic_Growth_Limits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 1 demonstrated that the laws of physics and mathematical logic render a constant few-percent growth trajectory to be absurd and untenable even a few hundred years into the future. In this chapter, we develop implications for the less physics-bound concept of economic growth, which is a cornerstone of modern society. Investment, loans, retirement and social security schemes all assume the march of growth. The conclusion of this chapter is that economic growth will not be able to continue at any significant rate in the absence of physical growth-which we have seen cannot continue indefinitely.+++(5)+++ The suggestion usually evokes quick criticism from economists, but they can be talked down, with patience.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This is how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Population</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/1_setting_the_stage/3_Population/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/1_setting_the_stage/3_Population/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Underlying virtually every concern relating to our experience on this planet is the story of human population. The discussion of continued energy growth in Chapter 1 was based on the historical growth rate of energy, which is partly due to growing population and partly due to increased use per capita. But the notion that population will continue an exponential climb, as is implicit in the Chapter 1 scenario, is impractical one of many factors that will render the &amp;ldquo;predictions&amp;rdquo; of Chapter 1 invalid and prohibit &amp;ldquo;growth forever.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Space Exploration vs Colonization</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/1_setting_the_stage/4_Space_Exploration_vs_Colonization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/1_setting_the_stage/4_Space_Exploration_vs_Colonization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This textbook assesses the challenges and limitations imposed upon us by living on a finite planet having finite resources. If harboring expectations that we will break out into a space-faring existence as a way to mitigate our earthly challenges, then it becomes harder for us to respond earnestly to information about where things are headed on Earth. This chapter is placed where it is to &amp;ldquo;close the exit&amp;rdquo; so that the content in the rest of the book might become more relevant and worth the investment to learn. Some of the sections in this chapter offer more of an author&amp;rsquo;s perspective than might be typical for a textbook. Some may disagree with the case that is made, but consider that the burden of proof for a way of life unfathomably beyond our current means should perhaps fall to the enthusiasts.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
