<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/nutrients/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/nutrients/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Creatine</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/nutrients/articles/creatine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/nutrients/articles/creatine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/johnnyxbrown/status/1828398065478218105&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Creatine is one of the most researched, tested, and effective supplements available.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 ways it can boost your performance:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Enhances muscle strength. Just like your brain needs ATP for energy, your muscles require it for strength. Creatine boosts ATP production, giving your muscles the energy they need while training. This yields significant strength gains, especially during intense exercises.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Accelerates muscle growth. When you&amp;rsquo;re aiming for muscle growth, every bit counts. Creatine accelerates muscle fiber growth by promoting water retention and protein synthesis in muscles. This leads to quicker, more visible muscle gains, making it a favorite among bodybuilders.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Improves exercise performance. High-intensity workouts demand a lot from your body. Creatine enhances your overall exercise performance, from sprinting to weightlifting, by improving endurance and reducing fatigue. This means you can train harder and achieve better results.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Supports muscle recovery. Recovery is as important as the workout itself. Creatine reduces muscle inflammation and damage post-exercise, speeding up recovery. This allows for more frequent and effective training sessions, with less downtime.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Boosts anaerobic power. Anaerobic exercises like sprinting and heavy lifting rely heavily on quick energy bursts. Creatine boosts your muscles&amp;rsquo; ability to perform in these high-intensity activities. This allows you to push your limits and achieve new personal bests.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reduces brain fatigue. Just like your muscles need energy to sustain a workout, your brain requires constant fuel to power through challenges. Creatine delivers that fuel by restoring ATP to your brain cells. This keeps you mentally engaged and sharp for longer periods.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Improves mood. If you are low on energy, your dopamine levels decrease. This causes your confidence and happiness to plummet. The ATP replenished by creatine helps control dopamine levels for better mood regulation.+++(5)+++&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Enhances memory. Low energy can lead to brain fog, confusion, and loss of memory. Creatine boosts cognitive energy, supporting the processes that underlie memory formation and recall. This makes creatine a great tool whether you’re lifting in the gym or reading in the library.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Improves sleep. Creatine promotes the production of serotonin by keeping your brain energized. This neurotransmitter plays a key role in regulating sleep and stress. Creatine also helps optimize overall energy levels, making it easier to maintain a consistent sleep routine.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These benefits can be achieved with any creatine monohydrate. Take 5-10g of your preferred creatine per day, every day. No need to cycle on/off. You’ll notice a significant boost in physical strength and mental fortitude.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mg supplementing</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/nutrients/articles/Mg_supplementing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/nutrients/articles/Mg_supplementing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.rattibha.com/thread/1657280703778938880&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thread by @mindmusclepro&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;role-in-body&#34;&gt;Role in body&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Magnesium is a nutrient that is essential for so many functions in the human body.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Magnesium is required to make hundreds of enzymes work and assists with thousands of others.&#xA;The most important of these is the enzyme reaction tht involves the creation of energy by activating adenosine triphosphate (ATP), the fundamental energy storage molecule of the body.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No Magnesium = No energy.&#xA;Magnesium along with some other nutrients are essential to create structural components of the body&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
