<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;7 Aurangzeb – from Prince to Emperor ‘Alamgir, 1618–1707 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;7 Aurangzeb – from Prince to Emperor ‘Alamgir, 1618–1707 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 PRINCE AURANGZEB – FOUR VIGNETTES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/01_PRINCE_AURANGZEB_FOUR_VIGNETTES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/01_PRINCE_AURANGZEB_FOUR_VIGNETTES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 7 June 1633, Shah Jahan indulged in one of his favourite pastimes: watching two huge male elephants engage in combat. The spectacle was usually performed near the banks of the Jamuna and viewed from a balcony built into the emperor’s palace in Agra. At one point on this occasion, the two beasts had grappled with each other directly below the emperor’s balcony, preventing him from seeing the action. So he and his three eldest sons – Dara Shukoh, Shuja‘ and Aurangzeb – went down to the ground level, mounted horses and rode out to have a closer look. Noticing the newcomers, one of the elephants suddenly wheeled, trumpeted loudly and charged the nearest figure in sight, which happened to be the fourteen-year-old Aurangzeb. ‘The lion-hearted youth,’ records a chronicler of Shah Jahan’s reign:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 WAR OF SUCCESSION, 1657–9</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/02_WAR_OF_SUCCESSION_16579/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/02_WAR_OF_SUCCESSION_16579/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 6 September, within a month of Aurangzeb’s withdrawal from Bijapur, Shah Jahan fell ill, so grievously that rumours sped throughout India that he faced imminent death. From an early age Mughal princes were acutely aware that their brothers, though possibly playmates in childhood, would become deadly enemies when their father died. And they well understood that only one of them would survive the struggle to succeed him: according to the well-known Persian proverb, it was ‘either the throne, or the coffin’ (&lt;em&gt;ya takht, ya takhta&lt;/em&gt;). The news of the emperor’s illness therefore sparked a four-way struggle among Shah Jahan’s four sons, India’s bloodiest and most notorious war of succession.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 EMERGING IDENTITIES: THE MARATHAS FROM SHAHJI TO TARABAI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/03_EMERGING_IDENTITIES_THE_MARATHAS_FROM_SHAHJI_TO_TARABAI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/03_EMERGING_IDENTITIES_THE_MARATHAS_FROM_SHAHJI_TO_TARABAI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As they crossed the Vindhyas and entered the Marathi-speaking western Deccan, Durga Das and Prince Akbar encountered a political culture very different from the Rajput world they had left behind. By the seventeenth century, sovereign territories in Rajasthan were dominated by members of a single Rajput lineage that claimed descent from a common conqueror–ancestor. Land was parcelled out to &lt;em&gt;sardar&lt;/em&gt;s, who were hereditary leaders of sub-clans and loyal to the clan’s ruler, or raja, who was supposed to be the nearest legitimate descendant in direct male line from the state’s conqueror–ancestor, and the firstborn of his generation. Because all clan members were morally obliged to support the raja in times of war, and because by this time they had absorbed the martial ideology of the &lt;em&gt;kshatriya&lt;/em&gt; warrior class, the constituent members of Rajput states could be readily mobilized for collective action, political or military. By ‘Alamgir’s day, moreover, most Rajput states had submitted to the Mughal empire, symbolized by a raja’s acknowledging the emperor’s right to apply a vermilion &lt;em&gt;tika&lt;/em&gt; to his forehead – itself a Rajput political ritual – and by attending the Mughal court. The Rajputs’ hierarchically structured polities thus allowed the Mughals access to considerable military manpower, since the submission of any given raja implied that of his entire clan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 RELIGION AND SOVEREIGNTY UNDER ‘ALAMGIR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/04_RELIGION_AND_SOVEREIGNTY_UNDER_ALAMGIR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/04_RELIGION_AND_SOVEREIGNTY_UNDER_ALAMGIR/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In his personal habits, ‘Alamgir was notoriously austere and abstemious – traits which converted into a religious sensibility that was pious to the point of puritanical. When he was a prince, some regarded this as an affectation fashioned to mask a secret ambition to power.75 During his struggle to win the Peacock Throne, his piety served to distance him both from the lavish indulgences of his father – whom one modern historian calls a ‘glorified jeweler’76 – and the religious adventurism of his elder brother Dara. Further defining his religious posture were the events surrounding his actual accession to supreme power. This was because the crisis of 1657–9 was not a typical Turko-Mongol, or even Mughal war of succession in which the princes and their armies engaged in an armed struggle over a vacant throne. The problem this time was that Shah Jahan had not died, even though it was widely believed when war broke out that he already had, or that his death was imminent. By November 1657, just two months after he fell ill, the stricken emperor had fully recovered. By that time, though, military orders had already been issued, armies had been mobilized, one son had already crowned himself, and another would follow suit a month later. The customary machinery for replacing a deceased sovereign having been set in motion, the inevitable struggle had to be played out to the full, until the drama’s final curtain would come down with a new emperor formally installed on the Peacock Throne.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 CONCLUSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/05_CONCLUSION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/05_CONCLUSION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For nearly a half century, the Mughal empire was ruled by one of the most complex and controversial figures in Indian history. ‘Alamgir’s character was defined by many qualities, some of them contradictory. From an early age he showed remarkable courage, which was repeatedly displayed on battlefields. A steely sense of duty and self-discipline translated into a lifelong commitment to administrative detail, if not minutiae; in modern times he might be called a workaholic. His court historian Muhammad Kazim records that he slept only three hours a night.118 The Italian traveller Manucci corroborates this observation, adding that he sat up until midnight ‘unceasingly occupied’ with official business.119 Yet his devotion to work also prevented him from delegating authority to others and led to meddling in the affairs of his officers and his sons. ‘I came to know’, he wrote disapprovingly to his second son Mu‘azzam, ‘that you disregard the soldiers and care more for the highly paid servants.’ Or again, to the same son, ‘I came to know from a letter of a dear friend that you attend the court with a saffron-like turban on your head.’120&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 POLITICAL CHANGES, 1707–48</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/06_POLITICAL_CHANGES_170748/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/06_POLITICAL_CHANGES_170748/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In accordance with Mughal practice, a deadly struggle between ‘Alamgir’s three surviving sons – A‘zam, Mu‘azzam and Kam Bakhsh – followed the emperor’s death. Prince A‘zam, at the time in the Deccan, at once declared his sovereignty and began marching north towards Agra. Prince Mu‘azzam, then posted near Peshawar on the north-west frontier, also declared his sovereignty and, adopting the title Bahadur Shah, rapidly marched south, beating A‘zam in the race to Agra. In June 1707 he defeated his younger brother, who died in battle near Agra. After spending nearly a year consolidating power in upper India, the new emperor marched to the Deccan to confront ‘Alamgir’s youngest son, Kam Bakhsh, who had also declared his sovereignty and established himself in Hyderabad. Badly outnumbered, however, he too was killed in battle, thereby completing another war of succession, albeit one far less bloody than the war that had raised ‘Alamgir to power.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 MARATHA UPRISINGS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/07_MARATHA_UPRISINGS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/07_MARATHA_UPRISINGS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Of the various uprisings that challenged Mughal power and authority in the eighteenth century, that of the Marathas was the most sustained and consequential. From 1682 to 1699 the Maratha state had waged a defensive war against ‘Alamgir’s aggressive campaigns in the western Deccan. But between 1700 and 1707 Tarabai, governing the kingdom as regent for her infant son, co-ordinated the defence of Maratha strongholds against ‘Alamgir’s armies while establishing a permanent Maratha presence in parts of Khandesh, Malwa and Gujarat. In those provinces her agents extracted a fourth of the revenue normally paid to the Mughals. This levy, called &lt;em&gt;chauth&lt;/em&gt;, in effect served as protection money against further Maratha raids, which Mughal authorities were powerless to prevent. But, after 1707, many of Tarabai’s former supporters drifted to Shahu, the adult grandson of Shivaji whom ‘Alamgir had captured in 1689 and held for eighteen years. After the emperor’s death, he was strategically released for the purpose of dividing Maratha loyalties. The ploy succeeded. Maratha chieftains soon split between supporters of Shahu, the son of Shivaji’s first son Sambhaji, and Tarabai, the widow of Shivaji’s second son Rajaram.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 SIKH UPRISINGS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/08_SIKH_UPRISINGS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/08_SIKH_UPRISINGS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The other formidable challenge to Mughal authority in the eighteenth century was mounted by the Sikhs. Unlike the Marathas, who contested Mughal power throughout India, the Sikh rebellion was confined to the Punjab. And whereas the Marathas initially resisted the Mughals but ended up defending the crippled empire, with the Sikhs it was the reverse. The movement launched by Guru Nanak had emerged in the sixteenth century within the matrix of the Mughal imperium, with which it was once on generally good terms. But over time relations between the two grew increasingly hostile. How and why, then, did the Sikhs’ militantly anti-Mughal posture incubate and grow?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 EMERGING IDENTITIES: MUSLIMS IN BENGAL AND PUNJAB</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/09_EMERGING_IDENTITIES_MUSLIMS_IN_BENGAL_AND_PUNJAB/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/09_EMERGING_IDENTITIES_MUSLIMS_IN_BENGAL_AND_PUNJAB/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the very time that the Mughal empire’s central institutions had reached an advanced state of decay, India’s largest Muslim community was emerging along the empire’s eastern frontier.38 Bengali Muslims, most of whom inhabit present-day Bangladesh, comprise the world’s second-largest ethnic community of Muslims. Their appearance was actually one dimension of a larger transformation of the region’s politics and economy, which coincided with the delta’s shifting geomorphology. The story of the growth Bengal’s Muslim population therefore begins with the land itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 EARLY MODERN GLOBALIZATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/10_EARLY_MODERN_GLOBALIZATION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/10_EARLY_MODERN_GLOBALIZATION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Partly responsible for these changes in cultural identity were powerful, interconnected transregional forces. These included the movement of pastoral communities into agrarian zones, the expanding geographical and social reach of cash, and the growing integration of India’s economy and society with wider networks of commerce. Such forces were part of a quickened, worldwide exchange of ideas, commodities, technologies, peoples, diseases and cultural traditions that transformed all participants, not least the Mughal empire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 CONCLUSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/11_CONCLUSION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/7_Aurangzeb_from_Prince_to_Emperor_Alamgir_16181707/11_CONCLUSION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As signs of Mughal decline, it is easy to conjure up striking images of foreign invaders pillaging the north Indian countryside. One can readily visualize Nadir Shah, having sacked Delhi in 1739, marching through the Khyber Pass with long columns of pack animals loaded with looted treasures that included Shah Jahan’s Peacock Throne and the Koh-i-Noor diamond. A more accurate image of imperial decline, however, would be of the empire being undermined from within and below, in the way that termites silently hollow out the base of a wooden structure. Across eighteenth-century India, local power holders were able to challenge imperial authority with resources ultimately derived from the higher volume of cash that circulated throughout Indian society as a result of the commercialization of the entire Indian Ocean region. As merchant wealth expanded, new market centres were established, boosting development in both agrarian and manufacturing sectors. Land use was greatly intensified, as happened when pioneers in Bengal used cash to mobilize labour for transforming dense jungle into arable fields for the cultivation of food crops.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
