<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;kAshmIra on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;kAshmIra on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>100-acres</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/100-acres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/100-acres/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Pr, an IISc prof, Oct 2023&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today I had a very horrifying experience - I spoke to a student whose family is a direct victim of Kashmir exodus. They lost 100s of acres of land overnight. His house was burnt thinking that the members were inside while they had just managed to escape. They became riches to rags overnight. The story of the girl who was forced to eat rice with her husband&amp;rsquo;s blood (as shown in the Kashmir files movie) happens to be a relative of his family. He said, what you see in that movie is just 1% of what we have gone through. What militants with women and children can&amp;rsquo;t even be described in words. Hearing this I am totally shocked. If this can happen in our own times in an independent sovereign country, imagine what could have happened during the historical invasion. This message is not a forwarded one, it is my own student at IISc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Escaping bitta</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/escaping-bitta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/escaping-bitta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1505733492860141568.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is how my mama ji (uncle) escaped a bullet from Bitta Karate and is still alive today. I have not told this story before. #TheKashmirFiles #KashmirFiles. Before Farooq Ahmed Dar became a psychopath terrorist, he was just another kid with a pet name of Bitta who used to play cricket in Srinagar with my family. My uncle even gave him money for school.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After Bitta returned from terror training in PoK, he was given orders to assassinate my uncle. Bitta had another JKLF terrorist watch my uncle leave his home for work, walking through an intersection in Haba Kadal. The plan was to shoot my uncle from behind at close range. The spotter saw my uncle leave the house at 9:30 am on 16 February 1990, wearing a leather jacket. Bitta was given this information and got his pistol ready. Suddenly, my uncle remembered it was his elder brother&amp;rsquo;s birthday, so he went back home to participate in the pooja. The spotter didn&amp;rsquo;t see my uncle turn around to go home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fake-brAhmaNa-converts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/fake-brAhmaNa-converts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/fake-brAhmaNa-converts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/arya_amsha/status/1767606200751866053&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While many Kashmiri Muslims claim to be &amp;ldquo;Brahmin converts&amp;rdquo;, this is almost certainly not true for the vast majority. It was very easy to adopt a fake caste name in Kashmir.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The example below shows Kashmiris of the boatmen caste had appropriated the upper-caste surname Dar/Dhar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There may be some foundation for these theories; but the krams are now mixed, and confusion is increasing owing to the fashion of the lower castes who arrogate the krams of the respectable families. Thus the Dums, the gardeners, and the butchers have begun to call themselves Ganais, much to the annoyance of the true Ganais. And the boatmen, a most disreputable community, have appropriated the kram name of Dar. The social system is very plastic, and prosperity and a very little wealth soon obliterate a humble origin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freedom from Hindus</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/freedom_from_hindus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/freedom_from_hindus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rattibha.com/thread/1507300713881227266?lang=en&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Kashmiri problem is very simple. Indian muslims believe that once they become a majority in any part of India, they must secede and join the Islamic world. They find it humiliating to be ruled by Hindus, since they were the kingmakers for centuries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Kashmiri problem is very simple. Indian muslims believe that once they become a majority in any part of India, they must secede and join the Islamic world. They find it humiliating to be ruled by Hindus, since they were the kingmakers for centuries. Ambedkar pointed this out. In Hyderabad, they were a ultra-rich minority and there they did not want democracy. In Kashmir, where the demographics favour them, they aggressively demand democracy since they benefit from majoritarianism. The issue is civilizational.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hindu separatists</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/hindu-separatists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/hindu-separatists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ironically it was a confluence of far left communists and far right koshur ethnic chauvinists. One of them was given a ministerial position in their government in exile&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some like Prem Nath Bajaj became separatists.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;JKLF also had a Hindu leader who stayed .&lt;br&gt;&#xA;One (a communist party member) died last year also.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enquiry&#34;&gt;Enquiry&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;काश्मीरिपण्डितो मे से कुछ लोग jklf, आज़ाद-काश्मीर इत्यादि सङ्घटनोँ से मिलकर भारत के विरुद्ध मुसल्मानोँ के साथ लडे और जुडे - ऐसा मैने सुना (&lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/MohitPandita108/status/1988625976503246984&#34;&gt;https://x.com/MohitPandita108/status/1988625976503246984&lt;/a&gt; )। क्या यह सछ है? उन का कितना प्रभाव था  ?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HoB genocide</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/HoB-genocide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/HoB-genocide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/humans-of-bombay_kashmir-kashmirfiles-genocide-activity-6909332553522950144-f4Se/&#34;&gt;HoB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Kashmir that I grew up in was different– whenever I close my eyes, I can see the gorgeous Chinar tree, the Dudhganga river, and the Bhairav temple lit all year round. I grew up in a close-knit Pandit family of 18 members in my ancestral home. But in 1989, everything changed–bandhs had become the norm; we’d have strikes every alternate day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Kashmiri Pandit judge was gunned down–we were too slow to understand why we were being targeted. The family elders speculated–Dad would say, ‘Maybe because they were in high positions?’ Thathyaji, my grandfather, guessed, ‘They must’ve clashed with politicians.’ The first blow struck us when a relative was shot dead by terrorists in broad daylight. Still, nobody had the slightest suspicion that a conspiracy was being hatched to wipe out an entire race.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kashmir files review</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/kashmir-files-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/kashmir-files-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: TW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;research&#34;&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is my promised thread on @vivekagnihotri ji&amp;rsquo;s #TheKashmirFiles. Before &amp;amp; after the amendments to Article 370,I did a fair bit of reading on Kashmir including documents on the portal iKashmir, and books by Shri Jagmohan and @rahulpandita. So in that sense I &amp;ldquo;knew&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The confidence of the makers of this movie is evident right from the word go. As opposed to the usual escapist and evasive disclaimers, this movie&amp;rsquo;s disclaimer does not distance the makers from the movie. Instead,they own upto it. That shows how their faith in their research.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>muqbIr-killing</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/muqbIr-killing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/muqbIr-killing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;‘You Never Blamed Dahshat-Gard’: Open Letter to Kashmir Author from Kupwara Man Whose 3 Sons Were Killed by Terrorists&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Written By: Mohammad Sadeeq Wani&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Last Updated: March 16, 2023, 20:03 IST&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, India&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After the abrogation of Article 370, we feel that the UT Administration is finally taking the right steps for Kashmir. (Representative image)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After the abrogation of Article 370, we feel that the UT Administration is finally taking the right steps for Kashmir. (Representative image)&#xA;Anuradha ji, you are crying and telling the world that PM Modi has finished all media freedom in Kashmir. You are a journalist and you claim that you speak the truth. Did you ever write that the terrorists finished the freedom of the Kashmiri people?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One mistake</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/one-mistake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/one-mistake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kashmiri Muslims only made one mistake.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;By Kalavai Venkat&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After watching the movie Kashmir Files, as I came out of the cinema, I talked to a Kashmiri Pandit couple in the parking lot, where their car was parked next to mine. The woman initiated the conversation, &amp;ldquo;Everything the movie showed is the truth.&amp;rdquo; I was too numb to even respond verbally. I barely asked, &amp;ldquo;You lived in Kashmir when &amp;hellip; ?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pro india muslims</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/pro-india-muslims/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/pro-india-muslims/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;maqbool-sherwani&#34;&gt;Maqbool Sherwani&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maqbool Sherwani was a young Kashmiri Muslim from Baramulla who stalled Pakistani tribal raiders in October 1947 by misleading them with false reports of heavy Indian troop presence ahead. His deception delayed their advance on Srinagar for crucial days, enabling the Indian Army&amp;rsquo;s airlifted reinforcements to arrive and defend the valley. Captured and martyred on November 7, he&amp;rsquo;s remembered as the &amp;ldquo;Lion of Baramulla&amp;rdquo; for saving Kashmir from falling to invaders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sanjay sharmA killing</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/sanjaya-sharmA-killing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/kAshmIr/sanjaya-sharmA-killing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://unrollthread.com/t/1630246552345391104/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is HINDU HATRED &amp;amp; TOXIC HINDU PHOBIA not REALITY of KASHMIR Valley, India&amp;rsquo;s only Muslim majority administrative region ? This is Diksha Sharma, daughter of Sanjay Sharma, a Kashmiri Hindu Pandit who was murdered by terrorists in Pulwama yesterday at her father&amp;rsquo;s funeral.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was in (government) school, my teacher saw a temporary tattoo of Hanuman on my arm. He called me aside and angrily asked me as to why was I carrying a picture of &amp;ldquo;Shaitan&amp;rdquo; (evil monster) on my arm ? These days he privately imparts religious teaching to Muslim kids.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
