<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;INDIAN WAR OF INDEPENDENCE 1857 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;INDIAN WAR OF INDEPENDENCE 1857 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Oh Martyrs – London 1908</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/Oh_Martyrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/Oh_Martyrs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The battle of freedom once begun&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And handed down from sire to son&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Though often lost is ever won!!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To-day is the tenth of May!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was on this day, that in the ever memorable year of 1857, the first campaign of the War of Independence was opened by you, Oh Martyrs, on the battle-field of India. The Motherland, awakened to the sense of her degrading slavery, Unsheathed her sword, burst forth from the shackles and struck the first blow for her liberty and for her honour. It was on this day that the war-cry &amp;lsquo;Maro Feringhee Ko&amp;rsquo; was raised by the throats of thousands. It was on this day that the sepoys of Meerut, having risen in a terrible uprising, marched down to Delhi, saw the waters of the Jamuna, glittering in the sunshine, caught one of those historical moments which close past epoch to introduce a new one, and had found, in a moment, a leader, a flag and a clause, and converted the mutiny into a national and a religious war.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PUBLISHER’S NOTE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/publishers_note/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/publishers_note/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most historians, British as well as Indian, have described and dismissed the&#xA;rising of 1857 as a ‘Sepoy Munity’ or at best ‘The Indian Mutiny’. Indian revolution is on&#xA;the other hand, and national minded leaders thinkers have regarded it as a planned and&#xA;organised olitical and military rising aimed at destroying the British power in India.&#xA;Mr. Sawarkar’s is an attempt to look at the incidents of 1857 from the Indian&#xA;point of view. A leading revolutionary himself, was attracted and inspired by the burning&#xA;zeal, the heroism, bravery, suffering and tragic fate of the leaders of 1857, and he decided to&#xA;re-interpret the story and to relate it in full with the help of all the material available to him at the time. He spent days and months at the India Office Library studying the period. Finally, his work was published in 1909, under the title “The Indian War of Independence –1857”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
