<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;00 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/00/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;00 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/00/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00 CONTENTS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/00/00_CONTENTS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/00/00_CONTENTS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abbreviations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IVAN’S PARENTS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CHILDBIRTH, CHRISTENING, WIFE BEATING&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CHILDHOOD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;COURTSHIP AND SEXUAL RELATIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IVAN PREPARES FOR MARRIAGE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PLEDGING THE BRIDE, THE BRIDE-SHOW, AND MARRIAGE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;INFANTICIDE, EMOTION, SEXUAL DISORDER, DRINK AND FOOD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HOUSING, PROPERTY, TRADES, BUDGETS, AND RELIGIOUS BELIEF&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PEASANT IDEALS, WORK HABITS, AND CAUSES OF POVERTY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;COURT CASES AND POLITICAL STRUCTURE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Appendix&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Suggestions for Further Reading&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/00/01_ACKNOWLEDGMENTS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/00/01_ACKNOWLEDGMENTS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project has been assisted by support from a number of foundations and individuals. A Mellon Grant through the Russian and East European Institute of Indiana University paid Michael Levine for his collaboration in the translation. During 1989-1990, when I received funding from the Guggenheim Foundation, the International Research and Exchanges Board (IREX), and a Fulbright-Hays fellowship, I was able to devote a portion of my time to this project, in particular the work in Russian archives. I am grateful to the donors and staffs of these funding agencies for their generous support.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Note on the Text</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/00/02_Note_on_the_Text/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/00/02_Note_on_the_Text/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have used the Library of Congress system of transliteration throughout; however, some minor modifications have been made in the text so that readers unfamiliar with Russian can approximate the correct pronunciation of names and terms. For example, the Russian letter &lt;em&gt;ë&lt;/em&gt; has been rendered as &lt;em&gt;yo;&lt;/em&gt; soft vowels are rendered as &lt;em&gt;ya, yu&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;ye&lt;/em&gt; at the beginning of a word, and as &lt;em&gt;ia, iu&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;e&lt;/em&gt; elsewhere. Soft signs have been omitted from transliterated Russian first names in the body of the book but retained in the notes for proper reference.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 ABBREVIATIONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/00/03_ABBREVIATIONS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/00/03_ABBREVIATIONS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AGO AN SSSR&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Archive of the Russian Geographical Society, St. Petersburg&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arkhiv AN SSSR&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Archive of the Russian Academy of Sciences, St. Petersburg branch&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LGALI&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Leningrad State Archive of Literature and Art&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 INTRODUCTION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/00/04_INTRODUCTION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/00/04_INTRODUCTION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Russia in the late nineteenth century was a society in crisis. For some, the pace of development was too slow. Germany, France, England, and the United States—the countries to which most educated Russians instinctively compared their own—were well ahead of Russia in industrialization and urbanization, and they had a far higher level of general education and culture. For others, change was too rapid. They blamed the government’s drive to catch up with the West for the increasingly deep fissures in society, which seemed to threaten the country with revolution. Yet, however educated Russians may have viewed the sources of the crisis, most believed that its resolution depended ultimately on the attitudes and actions of the common people, the peasants, who constituted about 85 percent of the nation’s population. Peasants not only were rural dwellers, but they also, as migrant laborers in the cities and factory towns, made up the majority of the industrial working class. As peasants in uniform, they composed the bulk of the armed forces. Curiously enough, both radical critics of the established regime and its conservative defenders, despite their differences with one another and their shared ignorance of village life, were convinced that they knew what the common people wanted and needed and could speak in their name. As a consequence, discussion of peasants and of Russia’s future, an important part of public discourse in late tsarist Russia, was filled with a great many myths and misconceptions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 APPENDIX</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/00/05_APPENDIX/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/00/05_APPENDIX/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Form of a Contract between Seasonal Employers and Peasants&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the 2nd of October, 1899, we, the undersigned peasants of Yepifanskii &lt;em&gt;uezd&lt;/em&gt; of Murashenskii township and Chernyshevka village, Yakov Matveev Marsakov, Pavel Spiridonov Shikunov, Nikita Pavlov Blagov, and Maksim Grigoriev Seleznyov, have filed this contract with the Karavaevo office of Semyon Tikhonovich Blagopoluchnyi, merchant of the 2nd guild, to the effect that:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We, the peasants, have undertaken to farm in the coming year 6 desiatinas of rye and 6 of oats on the estate owned by Semyon Tikhonovich Blagopoluchnyi, merchant of the 2nd guild.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 SUGGESTIONS FOR FURTHER READING</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/00/06_SUGGESTIONS_FOR_FURTHER_READING/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/00/06_SUGGESTIONS_FOR_FURTHER_READING/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Atkinson, Dorothy. &lt;em&gt;The End of the Russian Land Commune&lt;/em&gt;. Stanford: Stanford University Press, 1985.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bartlett, Roger, ed. &lt;em&gt;Land Commune and Peasant Community in Russia: Communal Forms in Imperial and Early Soviet Society&lt;/em&gt;. New York: St. Martin’s Press, 1990.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Benet, Sula, ed. &lt;em&gt;The Village of Viriatino&lt;/em&gt;. New York: Doubleday, 1970.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bohac, Rodney D. “Peasant Inheritance Strategies in Russia.” &lt;em&gt;Journal of Interdisciplinary History&lt;/em&gt;, 16:1 (1985), 23-42.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bradley, Joseph. &lt;em&gt;Muzhik and Muscovite: Urbanization in Late Imperial Russia&lt;/em&gt;. Berkeley: University of California Press, 1985.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excerpt</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/00/excerpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/00/excerpt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1634653358110941184.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Things I learned from &amp;ldquo;Village Life In Late Tsarist Russia&amp;rdquo;, the first-ever systematic ethnography of a Russian peasant community, done in 1902 by Olga Tian-Shanskaya but never published in her lifetime (A warning: it&amp;rsquo;s extremely depressing.).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;anti-natal-attitude&#34;&gt;Anti-natal attitude&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The single most surprising thing by far was how anti-natal peasant attitudes were. Central Russia may have had the highest fertility of anywhere in Europe, to the point where it was facing a Malthusian crisis, but it &lt;em&gt;wasn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; because peasants wanted a lot of kids.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
