<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;११ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2003/11/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;११ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2003/11/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dream interrupted</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2003/11/2003-11-06_dream-interrupted/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2003/11/2003-11-06_dream-interrupted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/11/06/dream-interrupted/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We moved up the hill rapidly (remember the hill which came in the&#xA;dreams!). It was the brief pleasure sent by the gods. It was like that,&#xA;which had visited the four kings, namely divodAsa, uShinAra, vishvAmitra&#xA;etc in the form of yayAti’s daughter mAdhavi. But it was the shorter and&#xA;wholly empty unlike that briefly enjoyed by those great kshatriyas of&#xA;yore. Coursing freely in a rapid ratha we reached the paravata. Before&#xA;dismounting from the ratha, I acted in the most atypical manner&#xA;deviating significantly from the norms that exist. Yet nothing happened!&#xA;I took it as sign of victory. On reaching the parvata we freely moved in&#xA;the manner of vishvAmitra on the slopes of the himapArvata, brushing&#xA;aside the dark nishAdas and dAsas who infested the mountain strongholds.&#xA;Having reached the upper reaches we beheld the yonder territory, like&#xA;videgha mAthava beholding the expanses of mithila ripe for conquest. I&#xA;did not realize at that time that I lacked the equivalent of the son of&#xA;rAhUgaNa beside me. Then we descended. The solitude allowed some images&#xA;to hang motionlessly. This was a sign that indicated a total victory.&#xA;After all it was ordained that those pleasures were even destined for me&#xA;in the very kshetra, where I had observed the vratas. Then having moved&#xA;amidst the settlements of the nishadas and dasyus we returned to my&#xA;place. The black bitch signalled that the noose of karma could not be&#xA;escaped, even as the great viShNu could not escape his 10 incarnations.&#xA;I returned like yayAti after a stroll in shakra’s garden. Then, just as&#xA;yayAti having exhausted his stay in svargo loka fell head-long back to&#xA;the midst of mortals, my karma having been exhausted I descended to the&#xA;lower worlds. When my descent was complete and my feet hit the ground, I&#xA;looked around. Unfortunately, unlike yayAti, there was no pratardana,&#xA;vasumanA, aShTaka or shivi to revive me and remained trapped in the dark&#xA;lower loka!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R’s words</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2003/11/2003-11-04_rs-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2003/11/2003-11-04_rs-words/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/11/04/rs-words/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some years ago R and me were lying on the grass following our quarry, a&#xA;goodly specimen of Menemerus, that kept saltating in search of its&#xA;quarry. Then our eyes caught sight of a Salticus specimen that was&#xA;capturing a small earwig and we kept following it to observe the&#xA;process. R then moved on to a Marpissa mucosa, while I drifted away&#xA;towards a gorgeous Icius. At the that point for some reason we paused. R&#xA;pulled my collar and pointed to a Calotes soulfully seated on a bough. I&#xA;was a bit surprised and asked: So what. She then said: Did you think&#xA;over my words last night.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
