<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;02 LANGUAGE on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/02_LANGUAGE/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;02 LANGUAGE on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/02_LANGUAGE/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>11 Changing Channels with Pirahã Sounds</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/02_LANGUAGE/11_Changing_Channels_with_Pira/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/02_LANGUAGE/11_Changing_Channels_with_Pira/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;aboclos, travel, and other experiences of the Amazon were ultimately just means to an end. My experiences in the region were ordered around my struggle to figure out the grammar of Pirahã. As I made progress, excruciatingly slowly, I realized that this language was unusual—profoundly so. Initially I recognized this as I analyzed the way it organized its sounds into words. I based my conclusions about its uniqueness on field research with Tzeltales in southern Mexico, training with Comanche and Cherokee speakers in Oklahoma, helping missionaries analyze other Amazonian languages, and wide reading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Pirahã Words</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/02_LANGUAGE/12_Pirah_Words/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/02_LANGUAGE/12_Pirah_Words/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;F&lt;/strong&gt;ieldwork demands constant attention to details. And it can be hard in the jungle to continue to pay close attention day after day to anything, whether language or any other important part of life. Each day requires disciplined routine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the rainy season, there are frequent all-night downpours. I learned that it took only a couple of hours for a heavy rain to sink my boat. My motor was bolted onto the stern and it weighed about 150 pounds, so I could not remove it at the end of each day and put it on dry land. The motor stayed on the boat. But when it rained, the weight of the motor pulled the boat down just enough so that all the rainwater rushed aft. In an Amazonian rainstorm, it doesn’t take long for enough water to accumulate there to push the stern under the water and sink the boat—even though my boat could hold one ton of cargo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 How Much Grammar Do People Need?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/02_LANGUAGE/13_How_Much_Grammar_Do_People/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/02_LANGUAGE/13_How_Much_Grammar_Do_People/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;n &lt;em&gt;Mrs. Doubtfire,&lt;/em&gt; the Robin Williams character phones the Sally Field character and says, in reference to an ad, “I . . . am . . . job?”Besides being funny in the context of the film, both the movie characters and the audience know immediately that what the speaker &lt;em&gt;means&lt;/em&gt; is “I want the job you have advertised.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How does the audience know this? It isn’t in the words or the way they are put together in a sentence, not completely anyway. The relevant meaning that someone wants a job comes rather from the context, in a movie or in life, and the culture in which the sentence is spoken. That is, grammar is a component of communication but it is not all there is to communication. In the &lt;em&gt;Mrs. Doubtfire&lt;/em&gt; example, the grammar is almost all wrong and yet the correct meaning is still communicated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Values and Talking: The Partnership</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/02_LANGUAGE/14_Values_and_Talking_The_Par/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/02_LANGUAGE/14_Values_and_Talking_The_Par/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;between Language and Culture&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O&lt;/strong&gt;ne of the most interesting conversations I’ve had about food was with a Pirahã. It occurred when I ate a salad in the village for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rice, beans, fish, and wild game, smothered under copious amounts of Tabasco sauce, can keep one’s culinary drive satisfied up to a point. But if you like the crunch of fresh lettuce, then after a few months you might begin to dream about eating a salad.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Recursion: Language as a Matrioshka Doll</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/02_LANGUAGE/15_Recursion_Language_as_a_Ma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/02_LANGUAGE/15_Recursion_Language_as_a_Ma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T&lt;/strong&gt;heories affect our perceptions. They are part of the cultural information that constrains the way we see the world around us. There are many examples of culture-perception connections that don’t involve science but which illustrate my point, such as the time I mistook an anaconda for a floating log. My culture told me to look for logs when traveling by boat (universally good advice!). And it gave me information on what floating logs look like in a river. But it didn’t have anything to tell me about what very large anacondas look like swimming toward you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Crooked Heads and Straight Heads:</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/02_LANGUAGE/16_Crooked_Heads_and_Straight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/02_LANGUAGE/16_Crooked_Heads_and_Straight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Perspectives on Language and Truth&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T&lt;/strong&gt;he Pirahãs’ language and culture began to attract the attention of some Brazilian anthropologists not long after my trip with the FUNAI to map the people’s reservation. One new graduate student, a young man from Rio de Janeiro, contacted me to enlist my help in working with the Pirahãs. To aid his efforts in establishing himself among them, I recorded a tape in Pirahã, introducing him to the people, telling them that he wanted to learn their language, and asking them to build him a house. The Pirahãs heard my voice coming out of his tape recorder and assumed that it was like a two-way radio, a device with which they are familiar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
