<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Mental on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/mental/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Mental on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/mental/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aging</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/mental/aging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/mental/aging/</guid>
      <description>In general, memory declines with age. But, for a few people, it remains clear and functional. [National Geographic, Nov 2007]
Metrics White matter naturally degrades as we age—causing disrupted communication between brain regions and memory deficits—after conducting a battery of cognitive tests and brain scans on 93 healthy volunteers, ages 18 to 93. The observed weakening of these brain network interactions (associated with default state and executive functions) was significantly correlated with a measured decline of cognitive functions as a result of aging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain health</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/mental/brain_health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/mental/brain_health/</guid>
      <description>Genetics Some special genes can predispose you or increase resistance to diseases, including cognitive ones like alzheimers. As explained in the human society survey, genes play a limited role in general in the heritability of intellect.
Blood supply to the brain Fatty build up in blood vessels is linked with brain impairment, and deadly strokes and heart attacks. The brain relies on a good blood supply to keep its functions and processes in top order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/mental/sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/mental/sleep/</guid>
      <description>Some aspects of memory consolidation only happen with more than six hours of sleep. [Ref]
Teenagers who stay up late on school nights and make up for it by sleeping late on weekends are more likely to perform poorly in the classroom. This is because, on weekends, they are waking up at a time that is later than their internal body clock expects. [Ref] Sleep debt can be repaid, though it won&amp;rsquo;t happen in one extended snooze marathon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stress</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/mental/stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/mental/stress/</guid>
      <description>Negative effects of excess Stress hormones, in preparing the body for the fight or the flight, cause blood to be shunted away from nonessential areas, including the liver, which filters away cholesterol. It has been associated with:
 back pain depressed immune response hair loss even situational homosexuality irritable bowel syndrome  In medical students studying for exams, the medial prefrontal cortex shrinks during cram sessions but grows back after a month off.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>