<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;bAjI rAv on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/bAjIrAv/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;bAjI rAv on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/bAjIrAv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>bAjI advice to raghunAth</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/bAjIrAv/bAjI-advice_to_raghunAth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/bAjIrAv/bAjI-advice_to_raghunAth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hope you will well remember the various instructions I gave you at our last parting. Do not forget to keep up the daily revision of the Vidurniti, selections from Chanakya and other portions that you have learned. You must also learn more every day from the Shastris, and read the Mahabharat whenever you have leisure from the Virat Parva onward, and not waste time in constant reading. You must also keep up the practice of memorizing accounts in weights and measures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>chimAjI on bAjIrao</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/bAjIrAv/chimAjI_on_bAjIrAv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/bAjIrAv/chimAjI_on_bAjIrAv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is the relevant portion from Chimaji Appa&amp;rsquo;s letter (June 1740 A.D.) to Mahadeo Bhat Hingne at Jaypur which throws ample light on the role played by Bajirao in his North Indian politics, and states clearly the aims of the Maratha rule in general.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read the details of your letter. The objects of the late Rao for the last eight or ten years were to please the Emperor by way of integrating the Imperial rule by bringing back to Imperial fold the Semi-Independent Amirs who cared little for the Emperor&amp;rsquo;s orders at their posts and thus to strengthen the administrative forces (resulting into peace and properity) and to gain thereby the good will of the rayat, the poor and the needy, to enhance the Imperial treasury and thus to acquire highest fame and the esteem of the Emperor. For all this he had kept constant touch with Nawab Khan Dauran thorugh Sawai Jaysing, and many schemes had been planned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>dondho govind to bAji rAv</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/bAjIrAv/dhondho-govind_to_bAji-rAv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/bAjIrAv/dhondho-govind_to_bAji-rAv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nadirshah is no God, that he could destroy the earth. He possesses sense enough and knows business. He will not break with you, but will effect a friendly understanding when he knows that you are strong enough to oppose him. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect actual hostilities to break between him and you. J&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;aysing and yourself aided by the Bundela Chiefs will be quite a strong Hindu front which providence will surely crown with success. Jaysing is anxiously waiting for your arrival to take the lead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Misc</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/bAjIrAv/misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/bAjIrAv/misc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Meeting with a mogol courtier -&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whatever you have said is correct, but, for a very long time, it used to be very difficult for us to have a ceremonial bath in the river Narbada, though we people were very eager to have it, to day, by the imperial favour, I am in a position to take a dip in the river Ganges at Kashipur and Benares, and even beyond that From this end to that, none stands in our way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
