<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Tax on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/tax/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Tax on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/tax/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Capital gains</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/tax/capital-gains/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/tax/capital-gains/</guid>
      <description>Tax is levied on one’s gains realized using the sale of security holdings or from interest/ dividend income on such securities, with some quirky rules.
Term Long-term capital gains (Eg: selling stock after holding it for a year) are usually taxed at a lower rate.
Subscribing to a dividend reinvestment plan complicates calculation of capital gains.
Wash sale One can offset gains obtained by selling some securities by selling securities on which one has made a loss - but it is forbidden to buy the same security again immediately after doing so (wash sale).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/tax/india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/tax/india/</guid>
      <description>Tax residency Resident if one of the following is true
 present in India for: 182 days or more in a fiscal year 60 days or more in a fiscal year and 365 days or more during the preceding 4 fiscal years; the 60 days may be extended to 182 days in certain cases.  Income tax Non-Residents are taxed on India income only. Residents are taxed on worldwide income (subject to DTAA(Double Taxation Avoidance Agreement) with the foreign countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saving incentives</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/tax/savings-schemes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/tax/savings-schemes/</guid>
      <description>To facilitate and encourage saving for large expenses in the future, governments often provide tax breaks for special investment accounts for retirement, medical expenses and children’s education (college funds).
See here.
Taxation-deferred funds Incomes earned using these special accounts are exempt from taxes while they stay within the fund. However, withdrawals, which are only under very restricted circumstances, are taxed.
Eg: Individual Retirement Account [IRA] in USA.
Profit-tax free funds Money may be taxed at the time it is deposited in the fund, while withdrawals are tax-free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USA</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/tax/usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/tax/usa/</guid>
      <description>Residency for tax purposes  Passing Green card test or substantial presence (roughly- in use for over 183 days recently) test means you are a resident.  Income tax Retirement savings incentives For conceptual details, see the capital-gains page.
Pre tax retirement savings (taxed on withdrawal):
 401(k) a type of 401(a) plan. IRA  Post tax retirement savings (not taxed on withdrawal):
 Roth IRA. Contributions can be withdrawn anytime.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>