<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3 day camp</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/3-day-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/3-day-camp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/ByRakeshSimha/status/2006731646880591975&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My 3-Day Stay at an RSS Camp in Kerala&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For as  long as I can remember, 31st December has been an occasion to party. But this year I got an unusual invite - to attend a 3 day RSS camp that offered training in how to take part in - and organise - an RSS shaka. The moment the offer came over the phone, I said yes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To be honest, the camp was way outside my comfort zone. In fact, the word comfort does not even come into the picture. From the moment I and 5 others (all over 45 years of age) walked into the camp, in lush green Kerala, it was back to the basics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti-savarNa leaning RSS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/anti-savarNa-leaning_RSS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/anti-savarNa-leaning_RSS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Author: Gautama on TW.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;RSS, like every organisation has its blind spots. It can make wrong decisions whose consequences will be detrimental to Hindus given its outreach and influence. Hence Hindus have it in their interest to understand where RSS may be going can be wrong. IMO RSS ignoring the concerns of the general category while going all out to expand its outreach among the other categories is not a correct decision. Is it fair for the RSS to ignore the concerns of crores of honest, hardworking tax paying Indians who have never been a burden on the country, who have gone out of their way to make ends meet, to raise their standards of living, to contribute positively to the growth of this nation? All they have been expecting from the Indian state is opportunity to do so. Not doles. Not reservations. Not tax breaks. And it is these very opportunities that have been shrinking over the years because organisations such as the RSS believe outreach is more important.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti-savarNa leaning: BJP</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/anti-savarNa-leaning_BJP/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/anti-savarNa-leaning_BJP/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Author: Gautama&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Though UCs have traditionally been the core supporters of BJP, their numbers are decreasing. Attribute it to low TFR or other factors but relative to the other caste groups the numbers are dropping.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the democratic setup the numbers matter (even in any alternate setup there is a critical mass that ought to be there). So it is but natural that a party such as BJP, in order to expand, will look towards other jAtis. People may think that political parties fight on the basis of ideologies, but the stark reality is that ideologies are chosen to target voting blocs. Denying it would be foolish. Right now the more attractive voting bloc for the BJP are the OBCs and the SC/STs who have traditionally supported congress or regional satarps. I do not have an understanding of what the electoral math looks like for the coming elections, but let us for now give BJP the benefit of doubt and accept that it cannot win those without swinging the votes of the OBC and SC/ST blocs in their favor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As sampradAya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/as_sampradAya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/as_sampradAya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bhAratenduH/status/1747308309693022703&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sangh may indeed be a quasi Sampradaya.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It has declared its own Guru - dhwaja.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It has its own celibate Sanyasis and Parivrajakas, whom it calls Pracharaka. It has laity positions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It even has its own Praatah Smarana prayer in Sanskrit, taken in pieces from our ancient Puranas, but padded with shlokas in praise to social reformers like Phule and Ambedkar, ending finally with a prayer to RSS founder and his first successor. Read every morning.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It does aggressive missionary work to recruit followers and tableegh (for the lack of better words) to keep them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For Smritis it says Manu Smriti is invalid now and it’s smriti is Bharat ka Samvidhaan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is Sangh not a quasi Sampradaya? - This is not an unfair question to ask.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mohan bhAgvat speeches</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/mohan-bhAgwat-speeches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/mohan-bhAgwat-speeches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;MB refers to his previous statement in Delhi about &amp;ldquo;Hindutva being incomplete without Muslims&amp;rdquo; that it did raise eyebrows in the Hindu society. But says, these is the ideology of the Sangh since the beginning, can be found in &amp;ldquo;Bunch of Thoughts&amp;rdquo; as well.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rAma_jAmadagnya/status/1421168347199131652&#34;&gt;RJ&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;किन्तु &lt;a href=&#34;https://hindutva.github.io/books/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/03_Part_Two_The_Nation_and_Its_Problems/08_XVI_Internal_Threats/&#34;&gt;BOT&lt;/a&gt; इति श्रीमद्गुरुवर्यवचनान्य् अवधार्य विपरीतम् उक्तम् इति प्रतिभाति। तत्र मरून्मत्ता अहिन्दुका, अस्मच्छत्रवः, महत्या जागरूकताया वर्तनीयम् इति प्रपञ्चितम्। तर्ह्य् एतैः भागवतादिभिः शब्दपरिवर्तनमात्रम् अतिक्रम्य तत्त्वविकार एव सम्पाद्यमानो वेति सन्देह्मि। (सामरस्यसम्पादनप्रयत्ने द्रोहभिज्ञानदक्षताहानिर् भवतीति च।)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mohan Bhagwat quite categorically clarifies that this is the age of democracy and we do not fight for Hindu supremacy. Neither should anyone fight for Muslim supremacy.&amp;rdquo; इत्यप्य् अत्र &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rAma_jAmadagnya/status/1421180681313427456&#34;&gt;RJ&lt;/a&gt; ।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;MB recognizes there along with a majority of Hindus who will support his statement, there are those who will oppose his views as being harmful to Hindu society.&amp;rdquo; इत्यपि वर्तते।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suren: Disaster relief experience</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/suren_disaster-relief-exp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/suren_disaster-relief-exp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1993, there was a terrible earthquake in Latur. I wanted to do something, but didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to do. Someone sent me to Kurla and I met the Kurla Vyapari Sangh rep. He put me and another guy on a truck with groceries to Latur. We were given food at dharamshalas on the way. When we got down at district headquarters, a middle-aged guy greeted us.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He looked at us up and down - Young, tall and strong. Go to Mangrul. We got on another truck. This time, all the guys travelling with me were between 18 and 30 only. We got down in an open field. 2 days after the earthquake, there were tents on an open field. We were given bhakris, boiled besan and a raw onion. We started by taking vans to the village and helping people salvage their stuff. We set up tents, fed the people. The ABVP camp accepted anyone - whether they needed help or whether they had come to help. On the 4th day, a pracharak arrived. They started classes for the kids. On the 5th day, all of us volunteers attended our first shakha. I had just sent a postcard to my parents that I was going to Latur. I came back to my room after 10 days to see 2 frantic telegrams from my parents. My Dad sent a friend of his to the hostel to find out what happened. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even tell my hostel warden what I was up to. I lost touch with those swayamsevaks, but I will never forget one thing. When shit happens, the Sangh&amp;rsquo;s got your back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vs Conservatives</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/vs_conservatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/vs_conservatives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hindu conservatism is the last bastion that right-wing populism seeks to vanquish effectively&#xA;The proposed ceremony to lay the foundation stone for the Ram Mandir in Ayodhya on August 5 has generated three broad responses: euphoria from supporters; outrage from the Left, Ambedkarites and secularists; and strong disapproval on procedural grounds from eminent Hindu saints. While the first two responses were expected, it is dissenting voices emanating from Hindu religious authorities that merit attention. The accusations of the Dharmagurus deal with the emerging process of de-ritualisation of the Hindu religion by Hindutva in the following ways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
