<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;3 Timur’s Invasion and Legacy, 1400–1550 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;3 Timur’s Invasion and Legacy, 1400–1550 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 OVERVIEW</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/01_OVERVIEW/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/01_OVERVIEW/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Above is the brief prologue that, in late 1587, introduced an audience in Elizabethan London to the first performance of &lt;em&gt;Tamburlaine&lt;/em&gt;, Christopher Marlowe’s bold new play. No audience in England had heard anything like it before. In point of form, its author had broken radically with literary convention, and he knew it. The play’s very first lines airily dismiss the entire legacy of Renaissance drama – its ‘jigging veins of rhyming mother-wits’ – as mere clowning. Now, for the first time, audiences would hear blank verse, freed from rhymes, in the very iambic pentameter that William Shakespeare would soon deploy in his own plays.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 UPPER INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/02_UPPER_INDIA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/02_UPPER_INDIA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nowhere were the effects of Timur’s invasion more acutely felt than in the heartland of the former Tughluq domain – the wide, densely populated Indo-Gangetic plain that extended from the Punjab through the upper and mid-Gangetic basin to the Bengal delta. The career of Khizr Khan, a Punjabi chieftain belonging to the Khokar clan, illustrates the transition to an increasingly polycentric north India. Sultan Firuz Tughluq (r. 1351–88) had earlier appointed this chieftain as his governor of Multan. But when Timur’s army sacked Delhi in 1398–9, Khizr Khan shrewdly ingratiated himself with the Central Asian warlord. His efforts paid off. Before leaving India, Timur made the Khokar chieftain governor of the Punjabi cities of Lahore, Multan and Dipalpur. Khizr Khan also visited Timur’s capital at Samarqand to negotiate the annual tribute that he would send to his treasury. Then in 1414, shortly after the death of the last Tughluq monarch and nearly a decade after Timur’s death, he managed to wrest control of Delhi itself and launch his own dynasty of monarchs, the so-called Saiyid dynasty (1414–51). Yet even then he refrained from using sovereign titles, preferring instead to rule as the viceroy of Timur’s son and successor, Shah Rukh of Herat (r. 1405–47), to whom he regularly sent tribute. This was one way that Timur’s legacy lingered on in northern India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 BENGAL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/03_BENGAL/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/03_BENGAL/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apart from catalysing the emergence of new states, Timur’s invasion also gave rise to regional cultures in former Tughluq provinces. But in the case of Bengal, a former Tughluq governor, Shams al-Din Ilyas Shah, had established the delta’s first independent dynasty nearly sixty years before Timur sacked Delhi. During this prolonged period of autonomy, which covered the latter half of the fourteenth century, Bengal’s ancient class of Hindu aristocrats rose to prominence in the state’s government. By the end of that century, elements of the delta’s native ruling class had gained so much authority as to unsettle the Bengal sultanate’s elite Sufi shaikhs, champions of a reformed and purified Islam.4 The most important of these native nobles was Raja Ganesh, a powerful Bengali landholder whose family had enjoyed prominent status in the delta for four centuries. In 1410 the high-born patrician audaciously usurped power and for five years governed the kingdom through a succession of Muslim puppet-sultans. In 1415 he went so far as to enthrone his own son, a lad of only twelve years named Jadu, while continuing to govern as regent. But Ganesh never sought to revive the Brahmanically defined model of kingship of classical Indian tradition. Rather, a compromise formula was worked out between political brokers for the court’s Muslim and non-Muslim factions, whereby young Jadu was allowed to rule on condition that he convert to Islam, which he did, reigning as Sultan Jalal al-Din Muhammad (r. 1415–32). Soon after his enthronement, coins bearing his name were simultaneously issued from Bengal’s principal urban centres – Pandua, Chittagong, Sonargaon and Satgaon – suggesting a calculated attempt by Raja Ganesh to ensure the acceptance of his son’s accession throughout the delta.5&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 KASHMIR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/04_KASHMIR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/04_KASHMIR/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like many conquerors before him, Timur bypassed the Kashmir valley during his invasion of India, fixing his sights on the Tughluq capital of Delhi. In the autumn of 1398 his army had already marched across Afghanistan and was moving through the passes leading to the upper Indus valley. Yet his reputation for wholesale massacres of great cities had preceded his arrival in India, which is why Kashmir’s Sultan Sikandar (r. 1389-1413), on hearing that the Central Asian warlord was nearing his neighbourhood, rushed envoys to Timur’s camp bearing gifts and fervent pledges of loyalty. Although Timur only wanted Sikandar’s formal appearance, and no cash, his unscrupulous envoys caused the Kashmiri court to understand that it would have to furnish horses and a large sum of money. Puritanical and influential Muslims in Srinagar seized this moment to advance their religious agenda. One of these was Saiyid Muhammad Hamadani, a revered shaikh who, like his father ‘Ali Hamadani, had migrated from Iran. Also influential was a group of Muslim clerics, the Baihaqi saiyids. In order to meet Timur’s alleged financial demands, the latter urged the sultan to demolish Hindu temples and convert their images to bullion. The sultan’s chief minister, Suha Bhatta, himself a zealous convert to Islam, persuaded Sikandar to destroy at least four major temple complexes in the valley – Parihaspura, Bijbehara, Tripureśvara and Martand – which earned the sultan the title &lt;em&gt;butshikan&lt;/em&gt;, ‘temple-destroyer’.11 Sikandar also undermined the influence of the valley’s powerful class of Brahmins by revoking their tax-free holdings and destroying their Sanskrit books.12 Owing to such coercive measures, plus his imposition of the discriminatory &lt;em&gt;jizya&lt;/em&gt; tax on non-Muslims, the charge of anti-Hindu bigotry has ever since clung to Sikandar’s memory.13 But not to that of his son.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 GUJARAT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/05_GUJARAT/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/05_GUJARAT/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unlike Kashmir or Bengal, Gujarat had been politically well integrated with the Tughluq empire ever since Sultan ‘Ala al-Din Khalaji annexed this commercially rich region in the early fourteenth century. Basing themselves in the province’s eastern corridor that leads to upper India, the Delhi sultanate’s governors were well positioned to profit from the caravans transiting from the seaports to India’s interior, and courtiers paid substantial bribes to be appointed provincial governors or commanders of strategic Gujarati forts.30 Merchants and rulers, moreover, were mutually dependent. The former needed the security, the stable currency and the predictable taxation that the state could provide, while rulers required the silver, the horses and the arms that could be obtained from merchants. By the late fourteenth century, though, Tughluq rulers had become displeased with their governor in Gujarat over his failure to remit taxes to the central administration. They also feared that he had set down local roots and had built up a provincial army composed mainly of local soldiers. Keeping provincial rulers loyal to the political centre being a perennial metropolitan anxiety, in 1392 Zafar Khan, the son of a peasant convert to Islam and a former confident of Sultan Firuz Tughluq, was sent down to restore central rule in the wayward province. After confronting and defeating the former governor, the khan managed to pacify the province’s strategically important eastern corridor leading to the sea, though he spent the rest of his life battling recalcitrant chieftains both in the mountains to the east and in the Saurashtra peninsula to the west.31&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 MALWA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/06_MALWA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/06_MALWA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1391, just seven years before Timur launched his India campaign, four governors were sent out from Delhi to bring order to the provinces of an unsteady Tughluq empire. Each would establish an independent sultanate soon after the Turkish warlord sacked Delhi. Khizr Khan founded the Saiyid dynasty of rulers in Delhi, Malik Sarwar the Sharqi sultanate of Jaunpur and Zafar Khan the Gujarat sultanate. The fourth governor, Dilawar Khan Ghuri, was posted to Malwa, the rich though landlocked tableland in west-central India north of the Narmada. When Timur began sacking Delhi in December 1398, the last Tughluq sultan, not a paragon of courage, quietly slipped out of Tughluqabad fort and fled to Gujarat. He had hoped that Zafar Khan would help him reclaim his capital. When such assistance was not forthcoming, the fugitive king moved on to Malwa, where Dilawar Khan hosted him for several years. So long as the royal exile was his guest, Dilawar Khan tactfully refrained from declaring his independence. But as soon as the erstwhile sultan had taken his leave, Dilawar declared himself sovereign and built congregational mosques in what would be the core cities of the Malwa sultanate: Ujjain, Lalitpur, Mandu and Dhar. Meanwhile his son, Alp Khan, busied himself strengthening the fort of Mandu. Situated in a spectacular natural setting some thirty-five kilometres south of Dhar, this would soon become one of the architectural gems of medieval India. Jutting out from the Vindhya Mountains, its southern side sharply dropping 400 metres to the Nimar plain below, the city stretches along a jagged-edged plateau about twenty-five kilometres north of the Narmada. This would be Alp Khan’s new capital when he succeeded to his father’s throne as Sultan Hoshang Shah (r. 1406–35).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 EMERGING IDENTITIES: THE IDEA OF ‘RAJPUT’</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/07_EMERGING_IDENTITIES_THE_IDEA_OF_RAJPUT/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/07_EMERGING_IDENTITIES_THE_IDEA_OF_RAJPUT/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was only from the sixteenth century that the word ‘Rajput’ became securely associated with territorially based, closed clans claiming deep genealogical roots and nurturing a warrior ethos of heroism and martyrdom.55 In inscriptions from western and central India dating from the eleventh to the fourteenth centuries, the Sanskrit term &lt;em&gt;rajaputra&lt;/em&gt;, ‘a king’s son’, appears simply as a title indicating a rank or official position, but not one that was inheritable by subsequent generations or associated with martial heroism.56 In those earlier centuries, kings received military service from subordinate chieftains, called &lt;em&gt;ranaka&lt;/em&gt;s or &lt;em&gt;thakura&lt;/em&gt;s, in return for gifts of land that the latter gave to their own cavalry commanders, called &lt;em&gt;rauta&lt;/em&gt;s, a term derived from &lt;em&gt;rajaputra.&lt;/em&gt; In Persian sources dating to the early thirteenth century these commanders are called &lt;em&gt;rawat&lt;/em&gt;, also derived from &lt;em&gt;rajaputra&lt;/em&gt;.57 In the early fifteenth century, the label ‘Rajput’ was still associated with successful military service performed by men who had taken up soldiering on behalf of a deserving king. But by the end of that century, the word was well on the way to referencing entire aristocratic lineages bearing a martial ethos of courage, heroism and martyrdom. Such lineages included the Chauhans of Ajmer, the Tomaras of Delhi, the Gahadavalas of Kanauj and the Chandelas of Kalinjar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 WRITING IN VERNACULAR LANGUAGES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/08_WRITING_IN_VERNACULAR_LANGUAGES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/08_WRITING_IN_VERNACULAR_LANGUAGES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was also in the long fifteenth century that across much of South Asia vernacular, spoken languages appeared in written form, for both documentary and expressive purposes. This ‘vernacular revolution’, however, did not displace India’s older, transregional literary traditions, Sanskrit and Persian, but occurred alongside and in dialogue with them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like the emergence of regional and Rajput identities, the appearance of vernacular literatures was associated with the Delhi sultanate’s diminished status following Timur’s invasion. As Delhi’s authority receded, former imperial governors, lesser regional chiefs and local warlords all asserted themselves politically. Larger players such as the sultans of Bengal, Jaunpur, Gujarat or Malwa could do this by patronizing imposing works of architecture or by maintaining substantial numbers of armed retainers. But smaller chiefs or warlords, possessing fewer resources, had fewer options. Just to survive amidst a patchwork of mutually hostile states meant spending much of their limited resources on recruiting mercenaries from India’s military labour market. On the other hand, what small but ambitious warlords could feasibly manage was to build up large households and attain local renown by patronizing the best and the brightest literati they could find. These would be poets, singers or bards who composed and propagated literary works intended for as wide a circulation as possible within their patron’s realm. But because such states might be of modest size, the literature was likely to be composed in the spoken language and dialect specific to a state’s sovereign domain. These could be songs extolling their patron’s generosity or power, genealogies, biographies, hagiographies, popular narratives dedicated to a political patron or, most commonly, vernacular adaptations either of Persian classical genres such as romance literature, or of Sanskrit classical genres such as courtly epics. In creative ways, then, India’s two transregional literary traditions were effectively reinvented in ways that could be intelligible in the more fragmented political and social world that had emerged in the wake of Timur’s invasion.66&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 CONCLUSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/09_CONCLUSION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/3_Timurs_Invasion_and_Legacy_14001550/09_CONCLUSION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Persian chronicles compiled in the fourteenth century convey the impression of the Delhi sultanate’s sovereign territory as a politically uniform terrain. Even if reality never did match such a monolithic vision, it was at least possible to imagine the sultanate in such terms. But Timur’s sack of Delhi upended all that, setting off a chain reaction of processes that would define the long fifteenth century.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, Timur’s invasion was followed by former Tughluq governors declaring their independence from Delhi and setting down roots in their respective regions, a process already begun in Bengal and the Deccan when those regions were lost to Delhi in the mid fourteenth century. Second, the shrinking of Delhi’s political authority disrupted overland trade routes that carried caravans of war-horses from Central Asia to north India. As a result, independent rulers were forced to rely less on cavalry and more on war-elephants, to which they had ready access, together with manpower recruited not from upper India or points west, but from India’s own military labour markets, especially the lower Ganges region, or Purbiya.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
