<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Atwill - chinese sultanate on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Atwill - chinese sultanate on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 A Mandarin&#39;s Tale</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/01_A_Mandarins_Tale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/01_A_Mandarins_Tale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER I A Mandarin&amp;rsquo;s Tale The End of the Beginning On a warm summer evening in July 1857, Governor-General Hengchun stood on the city wall of Kunming surveying the chaotic scene all around him.1 Dragon Gate Temple, carved into the steep cliffs of the Western Hills and normally visible across Dianchi Lake, was obscured by thick columns of smoke rising from the city&amp;rsquo;s burning suburbs and adjacent fields. The wealthy caravansaries, the thriving markets, and the innumerable houses outside the massive city walls had all been looted and were now in flames.2 Thousands of city residents and refugees from other parts of the province of Yunnan had thought their capital would be safe; all had been caught in the sudden offensive of the rebel army.3 Hengchun knew the Chinese Empire was staggering from advances being made by the rebel leader Hong Xiuquan and his Taiping army far to the east in the strategic lower Yangtze valley. Thus, the central government was unlikely to send him either military reinforcements or funds to relieve the siege of Kunming. Yunnan was one of the poorest and most distant provinces of the Qing Empire. Its greatest value to the imperial court had been its mineral reserves, especially copper. But early in the 1800s, many of Yunnan&amp;rsquo;s mines had begun to close as the quality of the copper declined, deposits were depleted, and transportation costs rose. The trade in Yunnan&amp;rsquo;s famous tea was still lucrative, but except for that the province rarely drew the court&amp;rsquo;s already strained attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 South of the Clouds:</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/02_South_of_the_Clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/02_South_of_the_Clouds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 2 South of the Clouds: The World of Nineteenth-Century Yunnan Framed by the remote upper reaches of the Yangtze River to the north, by the lofty Himalayan peaks of Tibet to the west, and by the steamy highlands of Southeast Asia to the south, Yunnan Province marked the southwestern limit of Qing control in the mid-nineteenth century. Chinese imperial sources dating back more than two thousand years have consistently labeled this region Yunnan-literally, the land &amp;ldquo;south of the clouds.&amp;rdquo; According to traditional lore, the name &amp;ldquo;Yunnan&amp;rdquo; denoted the region&amp;rsquo;s position just south of the misty, humid, and often overcast Sichuan Basin. &amp;ldquo;South of the clouds&amp;rdquo; suited the image of the region held by outsiders; figuratively speaking, Yunnan was obscured by drifting clouds that allowed only enigmatic glimpses of a distant horizon. Indeed, this region &amp;ldquo;south of the clouds&amp;rdquo; was dramatically different, both in its external realities and in people&amp;rsquo;s minds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Shades of Islam: The Muslim Yunnanese</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/03_Shades_of_Islam_The_Muslim_Yunnanese/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/03_Shades_of_Islam_The_Muslim_Yunnanese/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 3 Shades of Islam: The Muslim Yunnanese&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-islamic-roots&#34;&gt;Introduction: Islamic Roots&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yunnan&amp;rsquo;s first contact with the Islamic world can be traced to the Tang and Song dynasties (618-1276). In those eras, Muslim traders were plying the prosperous Southwestern Silk Road, which traversed Yunnan and linked central China with the prospering Indian Ocean trading networks.1 Islam became firmly established in Yunnan during the Yuan dynasty in the thirteenth century, when Khubilai Khan&amp;rsquo;s armies conquered the region and fully integrated it into the Chinese Empire. This subjugation occurred after Yunnan had experienced several centuries of independent rule under the Nanzhao (738-902) and Dali (937-1253) kingdoms.2 The &amp;ldquo;first tide&amp;quot;3 of Muslims to enter Yunnan arrived from Central Asia. They served as soldiers and administrators for the Mongol rulers of the Yuan dynasty, who viewed them as more trustworthy than the indigenous Yunnanese or the Chinese. In particular, these early groups of Muslims benefited from Khubilai&amp;rsquo;s appointment of Sayyid &amp;lsquo;Ajall Shams al-Din (Ch. Saidianchi Shansiding Wuma&amp;rsquo;er), a Muslim from Bukhara (in present-day Uzbekistan), as governor of the province in 1274. He held this post until his death five years later.4 Traditional imperial histories largely ignore Sayyid &amp;lsquo;Ajall&amp;rsquo;s Muslim identity and the role he played in establishing Islam in Yunnan. Armijo-Hussein notes that court historians lauded him for &amp;ldquo;introducing the most important of the traditional Han Chinese customs, values and rituals&amp;rdquo; during his sixyear reign. According to Rossabi and others, although Sayyid &amp;lsquo;Ajall promoted Chinese culture in the region and never set out to convert the multiethnic populace to Islam, Yunnan remained &amp;ldquo;the one area in early Yüan China in which Muslim jurisdiction was virtually unchecked&amp;rdquo; by the Mongol court. As a consequence, the region had one of the largest Muslim populations outside the &amp;ldquo;Quran Belt&amp;rdquo; of northwestern China.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Rebellion&#39;s Roots: Hanjianism, Han Newcomers, and Non-Han Violence in Yunnan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/04_Rebellions_Roots_Hanjianism_Han_Newcomers_and_Non-Han_Violence_in_Yunnan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/04_Rebellions_Roots_Hanjianism_Han_Newcomers_and_Non-Han_Violence_in_Yunnan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 4 Rebellion&amp;rsquo;s Roots: Hanjianism, Han Newcomers, and Non-Han Violence in Yunnan Converting Yunnan At the beginning of the Qing dynasty in 1651, Yongli, the last known surviving grandson of the Ming emperor, found himself pursued by Qing forces who had overthrown the Ming court in Beijing and who were now consolidating their control across the empire. He and his dwindling group of loyalists swept into Yunnan, where they established a government-inexile that lasted for nearly eight years before they were forced by Qing troops to flee into Burma. The Burmese king, likely realizing there was little to be gained from such an arrangement, switched his allegiance from the ousted Ming to the emergent Manchu and took the prince and his family hostage. He placed them under virtual house arrest and executed many of their retainers. Yongli&amp;rsquo;s dismal existence ended in 1662, when the Burmese court handed him over to the Qing general, Wu Sangui, who escorted him back into Yunnan. There the prince and his son were executed by strangulation.1 The death of the last Ming heir quelled the Qing court&amp;rsquo;s fears of a Ming restoration led by a blood descendent. However, a new danger soon arose, from General Wu Sangui, the same general who had helped the Manchu overthrow the Ming. Wu Sangui was growing increasingly dissatisfied with his subordinate role to the Qing throne and was not content to be even nominally under Qing control, so he dissolved his allegiance to the Qing and in 1678 declared himself emperor of a new dynasty. Only months after this, however, he died of dysentery. Later that same year, Qing forces recaptured Kunming (although remnants of Wu&amp;rsquo;s forces would remain in Yunnan until 1681). Nearly four decades after the Qing dynasty was founded in 1644, Yunnan became the last of the Chinese provinces to be formally brought under Qing authority.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 Spiraling Violence: The Rise of Anti-Hui Hostilities</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/05_Spiraling_Violence_The_Rise_of_Anti-Hui_Hostilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/05_Spiraling_Violence_The_Rise_of_Anti-Hui_Hostilities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 5 Spiraling Violence: The Rise of Anti-Hui Hostilities The Xiyi Mine Incident of 1800 Early in the spring of 1800, at a small silver mine in Shunning County on the far western border of Yunnan, a quarrel broke out between a Han migrant from Hunan and a Muslim Yunnanese. The exact circumstances are unclear, but according to confessions in the official records, the argument between the two men-a Hui and a Han-quickly led to a street brawl during which Hui damaged several Hunanese shops.1 In retaliation, more than 180 Hunanese Han formed a band and over the next several days carried out extended attacks on the Hui community, killing a Hui team boss and at least eighteen other Hui. Several Hunanese were wounded in the fighting, but none were killed.2 Remarkably, the Han from other provinces never joined the fray; they stayed on the sidelines in groups based on their native provinces (Jiangxi and so on).3 At the time the clash occurred, the Xiyi mine had been open &amp;ldquo;officially&amp;rdquo; for less than two decades (it had been operating outside Qing oversight since at least the early eighteenth century). In 1800, several thousand miners, workers, and merchants were working in or near the mine and living close by. Because of its remote location near upland Southeast Asia, the local population included Yi, Han, and Hui.6 From the perspective of Qing officials, mining populations were innately unstable and those on the empire&amp;rsquo;s periphery especially so. One official in Yunnan bemoaned that the Yunnan mines were difficult to control: &amp;ldquo;Everywhere there are covert bandits and hanjian establishing gangs and miners predisposed to fight and rob&amp;hellip;. What is the method to repress and govern [such behavior]? How can that be easily changed when the majority of the gold, silver, and iron mines are all like this?&amp;ldquo;7 The Xiyi mine was distant from Yunnan&amp;rsquo;s administrative center, yet it had experienced the full impact of Han in-migration. The result was an unstable mixture of lawlessness, ethnic tension, and greed. The incident was [[65]] similar to many other ethnic flare-ups in Yunnan during this period, and thus seemed like nothing out of the ordinary, so officials were little concerned and took no action.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 &#34;All the Fish in the Pond&#34;: The Kunming Massacre and the Rise of the Panthay Rebellion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/06_All_the_Fish_in_the_Pond_The_Kunming_Massacre_and_the_Rise_of_the_Panthay_Rebellion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/06_All_the_Fish_in_the_Pond_The_Kunming_Massacre_and_the_Rise_of_the_Panthay_Rebellion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 6 &amp;ldquo;All the Fish in the Pond&amp;rdquo;: The Kunming Massacre and the Rise of the Panthay Rebellion Governor-General Lin Zexu, in departing to serve in a new post in 1849, claimed that as a result of his efforts Yunnan would be secure for ten more years.1 This was optimistic of him, given the uncertain times. During his two short years he had barely secured peace in Baoshan, let alone the whole of Yunnan. Lin was leaving Yunnan believing the Hui were at the root of the province&amp;rsquo;s violence. All of his solutions to the unrest focused on the Hui and ignored the strong anti-Hui bias among the Han. Lin&amp;rsquo;s actions had only alleviated the symptoms; the deeper problem of Han chauvinism was as potent as when he arrived.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 Ambiguous Ambitions: Ma Rulong&#39;s Road</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/07_Ambiguous_Ambitions_Ma_Rulongs_Road/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/07_Ambiguous_Ambitions_Ma_Rulongs_Road/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 7 Ambiguous Ambitions: Ma Rulong&amp;rsquo;s Road to Power, 1860-1864 The early years of the Panthay Rebellion were extremely taxing on the Qing court and their representatives in Yunnan. The central court faced threats in all parts of the empire and had few resources to spare for the provincial officials who were trying to bring the province back under government control. In spite of this lack of central support, provincial Qing officials were able to mount several concerted attacks against the rebels in Dali. That city being the former western administrative center of the Qing in Yunnan, they considered the rebels who held it the biggest threat to Qing dominion in the region; thus Dali quickly became the focus of all the military campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 Rebellious Visions: Du Wenxiu and the Creation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/08_Rebellious_Visions_Du_Wenxiu_and_the_Creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/08_Rebellious_Visions_Du_Wenxiu_and_the_Creation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 8 Rebellious Visions: Du Wenxiu and the Creation of the Dali Sultanate Defending the Yunnan World For the Beijing court, Ma Rulong had been the face of the rebellion in the years following the Kunming Massacre. But for those experiencing the rebellion firsthand, the key political, ideological, and military leader of the rebels was Du Wenxiu. After he captured Dali and was selected as Generalissimo, Sultan, and Leader of all Muslims, Du guided the rise of the independent Dali sultanate in western Yunnan. Throughout his eighteen-year tenure, he worked to establish a style of government that reflected Yunnan&amp;rsquo;s ethnic and religious diversity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 Ethereal Deeds: The Struggle to Reclaim Yunnan, 1867-1873</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/09_Ethereal_Deeds_The_Struggle_to_Reclaim_Yunnan_1867-1873/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/09_Ethereal_Deeds_The_Struggle_to_Reclaim_Yunnan_1867-1873/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 9 Ethereal Deeds: The Struggle to Reclaim Yunnan, 1867-1873 The Pinnacle of Success: The Pingnan State, 1867-1869 In the spring of 1867, Du Wenxiu, the leader and commander-in-chief of the multiethnic Dali Kingdom, launched his troops from the city of Dali in a massive assault on Kunming, the last major imperial stronghold in Yunnan Province. Five columns of troops spread out from north to south and attacked along an eastward trajectory with devastating effectiveness, capturing all towns they encountered. For nearly ten years, Dali had been the political, cultural, and commercial center of the Hui-led insurgency against the Qing dynasty. Over that time the rebels had slowly strengthened their control over much of eastern and southern Yunnan. Just over six months after opening their initial campaign in the east, Du&amp;rsquo;s generals surrounded Kunming, trapping the bulk of the imperial army and leaving only a few of the province&amp;rsquo;s easternmost prefectures under imperial control. For the next two years Du and his multiethnic allies were the undisputed masters of Yunnan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Epilogue: The Aftermath of Rebellion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/10_Epilogue_The_Aftermath_of_Rebellion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/atwill_chinese-sultanate/10_Epilogue_The_Aftermath_of_Rebellion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER IO Epilogue: The Aftermath of Rebellion&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The static, two-dimensional, and-for the imperial court-convenient portrayal of the Panthay Rebellion as simply a &amp;ldquo;Muslim rebellion&amp;rdquo; has endured until the present day. It was the last of the mid-nineteenth-century rebellions in China to be suppressed, and this narrative of the rebellion meshed nicely with the court&amp;rsquo;s efforts to portray itself as a powerful government that was not morally bankrupt. It is notable that representations of the Yunnan Hui in Western and Chinese scholarship have barely changed since the Hui were assigned an ethnic classification separate from the Han and the Yi in the nineteenth century.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
