<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;1 The Growth of Turkic Power, 1000–1300 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/1_The_Growth_of_Turkic_Power_10001300/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;1 The Growth of Turkic Power, 1000–1300 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/1_The_Growth_of_Turkic_Power_10001300/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 A TALE OF TWO RAIDS: 1022, 1025</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/1_The_Growth_of_Turkic_Power_10001300/01_A_TALE_OF_TWO_RAIDS_1022_1025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/1_The_Growth_of_Turkic_Power_10001300/01_A_TALE_OF_TWO_RAIDS_1022_1025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the early second millennium, within only three years of each other, two armies marching from opposite directions raided north India. Neither would remain to govern or colonize conquered territory. Although both expeditions were successful in their own ways, they harboured different objectives, had different martial traditions and were informed by very different political systems. The two invasions also suggest why the opening of the second millennium marked a major transition in India’s long history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 POLITICAL CULTURE IN THE SANSKRIT WORLD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/1_The_Growth_of_Turkic_Power_10001300/02_POLITICAL_CULTURE_IN_THE_SANSKRIT_WORLD/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/1_The_Growth_of_Turkic_Power_10001300/02_POLITICAL_CULTURE_IN_THE_SANSKRIT_WORLD/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The culture that had informed Rajendra Chola’s political actions, including his raid on Bengal, was derived from Sanskrit treatises on power, wealth and rulership. It presumed a political universe crowded with little kings, bigger kings and emperors – that is, kings of kings. It also presumed a world of shifting political sands, where rulers had neither permanent enemies nor permanent allies. In conducting the business of warfare, therefore, classical Indian thought recommended that enemies not be annihilated, but rather co-opted and transformed into loyal subordinates&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  who could be put to use as allies against future enemies. Thus the same inscription that describes the Chola raid on Bengal records that when Rajendra returned from his victorious northern expedition:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 POLITICAL CULTURE IN THE PERSIANATE WORLD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/1_The_Growth_of_Turkic_Power_10001300/03_POLITICAL_CULTURE_IN_THE_PERSIANATE_WORLD/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/1_The_Growth_of_Turkic_Power_10001300/03_POLITICAL_CULTURE_IN_THE_PERSIANATE_WORLD/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If Rajendra Chola’s raid on Bengal had operated within the world of the &lt;em&gt;mandala&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;digvijaya&lt;/em&gt; and South Asia’s sacred geography, Mahmud of Ghazni’s 1025 raid on Somnath – like his sixteen previous raids on northern India – was driven by very different ideas. The core of Mahmud’s forces was composed of Turkish slaves or &lt;em&gt;mamluk&lt;/em&gt;s, who, as young men typically captured in war and separated from their kin groups, had been recruited to eastern Afghanistan from Central Asia on account of their exceptional military skills. They were ‘Turks’ inasmuch as their native language was Turkish, dialects of which in the eleventh century were spoken from the western frontiers of China across Central Asia to the Oxus River (Turkish-speakers would not occupy Anatolia – that is, most of present-day Turkey – until several centuries later). And they were slaves inasmuch as they were attached neither to their natal kin nor to land, but to their masters, who were typically state officials. But, because they were entrusted with weapons and lived in close quarters with their masters, this type of ‘elite’ or ‘military’ slavery differed fundamentally from the plantation slavery typical of the early modern Atlantic world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 THE GHURID CONQUEST OF NORTH INDIA, 1192–1206</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/1_The_Growth_of_Turkic_Power_10001300/04_THE_GHURID_CONQUEST_OF_NORTH_INDIA_11921206/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/1_The_Growth_of_Turkic_Power_10001300/04_THE_GHURID_CONQUEST_OF_NORTH_INDIA_11921206/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For most of the twelfth century, the Seljuqs and Ghaznavids ruled over Khurasan and Afghanistan respectively. But this changed in the latter part of that century when the Ghaznavids’ steady decline created a power vacuum in eastern Afghanistan and the Punjab. That vacuum would be filled not by the Ghaznavids’ historic rivals, the Seljuqs, but by one of their own former client states – Ghur, a kingdom centred in the remote and rugged heart of Afghanistan’s Hindu Kush Mountains. Rising from obscurity in the mid twelfth century, chieftains of this kingdom would soon roll over the Ghaznavids on their way to defeating the dominant martial lineage of northern Rajasthan, the Chauhans, thereby paving the way for the establishment of the Delhi sultanate (1206–1526).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 THE DELHI SULTANATE UNDER THE MAMLUKS, OR SLAVE KINGS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/1_The_Growth_of_Turkic_Power_10001300/05_THE_DELHI_SULTANATE_UNDER_THE_MAMLUKS_OR_SLAVE_KINGS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/1_The_Growth_of_Turkic_Power_10001300/05_THE_DELHI_SULTANATE_UNDER_THE_MAMLUKS_OR_SLAVE_KINGS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Delhi, these issues were settled when Aibek’s favourite slave, Iltutmish, defeated both his fellow slave cohorts and his former master’s son, Aram Shah, after which he claimed the throne. However, a contradiction lies at the heart of Iltutmish’s momentous reign, which lasted from 1210 to 1236. Though himself a slave – indeed, a slave of a slave – Iltutmish assiduously endeavoured to establish the Delhi sultanate as a hereditary monarchy, endowed with all the trappings of Persian imperial symbolism and rituals. This effort began immediately on the death of Aibek, whose own son, Aram Shah, had staked a claim to the throne. But Iltutmish confronted and defeated the party of Turks loyal to Aram Shah, who died in the conflict. Then, in an attempt to defuse the bad press surrounding his usurpation of power and his killing of Aibek’s son, Iltutmish married Aibek’s daughter. This made him the son-in-law of his deceased master – not quite the same as a direct descendant of Aibek, but a close approximation thereof.49&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 CONCLUSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/1_The_Growth_of_Turkic_Power_10001300/06_CONCLUSION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/1_The_Growth_of_Turkic_Power_10001300/06_CONCLUSION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In assessing the impact of the conquest on north India’s subject population, one must distinguish the rhetoric of conquest from the practices of conquerors and rulers. Many contemporary chroniclers were themselves immigrants or their near-descendants, who had been traumatized by the destructive invasions of their native Central Asia by pagan Mongols. They consequently looked to Delhi as a safe haven for themselves and for Islam.61 They also trumpeted a narrative of Muslim invaders triumphantly vanquishing a mass of Indian infidels. But such rhetoric stood at odds with the practice of the Delhi sultanate’s rulers, who needed to govern a huge population accustomed to their own ways of managing affairs. Overruling objections from their more conservative Muslim advisers, they followed the policies of their Ghaznavid and Ghurid predecessors by integrating defeated Indian elites into their political systems and aligning their coinage with indigenous numismatic traditions. Although Brahmins who had been attached to the courts or temples of north India’s defeated ruling houses lost their institutional bases, the many who were not so affiliated continued their traditional vocation as local priests. As long as sultanate officials were seen as preserving the social order, Brahmins such as Pandit Yogishvara appear to have given their assent to Delhi’s rule.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
