<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;१२ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/12/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;१२ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/12/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cynosure</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/12/2005-12-29_cynosure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/12/2005-12-29_cynosure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/12/29/cynosure/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For some reason I used the word cynosure. The muni and I had a brief&#xA;discussion on this word some time ago. It appears the the word cynosure&#xA;is from the name tail of Canis Major (cynos-ura). This construct seems&#xA;to be an archaic Indo-European word because we encounter a similar set&#xA;of words as the names of the sons of the fallen bhArgava ajigarta. The&#xA;most famous of them was the bhArgava R^iShi shunaHshepa Ajigarti who&#xA;later became devarAta vaishvAmitra. He amongst other mantras composed&#xA;the celebrated vAravantIya. The power of the vAranvantIya is&#xA;indescribable. The fury of vaishvAnara can only be channelized by the&#xA;vAravantIya.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The days of bhoga</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/12/2005-12-28_the-days-of-bhoga/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/12/2005-12-28_the-days-of-bhoga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/12/28/the-days-of-bhoga/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A friend, in course of a yarning session, reminded me of the days of&#xA;bhoga. In a social situation with Marc, R and Hayastanika we were all&#xA;ganging to make fun of R. A person, who shall go un-named, remarked in&#xA;full auditory range of Marc that, if R is around, people stop paying&#xA;attention everyone else but her. This statement by that person could&#xA;have caused me enormous social damage in an as-it-is tense situation. So&#xA;I tried to do some talking to divert attention. I remembered our days of&#xA;bhoga (like that of yayAti when his puNya still lasted) and recalled the&#xA;college program which was being recorded for possible screening on local&#xA;TV. These college programs were really not places for the seeker of&#xA;brahman, but like the pAshupata, we were free from the pAshas of the&#xA;mundane, and we passed through the venue on our way to visit the shrine&#xA;of the simian emanation of the fiery bhairava. The TV camera, for&#xA;reasons pretty obvious to the pumAn, focussed on R (oo… I fear she may&#xA;demand removing this post, for I was supposed to be revealing only some&#xA;specifically triaged stuff here). Later my janani who saw the clip on TV&#xA;stated that R carries herself remarkably well and that her nose-ring and&#xA;tilaka looked good. She said: even R’s own prasU thinks she is&#xA;self-conscious, but I think she has the full confidence of always being&#xA;in command.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Liberation of Jx</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/12/2005-12-17_the-liberation-of-jx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/12/2005-12-17_the-liberation-of-jx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/12/17/the-liberation-of-jx/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The clansmen got to gether to take stock of the proceedings. The case of&#xA;Jx was remarkable. He had been pinned down by the attack of the vairi-s&#xA;who were deluding him. He finally woke up on that fateful Monday&#xA;morning. His purohita pressed home with the fierce attack that hurled&#xA;arrows like a hail on the attack. His vairi-s were completely gone. They&#xA;were gone like the sky blown clean of all the clouds to reveal the azure&#xA;heights, with nothing but the midday sun blazing on the cobalt vault.&#xA;His dhanakShaya had been ended. He had suffered one major loss, but&#xA;otherwise had at least emerged on the other shore with his life. He felt&#xA;it was great victory and was ecstatic. But the other clansmen were vary.&#xA;While he had finally repulsed the attackers, there could be more. They&#xA;assembled and asked: O bhArgava what do you think? Is this victory&#xA;complete?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Under the karNamoTA tree</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/12/2005-12-06_under-the-karnamota-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/12/2005-12-06_under-the-karnamota-tree/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/12/06/under-the-karnamota-tree/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We walked up the path of the hill of the vAnara, when the dasyus were&#xA;not its rulers yet. There was a glorious cleft on the side of the&#xA;hillock, which led to a deep valley with wonderfully eroded paths. There&#xA;a cool breeze often blew and we wandered around with the muni,&#xA;kumbhodbhavA, and occasionally kR^iShNavarNa and the rAmAnujavAdin. The&#xA;muni and myself had installed a installed a large li~Nga there for the&#xA;worship of The god in the cleft and worshipped it with the brAhmi plant&#xA;and the sha~Nka puShpa. We learned from the kumbhodbhavA that a few&#xA;days later the place had been defiled by dasyus. We first reconnoitered&#xA;and found that there was an enormous band of dasyus whom we could not&#xA;fight on our own. We also noticed that the li~Nga had been stolen by&#xA;the dasas and the place dug up. We were furious but could not do much.&#xA;We worshipped mahAdeva with the hima offering and saw him conjoint with&#xA;the shakti who gave us the signal to attack. In the deathly spot near&#xA;where we fought our enemies grew the huge karNamoTA tree, which is&#xA;related to khadira tree. We walked in a straight line from the small&#xA;khadira tree in the spot of dattAtreya to the giant the karNamoTA tree&#xA;and tied the mystic oShadhi known as vArAhI to the trunk of the&#xA;karNamoTa tree.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the lap of dhUmAvatI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/12/2005-12-01_in-the-lap-of-dhumavati/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/12/2005-12-01_in-the-lap-of-dhumavati/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/12/01/in-the-lap-of-dhumavati/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The harsh cawing of the solitary crow at night announces her presence.&#xA;Of large size with dishevelled hair she roams. The severed heads of&#xA;viShNu and rudra are seen beside her. The mystic bIja graaaM is&#xA;reverberating all around her. There are the senAs of the lulApamukhas&#xA;around her commanded by the dreaded kAlavAhanavadana. Beside her sits&#xA;her fair daughter rakta-jyeShThA or upa-dhUmrA. Her pArshadhas are&#xA;yelling hideous statements like without shivA, shiva is but a shava.&#xA;Others yell it is not in this jagat. In her hand she holds a large&#xA;terrible shUla.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
