<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Anandrao Bhosle</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-12-26_anandrao-bhosle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-12-26_anandrao-bhosle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/12/26/anandrao-bhosle/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This remarkable issue was brought to my attention by a person who&#xA;specifically wishes to remain un-named on these pages on account of&#xA;certain private reasons related to this narrative. It is clear that&#xA;Shahji was a rather distinguished military leader and he had transmitted&#xA;this genetically influenced trait to not only his famous son Shivaji,&#xA;but also the forgotten elder son&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://manollasa.blogspot.com/2006/07/some-notes-on-shahji-and-sambhaji.html&#34;&gt;Sambhaji&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;In reality he also passed these genes on to another son who has been&#xA;largely forgotten in modern Maharatta histories. When Shahji was was in&#xA;Bijapur having left his wife in the environs of Pune, he secretly took&#xA;up a woman of unknown provenance as a sexual partner. This fact would&#xA;have been quite improper for a well-bred Maratha of the era, and was&#xA;accordingly hushed up, except for the Shedgaonkar bakhar that explicitly&#xA;mentions it. As a result of this union was born a son called Anandrao&#xA;Bhosle. He was placed in the custody of the young deshastha brAhmaNa&#xA;Venkoji Datto and subsequently served in the Shahji’s command at Bijapur&#xA;in his early youth. He and Venkoji Datto then left Shahji’s service and&#xA;moved over to Pune and enrolled themselves with Shivaji to defend the&#xA;Hindu Svarajya. The Sabhasad chronicle also confirms this by mentioning&#xA;that mentions that “Venkoji Datto, an able brahmin officer of great&#xA;accomplishment, and Shahji’s son Anandrao joined Shivaji’s service at&#xA;Pune after leaving Shahji at Bijapur”. Shivaji appointed both of them to&#xA;the rank of Panch-hazari (commander of 5000), which was a high rank in&#xA;the Maratha army of the time that could possibly be attained only due&#xA;high military ability or perhaps genetic relationship in the case of&#xA;Anandrao. In any case Anandrao clearly proved himself to be of high&#xA;military distinction. They were placed under the Sarnobat of the Maratha&#xA;army, Prataprao Gujjar and marched with him for the attack on Surat.&#xA;Following the plundering of Surat, Daud Khan Quereshi led the Moslem&#xA;hordes along with Ikhlas Khan and suddenly ambushed Shivaji between Vani&#xA;and Dindori in Northern Maharashtra. Shivaji quickly divided his forces&#xA;into four divisions and began harrying the Mughals avoiding open&#xA;confrontation. He personally led one division, even as he gave command&#xA;of another to Anandrao. Anandrao distinguished himself on the field by&#xA;leading the Marathas to safety when the Mogols pressed with great&#xA;ferocity on his division. This distractionary move allowed Shivaji to&#xA;personally attack the Mogol army after his division united with that of&#xA;Anandrao’s and kill 3000 Moslems in the encounter that followed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The origin of the royal bhosles</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-11-26_the-origin-of-the-royal-bhosles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-11-26_the-origin-of-the-royal-bhosles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/11/26/the-origin-of-the-royal-bhosles/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem of the origin of the royal Bhosles, or the clan of Shivaji&#xA;the reviver of Hindu fortunes, has interested me at various points due&#xA;to a variety of reasons. I had come across the notorious stone&#xA;inscription in Thanjavur that gave a peculiar genealogy that did not&#xA;match any other genealogy from Maharashtra. During my peregrinations in&#xA;the Maharatta country I came across tribal Bhosles who were&#xA;cattle-herders, and many other tribal groups bearing traditionally&#xA;Maharatta last names- e.g. the Shinde, the Holkar and the Gaikavad.&#xA;There is evidence that these later Maharatta princes were originally&#xA;shUdras who attained royal status due their military distinction. So&#xA;given the Thanjavur inscription, I did not find it impossible if the&#xA;royal Bhosles were also shUdras who attained royal status as the latter&#xA;Maharatta princes had done. Per say, this phenomenon was pretty&#xA;widespread: In Andhra, in the years of the great struggle, we have the&#xA;Kamma and Reddi shUdras attain royal status as a consequence of their&#xA;valiant struggle against the Moslems [Though there are other lines of&#xA;evidence that they were originally kShatriya-s who were merely&#xA;reassuming their lost status]. In support of such origins for the&#xA;Bhosles we have the statement of Jadhavrao the father-in-law of Shahji.&#xA;When Shahji’s father, Maloji, asked him for his daughter’s had he&#xA;refused initially citing his higher status as result of his descent from&#xA;the yAdava clan who were originally rulers of Maharashtra before the&#xA;Islamic deluge. The name bhosle is variously hyper-sanskritized:&#xA;paramAnanda makes it bR^iShabala. A smArta eulogist from Thanjavur made&#xA;it bhAsvata-kula. This suggests that it probably did not really have a&#xA;Sanskrit original.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some notes on Shahji and Sambhaji the brother of Shivaji-IV</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-07_some-notes-on-shahji-and-sambhaji-the-brother-of-shivaji-iv/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-07_some-notes-on-shahji-and-sambhaji-the-brother-of-shivaji-iv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/07/07/some-notes-on-shahji-and-sambhaji-the-brother-of-shivaji-iv/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sambhaji and Shivaji break free&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Following Shahji’s arrest his sons Sambhaji in Banglore and Shivaji in&#xA;Pune started asserting their independence against the Moslems. With the&#xA;help of the Brahmin advisers they started acting as independent&#xA;*Hindu* rulers and did not remit any tributes to the Adil Shah. The&#xA;Sultan acted quickly and sent a force under Asad Khan from Jinji to take&#xA;Bangalore from Sambhaji. Sambhaji gave a notable display of his valor by&#xA;routing the Moslem force advancing towards Banglore by after&#xA;intercepting it on the way to the city. Shivaji was in the mean time&#xA;attacked in both Purandar and Kondana by two columns of the Sultan’s&#xA;army, but he too gave an ample taste of his valor by defeating both the&#xA;Moslem armies. The action by Shahji’s sons and their ability to punish&#xA;the Moslem armies both in North and South made the Sultan wary of any&#xA;action on Shahji. In the meantime the brothers tried an unusual&#xA;political move by contacting a representative of the Mogol emperor to&#xA;negotiate with the Sultan for their father’s safety and possible release&#xA;from captivity. Ahmad Khan the Moslem commandant agreed to negotiate his&#xA;safe release provided his sons surrendered Kondana and Banglore. Shahji&#xA;agreed to such a deal and was released. His sons on the surface agreed&#xA;to do so but secretly harbored plans to seize back their territory from&#xA;the Moslems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some notes on Shahji and Sambhaji the brother of Shivaji-II</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-06_some-notes-on-shahji-and-sambhaji-the-brother-of-shivaji-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-06_some-notes-on-shahji-and-sambhaji-the-brother-of-shivaji-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/07/06/some-notes-on-shahji-and-sambhaji-the-brother-of-shivaji-ii/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Randulla Khan’s invasion of the South&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Muhammad who succeeded Ibrahim, as the Adil Shahi Sultan was a fanatic&#xA;Jihadi who wanted to put the Hindus in their place and bring the whole&#xA;of South India under the cresent banner. Muhammad gathered under his ace&#xA;commander Randulla Khan several vigorous green holy warriors of the&#xA;cresent who shared his vision – Mustafa Khan, Afzal Khan and Asad Khan&#xA;were the chief of these. There was also the African warrior Siddi Jawhar&#xA;fighting on their side. The Adil Shah ordered Randulla Khan to lead&#xA;these forces into the Vijayanagaran territory and systematically attack&#xA;Darwar, Lakshmeshvar, Penukonda, Vellore, Chandragiri, Shira, Ikkeri and&#xA;Jinji and plunder the cities and destroy Hindu temples situated there.&#xA;The renegade brahmin Murar Jagdev tried to negotiate with regards to the&#xA;Hindus with the Sultan. He was murdered by Pathans sent by Mustafa Khan&#xA;at night. Shahji who was forced to surrender after being starved in the&#xA;siege of Mahuli, was asked to accompany the invasionary force with his&#xA;surviving troops. The Moslem plan was simple but the utter strategic&#xA;failure of the Vijayanagaran Nayakas and their armies allowed the Army&#xA;of Islam to execute it. Every invasion they would leave immediately&#xA;after monsoons and return just before the next monsoons to Bijapur.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some notes on Shahji and Sambhaji the brother of Shivaji-III</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-06_some-notes-on-shahji-and-sambhaji-the-brother-of-shivaji-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-06_some-notes-on-shahji-and-sambhaji-the-brother-of-shivaji-iii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/07/06/some-notes-on-shahji-and-sambhaji-the-brother-of-shivaji-iii/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mustafa Khan’s invasions&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Shah Jahan called on Adil Shah and Qutb Shah to destroy the Hindus of&#xA;the South and bring the whole of Hind under Islam. First, Mustafa Khan&#xA;attacked the Vijayanagaran army lead by the Nayaka Shivappa who had&#xA;liberated Ikkeri (1645). The Hindus fought with great fury and inflicted&#xA;severe losses on the Moslems in the battle of Sagar. But Mustafa Khan&#xA;who greatly hated the Hindus was strengthened by reserves and he fell&#xA;back on Shivappa Nayaka, routing him in the second battle of Ikkeri. But&#xA;Shriranga III began his counter-operations right away and captured&#xA;Vellore. The Moslems were alarmed and the Qutb Shah and Adil Shah made a&#xA;common cause and dispatched a large army of Jihad against Shriranga.&#xA;Shahji refused to join this army eventhough he was asked to. At that&#xA;time his young son Shivaji in Maharashtra instead started making&#xA;preparations to take a critical fort of Kondana near Pune from the&#xA;Moslems. His other son Sambhaji started secret negotiations with Hindu&#xA;Palegars to look upto Shahji and not side the Moslem invasionary force.&#xA;Mustafa Khan struck rapidly and captured Vellore. But as soon as Mustafa&#xA;Khan returned to Bijapur, Shahji and Sambhaji secretly provided&#xA;intelligence and help to Shriranga and he was able to defeat the Moslems&#xA;and recapture Vellore. Furious, the Sultan sent Mustafa Khan along with&#xA;Afzal Khan and Asad Khan to destroy Shiranga. Shahji was ordered to help&#xA;the invasion and threatened with arrest if he sided with the Hindus.&#xA;Shriranga contacted Shahji and asked him to open negotiations for peace&#xA;with Mustafa. Shahji duely did so and was trying to buy time for the&#xA;Vijayanagarans, when Shriranga thought he might succeed by launching a&#xA;preemptive strike on the Moslems. However, he was mistaken– while&#xA;outwardly the Moslems seemed to be negotiating peace as per Shahji’s&#xA;moves, they were themselves preparing to strike. So Shriranga’s element&#xA;of surprise was completely blown off and the Moslems slaughtered his&#xA;forces in the battle and seized Vellore. However, Shahji helped him&#xA;escape with life. While the Adil Shahi army was tied with Shriranga,&#xA;Shahji’s son Shivaji captured the Kondana fort from the Moslems, while&#xA;his elder son Sambhaji quite deposed a Moslem palegar in the Raichur&#xA;Doab and was bringing territory under his control in contrivance with&#xA;the local Hindu population.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some notes on Shahji and Sambhaji the brother of Shivaji-I</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-05_some-notes-on-shahji-and-sambhaji-the-brother-of-shivaji-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-05_some-notes-on-shahji-and-sambhaji-the-brother-of-shivaji-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/07/05/some-notes-on-shahji-and-sambhaji-the-brother-of-shivaji-i/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my childhood I was quite disappointed with our history books not&#xA;providing any details what so ever, beyond even the merest mention,&#xA;about the life and role of Sambhaji the brother of the founder of the&#xA;Maharatta nation. So for long I wished to write a brief history&#xA;Sambhaji, the brother of Shivaji, his contributions to the Hindu&#xA;struggle and his early death on the battlefield. What ever we know of&#xA;his struggle is mainly from Sanskrit chronicles like those of Paramanand&#xA;and Jayaram Pandit (Maharatta Brahmin historians and contemporaries),&#xA;supplemented by bakars and Farmans of the Mohammedans. The core of the&#xA;narrative here of course follows Paramanand and Jayaram’s efforts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shambhaji’s inaugural campaign</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-10-22_shambhajis-inaugural-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-10-22_shambhajis-inaugural-campaign/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/10/22/shambhajis-inaugural-campaign/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After Shambhaji had crowned himself Chatrapati, in Oct 1680 on the Vijaya Dashmi day decided to inaugurate his campaigns with strike against the Mogols. He set off with 3 divisions of the Maharatta cavalry:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One division moved to attack the Mogol garrison at Surat via the parallel to coast northwards along the Konkans.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The second division of Maharatta horse invaded Khandesh to strike a Mogol outpost there.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Simultaneously a 3rd division moved to attempt a liberation of the Mogol outpost of Aurangabad in Maharashtra.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Awrangzeeb dispatched Khan-i-Jahan Bahadhur Khan with the central Mogol army to counter the Maharastras. Shambhaji led his division as though to attack Berar and then suddenly swerved and attacked Burhanpur in Khandesh through a very rapid forced march. The Maharattas destroyed the Mogol garrisons and captured the vasty booty of the Mogol camps in Burhanpur and Hasanpur. The Maharattas demolished the Masjids and in both the places and put the terrible Mussalmans invaders to sword.+++(5)+++ Khan-i-Jahan tried to retrieve the cities but he was beaten by the Maharatta army and they fell back to defend from the fort of Salhir.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The end of Sambhaji</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-06-13_the-end-of-sambhaji/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-06-13_the-end-of-sambhaji/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/06/13/the-end-of-sambhaji/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After the death of &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/06/02/the-death-of-hambirrao/&#34;&gt;Hambirrao&#xA;Mohite&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;the Mogol armies pressed hard on the Maharattas forcing them to the&#xA;strongest fortresses in Sahayadris for shelter. Awrangzeeb’s army was&#xA;struck by bubonic plague, but he continued moving his vast divisions&#xA;westwards to encircle the Maharattas. He also sent a division towards&#xA;Bangalore and Tamil Nad to cut out the southern base of the Marathas.&#xA;Sambhaji, without his ace general was entirely in the control of his&#xA;base Kanyakubja Brahmin minister Kalash. As long as Raigad remained in&#xA;the Maharatta hands it could offer a formidbable bulwark against the&#xA;Mogols from where Sambhaji could continue the legacy of his great&#xA;father. But Kalash, who was given to pleasures wanted to spend the&#xA;summer of 1688 in the bracing climate of the Konkan forests. So he had a&#xA;residence of the Sardesais of Samgameshvar converted into a palace for&#xA;his vacation and suggested to Sambhaji that he too take it easy and&#xA;vacation with him. Sambhaji ever-willing to pleasure himself, accepted&#xA;the plan and told his generals that the forests surrounding Samgameshvar&#xA;were sufficient for his defense. Sambhaji spent the summer and monsoons&#xA;of 1688 in an orgy of women, wine and drugs. Luckily for him the weather&#xA;had staved off any further Mogol advance and no major damage would have&#xA;been done had he returned to Raigad after that to take charge of&#xA;matters. However, Kalash brought him a new woman and he was lost in&#xA;writing erotic verse in Hindi as he gamboled with her in his sylvan&#xA;retreat. Soon thereafter he saw a beautiful Maharatta woman was on her&#xA;way to join her husband. Kalash informed him of her presence and he&#xA;moved by lust raped her. This raised a huge storm and he decided to hide&#xA;in Samgeshvar for some more time till the noise died down.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The death of Hambirrao</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-06-02_the-death-of-hambirrao/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-06-02_the-death-of-hambirrao/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/06/02/the-death-of-hambirrao/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By 1687 the Mogol tyrant from Dilli, had fulfilled the dream cherished&#xA;by his ancestors since the days of the tyrant Akbar, namely to conquest&#xA;of the Deccan Sultanates. In a whirl wind campaign Awrangzeeb had&#xA;conquered the Adil Shahi kingdom, founded by the prince Adil Khan the&#xA;brother of the Ottoman sultan Mehmet II Fathi of Turkey and the Qutb&#xA;Shahi kingdom which was bravely defended to the very end by the Turk,&#xA;Abdur Razzak. Awrangzeeb had accused the two Islamic principalities of&#xA;being to lenient with the infidels and not prosecuting Jihad with&#xA;sufficient vigor. Now only his arch enemy the Maratha kingdom remained&#xA;independent in the Deccan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sant Ramadas’ letter to Sambhaji</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-05-23_sant-ramadas-letter-to-sambhaji/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-05-23_sant-ramadas-letter-to-sambhaji/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/05/23/sant-ramadas-letter-to-sambhaji/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Sambhaji seized power he invited his father’s advisor the bhakti&#xA;saint Ramadas to meet him. However, Ramadas displeased by Sambhaji’s&#xA;brutalities that accompanied his accession refused to meet him. His&#xA;disciples however begged on him to advice the prince. Accordingly he&#xA;sent him the following letter:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Always be on guard and never lower you guard. Control your temper and&#xA;be good and kind towards others. Forgive your subjects for their faults&#xA;and bind them to your person by making them happy. The happier they are,&#xA;easier would be your task. If they are against you, your task would be&#xA;hard. If you and your generals break apart your enemies will profit. Let&#xA;all of you live in unity. Seek out your Mohammedan enemies and remove&#xA;them from your path. Create fear in other not by your cruelty but by&#xA;your valor. Otherwise, your State will be in danger. Deal with each&#xA;difficulty as it arises. Keep your anger under control or at least do&#xA;not betray it in the presence of others. Make your subjects your&#xA;friends. Let them love rather than fear you. &lt;strong&gt;Make the people one; fill&#xA;their minds with the single thought of resisting the Mleccha enemy.&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;Guard what you already have, add to it by your own exertions and so&#xA;extended the Maharatta kingdom. Be dignified and wear the sword of&#xA;ambition. That way lies the path to success. Bear Shivaji Raje in mind.&#xA;Consider yourself a mere trifle and place your self in the quest for&#xA;fame in this world and there after. Keep the model of Shivaji before&#xA;your eyes and think of his valor and deeds. Remember always what he did&#xA;in battle and how he acted towards his friends. Give up sloth and love&#xA;of ease. Keep before you a certain goal and try to reach it. Never&#xA;forget how Shivaji won Svarajya. If you call yourself a man , try and do&#xA;better than he did.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netaji Palkar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2003-08-15_netaji-palkar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/articles/MT_lekhAH/2003-08-15_netaji-palkar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/08/15/netaji-palkar/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1667, the great Maharatta general Netaji was arrested by the lowly Hindu traitor Mirza Raje Jaisingh under the orders of the Padishah Awrangzeb and placed in the custody of the Qazi of Delhi. The Maharatta was give given three days to chose between the options of losing his head or his foreskin. Netaji decided to forego the latter and was duely made Muhammad Quli. His wife and children were also captured and converted to the fold of Allah. He was then sent to Afghanistan to quell the rebellions of the Afghans and battle the Iranians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
