<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;07 The Oligarchic Reaction 77-60 B C on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/07_The_Oligarchic_Reaction_77-60_B_C/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;07 The Oligarchic Reaction 77-60 B C on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/07_The_Oligarchic_Reaction_77-60_B_C/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 THE GOVERNMENT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/07_The_Oligarchic_Reaction_77-60_B_C/01_THE_GOVERNMENT/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/07_The_Oligarchic_Reaction_77-60_B_C/01_THE_GOVERNMENT/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NEVERTHELESS, Sulla had erred twice on the side of generosity. He had spared the son and nephew of his enemies, the gay and brilliant Caius Julius Caesar, who was entering his twenties in the proscription years; Sulla had nominated him for death, but let him go on the importuning of their common friends; his judgment, however, was not mistaken when he remarked, “In that young man go many Mariuses.”1 And perhaps he erred in resigning too soon and enjoying himself to an early end. Had his patience and insight equaled his ruthlessness and courage, he might have saved Rome a half century of chaos and given her in 80 B.C.. the peace and security, order and prosperity, that Augustus would bring back from Actium. He restored the old when he should have created the new.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 THE MILLIONAIRES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/07_The_Oligarchic_Reaction_77-60_B_C/02_THE_MILLIONAIRES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/07_The_Oligarchic_Reaction_77-60_B_C/02_THE_MILLIONAIRES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The business classes reconciled themselves to the rule of the Senate because they were better prepared than the aristocracy to exploit the provinces. That “concord of the orders,” or co-operation of the two upper classes, which Cicero was to preach as an ideal, was already a reality in his youth; they had agreed to unite and conquer. Businessmen and their aggressive agents crowded the basilicas and streets of Rome and swarmed into provincial markets and capitals. Bankers issued letters of exchange on their provincial affiliates,13 and lent money for everything, even political careers. Merchants and financiers swung their influence to the &lt;em&gt;populares&lt;/em&gt; when the Senate proved selfish, and back to the &lt;em&gt;optimates&lt;/em&gt; when democratic leaders tried to keep their pre-election promises to the proletariat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 THE NEW WOMAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/07_The_Oligarchic_Reaction_77-60_B_C/03_THE_NEW_WOMAN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/07_The_Oligarchic_Reaction_77-60_B_C/03_THE_NEW_WOMAN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The increase of wealth conspired with the corruption of politics to loosen morals and the marriage bond. Despite increasing competition from women and men, prostitution continued to flourish; brothels and the taverns that usually housed them were so popular that some politicians organized votes through the &lt;em&gt;collegium lupanariorum,&lt;/em&gt; or guild of brothelkeepers.25 Adultery was so common as to attract little attention unless played up for political purposes, and practically every well-to-do woman had at least one divorce. This was not the fault of women; it resulted largely from the subordination of marriage, in the upper classes, to money and politics. Men chose wives, or youths had wives chosen for them, to get a rich dowry or make advantageous connections. Sulla and Pompey married five times. Seeking to attach Pompey to him, Sulla persuaded him to put away his first wife and marry Aemilia, Sulla’s stepdaughter, who was already married and with child; Aemilia reluctantly agreed, but died in childbirth shortly after entering Pompey’s house. Caesar gave his daughter Julia to Pompey in marriage as an item in their triumviral alliance. The Empire, growled Cato, had become a matrimonial agency.25a Such unions were &lt;em&gt;mariages de politique;&lt;/em&gt; as soon as their utility ended, the husband looked for another wife as a steppingstone to higher place or greater wealth. He did not need to give a reason; he merely sent his wife a letter announcing her freedom and his. Some men did not marry at all, alleging distaste for the forwardness and extravagance of the new woman; many lived in free unions with concubines or slaves. The censor Metellus Macedonicus (131) had begged men to marry and beget children as a duty to the state, however much of a nuisance &lt;em&gt;{molestia)&lt;/em&gt; a wife might be;26 but the number of celibates and childless couples increased more rapidly after he spoke. Children were now luxuries which only the poor could afford.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 ANOTHER CATO</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/07_The_Oligarchic_Reaction_77-60_B_C/04_ANOTHER_CATO/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/07_The_Oligarchic_Reaction_77-60_B_C/04_ANOTHER_CATO/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amid all this corruption and laxity one man stood out as an exemplar and professor of the ancient ways. Marcus Porcius Cato the Younger had violated a precept of his great-great-grandfather by studying Greek; from it he derived that Stoic philosophy which shared with his republican convictions the inflexible devotion of his life. He inherited 120 talents ($432,000), but lived in sedulous simplicity. He lent money, but took no interest. He lacked his ancestor’s rough humor, and frightened people by what seemed to them his obstinate incorruptibility and his untimely addiction to principles. His life was an unforgivable indictment of theirs; they wished he would sin a little, if only out of a decent respect for the habits of mankind. They must have rejoiced when, with an almost Cynical conception of woman as a biological instrument, he “lent” his wife Marcia to his friend Hortensius—i.e., divorced her and assisted at her marriage to the orator—and later, when Hortensius died, took her again to wife.28 He could not be popular, for he was the relentless enemy of all dishonesty, the stern defender of the &lt;em&gt;patria potestas,&lt;/em&gt; a more merciless &lt;em&gt;censor moralium&lt;/em&gt; than Cato Censor himself. He seldom laughed or smiled, made no effort to be affable, and sharply reprimanded any who dared to flatter him. He was defeated for the consulship, said Cicero, because he acted like a citizen in Plato’s republic instead of a Roman living among “the dregs of Romulus’ posterity.”29&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 SPARTACUS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/07_The_Oligarchic_Reaction_77-60_B_C/05_SPARTACUS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/07_The_Oligarchic_Reaction_77-60_B_C/05_SPARTACUS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Misgovernment now reached a height, and democracy a depth, rare in the history of states. In 98 B.C.. the Roman general Didius repeated the exploit of Sulpicius Galba: he lured a whole tribe of troublesome natives into a Roman camp in Spain by pretending to register them for a distribution of land; when they had entered, with their wives and children, he had them all slaughtered. On his return to Rome he was awarded a public triumph.30 Shocked by the brutalities of empire, a Sabine officer in the Roman army, Quintus Sertorius, went over to the Spaniards, organized and drilled them, and led them to victory after victory over the legions sent to subdue him. For eight years (80-72) he ruled a rebel kingdom, winning the affection of the people by his just administration and by his establishment of schools for the education of native youth. Metellus, the Roman general, offered a hundred talents ($360,000) and 20,000 acres of land to any Roman who should kill him. Perpenna, a Roman refugee in Sertorius’ camp, invited him to dinner, assassinated him, and made himself master of the army that Sertorius had trained. Pompey was sent against Perpenna and easily defeated him; Perpenna was executed, and the exploitation of Spain was resumed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 POMPEY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/07_The_Oligarchic_Reaction_77-60_B_C/06_POMPEY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/07_The_Oligarchic_Reaction_77-60_B_C/06_POMPEY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Crassus and Pompey returned from this campaign they did not, as the Senate wished and law required, disband or disarm their troops at the gates. Camping outside the walls, they asked permission to stand for the consulate without entering the city—again a violation of precedent; in addition Pompey demanded land for his soldiers and a triumph for himself. The Senate refused, hoping to play one general against the other. But Crassus and Pompey joined hands, made a sudden alliance with the &lt;em&gt;populares&lt;/em&gt; and the business class, and by generous bribery won election as consuls for 70 B.C. The magnates entered the partnership for two immediate ends: to recapture power in the juries that tried them, and to replace Lucullus—who had ruled the Roman East with unprofitable integrity—by a man of their own class and views. In Pompey they recognized their man.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 CICERO AND CATILINE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/07_The_Oligarchic_Reaction_77-60_B_C/07_CICERO_AND_CATILINE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/07_The_Oligarchic_Reaction_77-60_B_C/07_CICERO_AND_CATILINE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Plutarch thought that Marcus Tullius was called Cicero because of a wart, shaped like a vetch (&lt;em&gt;cicer),&lt;/em&gt; on an ancestor’s nose; more probably his forebears had earned the cognomen by raising renowned crops of chick-peas. In his &lt;em&gt;Laws&lt;/em&gt; Cicero describes with engaging tenderness the modest villa that had seen his birth near Arpinum, halfway between Rome and Naples, in the foothills of the Apennines. His father was just rich enough to give his son the best education that the age could provide. He engaged the Greek poet Archias to tutor Marcus in literature and Greek and then sent the youth to study law with Q. Mucius Scaevola, the greatest jurist of his time. Cicero listened eagerly to the trials and debates in the Forum, and rapidly learned the arts and tricks of forensic speech. “To succeed in the law,” he said, “a man must renounce all pleasures, avoid all amusements, say farewell to recreation, games, entertainment, almost to intercourse with his friends.”36&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
