<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;rAthoDa on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/rAShTraka/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;rAthoDa on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/rAShTraka/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ajit Singh of Marwar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/rAShTraka/Ajit_Singh_of_Marwar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/rAShTraka/Ajit_Singh_of_Marwar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ruler of Jodhpur, whom durgAdAsa brought to power, who restored temples destroyed by Awrangzeb, took back the daughter he had given to the moghul.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;jaya-simha 2 &amp;ldquo;Sawai&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jai_Singh_II#Sawai_Jai_Singh_and_the_Marathas&#34;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;] of amber&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;raised to serve mogol emperors but later took wings,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;who like akaNNa and madaNNa conspired with the marATha-s to reduce Islamic power.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;tried in vain to constrain jaT and marATha rise with a partial rAjaputra alliance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;whose force of 50,000 soldiers who were all well-educated, was the most modern army in the whole of India&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;brought a stop to extravagantly lavish weddings, female infanticide, etc. through strict orders&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;who built jantar mantar, patronized scholarship and even conducted an ashvamedha.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;removed the jizya tax that was levied on tirthayatras and at tirthakshetras forever (When Bahadur Shah offered him a reward of two crores, he declined it and instead asked for an order for a permanent removal of the tax!)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;had rest houses and Dharmashalas built at Mathura, Brindavan, Kashi, Gaya, Pune, Kabul, Lahore, Agra, Delhi, Chitrakoot, Ayodhya, Haridwar, Ujjain, and other sacred spots&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;had Euclid&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Elements of Geometry&amp;rdquo; translated into Sanskrit as also several works on trigonometry, and Napier&amp;rsquo;s work on the construction and use of logarithms&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;at some point he ceased issuing bilingual, i.e., Rajasthani and Persian, deeds and by 1712 was using only a form of Dhundari, the local dialect of Rajasthani, for such documents (Horstmann 1999a, 49).&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;He had also stopped using the Persian calendar, using instead the Vikram dating system.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;In 1716, he ceased paying tribute to the emperor on his official seal, a tradition that went back many generations, and began to pay tribute to his own father, Bishan Singh. Later, in 1727, the seal was dedicated to the deity Sri Sitaramji.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;On a more personal note, he refrained from formally or publicly using the&#xA;title “Mirza Raja&amp;rdquo;, which had been conferred in 1712 by both Jahandar Shah and&#xA;Farrukhsiyar. Perhaps he simply preferred the title “Sawai”&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>chandrasena</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/rAShTraka/chandrasenaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/rAShTraka/chandrasenaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This lord of Marwar, refused to have any form of alliance with the Mughals and he defended his kingdom for nearly two decades against relentless attacks from the Mughals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Born on 30 July 1541, Chandrasen was the son of Rao Maldeo, Raja of Marwar and Rani Swarup Deviji, daughter of Jhalo Jaito Sajivat. He was also the younger and only full-brother of Udai Singh, his successor. Rao Chandrasen Rathore became the Raja of Jodhpur at the age of 21 (1562). His father Maldeo named him as his successor, putting aside the claims of his older brothers, Ram and Udai Singh. This led to an eternal rivalry between Chandrasen and Udai Singh. In 1562, Ramchandra, Udai Singh and Raimal rebelled at Sojat, Gagani and Dunda respectively. Chandrasen then fought Ramchandra at Nadol in 1563 and when Ramchandra saw no chance of his success, he fled to Nagore. The initial six years of his exile seems to be the hardest and he was forced to sell his family&amp;rsquo;s heirlooms in order to continue his struggle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>durgAdAsa rAthoDa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/rAShTraka/durgAdAsa_rAthoDa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/rAShTraka/durgAdAsa_rAthoDa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;steadfastly opposed Awrangzib and restored Marwar to Ajita simha [&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Durgadas_Rathore&#34;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;]. Awrangzeb had tried to convert the infant to Islam. &amp;ldquo;The brave durgAdAs rAthoD spirited the infant away from the Mohammedans and raised a rebellion against the Mogols by helping Akbar rise against his father Awrangzeb. Then durgAdAs and Akbar were given shelter by shaMbAjI as they were pursued by the Mogols.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Referred to in &lt;a href=&#34;../docs/sambhAji-letter/&#34;&gt;sambhAji&amp;rsquo;s letter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;he had personally met sambhAji to hand over the custody of the rebellious son of awrangzib&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;kept a Moghal princess, a grand-daughter of awrangzib, in a respectful detention in mAravADa until awrangzib himself begged for the demand of whatever ransom and terms of release&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jasvant singh</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/rAShTraka/jasvant-singh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/rAShTraka/jasvant-singh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maharaja Jaswant Singh and a 10,000 strong force under him were just across the road, but they did not move a muscle to protect Awrangzib’s uncle Shaista Khan as Shivaji mauled him, nor did he order a chase as Marathas retreated. Mughals strongly suspected Rathors of complicity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;tavArikh i muhammad shahi says that when Awrangzib heard of Maharaja Jaswant Singh’s demise in distant Kabul, he instantly broke out in jubilation and uttered: “darwaza-e-kufr shikast! shikast!” - door that saved Kafirs, fall! Same year Jazia was imposed all over the empire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mAn-singh-rAthod</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/rAShTraka/mAn-singh-rAthoD/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/rAShTraka/mAn-singh-rAthoD/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was once made a desperate attempt by a visionary Rajput youngster Man Singh Rathod of Jodhpur to forge a rajput-jat-holkar-sikh-gorkha alliance against the British. He voluntarily sent his marwad army (and a fighting Naga band) to join the Holkar-Jat alliance fighting under Yaswantrav Holkar at Bharatpur. The Holkar family was brought safely to his Jodhpur palace where they spent a year despite all the British pressure on Man Singh to hand them over to the Brits. At this time he also sent secret letters to the other Maratha chiefs to forget the mutual rivalry in joining their forces again. It is to this effect that he also brought the deposed Bhosla king from Nagpur to Jodhpur, where he died after living there some years. The Rathod prince also wrote secret letters to the Gorkhas (who were his Gurubhai-s, he himself being a nath-yogi of the western Goraksha tradition like the Gorkhali king) and Maharaja Ranjit Singh at Lahore to abandon their mutual struggles and join hand for a larger alliance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rai Jaimal</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/rAShTraka/jaimal_rAShTraka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/rAShTraka/jaimal_rAShTraka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rai Jaimal was the brother of the bhakti poetess Mirabai and&#xA;was entrusted the defence of Chittor when it was assaulted by the army&#xA;of Islam, led by Akbar. Jaimal was a victor of many battles is well&#xA;remembered as the hero of Badnor who placed a wall of steel against the&#xA;advance of the Mogols and other Moslem marauders like the Turkic clans&#xA;of Afghanistan that were lashing against the land. Given his victorious&#xA;track record he was entrusted the defence of Chittor along with the&#xA;relative of the Rana Udaisingh, the chief of Salumbar. His son was the&#xA;16 year old Udayabhanu Pratap (Patta) who, along with his young bride&#xA;died fighting the Mogols.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thakur Kushal Singh Rathore</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/rAShTraka/Thakur_Kushal_Singh_Rathore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/rAShTraka/Thakur_Kushal_Singh_Rathore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;who, with some 5,000 Rajputs of Auwa rose up in arms against the British. Defeated and killed Captain Mason who came from jodhpur. Was defeated by 30,000 troops from the British governor general for Rajputana. Escaped and surrendered in 1860. Exiled to Udaipur, where he died a broken man.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
