<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/sumerian/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/sumerian/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fall to xerxes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/sumerian/articles/fall_to_xerxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/sumerian/articles/fall_to_xerxes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.livius.org/articles/person/bel-simanni-and-samas-eriba/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bêl-šimânni and Šamaš-eriba&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bêl-šimânni and Šamaš-eriba: name of two Babylonian rebel kings who rose against his Persian overlord Xerxes in the summer 484 BCE.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Daiva inscription&amp;rdquo; (XPh)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reconstruction of the brief reigns of Bêl-šimânni and Šamaš-eriba is not unlike a puzzle.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Scholars have adduced many pieces of evidence,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;but it is plausible that not every item is really connected to the insurrection:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Contemporary documents in Babylonian archives dating to the reigns of Bêl-šimânni and Šamaš-eriba;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The division of the large satrapy of Babylonia, early in the reign of the Achaemenid king Xerxes, into two parts, which were more or less identical to Iraq and modern Syria/Israel;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &amp;ldquo;daiva inscription&amp;rdquo; of Xerxes, which records the suppression of a religious revolt somewhere in the empire;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A remark by the Greek researcher Herodotus of Halicarnassus, writing about a generation after the events, that the Achaemenid king Xerxes captured Babylon and took away a statue from the main temple, the Esagila;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A remark by the notoriously unreliable Greek historian Ctesias that there were two rebellions on two occasions; the first of these was repressed by a nobleman named Megabyzus, the second needed personal intervention by the king;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A remark by Arrian of Nicomedia, a Roman author using fourth-century BCE sources, who states that Xerxes subdued a Babylonian revolt when he was on his way back from Greece (479). According to Arrian, Xerxes punished the city by closing the Esagila +++(=marduk temple)+++.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best way to approach the problem is the study of the Babylonian archives, which are contemporary with the events. In the figure below, the dates and sites of the four tablets of Bêl-šimânni and the thirteen tablets of Šamaš-eriba are shown. All tablets are dated to the accession year of these kings and belong, therefore, to the same period of three months in the late summer of an unknown year after 12 April 485, because one of the tablets refers to a payment on this date.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On martus (westerners)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/sumerian/articles/on_martus_westerners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/sumerian/articles/on_martus_westerners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/GraniRau/status/1892437174525509784&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Listen, the Martus, their hands are destructive and their features are those of monkeys; he is one who eats what Nanna forbids and does not show reverence. They never stop roaming about &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;, they are an abomination to the gods&amp;rsquo; dwellings. Their ideas are confused; they cause only disturbance. He is clothed in sack-leather &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;, lives in a tent, exposed to wind and rain, and cannot properly recite prayers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
