<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Labor on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/labor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Labor on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/labor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>01 Hiring in businesses</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/labor/01_Hiring_in_businesses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/labor/01_Hiring_in_businesses/</guid>
      <description>Academic hiring follows a different pattern.
Selectivity Hiring people is generally easier than getting rid of them. So, when possible, businesses create interview processes which have low ’false positive’ rates - even at the cost of high ’false negative’ rates.
Process Often, specialized recruiters are used to make initial contacts with people - in order to get an idea of where how the candidate may fit the company’s needs. That person then may pitch the candidate to potential hirers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Motivating employees</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/labor/02_Motivating_employees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/labor/02_Motivating_employees/</guid>
      <description>Motivating a hired employee to do his job involves ensuring that his pleasure/ satisfaction (perhaps even pain) coincides with benefits and loss of the company.
The best case is when the employee, by nature, cares deeply about doing his job well - which is why good hiring is important.
Another alternative is to do this using rewards and threats. Research shows that for menial/ mechanical tasks, this works; but for creative work, this approach is counter-productive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 Variation parameters</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/labor/03_Variation_parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/labor/03_Variation_parameters/</guid>
      <description>Employment term Employment may be short term or long term. Laws usually guarantee minimum daily wages.
Hire and fire pattern Some businesses treat employees like extended family. Won&amp;rsquo;t fire or lay off - prefer salary cuts and innovation. +++(5)+++
Mobility Contracts or laws may limit a worker’s mobility.
Indentured laborers have agreed to serve for a certain period of time under certain conditions in exchange for money/ transportation paid in advance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 Labor unions</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/labor/04_Labor_unions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/labor/04_Labor_unions/</guid>
      <description>Workers collectively have greater bargaining power while negotiating terms of employment (salary, benefits, leave, penalties) with their employer. To this end, they form trade unions.
Breakdown of negotiations When negotiations with employers break down, they go on strike - that is halt work without pay, thereby causing loss to the employers. Employers sometimes try to get around the problem by hiring new workers who will accept poorer conditions and work - which often leads to violence and damage, and hence is an unattractive option.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>