<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/tibeto-burman/tangut/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/tibeto-burman/tangut/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mongolica: The Tangut empire</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/tibeto-burman/tangut/articles/MT/2019-02-15_mongolica-the-tangut-empire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/tibeto-burman/tangut/articles/MT/2019-02-15_mongolica-the-tangut-empire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2019/02/15/mongolica-the-tangut-empire/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the early 1100s of the CE Rtsa-mi lotsawa Sangs-rgyas grags-pa was in Nālandā, India, to study and transmit the latest that the tāntrika strain of Bauddha-mata had to offer. Within a century both his world and that of his Indian hosts was to come crashing down. It was almost as if the prophetic section of the nāstika Kālacakra-tantram that he was there to study and take to his lands would play out unerringly as the yuga-cakra turned with the irruption of the demons of makkhaviṣaya and the mlecchendra-duṣṭa-s. Sometime close to the beginning of the 1200s a marauding band of Mohammedans led by the Moslem Turk Ghazi Ikhtiyar al-Din Muhammad Bakhtiyar Khalji razed to ground this famed mahāvihāra of Nālandā. Rtsa-mi lotsawa Sangs-rgyas grags-pa was a Tangut from their kingdom known as Xi Xia in inner Asia. In 1205 CE the Tanguts supported the fleeing rivals of Chingiz Khan and were subject to a swift punitive assault by the Mongols from the western corridor. The Mongols followed it up by further invasions in the Tangut territory in 1207-8, 1209-10 and 1215 CE, in each case punishing them, seizing bits of their kingdom and forcing them to vassalage. In 1217 CE the great Khan sent an emissary asking the Tangut kingdom to join the Mongols in the great assault on the Mohammedans of Khwarazm. The Tangut king arrogantly responded: “If you have no strength [to fight on your own] there is no reason to be a Khan.” The Tanguts were pay dearly for this: they became the target of the final campaign of Chingiz Khan. By 1227 CE the Mongols had &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2018/08/31/a-brief-overview-of-the-last-campaign-of-chingiz-khan-and-the-issue-of-succession-in-the-mongol-empire/&#34;&gt;erased the Tangut kingdom off the face of the earth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tangut-pAla-connection</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/tibeto-burman/tangut/articles/MT/tangut-pAla-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/tibeto-burman/tangut/articles/MT/tangut-pAla-connection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Several Tanguts received mantra-dIkSha from nAstika-mantravAdin-s from va~Nga. They also acquired the art of making pala-style images of deities direct from the pAla realm rather than an intermediary. This is how that tradition was in part transmitted to chIna. Some of their karmapas had been directly trained in the universities of the pAla empire.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(They in turn influenced Mongols and Chinas.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pala aesthetics had made their inroads into the Yuan court. We find the very famous Miaoying Temple built by the Nepali artist Anige, titled the Duke of Liang, in Qubilai’s court shares design with Pala ones &amp;amp; some Indian architecture treatises seem to be translated into Chinese. We also find the Han sktist Cheng Jufu writing that the Phagpa was was particularly interested in hiring Indian artists at Anige’s word bcos they were considered superior to those found in China. The demand was so great that the king of Nepal couldn’t keep up. Anige’s exceptional portraits of Qubilai &amp;amp; Chabi even influenced Ming-Qing aesthetics apart from the regular hold on Tibet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
