<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Austronesian on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Austronesian on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/indonesia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/indonesia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chinese-role&#34;&gt;Chinese role&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Anti chinese riots in may 1998, involving looting, burning, temple desecration, gang rapes, murders - &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/May_1998_riots_of_Indonesia&#34;&gt;WI&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=414&amp;amp;v=soB7rosSWWU&#34;&gt;YT&lt;/a&gt;; resulting in many Chinese fleeing the country, and some converting to Islam.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;karo-hindus&#34;&gt;kAro hindus&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Karo Hindu from Sumatra worshipping Shiva. What&amp;rsquo;s interesting about Karo Hindus is that they claim to be descended of ancient Tamil migrants (specifically the Kongu region), so their rituals are closer to Tamils than Javanese or Balinese (who are closer to Odias).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malagasy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/malagasy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/malagasy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;despite the island being close to Africa, the vocabulary of the Malagasy language largely originated from one that was spoken along the Barito River valley of southeast Borneo. Some 90% of Malagasy vocabulary is from the language of the Ma&amp;rsquo;anyan, an indigenous group of roughly 70,000 people who live in remote inland areas of southeastern Borneo. Less than 10% of the vocabulary of the Malagasy language is from African languages (mainly Sabaki, a branch of Bantu).&#xA;Archaeologists have also found cultural evidence — including ironworking techniques, outrigger boats, musical instruments such as the xylophone, and the cultivation of rice, bananas, yams and taro (a “tropical food kit”) — that supports a strong Southeast Asian connection.&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://theconversation.com/how-the-banjar-people-of-borneo-became-ancestors-of-the-malagasy-and-comorian-people-90476&#34;&gt;TC20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaysia</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/malaysia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/malaysia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;parameshvaras-conversion&#34;&gt;parameshvara&amp;rsquo;s conversion&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By this time, Muslims, settled centuries ago, had a significant presence in the port city of Malacca. Mainly merchants in profession, they were crucial for Malacca&amp;rsquo;s flourishing trade with India. Muslims, therefore, received welcome in Parameswara&amp;rsquo;s court and slowly increased their presence in his court and influence on his political fortune. Muslims were drafted into his army and he was becoming increasingly dependent on them to stave off attacks from Siam and Majapahit. About this time, the Muslim advisors of Parameswara offered to send in more Muslim soldiers to fight on his side, if he converted to Islam. Parameswara rejected the offer. As his struggle with his sworn enemies continued over the succeeding years, his position became increasingly precarious.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phillipines</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/phillipines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/phillipines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hindu-past&#34;&gt;Hindu past&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;kingdoms&#34;&gt;Kingdoms&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prior to its Christianization and Islamization, Philippines used to have quite many Indianized kingdoms. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/porbotialora/status/1181221723280035846&#34;&gt;PB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These included&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-Tondo&#xA;-Butuan&#xA;-Cebu&#xA;-Madyas&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Rajahante of Cebu was interesting because it was found by Sri Lumay who claimed Chola descent. When the Cholas invaded Sriwijaya, a branch of Cholas settled there are married native Malay wives. One of the princes went to Philippines to establish his own kingdom.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;culture&#34;&gt;Culture&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some places in Philippines still have names of Sanskrit etymology (eg: visaya-s, manila); local language - esp religious language borrows from deva dharma. Eg. daiwata.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
