<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/items/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/items/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>maisUr-pAk-history</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/items/articles/maisUr-pAk-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/items/articles/maisUr-pAk-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.rattibha.com/thread/1606852904064876544&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Magic of Besan, Ghee and Sugar in the realm of Kandois - Fascinating story of Mesur Pak and its journey to the palace of Mysore.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Time to time one comes across the twitter about the various claims of the origin of Mysore pak. One of the most well accepted claim attributes its origin in Mysore palace during the reign of Rajarshi Maharaja - Krishnaraja Wodeyar in the early 20th century. Here is the brief story of the &amp;ldquo;accidental&amp;rdquo; invention of Mysore pak by the chef of Maharaja as narrated by the acclaimed historian Vikram Sampath ji himself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Milk anemia &amp; malaria</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/items/articles/milk-anemia_malaria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/items/articles/milk-anemia_malaria/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1742006339520336364.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why do the Somali have such thin bodies and large foreheads? This physical type is often explained as an adaptation to desert heat, but occurs in no other desert population outside Africa. The real culprit is milk anemia, a disease common in pastoralists and, once, in Europeans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are other African peoples, all pastoralists, that share many aspects of the Somali “look”. The type goes by many names: Hamitic, Cushitic, Ethiopid. Because they are often tall, the Belgian anthropologist Jean Hiernaux categorized them as “Elongated African&amp;quot;. The “F”s on Hiernaux’s map stand for Fulani, another pastoralist people. The Fulani have a striking physical resemblance to East African herders; many I think, could pass as Somali. There is though no close genetic link between them, something Hiernaux guessed 60 years ago. Early European explorers were so impressed with the Fulani (and charmed by the good looks of their women) that they assumed they were either mostly Caucasian or related to East Africans. Neither is true: Fulani are 3/4th West African. The &amp;ldquo;Somali&amp;rdquo; type has evolved more than once. Maybe more than twice. In the hottest Saharan depths live the Tuareg, another pastoralist people. They are mostly North African by descent, but all the same Carleton Coon thought the closest physical comparison to be found was with the Somali. This keeps happening: Somalification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Veg norm</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/items/articles/veg-norm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/items/articles/veg-norm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;iran&#34;&gt;Iran&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Changing Diet of the Iranians – From Quasi-Vegetarians to Quasi-Carnivores&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Until the 20th century&amp;hellip; Bread was the major staple, accompanied by vegetables, fruits, yoghurt, and nuts. Meat and rice were a luxury food for most consumers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/OTI6UuLUz1&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1694 a traveller noted that the Persians were satisfied with a little cheese and sour milk and soaking some bread in it. Though he did also mention that they consumed some rice, though only cooked with water. Pilau (stew with rice) was for the comfortably-off.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
