<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;04 Stoic Rome 508-202 B C on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/1_THE_REPUBLIC_-_508-30_B_C/04_Stoic_Rome_508-202_B_C/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;04 Stoic Rome 508-202 B C on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/1_THE_REPUBLIC_-_508-30_B_C/04_Stoic_Rome_508-202_B_C/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 THE FAMILY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/1_THE_REPUBLIC_-_508-30_B_C/04_Stoic_Rome_508-202_B_C/01_THE_FAMILY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/1_THE_REPUBLIC_-_508-30_B_C/04_Stoic_Rome_508-202_B_C/01_THE_FAMILY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Birth itself was an adventure in Rome. If the child was deformed or female, the father was permitted by custom to expose it to death.1 Otherwise it was welcomed; for though the Romans even of this period practiced some measure of family limitation, they were eager to have sons. Rural life made children assets, public opinion condemned childlessness, and religion promoted fertility by persuading the Roman that if he left no son to tend his grave his spirit would suffer endless misery. After eight days the child was formally accepted into the family and the clan by a solemn ceremony at the domestic hearth. A clan &lt;em&gt;(gens)&lt;/em&gt; was a group of freeborn families tracing themselves to a common ancestor, bearing his name, united in a common worship, and bound to mutual aid in peace and war. The male child was designated by an individual first name &lt;em&gt;(praenomen)&lt;/em&gt;, such as Publius, Marcus, Caius; by his clan name &lt;em&gt;(nomen),&lt;/em&gt; such as Cornelius, Tullius, Julius; and by his family name &lt;em&gt;(cognomen),&lt;/em&gt; such as Scipio, Cicero, Caesar. Women were most often designated simply by the clan name-Cornelia, Tullia, Claudia, Julia. Since in classical days there were only some fifteen first names for males, and these tended to be repeated confusingly in many generations of the same family, they were usually reduced to an initial, and a fourth—or even a fifth—name was added for distinctiveness. So P. Cornelius Scipio Africanus Maior, the conqueror of Hannibal, was differentiated from P. Cornelius Scipio Aemilianus Africanus Minor, the destroyer of Carthage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 THE RELIGION OF ROME</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/1_THE_REPUBLIC_-_508-30_B_C/04_Stoic_Rome_508-202_B_C/02_THE_RELIGION_OF_ROME/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/1_THE_REPUBLIC_-_508-30_B_C/04_Stoic_Rome_508-202_B_C/02_THE_RELIGION_OF_ROME/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-the-gods&#34;&gt;1. The Gods&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Roman family was both an association of persons with things and an association of persons and things with gods. It was the center and source of religion, as well as of morals, economy, and the state; every part of its property and every aspect of its existence were bound up in a solemn intimacy with the spiritual world. The child was taught, by the eloquent silence of example, that the undying fire in the hearth was the sign and substance of the goddess Vesta, the sacred flame that symbolized the life and continuity of the family; which therefore must never be extinguished, but must be tended with “religious” care, and fed with a portion of each meal. Over the hearth he saw the little icons, crowned with flowers, that represented the gods or spirits of the family: the Lar that guarded its fields and buildings, its fortune and destiny, and the Penates, or gods of the interior, who protected the accumulations of the family in its storerooms, cupboards, and barns. Hovering invisible but potent over the threshold was the god Janus, two-faced not as deceitful but as watching all entry and exit at every door. The child’s father, he learned, was the ward and embodiment of an inner &lt;em&gt;genius,&lt;/em&gt; or generative power, which would not die with the body, but must be nourished forever at the paternal grave. His mother was also the carrier of a deity and had likewise to be treated as divine; she had a &lt;em&gt;Juno&lt;/em&gt; in her as the spirit of her capacity to bear, as the father enclosed a &lt;em&gt;genius&lt;/em&gt; as the spirit of his power to beget. The child too had his &lt;em&gt;genius&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Juno,&lt;/em&gt; as both his guardian angel and his soul—a godly kernel in the mortal husk. Everywhere about him, he heard with awe, were the watchful &lt;em&gt;Di Manes,&lt;/em&gt; or Kindly Shades, of those male forebears whose grim death masks hung on the household walls, warning him not to stray from the ways of his ancestors, and reminding him that the family was composed not merely of those few individuals that lived in his moment but also of those that had once been, or would someday be, members of it in the flesh, and therefore formed part of it in its spiritual multitude and timeless unity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 MORALS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/1_THE_REPUBLIC_-_508-30_B_C/04_Stoic_Rome_508-202_B_C/03_MORALS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/1_THE_REPUBLIC_-_508-30_B_C/04_Stoic_Rome_508-202_B_C/03_MORALS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What kind of morality emerged from this life in the family and among the gods? Roman literature, from Ennius to Juvenal, idealized these earlier generations and mourned the passing of ancient simplicity and virtue. These pages too will suggest a contrast between the stoic Rome of Fabius and the epicurean Rome of Nero. But the contrast must not be exaggerated by a biased selection of the evidence. There were epicureans in Fabius’ days and stoics in Nero’s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 LETTERS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/1_THE_REPUBLIC_-_508-30_B_C/04_Stoic_Rome_508-202_B_C/04_LETTERS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/1_THE_REPUBLIC_-_508-30_B_C/04_Stoic_Rome_508-202_B_C/04_LETTERS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Roman was formed not only by the family, the religion, and the moral code, but, in less degree, by the school, the language, and the literature. Plutarch dates the first Roman school about 250 B.C..; 38 but Livy, perhaps romancing, describes Virginia, the desired of the Decemvir, as “going to a grammar school in the Forum” as early as 450.39 The demand for written laws, and the publication of the Twelve Tables, suggest that by that date a majority of the citizens could read.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 THE GROWTH OF THE SOIL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/1_THE_REPUBLIC_-_508-30_B_C/04_Stoic_Rome_508-202_B_C/05_THE_GROWTH_OF_THE_SOIL/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/1_THE_REPUBLIC_-_508-30_B_C/04_Stoic_Rome_508-202_B_C/05_THE_GROWTH_OF_THE_SOIL/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Roman of those centuries had little need of medicine, for his active life in farming or soldiering kept him healthy and strong. He took to the land as the Greek to the sea; he based his life on the soil, built his towns as meeting places for farmers and their products, organized his armies and his state on his readiness to defend and extend his holdings, and conceived his gods as spirits of the living earth and the nourishing sky.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 INDUSTRY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/1_THE_REPUBLIC_-_508-30_B_C/04_Stoic_Rome_508-202_B_C/06_INDUSTRY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/1_THE_REPUBLIC_-_508-30_B_C/04_Stoic_Rome_508-202_B_C/06_INDUSTRY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The soil was poor in minerals—a fact that would write much economic and political history in Italy. There was no gold and little silver; there was a fair supply of iron, some copper, lead, tin, and zinc, but too scarce to support an industrial development. The state owned all mines in the empire, but leased them to private operators, who worked them profitably by using up the lives of thousands of slaves. Metallurgy and technology made few advances. Bronze was still employed more frequently than iron, and only the best and latest mines were equipped with the winches, windlasses, and chain buckets that Archimedes and others had set up in Sicily and Egypt. The chief fuel was wood; trees were cut also for houses and ships and furniture; mile by mile, decade by decade, the forest retreated up the mountainside to meet the timber line. The most prosperous industry was the manufacture of weapons and tools in Campania. There was no factory system, except for armament and pottery. Potters made not only dishes but bricks and tiles, conduits and pipes; at Arretium and elsewhere the potters were copying Greek models and learning to make artistic wares. As early as the sixth century the textile industry, in the design, preparation, and dyeing of linen and wool, had grown beyond the domestic stage despite the busy spinning of daughters, wives, and slaves; free and unfree weavers were brought together in small factories, which produced not only for the local market but also for export trade.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 THE CITY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/1_THE_REPUBLIC_-_508-30_B_C/04_Stoic_Rome_508-202_B_C/07_THE_CITY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/1_THE_REPUBLIC_-_508-30_B_C/04_Stoic_Rome_508-202_B_C/07_THE_CITY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Through taxes, spoils, indemnities, and inflowing population Rome was now (202 B.C.) one of the major cities of the Mediterranean ensemble. The census of 234 listed 270,713 citizens—i.e., free adult males; the figure fell sharply during the great war, but rose to 258,318 in 189, and 322,000 in 147. We may calculate a population of approximately 1,100,000 souls in the city-state in 189 B.C., of whom perhaps 275,000 lived within the walls of Rome. Italy south of the Rubicon had some 5,000,000 inhabitants.67 Immigration, the absorption of conquered peoples, the influx, emancipation, and enfranchisement of slaves, were already beginning the ethnic changes that by Nero’s time would make Rome the New York of antiquity, half native and half everything.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 POST MORTEM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/1_THE_REPUBLIC_-_508-30_B_C/04_Stoic_Rome_508-202_B_C/08_POST_MORTEM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/1_THE_REPUBLIC_-_508-30_B_C/04_Stoic_Rome_508-202_B_C/08_POST_MORTEM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;War was the most dramatic feature of a Roman’s life, but it did not play so absorbing a role as in the pages of Rome’s historians. Perhaps even more than with us his existence centered about his family and his home. News reached him when it was old, so that his passions could not be stirred every day by the gathered turmoil of the world. The great events of his career were not politics and war, but anxious births, festal marriages, and somber deaths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
