<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MOM on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/MOM/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MOM on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/MOM/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2017 guin article</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/MOM/2017-guin-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/MOM/2017-guin-article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Making memories: a time capsule project for all of mankind&#xA;April 26, 2017 by MediaHub&#xA;Story by Rebekah Dare Guin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Photos and video by Jenn Morrison and Emma Carl&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HALLSTATT, Austria — Deep in the Austrian Alps sits the beginnings of an international treasure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a long and dangerous climb up the mountainside, or a lift ride for those without any treasure hunting experience, the entrance of a historic salt mine awaits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kunze - MOM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/MOM/kunze_mom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/MOM/kunze_mom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Image above] An example of the ceramic tokens that will contain a map to the Memory of Mankind archive. Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.memory-of-mankind.com/how-can-mom-ever-be-discovered-in-the-future/&#34;&gt;Memory of Mankind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By Laurel Sheppard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’ve all heard of time capsules, where artifacts from the current era are placed in a container and buried for someone to find years later. In fact, such a time capsule, buried for 118 years, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.whio.com/news/local/118-year-old-time-capsule-found-ohio-fire-station/Q7VUM5VOC5AIZJJHBZXWBG5BUA/&#34;&gt;was recently found in an Ohio fire station&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once hundreds or thousands of years have passed, however, the chances that the artifacts survived become less and less likely. That is because materials, no matter how well preserved, will eventually degrade. However, different materials degrade on vastly different timescales, which is why there are many examples of thousands-year-old pottery pieces but few examples of thousands-year-old animal skins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memory of mankind</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/MOM/memory-of-mankind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/MOM/memory-of-mankind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.memory-of-mankind.com/how-is-information-kept-legible-for-1-million-years/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The digital age carries with it the risk that records will either become swiftly illegible or completely vanish. (admittedly for 99% of the internet’s contents this is presumably not a great loss… ) Nevertheless, there is information that we are morally obliged to pass on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MOM developed ceramic data carriers which conserves analogue text and images for unlimited intervals of time. Deep within the world’s oldest and still active saltmine in Hallstatt/Austria the MOM archive is protected for at least 1 million years. MOM is a global project and is built of stories which are collected and contributed by individuals across the planet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
