<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/home_school/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/home_school/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BengaLUru shallaki</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/home_school/articles/bengaLUru-shallaki/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/home_school/articles/bengaLUru-shallaki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deccanherald.com/india/karnataka/bengaluru/entrepreneur-sets-up-free-alternative-school-3594359&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;The space, named Shallaki, will house around 9,000 books.Credit: Special Arrangement&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A city-based entrepreneur is setting up a small space in Nelamangala for an alternative school for homeschooled children. The space will be free of cost and accessible to a few families. It is expected to be ready by August.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Homeschooling came naturally to Hari Prasad Nadig and his wife, Suma Addoor. Soon after the birth of their daughter Samana, now 11, the couple realised it “would save her time and let her explore things” they couldn’t as children. Both Samana and their younger daughter, nine-year-old Sarayu, are homeschooled.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chennai homeschoolers 2022</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/home_school/articles/chennai-homeschoolers_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/home_school/articles/chennai-homeschoolers_22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Homeschooling helping Chennai kids pursue their interests&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Alternative methods of schooling&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Homeschooling is learner driven and has children researching subjects of their interest. Pic: Pxhere&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eight-year-old Dhrona has keen interest in music. Unlike many of his peers, he does not attend a traditional school. His parents have chosen to nurture his talent by enrolling him in music theory classes and keyboard classes under the ABRSM board which comes under the Royal School of Music. He is one of many children in Chennai taking to homeschooling and unschooling for various reasons&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kristina gumroad</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/home_school/articles/kristina-gumroad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/home_school/articles/kristina-gumroad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“In the beginning, I wasn’t trying to build a business. I was just writing for my own daughters.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For Kristina Garner — and for so many other creators — 2020 has been busy, chaotic, and unexpected. “I don’t know why,” she said, “but I just didn’t see this coming.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kristina is the Founder and CEO of Blossom and Root, a homeschool curriculum focused on nature study, literature, S.T.E.A.M. and the arts. The Blossom and Root curriculum serves homeschooling families around the world, and Kristina is one of the most successful creators on Gumroad this year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nihar unchooling</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/home_school/articles/nihAr-unchooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/home_school/articles/nihAr-unchooling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning to learn: a teen’s homeschooling experience&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Beyond school&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[Nihar on a cycle.] Pic credit: Anupama Thakkar&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It has been eight years now since we started down this path without setting any goals to reach anywhere. It was our son Nihar’s choice to learn at home by making things and working on projects rather than only through books. He proposed that to us, when he entered Class 4, as he felt that he wasn’t finding enough time to do the things he wanted to do. As parents, we valued his need to be free from systems and structures and to be motivated by his innate sense of wonder and curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unschooled bands</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/home_school/articles/unschooled-bands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/home_school/articles/unschooled-bands/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://aeon.co/essays/children-today-are-suffering-a-severe-deficit-of-play&#34;&gt;AE19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Excerpts below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hunter-gatherers have nothing akin to school. Adults believe that children learn by observing, exploring, and playing, and so they afford them unlimited time to do that. In response to my survey question, ‘How much time did children in the culture you observed have for play?’, the anthropologists unanimously said that the children were free to play nearly all of their waking hours, from the age of about four (when they were deemed responsible enough to go off, away from adults, with an age-mixed group of children) into their mid- or even late-teenage years (when they would begin, on their own initiatives, to take on some adult responsibilities). For example, Karen Endicott, who studied the Batek hunter-gatherers of Malaysia, reported: ‘Children were free to play nearly all the time; no one expected children to do serious work until they were in their late teens.’&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Us situation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/home_school/articles/us-situation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/home_school/articles/us-situation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;manish&#34;&gt;manIsh&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lot of people homeschool kids in the US. In California, it&amp;rsquo;s really easy. Many Christians and Muslims homeschool because they don&amp;rsquo;t want their kids indoctrinated. I pulled out my kids from publish high school (homeschooled for a year and then they did early college &amp;ndash; high school from community college). Both landed in good colleges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hindus here don&amp;rsquo;t homeschool because &amp;ndash; 1) they don&amp;rsquo;t know better [immigrants, still figuring the system out], 2) both parents want to earn [so bringing up of kids is totally outsourced], 3) they don&amp;rsquo;t understand the perils of the public school system here, 4) parents would rather earn and buy an expensive home in a &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; school district. As a result of all this - Hindu kids get brainwashed, become antiHindu and eventually become atheists by 25 years of ago (approx) [you may have noticed many Hindu youngsters in the forefront of free-gaza and all that. And they get ideas into their head that if their parents tell them to marry in their jAti then the parents are castiests! About 40% Hindus here marry outside Hindu community and a huge number marry across jAtis - so traditions get totally lost.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>गङ्गाधरमतम्</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/home_school/articles/gangAdhara-opinion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/home_school/articles/gangAdhara-opinion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After our own experience in Homeschooling and listening to our various mentors. Here are three most important things that form the foundation for successful homeschooling&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;foundation-1&#34;&gt;Foundation #1&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wife and Husband have to agree that Homeschooling/Unschooling is the way forward. It is important to invest time to figure out why you both are embracing homeschooling. It is ok for wife and husband to have differing opinions on ways to homeschool (it is natural and that difference in methods of Homeschooling is required, kids will adapt easily).&#xA;However the consensus to homeschool between the two of you has to be rock solid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
