<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;13 The Other Side of Monarchy A D 14-96 I on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/13_The_Other_Side_of_Monarchy_A_D_14-96_I/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;13 The Other Side of Monarchy A D 14-96 I on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/13_The_Other_Side_of_Monarchy_A_D_14-96_I/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 TIBERIUS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/13_The_Other_Side_of_Monarchy_A_D_14-96_I/01_TIBERIUS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/13_The_Other_Side_of_Monarchy_A_D_14-96_I/01_TIBERIUS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WHEN great men stoop to sentiment the world grows fonder of them; but when sentiment governs policy empires totter. Augustus had chosen Tiberius wisely, but too late. When Tiberius was saving the state with patient generalship the Emperor had almost loved him. “Farewell,” one of his letters ended, “most agreeable of men . . . most valiant of men, most conscientious of commanders.”1 Then the pathos of propinquity blinded Augustus, as later Aurelius; he set Tiberius aside for his pretty grandsons; compelled him to renounce a fortunate marriage to become the cuckold of Julia; resented his resentment, and let him grow old with philosophy in Rhodes. When at last Tiberius reached the principate he was already fifty-five, a disillusioned misanthrope who found no happiness in power.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 GAIUS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/13_The_Other_Side_of_Monarchy_A_D_14-96_I/02_GAIUS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/13_The_Other_Side_of_Monarchy_A_D_14-96_I/02_GAIUS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The populace celebrated the old Emperor’s passing with cries of “Tiberius to the Tiber!” and hailed the Senate’s ratification of Gaius Caesar Germanicus as his successor. Born to Agrippina as she was accompanying Germanicus on his northern campaigns, Gaius had been brought up among soldiers, had imitated their dress, and had been affectionately named Caligula, or Little Boot, from the half boot &lt;em&gt;(caliga)&lt;/em&gt; worn in the army. He now announced that he would follow the principles of Augustus in his policy and would co-operate respectfully with the Senate in everything. He distributed among the citizens the 90,000,000 sesterces that Livia and Tiberius had bequeathed them, and added a gift of 300 sesterces to each of the 200,000 recipients of state corn. He restored to the &lt;em&gt;comitia&lt;/em&gt; the power to choose the magistrates, promised low taxes and rich games, recalled the banished victims of Tiberius, and brought his mother’s ashes piously to Rome. He seemed to be in all ways the opposite of his predecessor—prodigal, cheerful, humane. Within three months of his accession the people had sacrificed 160,000 victims to the gods in gratitude for so charming and beneficent a prince.23&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 CLAUDIUS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/13_The_Other_Side_of_Monarchy_A_D_14-96_I/03_CLAUDIUS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/13_The_Other_Side_of_Monarchy_A_D_14-96_I/03_CLAUDIUS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Caligula had left the Empire in a dangerous condition: the Treasury empty, the Senate decimated, the people alienated, Mauretania in rebellion, Judea in arms at his insistence on placing his cult statue in the Temple of Jerusalem. No one knew where to find a ruler fit to face these problems. The Praetorians, coming upon the apparently imbecile Claudius hiding in a corner, proclaimed him &lt;em&gt;imperator.&lt;/em&gt; The Senate, in terror of the army, and perhaps relieved by the prospect of dealing with a harmless pedant instead of a reckless lunatic, confirmed the choice of the Guard; and Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus hesitantly mounted the throne.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 NERO</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/13_The_Other_Side_of_Monarchy_A_D_14-96_I/04_NERO/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/13_The_Other_Side_of_Monarchy_A_D_14-96_I/04_NERO/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On his father’s side Nero belonged to the Domitii Ahenobarbi—so named from the bronzelike beards that ran in the family. For five hundred years they had been famous in Rome for ability, recklessness, haughtiness, courage, and cruelty. Nero’s paternal grandfather had a passion for games and the stage; drove a chariot in the races, spent money with open hand on wild beasts and gladiatorial shows, and had to be reproved by Augustus for barbarous treatment of his employees and slaves. He married Antonia, daughter of Antony and Octavia. Their son Cnaeus Domitius enhanced the reputation of the family by adultery, incest, brutality, and treason. In A.D. 28 he married the second Agrippina, then thirteen years old. Knowing his wife’s ancestry and his own, he concluded that “no good man can possibly be born from us.”62 They named their only child Lucius, and added the cognomen Nero, meaning, in the Sabine tongue, valiant and strong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 THE THREE EMPERORS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/13_The_Other_Side_of_Monarchy_A_D_14-96_I/05_THE_THREE_EMPERORS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/13_The_Other_Side_of_Monarchy_A_D_14-96_I/05_THE_THREE_EMPERORS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Servius Sulpicius Galba reached Rome in June of 68. He was of noble birth, for he traced his lineage on his father’s side to Jupiter, and on his mother’s to Pasiphaë, wife of Minos and the bull. In this year of his exaltation he was already bald, and his hands and feet were so crooked with gout that he could not wear a shoe or hold a book.90 He had the usual vices, normal and abnormal, but it was not these that made his reign so brief. What shocked army and populace were his economy of the public funds and his strict administration of justice.91 When he ruled that those who had received gifts or pensions from Nero must return nine tenths to the Treasury, a thousand new enemies arose, and Galba’s days ran out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 VESPASIAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/13_The_Other_Side_of_Monarchy_A_D_14-96_I/06_VESPASIAN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/13_The_Other_Side_of_Monarchy_A_D_14-96_I/06_VESPASIAN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What a relief to meet a man of sense, ability, and honor! Vespasian, busy directing the war against Judea, took his time in coming to occupy the dangerous eminence that his soldiers had won for him, and which the Senate hurriedly confirmed. When he arrived (October, 70), he set himself with inspiring energy to restore order to a society disturbed in every aspect of its life. Perceiving that he would have to repeat the labors of Augustus, he modeled his behavior and policy upon those of that prince. He made his peace with the Senate and re-established constitutional government; he freed or recalled those who had been convicted of &lt;em&gt;lèse-majesté&lt;/em&gt; under Nero, Galba, Otho, and Vitellius; he reorganized the army, limited the number and power of the Praetorian Guard, appointed competent generals to suppress revolts in the provinces, and was soon able to close the Temple of Janus as a sign and pledge of peace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 TITUS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/13_The_Other_Side_of_Monarchy_A_D_14-96_I/07_TITUS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/13_The_Other_Side_of_Monarchy_A_D_14-96_I/07_TITUS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;His older son, named like himself Titus Flavius Vespasianus, was the most fortunate of emperors. Titus died in the second year of his rule and the forty-second of his age, while still “the darling of mankind”; time did not suffice him for the corruptions of power or the disillusionment of desire. As a youth he had distinguished himself in ruthless war and tarnished his name with loose living; now, instead of letting omnipotence intoxicate him, he reformed his morals and made his government a model of wisdom and honor. His greatest fault was uncontrollable generosity. He counted that day lost on which he had not made someone happy with a gift; he spent too much on shows and games; and he left the replenished Treasury almost as low as his father had found it. He completed the Colosseum and built another municipal bath. No one suffered capital punishment during his brief reign; on the contrary, he had informers flogged and banished. He swore that he would rather be killed than kill. When two patricians were detected in a conspiracy to depose him he contented himself with sending them a warning; then he dispatched a courier to relieve the anxiety of a conspirator’s mother by telling her that her son was safe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 DOMITIAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/13_The_Other_Side_of_Monarchy_A_D_14-96_I/08_DOMITIAN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/13_The_Other_Side_of_Monarchy_A_D_14-96_I/08_DOMITIAN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Of Domitian it is harder to paint an objective portrait than even of Nero. Our chief sources for his reign are Tacitus and the younger Pliny; they prospered under him, but belonged to the senatorial party that engaged with him in a war almost of mutual extermination. To set against these hostile witnesses we have the poets Statius and Martial, who ate or sought Domitian’s bread and literally praised him to the skies. Perhaps all four were right, for the last of the Flavians, like many of the Julio-Claudians, began like Gabriel and ended like Lucifer. In this respect Domitian’s soul walked with his body: in youth he was modest, graceful, handsome, tall; in later years he had “a protruding belly, spindle legs, and a bald head”—though he had written a book &lt;em&gt;On the Care of the Hair.103&lt;/em&gt; In adolescence he composed poetry; in obsolescence he distrusted his own prose and let others write his speeches and proclamations. He might have been happier had not Titus been his brother; but only the noblest spirits can bear with equanimity the success of their friends. Domitian’s jealousy soured into a taciturn gloom, then into secret machinations against his brother; Titus had to beg his father to forgive the younger son. When Vespasian died, Domitian claimed that he had been left partner in the imperial power but that the Emperor’s will had been tampered with. Titus replied by asking him to be his partner and successor; Domitian refused, and continued to plot. When Titus fell ill, says Dio Cassius, Domitian hastened his death by packing him about with snow.104 We cannot assess the truth of these stories, nor of those tales of sexual license that have come down to us—that Domitian swam with prostitutes, made the daughter of Titus one of his concubines, and “was most profligate and lewd toward women and boys alike.”105 All Latin historiography is present politics, a partisan blow struck for contemporary ends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
