<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fathil - Reject Mo</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/articles/Fathil_mo-rejection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/articles/Fathil_mo-rejection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Islam in Minority Muslim Countries: A Case Study on Japan and Korea Fauziah Fathil and Fathiah Fathil 2011&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition, personal reasons related to local custom and culture also forms obstacle for Islamic da&amp;rsquo;wah. Among the prospective Muslim converts, there is a fear of being isolated by their families and friends or discriminated at work if they converted to Islam. Such a feeling is primarily obvious among the Japanese since in Japan religion is part of the cherished national and traditional culture which needs to be maintained in order to avoid breakdown in the Japanese society. To most Japanese, abandoning religion is thus, seen as an act of selfishness on the part of the converts who place personal beliefs ahead of family or collective duties. Consequently, some Japanese converts have to face rejection by their families and alienation from friends as their conversion is seen as &amp;ldquo;un-Japanese&amp;rdquo; or an act of betrayal of Japanese customs and traditions, which form the Japanese identity. Apart from social ostracism by family and friends, conversion could also affect one&amp;rsquo;s economic security or employment in government or private enterprise [23].&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kokuiko - meaning of country</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/articles/kamo-no-mabuchi_kokuiko_meaning-of-our-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/articles/kamo-no-mabuchi_kokuiko_meaning-of-our-country/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reflections on the Meaning of Our Country: Kamo no Mabuchi’s Kokuikō&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Peter Flueckiger&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reflections on the Meaning  of Our Country&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Kamo no Mabuchi’s Kokuikô&lt;br&gt;&#xA;PETER FLUECKIGER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IN 1765, when Kamo no Mabuchi (1697–1769) wrote Kokuikô (Reflections on the Meaning of Our Country), he was already an accom plished scholar of the Japanese classics, having produced commentaries on such texts as the Man’yôshû , Kokinshû , and Ise monogatari as well as linguistic studies of ancient Japanese. He was also a prominent poet, famous for reviving the composition of poetry in the style of the Man’yôshû. From 1746 to 1760 he had served as the assistant in Japanese studies (wagaku goyô ) to Tayasu Munetake (1715–1771), son of the shogun Yoshimune (1684–1751, r. 1716–1745), and after retiring from this position, he continued to have an active career, teaching at his private academy in Edo and producing a range of scholarly works until his death in 1769. Although his works primarily took the form of commentaries or lexicons, he laid out his ideas in a more systematic form in his prefaces and in a number of stand-alone discursive essays.1 Kokuikô is the most ambitious of these essays, presenting a utopian vision of ancient Japan as a society governed in accordance with nature, which was then corrupted by the introduction of foreign philosophies, especially Confucianism. Mabuchi’s construction of Japanese cultural identity through reference to an idealized past, as well as his framing of this identity in terms of the difference between Japan and China, and between Japan’s native values and Confucianism, are approaches commonly associated with Kokugaku . One reading of Kokuikô would thus be to see it as a salvo in the contest between Kokugaku and Confucianism in Tokugawa Japan.2 Such an interpretation, however, raises as&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>meijI buddhist-suppression</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/articles/meijI_buddhist-suppression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/articles/meijI_buddhist-suppression/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The haibutsu kishaku during the Meiji Restoration, the most famous instance of the phenomenon, was an event triggered by the official policy of separation of Shinto and Buddhism (or shinbutsu bunri) that after 1868 caused great damage to Buddhism in Japan. The destruction of Buddhist property took place on a large scale all over the country. For example, Kōfuku-ji in Nara suffered greatly. The temple was hit with full force by the movement. The temple&amp;rsquo;s land was seized, the priests forced to become Shinto priests, walls were torn down, trees were planted, and the area became part of one of the city&amp;rsquo;s parks.[2] The anti-Buddhist riots caused damage to all large temples of the city.[3] The violence marked permanently every region of the country. Between 1872 and 1874, 18 thousand temples were eradicated, and maybe as many again from 1868 to 1872.[4] Japanologist Martin Collcutt believes Japanese Buddhism was on the verge of total eradication.[4]&#xA;It is estimated that 40,000 Buddhist temples were destroyed in Japan during this disastrous nationwide anti-Buddhist mayhem, and in certain places the percentage of Buddhist temples destroyed reached 80%.[9]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samurai disestablished</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/articles/samurai-disestablished/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/articles/samurai-disestablished/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/2384680?read-now=1&amp;amp;seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Samurai Disestablished&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Abei Iwane and His Stipend&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by SAKEDA MASATOSHI &amp;amp; GEORGE AKITA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SAKEDA MASATOSHI is professor of political science, Meiji Gakuin Daigaku, and GEORGE AKITA is professor of history, University of Hawaii.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On N 7 January 1874, the former samurai Abei Iwane wrote a lengthy position paper (kengensho -in) to Yasuba Yasukazu The governor of Fukushima prefecture, expressing his views on prefectural policy concerning the rehabilitation of former samurai, or shizoku .&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Iwane&amp;rsquo;s letter was blunt and forthright in the extreme.&#xA;&amp;lsquo;I cannot remain silent,&amp;rsquo; he declared.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;lsquo;There is nothing in what you have stated that I can respect&amp;hellip;. You are only trying to cover up your errors.&amp;rsquo;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;These were strong words for a former samurai, a member of a han - defeated only six years earlier in the battles at the time of the Meiji Restoration,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;to use when writing to a high-ranking official who represented the power and dignity of the central government.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective acceptance rejection</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/articles/selective-acceptance-rejection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/articles/selective-acceptance-rejection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/grok/status/2016885937419001871&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, the active ideological push by the state to reject Christianity &amp;amp; promotion of Shinto&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rejection of western sewer systems &amp;amp; continued use of humanure until all the way to 1960&amp;rsquo;s. Meiji leaders who traveled to the west even had a pointed criticism of the wasteful practices of western nations who imported tons of guano while flushing human shit into rivers poisoning them instead of putting it to use as fertilizer&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tokugawa and rituals</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/articles/tokugawa_and_rituals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/articles/tokugawa_and_rituals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TOKUGAWA APPROACHES TO THE RITUALS OF ZHOU: THE LATE MITO SCHOOL AND “FEUDALISM”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kate Wildman Nakai, Sophia University&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From early times government officials and scholars in Japan looked to  the Rituals of Zhou (Zhouli 周禮) as a source of information about  Zhou political institutions. The early-eighth-century governmental  codes, modeled after those of the Tang dynasty (618–907), designated  it as one of the seven Classics to be studied at the court university  (daigakuryō 大學寮) and as one of the possible subjects for the ex&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Western sjw attempt</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/articles/western-sjw-attempt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/articles/western-sjw-attempt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Legal &amp;amp; General Investment Management, the U.K.&amp;rsquo;s biggest asset manager, this year picked 19 large Japanese companies with no women on the board or at executive levels and began voting against their proposals. The asset manager exercises its voting rights for nearly 500 companies in Japan. - &lt;a href=&#34;https://asia.nikkei.com/Business/Finance/Global-investors-press-harder-for-women-on-Asian-boards&#34;&gt;2019 Nikkei&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
