<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CP Matthew</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/cp_matthew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/cp_matthew/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1452268359807012867&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1452268359807012867&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The old man in the right in this picture can be easily mistaken for a great priest !!! No! He is Dr. C P. Mathew who was the Head of the Oncology Department at Kottayam Medical College and later principal. On the &amp;lsquo;right&amp;rsquo; is Brahmashree Suryan Subramanian Bhattathiri. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr Mathew was the first oncology professor in Kerala, Head of the Oncology Department at Kottayam Medical College and then the principal. Later when he retired he was a flying doctor &amp;amp; visiting professor of allopathic cancer treatment at universities in more than 50 countries. At the age of 60, he decided to unlearn everything he had learnt earlier and accepted a &lt;em&gt;Lada Vaidyan&lt;/em&gt; (a physician of traditional tribal medical system), whom he met on the street, as his guru.Then this great doctor saved tens of thousands of cancer patients from death using the Siddha medicine he learned from the late &lt;em&gt;lada&lt;/em&gt; guru. Patients he saved include many rejects from the Mayo Clinic in America.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>K Ayastha chAmuNDa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/kAyastha-chAmuNDa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/kAyastha-chAmuNDa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kayastha Camunda and Nigama Kayasthas&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kayastha Camunda was a prominent 15th Century alchemist and tantra practioner.His Rasasanketakalika is considered a pioneering work on Rasayanas,their purification and different uses .&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Rasasanketakalika Camunda gives an esoteric description of the origin of Mercury and the reason behind its potency. Apart from Rasasanketakalika and Jvaratimirabhaskar,a text on fevers and their cures.He also wrote a prominent Tantra text &amp;ldquo;Varnanighanta&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Camundas life is shrouded in mystery but it is known that he was born in a Nigama Kayastha family.His fathers name was Kumbha. He was a great devotee of Siva,all of his works start with paying obeisance to Lord Siva. He wrote under patronage of King Rajamalla of Mewad(1474-1509AD)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>nammALHvAr - shrInivAsaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/nammALHvAr_shrInivAsaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/nammALHvAr_shrInivAsaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;by Prof. A. Srinivasa Raghavan&lt;br&gt;&#xA;October 1, 1974&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ramanuja.org/sv/alvars/nammalvar/periya-tiruvantati.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;0-prefatory-note&#34;&gt;0 Prefatory Note&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nammalvar is revered as a saint and his works have been accorded the authority of scriptures. The task of interpreting him began some seven hundred years ago and has resulted in commentaries some of which have now almost as much validity as Nammalvar&amp;rsquo;s words. To cover all that the great commentators say within the space available here is impossible, and is not attempted. Besides, it may not be of much interest to the non-Tamil general reader for whom this book is intended. So, many details of a purely theological nature have been omitted and only what was thought essential to a brief general survey has been retained.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Mag on M</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/open-mag_on_M/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/open-mag_on_M/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Guru M&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The fastest growing yogi of India doubles as a modern-day Kabir to spread the gospel of peace. We meet Sri M who was once Mumtaz Ali Khan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ullekh NP  | 06 Aug, 2014&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The fastest growing yogi of India doubles as a modern-day Kabir to spread the gospel of peace. We meet Sri M who was once Mumtaz Ali Khan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Renowned Malwi folk singer Prahlad Tipanya, who has made Kabir’s devotional songs such as Tu Ka Tu and Tara Rang Mahal Mein extremely popular overseas, was looking forward to meet the person he thought internalised the teachings of the 15th century saint-poet like no one else has done. “I also admire guruji Sri M for his simplicity and his innocent smile,” he says in chaste Hindi as we drive down from Bangalore to Madanapalle. Tipanya had met Sri M before, but not in Madanapalle, which is in Andhra Pradesh, where the 66-year-old yogi lives. A few hours later, the singer touches the feet of the guru who had initiated him into kriya yoga, which is at the heart of Sri M’s training as a member of the Nath tradition, just as it was Kabir’s. “The last time we met, you threw instructions in English and it was fun to hear it because I didn’t understand one bit,” Tipanya tells Sri M, who erupts in childlike laughter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rAma vAriar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/rAma-vAriar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/rAma-vAriar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Gr8 Sanskrit scholar of 20th CE KaikkulangaraRamaVarier learned Veda (Sruthi) by Sravana (listening). He voluntarily took up duties at a temple near to Thrissur BrahmasvaMatha where students are taught. He had the skill of Ekasandhagrahana(perception on a single instance) . Later, he brushed it up with YoganandaSwami He wrote several articles in Sanskrit on the subject Veda by the pen name Vaidehi It was well-appreciated by scholars all over Bharat &amp;amp; some scholars from Varanasi send him copies of Veda in print. He was of the opinion that people who didn&amp;rsquo;t have veda-adhikara should never recite it. He held on to that until his death. It is said that he donated the copies of Veda to veda-adhikari Brahmin before his death.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ravilochana on tirumalisai</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/ravilochana_tirumalisai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/ravilochana_tirumalisai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thirumalisai Alvar refers to Vishnu as Gunabharan. Now Gunabharan is a title of Mahendravarman Pallava. And Nagaswamy as well as other such people are very happy to point out that it is a title of Mahendravarman Pallava. So the Alvar must be a contemporary of Mahendravarman. That he was a contemporary of Simhavishnu and Mahendravarman is something which I am also ready to agree.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vellayi gopuram</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/vellayi-gopuram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/vellayi-gopuram/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://isharethese.com/vellayi-gopuram-srirangam-tamil-nadu/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sad Story of Vellayi Gopuram in Srirangam, Tamil Nadu&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have been to Srirangam you would have noticed only one of the tower gates is white in color and all others are multi colored. If you have not been to Srirangam yet let me tell you there are 21 gopuram (temple tower gates) in Sriramgam, one among the 21 is painted white. And this gopuram attracts attention in spite of its dull white color. It is called the Vellayi Gopuram and has a blood chilling story full of patriotism on why its is named and colored white.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vivekAnanda and eLavas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/vivekAnanda_and_eLavas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/vivekAnanda_and_eLavas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Rakesh Thiyyan &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1436946401116635140.html&#34;&gt;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1436946401116635140.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vivekananda is not Bengali. There is a saying in Hindi: &amp;ldquo;Jaato na poocho sant ki, pooch leejiyo gyan.&amp;rdquo; (Don&amp;rsquo;t ask the saint his caste, but ask for knowledge.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2017 I and a woke Bengali friend were travelling through Jodhpur when the fighting started. As we entered our room in Jodhpur, I got a call from my editor, asking me when I could send the story on how Vivekananda&amp;rsquo;s advice to Kerala&amp;rsquo;s Ezhava community prevented us from converting en masse to Christianity. I said I&amp;rsquo;d send it as soon as I returned to Delhi. My friend&amp;rsquo;s ear perked up when I mentioned the name of Vivekananda and asked me what I was writing about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>क्षत्रोपेतब्राह्मणाः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/xatropeta-brAhmaNa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/abrAhmaNAH/articles/xatropeta-brAhmaNa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: GhorAngirasa on twitter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paurāṇika pramāṇa (Vāyu iirc) makes it clear that Ṛṣis are restricted to V1-3.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most well known V3 Ṛṣi would be Bhalandana. Viśvāmitra would be V1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Manu is the main V2 Ṛṣi whose Mānava gotra some V2s used to have. Apart from this, there may be a couple of V2 Ṛṣis in RV (need to refer to anukrāmaṇika). Of course, there is the whole V2-&amp;gt;V1 kṣatropeta Brāhmaṇas but they are counted as V1s only, with the exception of their pravara Ṛṣis who were famous kṣatriyas such as Divodāsa, Mitrayu, etc. I call these the “unstable B/Ks” in my tweets on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
