<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;1 Right basics on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;1 Right basics on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Going It Alone</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/01_Going_I/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/01_Going_I/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are books to teach you how to build a house, how to repair engines, how to write a book. But I have not seen a book on how to build a nation out of a disparate collection of immigrants from China, British India and the Dutch East Indies, or how to make a living for its people when its former economic role as the entrepôt of the region is becoming defunct.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Building an Army from Scratch</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/02_Buildin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/02_Buildin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Parliament was due to open in December 1965, four months after our separation from Malaysia, Brigadier Syed Mohamed bin Syed Ahmad Alsagoff, who was in charge of a Malaysian brigade stationed in Singapore, called on me and insisted that his motorcycle outriders escort me to Parliament. Alsagoff was a stout, heavy-built Arab Muslim with a moustache, a Singaporean by birth who had joined the Malayan Armed Forces. To my amazement he acted as if he was the commander-in-chief of the army in Singapore, ready at any time to take over control of the island. At that time the First and Second Singapore Infantry Regiments (1 and 2 SIR) of about 1,000 men each were under Malaysian command. The Malaysian government had placed 700 Malaysians in 1 and 2 SIR, and posted out 300 Singaporean soldiers to various Malaysian units.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Britain Pulls Out</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/03_Britain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/03_Britain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Denis Healey laughed when Keng Swee and I asked him in October 1966 to sell us a squadron of Hawker Hunter fighter aircraft. He wagged his finger at us and asked what we were up to; British forces would look after us. We left London reassured that the RAF would stay in Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We badly needed the confidence British forces generated. If they were to leave suddenly before we had any capacity to defend ourselves, I did not think we could survive. Their presence gave people a sense of security, without which we would not get investments and be able to export our goods and services. That was the only way we could create enough jobs to absorb our school leavers and prevent massive unemployment. In January that year I had met Harold Wilson, the British prime minister, at an emergency Commonwealth prime ministers’ conference in Lagos on Rhodesia’s unilateral declaration of independence. In between meetings, we discussed the future of British forces in Singapore. He told me that he might have to take away 25,000 of the 50,000 troops guarding Malaysia. Although he said no decision had yet been taken, my impression was that he was moving towards troop reduction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Surviving Without a Hinterland</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/04_Survivi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/04_Survivi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1965, a few months after independence, an economic planner whom the Indian government had seconded to us presented me with a thick volume of his report. I scanned the summary to confirm that his plans were based on a common market with Malaysia. I thanked him, and never read it again. He did not understand that if Malaysia was not willing to have a common market while Singapore was a part of it, it was hardly likely to agree now we were independent. We were stripped of our role as the administrative, commercial and military hub of the British Empire in Southeast Asia. Unless we could find and attach ourselves to a new hinterland, the future was bleak.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 Creating a Financial Centre</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/05_Creatin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/05_Creatin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anyone who predicted in 1965 when we separated from Malaysia that Singapore would become a financial centre would have been thought mad. How did it happen, the gleaming modern office blocks in the city centre with banks of computers linking Singapore with London, New York, Tokyo, Frankfurt, Hong Kong and other major financial centres?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It had a most improbable start in 1968. In his oral history, Dr Winsemius recalls his telephone call to his friend, the vice-president of the Bank of America branch in Singapore, who was then in London. “Look here, Mr Van Oenen, we (Singapore) want, within ten years, to be the financial centre in Southeast Asia.” Van Oenen replied, “All right, you come to London. In five years you can develop it.” Winsemius immediately went to London where Van Oenen took him to a large globe standing in a boardroom, and said, “Look here, the financial world begins in Zurich. Zurich banks open at 9 o’clock in the morning, later Frankfurt, later London. In the afternoon Zurich closes, then Frankfurt and London. In the meantime, New York is open. So London hands over financial money traffic to New York. In the afternoon New York closes; they had already handed over to San Francisco. When San Francisco closes in the afternoon, the world is covered with a veil. Nothing happens until next day, 9:00 am Swiss time, then the Swiss banks open. If we put Singapore in between, before San Francisco closes, Singapore would have taken over. And when Singapore closes, it would have handed over to Zurich. Then, for the first time since creation, we will have a 24-hour round-the-world service in money and banking.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 Winning Over the Unions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/06_Winning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/06_Winning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started my political life fighting for the unions as their legal adviser and negotiator. By the mid-1950s the communists had gained control of most of them, and both communist and non-communist unions had turned combative. To attract investments, we had to free unions from communist control and educate union leaders and workers on the need to create new jobs by getting investments. This was easier said than done.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Given the communist hold on our unions, it was inevitable that we suffered endless strikes, go-slows and riots from the late 1940s to the 1960s. Between July 1961 and September 1962 we had 153 strikes, a record for Singapore. In 1969, for the first time since before the war, we had no strikes or work stoppages. How did we do this?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 A Fair, Not Welfare, Society</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/07_A_Fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/07_A_Fair/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We believed in socialism, in fair shares for all. Later we learnt that personal motivation and personal rewards were essential for a productive economy. However, because people are unequal in their abilities, if performance and rewards are determined by the marketplace, there will be a few big winners, many medium winners, and a considerable number of losers. That would make for social tensions because a society’s sense of fairness is offended.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 The Communists Self-destruct</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/08_The_Com/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/08_The_Com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the morning of 17 November 1965, the superintendent of Changi Prison noticed that Lim Chin Siong, who normally greeted him, was strangely silent. The leader of the communist united front in the 1950s and ’60s, and once PAP member of the Legislative Assembly, had been detained since a 1963 security operation. Lim was trembling. His clothes were dishevelled, his trousers torn, and he appeared to have been in a fight. He wanted to be transferred to another part of the prison. His fellow detainees asked and were allowed to interview Lim in the superintendent’s presence. Looking upset, Lim muttered, “They will beat me up, they will poison … I will finish myself or they will. … Ideological differences.” He again asked to be moved and was transferred to another section of the prison.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 Straddling the Middle Ground</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/09_Straddl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/09_Straddl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The PAP has won 10 successive general elections since 1959, a period of 40 years. It has not gone flabby or effete. How did we do it? Between 1959 and 1965, we had fearful clashes, first with the communists and then the Malay communalists. On independence, we faced dire threats, Indonesia confronting us and Malaysia determined to bypass us. This series of events forged a bond of trust between that generation of voters and the old guard PAP leaders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Nurturing and Attracting Talent</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/10_Nurturi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/10_Nurturi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the night of 14 August 1983, I dropped a bombshell in my annual National Day Rally address. Live on both our television channels, with maximum viewership, I said it was stupid for our graduate men to choose less-educated and less-intelligent wives if they wanted their children to do as well as they had done. The press named it the “Great Marriage Debate”. As I had expected, the speech stirred a hornet’s nest. My wife Choo had warned me there were many more women with only O levels than women with university degrees. It caused a drop of 12 percentage points in votes for the PAP in the election the following year, more than I had anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Many Tongues, One Language</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/11_Many_To/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/11_Many_To/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Both Choo and I had been educated in English-language schools. When we met students from China while studying in England, we became conscious of how deculturalised we were, almost like the Chinese students from the Caribbean. We felt a sense of loss at having been educated in a stepmother tongue, not completely accepting the values of a culture not our own. I felt separated from the mass of the ordinary Chinese who spoke dialect and Mandarin. My world of textbooks and teachers was totally unrelated to the world I lived in. We were like hundreds of Raffles College graduates, not formally tutored in their own Asian cultures, but not belonging to British culture either, lost between two cultures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Keeping the Government Clean</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/12_Keeping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/12_Keeping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the PAP government took office in 1959, we set out to have a clean administration. We were sickened by the greed, corruption and decadence of many Asian leaders. Fighters for freedom for their oppressed peoples had become plunderers of their wealth. Their societies slid backwards. We were swept up by the wave of revolution in Asia, determined to get rid of colonial rule, but angry at and ashamed of the Asian nationalist leaders whose failure to live up to their ideals had disillusioned us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Greening Singapore</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/13_Greenin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/13_Greenin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On my first visit to the Great Hall of the People in Beijing in 1976, there were spittoons in the meeting rooms where they greeted us. Some of the Chinese leaders actually used them. When Deng Xiaoping visited Singapore in 1978, we provided a Ming blue and white spittoon. Although we placed it next to his chair in the conference room, he did not use it. He might have noticed that Chinese Singaporeans did not spit. On my next visit to Beijing in 1980, I saw that spittoons had been removed from the Great Hall. A few years later, when I gave dinner in Singapore to Gu Mu, a state councillor in charge of economics, I mentioned that they had stopped using spittoons in the Great Hall of the People. He chuckled and said they had removed them from the meeting rooms but still used them in their offices – it was too old a habit to eradicate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Managing the Media</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/14_Managin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/14_Managin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the 40 years since 1959, the Singapore press has evolved away from the norms set by the colonial government. We brought this about by laying down out-of-bounds markers, mostly for our English-language pressmen. They had been influenced by the British editors and reporters who used to be their superiors in the Straits Times group. It took many years before a younger generation of journalists in the 1980s recognised that the political culture of Singapore was and will stay different from the Western norm. However, our journalists are exposed to and influenced by the reporting styles and political attitudes of the American media, always sceptical and cynical of authority. The Chinese and Malay press do not model themselves on newspapers in the West. Their cultural practice is for constructive support of policies they agree with, and criticism in measured terms when they do not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Conductor of an Orchestra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/15_Conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/1_right_basics/15_Conduct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My ministers and I remained friends and political colleagues for three to four decades. Several of us had been together since we met as students in England to discuss the future of Malaya and Singapore, then returned home and worked together to build mass support in the trade unions and in the PAP. Our commitment to a common cause and to each other was deep. We had abiding political convictions, or we would not have undertaken the risk of challenging both the British and the communists at the same time, and later the Malay Ultras. The strongest bonds that bound us were forged during our early struggles when often we looked like being swept away by overwhelming forces. Differences on policy we kept within the cabinet until we had resolved them and reached a consensus. Then we would put forth a clear line which people could understand and accept. Once a decision had been taken in cabinet, we made a point of abiding by it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
