<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;22 Appendix on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/22_Appendix/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;22 Appendix on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/22_Appendix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 EXPLOITATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/22_Appendix/1_EXPLOITATION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/22_Appendix/1_EXPLOITATION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SOME THOUGHTS ON THE EXPLOITATION OF NON-HUMAN ANIMALS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE MORE WE LEARN of the true nature of non-human animals, especially those with complex brains and correspondingly complex social behaviour, the more ethical concerns are raised regarding their use in the service of man—whether this be in entertainment, as “pets,” for food, in research laboratories or any of the other uses to which we subject them. This concern is sharpened when the usage in question leads to intense physical or mental suffering—as is so often true with regard to vivisection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 CHIMPANZEE CONSERVATION AND SANCTUARIES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/22_Appendix/2_CHIMPANZEE_CONSERVATION_AND_SANCTUARIES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/22_Appendix/2_CHIMPANZEE_CONSERVATION_AND_SANCTUARIES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THROUGHOUT THE WESTERN WORLD, and in many Third World countries, attitudes towards animals and the environment are changing. There is more awareness of the plight of chimpanzees than there was a few years ago, and with it a growing concern and desire to help. In answer to special needs, individuals emerge when they are most wanted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deeply involved in trying to instigate and assist conservation strategies in Africa is the Committee for Conservation and Care of Chimpanzees—“The Four C’s.” This is a body of scientists, all of whom are concerned with chimpanzee conservation and welfare. Its chairman is Dr. Geza Teleki, who is working with Dr. Toshisada Nishida and others to put together an action plan designed to help as quickly as possible the beleaguered chimpanzees across the African continent. The map on the next page shows the places where chimpanzees are still found, and the research projects, some of which (such as those at Gombe and Mahale Mountains in Tanzania, Tai Forest in Ivory Coast, and Lope in the Gabon) have been in progress for a good many years. In all cases these projects are highly beneficial to chimpanzee conservation in the immediate vicinity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
