<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;practical vedanta and other lectures on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;practical vedanta and other lectures on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>071 PRACTICAL VEDANTA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/071_practical_vedanta_part_i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/071_practical_vedanta_part_i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;practical-vedanta&#34;&gt;PRACTICAL VEDANTA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in London, 10th November 1896&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have been asked to say something about the practical position of the&#xA;Vedanta philosophy. As I have told you, theory is very good indeed, but&#xA;how are we to carry it into practice? If it be absolutely impracticable,&#xA;no theory is of any value whatever, except as intellectual gymnastics.&#xA;The Vedanta, therefore, as a religion must be intensely practical. We&#xA;must be able to carry it out in every part of our lives. And not only&#xA;this, the fictitious differentiation between religion and the life of&#xA;the world must vanish, for the Vedanta teaches oneness — one life&#xA;throughout. The ideals of religion must cover the whole field of life,&#xA;they must enter into all our thoughts, and more and more into practice.&#xA;I will enter gradually on the practical side as we proceed. But this&#xA;series of lectures is intended to be a basis, and so we must first apply&#xA;ourselves to theories and understand how they are worked out, proceeding&#xA;from forest caves to busy streets and cities; and one peculiar feature&#xA;we find is that many of these thoughts have been the outcome, not of&#xA;retirement into forests, but have emanated from persons whom we expect&#xA;to lead the busiest lives — from ruling monarchs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>072 PRACTICAL VEDANTA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/072_practical_vedanta_part_ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/072_practical_vedanta_part_ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;practical-vedanta&#34;&gt;PRACTICAL VEDANTA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART II&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in London, 12th November 1896&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I will relate to you a very ancient story from the Chhāndogya Upanishad,&#xA;which tells how knowledge came to a boy. The form of the story is very&#xA;crude, but we shall find that it contains a principle. A young boy said&#xA;to his mother, &amp;ldquo;I am going to study the Vedas. Tell me the name of my&#xA;father and my caste.&amp;rdquo; The mother was not a married woman, and in India&#xA;the child of a woman who has not been married is considered an outcast;&#xA;he is not recognised by society and is not entitled to study the Vedas.&#xA;So the poor mother said, &amp;ldquo;My child, I do not know your family name; I&#xA;was in service, and served in different places; I do not know who your&#xA;father is, but my name is Jabālā and your name is Satyakāma.&amp;rdquo; The little&#xA;child went to a sage and asked to be taken as a student. The sage asked&#xA;him, &amp;ldquo;What is the name of your father, and what is your caste?&amp;rdquo; The boy&#xA;repeated to him what he had heard from his mother. The sage at once&#xA;said, &amp;ldquo;None but a Brāhmin could speak such a damaging truth about&#xA;himself. You are a Brahmin and I will teach you. You have not swerved&#xA;from truth.&amp;rdquo; So he kept the boy with him and educated him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>073 PRACTICAL VEDANTA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/073_practical_vedanta_part_iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/073_practical_vedanta_part_iii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;practical-vedanta&#34;&gt;PRACTICAL VEDANTA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART III&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in London, 17th November 1896&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the Chhādogya Upanishad we read that a sage called Nārada came to&#xA;another called Sanatkumāra, and asked him various questions, of which&#xA;one was, if religion was the cause of things as they are. And&#xA;Sanatkumara leads him, as it were, step by step, telling him that there&#xA;is something higher than this earth, and something higher than that, and&#xA;so on, till he comes to Âkāsha, ether. Ether is higher than light,&#xA;because in the ether are the sun and the moon, lightning and the stars;&#xA;in ether we live, and in ether we die. Then the question arises, if&#xA;there is anything higher than that, and Sanatkumara tells him of Prāna.&#xA;This Prana, according to the Vedanta, is the principle of life. It is&#xA;like ether, an omnipresent principle; and all motion, either in the body&#xA;or anywhere else, is the work of this Prana. It is greater than Akasha,&#xA;and through it everything lives. Prana is in the mother, in the father,&#xA;in the sister, in the teacher, Prana is the knower.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>074 PRACTICAL VEDANTA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/074_practical_vedanta_part_iv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/074_practical_vedanta_part_iv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;practical-vedanta&#34;&gt;PRACTICAL VEDANTA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART IV&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in London, 18th November 1896&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have been dealing more with the universal so far. This morning I&#xA;shall try to place before you the Vedantic ideas of the relation of the&#xA;particular to the universal. As we have seen, in the dualistic form of&#xA;Vedic doctrines, the earlier forms, there was a clearly defined&#xA;particular and limited soul for every being. There have been a great&#xA;many theories about this particular soul in each individual, but the&#xA;main discussion was between the ancient Vedantists and the ancient&#xA;Buddhists, the former believing in the individual soul as complete in&#xA;itself, the latter denying &lt;em&gt;in toto&lt;/em&gt; the existence of such an individual&#xA;soul. As I told you the other day, it is pretty much the same discussion&#xA;you have in Europe as to substance and quality, one set holding that&#xA;behind the qualities there is something as substance, in which the&#xA;qualities inhere; and the other denying the existence of such a&#xA;substance as being unnecessary, for the qualities may live by&#xA;themselves. The most ancient theory of the soul, of course, is based&#xA;upon the argument of self-identity — &amp;ldquo;I am I&amp;rdquo; — that the I of yesterday&#xA;is the I of today, and the I of today will be the I of tomorrow; that in&#xA;spite of all the changes that are happening to the body, I yet believe&#xA;that I am the same I. This seems to have been the central argument with&#xA;those who believed in a limited, and yet perfectly complete, individual&#xA;soul.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>075 THE WAY TO THE REALISATION OF
A UNIVERSAL RELIGION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/075_the_way_to_the_realisation_of_a_universal_religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/075_the_way_to_the_realisation_of_a_universal_religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-way-to-the-realisation-of-a-universal-religion&#34;&gt;THE WAY TO THE REALISATION OF A UNIVERSAL RELIGION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in the Universalist Church, Pasadena,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;California, 28th January 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No search has been dearer to the human heart than that which brings to&#xA;us light from God. No study has taken so much of human energy, whether&#xA;in times past or present, as the study of the soul, of God, and of human&#xA;destiny. However immersed we are in our daily occupations, in our&#xA;ambitions, in our work, in the midst of the greatest of our struggles,&#xA;sometimes there will come a pause; the mind stops and wants to know&#xA;something beyond this world. Sometimes it catches glimpses of a realm&#xA;beyond the senses, and a struggle to get at it is the result. Thus it&#xA;has been throughout the ages, in all countries. Man has wanted to look&#xA;beyond, wanted to expand himself; and all that we call progress,&#xA;evolution, has been always measured by that one search, the search for&#xA;human destiny, the search for God.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>076 THE IDEAL OF A UNIVERSAL RELIGION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/076_the_ideal_of_a_universal_religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/076_the_ideal_of_a_universal_religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ideal-of-a-universal-religion&#34;&gt;THE IDEAL OF A UNIVERSAL RELIGION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HOW IT MUST EMBRACE DIFFERENT TYPES OF MINDS AND METHODS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wheresoever our senses reach, or whatsoever our minds imagine, we find&#xA;therein the action and reaction of two forces, the one counteracting the&#xA;other and causing the constant play of the mixed phenomena that we see&#xA;around us, and of those which we feel in our minds. In the external&#xA;world, the action of these opposite forces is expressing itself as&#xA;attraction and repulsion, or as centripetal and centrifugal forces; and&#xA;in the internal, as love and hatred, good and evil. We repel some&#xA;things, we attract others. We are attracted by one, we are repelled by&#xA;another. Many times in our lives we find that without any reason&#xA;whatsoever we are, as it were, attracted towards certain persons; at&#xA;other times, similarly, we are repelled by others. This is patent to&#xA;all, and the higher the field of action, the more potent, the more&#xA;remarkable, are the influences of these opposite forces. Religion is the&#xA;highest plane of human thought and life, and herein we find that the&#xA;workings of these two forces have been most marked. The intensest love&#xA;that humanity has ever known has come from religion, and the most&#xA;diabolical hatred that humanity has known has also come from religion.&#xA;The noblest words of peace that the world has ever heard have come from&#xA;men on the religious plane, and the bitterest denunciation that the&#xA;world has ever known has been uttered by religious men. The higher the&#xA;object of any religion and the finer its organisation, the more&#xA;remarkable are its activities. No other human motive has deluged the&#xA;world with blood so much as religion; at the same time, nothing has&#xA;brought into existence so many hospitals and asylums for the poor; no&#xA;other human influence has taken such care, not only of humanity, but&#xA;also of the lowest of animals, as religion has done. Nothing makes us so&#xA;cruel as religion, and nothing makes us so tender as religion. This has&#xA;been so in the past, and will also, in all probability, be so in the&#xA;future. Yet out of the midst of this din and turmoil, this strife and&#xA;struggle, this hatred and jealousy of religions and sects, there have&#xA;arisen, from time to time, potent voices, drowning all this noise —&#xA;making themselves heard from pole to pole, as it were — proclaiming&#xA;peace and harmony. Will it ever come?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>077 THE OPEN SECRET</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/077_the_open_secret/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/077_the_open_secret/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-open-secret&#34;&gt;THE OPEN SECRET&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at Los Angeles, Calif., 5th January 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whichever way we turn in trying to understand things in their reality,&#xA;if we analyse far enough, we find that at last we come to a peculiar&#xA;state of things, seemingly a contradiction: something which our reason&#xA;cannot grasp and yet is a fact. We take up something — we know it is&#xA;finite; but as soon as we begin to analyse it, it leads us beyond our&#xA;reason, and we never find an end to all its qualities, its&#xA;possibilities, its powers, its relations. It has become infinite. Take&#xA;even a common flower, that is finite enough; but who is there that can&#xA;say he knows all about the flower? There is no possibility of anyone&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;getting to the end of the knowledge about that one flower. The flower&#xA;has become infinite — the flower which was finite to begin with. Take a&#xA;grain of sand. Analyse it. We start with the assumption that it is&#xA;finite, and at last we find that it is not, it is infinite; all the&#xA;same, we have looked upon it as finite. The flower is similarly treated&#xA;as a finite something.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>078 THE WAY TO BLESSEDNESS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/078_the_way_to_blessedness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/078_the_way_to_blessedness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-way-to-blessedness&#34;&gt;THE WAY TO BLESSEDNESS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I shall tell you a story from the Vedas tonight. The Vedas are the&#xA;sacred scriptures of the Hindus and are a vast collection of literature,&#xA;of which the last part is called the Vedanta, meaning the end of the&#xA;Vedas. It deals with the theories contained in them, and more especially&#xA;the philosophy with which we are concerned. It is written in archaic&#xA;Sanskrit, and you must remember it was written thousands of years ago.&#xA;There was a certain man who wanted to make a big sacrifice. In the&#xA;religion of the Hindus, sacrifice plays a great part. There are various&#xA;sorts of sacrifices. They make altars and pour oblations into the fire,&#xA;and repeat various hymns and so forth; and at the end of the sacrifice&#xA;they make a gift to the Brahmins and the poor. Each sacrifice has its&#xA;peculiar gift. There was one sacrifice, where everything a man possessed&#xA;had to be given up. Now this man, though rich, was miserly, and at the&#xA;same time wanted to get a great name for having done this most difficult&#xA;sacrifice. And when he did this sacrifice, instead of giving up&#xA;everything he had, he gave away only his blind, lame, and old cows that&#xA;would never more give milk. But he had a son called Nachiketas, a bright&#xA;young boy, who, observing the poor gifts made by his father, and&#xA;pondering on the demerit that was sure to accrue to him thereby,&#xA;resolved to make amends for them by making a gift of himself. So he went&#xA;to his father and said, &amp;ldquo;And to whom will you give me?&amp;rdquo; The father did&#xA;not answer the boy, and the boy asked a second and a third time, when&#xA;the father got vexed and said, &amp;ldquo;Thee I give unto Yama, thee I give unto&#xA;Death.&amp;rdquo; And the boy went straight to the kingdom of Yama. Yama was not&#xA;at home, so he waited there. After three days Yama came and said to him,&#xA;&amp;ldquo;O Brahmin, thou art my guest, and thou hast been here for three days&#xA;without any food. I salute thee, and in order to repay thee for this&#xA;trouble, I will grant thee three boons.&amp;rdquo; Then the boy asked the first&#xA;boon, &amp;ldquo;May my father&amp;rsquo;s anger against me get calmed down,&amp;rdquo; and the second&#xA;boon was that he wanted to know about a certain sacrifice. And then came&#xA;the third boon. &amp;ldquo;When a man dies, the question arises: What becomes of&#xA;him: Some people say he ceases to exist. Others say that he exists.&#xA;Please tell me what the answer is. This is the third boon that I want.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Then Death answered, &amp;ldquo;The gods in ancient times tried to unravel the&#xA;mystery; this mystery is so fine that it is hard to know. Ask for some&#xA;other boon: do not ask this one. Ask for a long life of a hundred years.&#xA;Ask for cattle and horses, ask for great kingdoms. Do not press me to&#xA;answer this. Whatever man desires for his enjoyment, ask all that and I&#xA;will fulfil it, but do not want to know this secret.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;No sir,&amp;rdquo; said the&#xA;boy, &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;man is not to be satisfied with wealth; if wealth were wanted, we&#xA;should get it, if we have only seen you. We shall also live so long as&#xA;you rule. What decaying mortal, living in the world below and possessed&#xA;of knowledge, having gained the company of the undecaying and the&#xA;immortal, will delight in long life, knowing the nature of the pleasure&#xA;produced by song and sport? Therefore, tell me this secret about the&#xA;great hereafter, I do not want anything else; that is what Nachiketas&#xA;wants, the mystery of death.&amp;quot; Then the God of death was pleased. We have&#xA;been saying in the last two or three lectures that this Jnāna prepares&#xA;the mind. So you see here that the first preparation is that a man must&#xA;desire nothing else but the truth, and truth for truth&amp;rsquo;s sake. See how&#xA;this boy rejected all these gifts which Death offered him; possessions,&#xA;property, wealth, long life, and everything he was ready to sacrifice&#xA;for this one idea, knowledge only, the truth. Thus alone can truth come.&#xA;The God of death became pleased. &amp;ldquo;Here are two ways,&amp;rdquo; he said, &amp;ldquo;one of&#xA;enjoyment, the other of blessedness. These two in various ways draw&#xA;mankind. He becomes a sage who, of these two, takes up that which leads&#xA;to blessedness, and he degenerates who takes up the road to enjoyment. I&#xA;praise you, Nachiketas; you have not asked for desire. In various ways I&#xA;tempted you towards the path of enjoyment; you resisted them all, you&#xA;have known that knowledge is much higher than a life of enjoyment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>079 YAJNAVALKYA AND MAITREYI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/079_yajnavalkya_and_maitreyi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/079_yajnavalkya_and_maitreyi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;yajnavalkya-and-maitreyi&#34;&gt;YAJNAVALKYA AND MAITREYI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We say, &amp;ldquo;That day is indeed a bad day on which you do not hear the name&#xA;of the Lord, but a cloudy day is not a bad day at all.&amp;rdquo; Yājnavalkya was&#xA;a great sage. You know, the Shastras in India enjoin that every man&#xA;should give up the world when he becomes old. So Yajnavalkya said to his&#xA;wife, &amp;ldquo;My beloved, here is all my money, and my possessions, and I am&#xA;going away.&amp;rdquo; She replied, &amp;ldquo;Sir, if I had this whole earth full of&#xA;wealth, would that give me immortality?&amp;rdquo; Yajnavalkya said, &amp;ldquo;No, it will&#xA;not. You will be rich, and that will be all, but wealth cannot give us&#xA;immortality.&amp;rdquo; She replied, &amp;ldquo;what shall I do to gain that through which I&#xA;shall become immortal? If you know, tell me.&amp;rdquo; Yajnavalkya replied, &amp;ldquo;You&#xA;have been always my beloved; you are more beloved now by this question.&#xA;Come, take your seat, and I will tell you; and when you have heard,&#xA;meditate upon it.&amp;rdquo; He said, &amp;ldquo;It is not for the sake of the husband that&#xA;the wife loves the husband, but for the sake of the Âtman that she loves&#xA;the husband, because she loves the Self. None loves the wife for the&#xA;sake of the wife; but it is because one loves the Self that one loves&#xA;the wife. None loves the children for the children; but because one&#xA;loves the Self, therefore one loves the children. None loves wealth on&#xA;account of the wealth; but because one loves the Self, therefore one&#xA;loves wealth. None loves the Brāhmin for the sake of the Brahmin; but&#xA;because one loves the Self, one loves the Brahmin. So, none loves the&#xA;Kshatriya for the sake of the Kshatriya, but because one loves the Self.&#xA;Neither does any one love the world on account of the world, but because&#xA;one loves the Self. None, similarly, loves the gods on account of the&#xA;gods, but because one loves the Self. None loves a thing for that&#xA;thing&amp;rsquo;s sake; but it is for the Self that one loves it. This Self,&#xA;therefore, is to be heard, reasoned about, and meditated upon. O my&#xA;Maitreyi, when that Self has been heard, when that Self has been seen,&#xA;when that Self has been realised, then, all this becomes known.&amp;rdquo; What do&#xA;we get then? Before us we find a curious philosophy. The statement has&#xA;been made that every love is selfishness in the lowest sense of the&#xA;word: because I love myself, therefore I love another; it cannot be.&#xA;There have been philosophers in modern times who have said that self is&#xA;the only motive power in the world. That is true, and yet it is wrong.&#xA;But this self is but the shadow of that real Self which is behind. It&#xA;appears wrong and evil because it is small. That infinite love for the&#xA;Self, which is the universe, appears to be evil, appears to be small,&#xA;because it appears through a small part. Even when the wife loves the&#xA;husband, whether she knows it or not, she loves the husband for that&#xA;Self. It is selfishness as it is manifested in the world, but that&#xA;selfishness is really but a small part of that Self-ness. Whenever one&#xA;loves, one has to love in and through the Self. This Self has to be&#xA;known. What is the difference? Those that love the Self without knowing&#xA;what It is, their love is selfishness. Those that love, knowing what&#xA;that Self is, their love is free; they are sages. &amp;ldquo;Him the Brahmin gives&#xA;up who sees the Brahmin anywhere else but in the Self. Him the Kshatriya&#xA;gives up who sees the Kshatriya anywhere else but in the Self. The world&#xA;gives him up who sees this world anywhere but in that Atman. The gods&#xA;give him up who loves the gods knowing them to be anywhere else but in&#xA;the Atman. Everything goes away from him who knows everything as&#xA;something else except the Atman. These Brahmins, these Kshatriyas, this&#xA;world, these gods, whatever exists, everything is that Atman&amp;rdquo;. Thus he&#xA;explains what he means by love.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>080 SOUL, NATURE, AND GOD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/080_soul_nature_and_god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/080_soul_nature_and_god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;soul-nature-and-god&#34;&gt;SOUL, NATURE, AND GOD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to the Vedanta philosophy, man consists of three substances,&#xA;so to say. The outermost is the body, the gross form of man, in which&#xA;are the instruments of sensation, such as the eyes, nose, ears, and so&#xA;forth. This eye is not the organ of vision; it is only the instrument.&#xA;Behind that is the organ. So, the ears are not the organs of hearing;&#xA;they are the instruments, and behind them is the organ, or what, in&#xA;modern physiology, is called the centre. The organs are called Indriyas&#xA;in Sanskrit. If the centre which governs the eyes be destroyed, the eyes&#xA;will not see; so with all our senses. The organs, again, cannot sense&#xA;anything by themselves, until there be something else attached to them.&#xA;That something is the mind. Many times you have observed that you were&#xA;deeply engaged in a certain thought, and the clock struck and you did&#xA;not hear it. Why? The ear was there; vibrations entered it and were&#xA;carried into the brain, yet you did not hear, because the mind was not&#xA;joined to the organ. The impressions of external objects are carried to&#xA;the organs, and when the mind is attached to them, it takes the&#xA;impressions and gives them, as it were, a colouring, which is called&#xA;egoism, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo;. Take the case of a mosquito biting me on the finger when I&#xA;am engaged in some work. I do not feel it, because my mind is joined to&#xA;something else. Later, when my mind is joined to the impression conveyed&#xA;to the Indriyas, a reaction comes. With this reaction I become conscious&#xA;of the mosquito. So even the mind joining itself to the organs is not&#xA;sufficient; there must come the reaction in the form of will. This&#xA;faculty from which the reaction comes, the faculty of knowledge or&#xA;intellect, is called &amp;ldquo;Buddhi&amp;rdquo; First, there must be the external&#xA;instrument, next the organ, next the mind must join itself to the organ,&#xA;then must come the reaction of intellect, and when all these things are&#xA;complete, there immediately flashes the idea, &amp;ldquo;I and the external&#xA;object&amp;rdquo;, and there is a perception, a concept, knowledge. The external&#xA;organ, which is only the instrument, is in the body, and behind that is&#xA;the internal organ which is finer; then there is the mind, then the&#xA;intellectual faculty, then egoism, which says, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo; — I see, I hear, and&#xA;so forth. The whole process is carried on by certain forces; you may&#xA;call them vital forces; in Sanskrit they are called Prāna. This gross&#xA;part of man, this body, in which are the external instruments, is called&#xA;in Sanskrit, Sthula Sharira, the gross body; behind it comes the series,&#xA;beginning with the organs, the mind, the intellect, the egoism. These&#xA;and the vital forces form a compound which is called the fine body, the&#xA;Sukshma Sharira. These forces are composed of very fine elements, so&#xA;fine that no amount of injury to this body can destroy them; they&#xA;survive all the shocks given to this body. The gross body we see is&#xA;composed of gross material, and as such it is always being renewed and&#xA;changing continuously. But the internal organs, the mind, the intellect,&#xA;and the egoism are composed of the finest material, so fine that they&#xA;will endure for aeons and aeons. They are so fine that they cannot be&#xA;resisted by anything; they can get through any obstruction. The gross&#xA;body is non-intelligent, so is the fine, being composed of fine matter.&#xA;Although one part is called mind, another the intellect, and the third&#xA;egoism, yet we see at a glance that no one of them can be the &amp;ldquo;Knower&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;None of them can be the perceiver, the witness, the one for whom action&#xA;is made, and who is the seer of the action. All these movements in the&#xA;mind, or the faculty of intellection, or egoism, must be for some one&#xA;else. These being composed of fine matter cannot be self-effulgent.&#xA;Their luminosity cannot be in themselves. This manifestation of the&#xA;table, for instance, cannot be due to any material thing. Therefore&#xA;there must be some one behind them all, who is the real manifester, the&#xA;real seer, the real enjoyer and He in Sanskrit is called the Atman, the&#xA;Soul of man, the real Self of man. He it is who really sees things. The&#xA;external instruments and the organs catch the impressions and convey&#xA;them to the mind, and the mind to the intellect, and the intellect&#xA;reflects them as on a mirror, and back of it is the Soul that looks on&#xA;them and gives His orders and His directions. He is the ruler of all&#xA;these instruments, the master in the house, the enthroned king in the&#xA;body. The faculty of egoism, the faculty of intellection, the faculty of&#xA;cogitation, the organs, the instruments, the body, all of them obey His&#xA;commands. It is He who is manifesting all of these. This is the Atman of&#xA;man. Similarly, we can see that what is in a small part of the universe&#xA;must also be in the whole universe. If conformity is the law of the&#xA;universe, every part of the universe must have been built on the same&#xA;plan as the whole. So we naturally think that behind the gross material&#xA;form which we call this universe of ours, there must be a universe of&#xA;finer matter, which we call thought, and behind that there must be a&#xA;Soul, which makes all this thought possible, which commands, which is&#xA;the enthroned king of this universe. That soul which is behind each mind&#xA;and each body is called Pratyagātman, the individual Atman, and that&#xA;Soul which is behind the universe as its guide, ruler, and governor, is&#xA;God.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>081 COSMOLOGY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/081_cosmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/081_cosmology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;cosmology&#34;&gt;COSMOLOGY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two worlds, the microcosm, and the macrocosm, the internal and&#xA;the external. We get truth from both of these by means of experience.&#xA;The truth gathered from internal experience is psychology, metaphysics,&#xA;and religion; from external experience, the physical sciences. Now a&#xA;perfect truth should be in harmony with experiences in both these&#xA;worlds. The microcosm must bear testimony to the macrocosm, and the&#xA;macrocosm to the microcosm; physical truth must have its counterpart in&#xA;the internal world, and the internal world must have its verification&#xA;outside. Yet, as a rule, we find that many of these truths are in&#xA;conflict. At one period of the world&amp;rsquo;s history, the internals become&#xA;supreme, and they begin to fight the externals. At the present time the&#xA;externals, the physicists, have become supreme, and they have put down&#xA;many claims of psychologists and metaphysicians. So far as my knowledge&#xA;goes, I find that the real, essential parts of psychology are in perfect&#xA;accord with the essential parts of modern physical knowledge. It is not&#xA;given to one individual to be great in every respect; it is not given to&#xA;one race or nation to be equally strong in the research of all fields of&#xA;knowledge. The modern European nations are very strong in their research&#xA;of external physical knowledge, but they are not so strong in their&#xA;study of the inner nature of man. On the other hand, the Orientals have&#xA;not been very strong in their researches of the external physical world,&#xA;but very strong in their researches of the internal. Therefore we find&#xA;that Oriental physics and other sciences are not in accordance with&#xA;Occidental Sciences; nor is Occidental psychology in harmony with&#xA;Oriental psychology. The Oriental physicists have been routed by&#xA;Occidental scientists. At the same time, each claims to rest on truth;&#xA;and as we stated before, real truth in any field of knowledge will not&#xA;contradict itself; the truths internal are in harmony with the truths&#xA;external.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>082 A STUDY OF THE SANKHYA PHILOSOPHY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/082_a_study_of_the_sankhya_philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/082_a_study_of_the_sankhya_philosophy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-study-of-the-sankhya-philosophy&#34;&gt;A STUDY OF THE SANKHYA PHILOSOPHY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prakriti is called by the Sānkhya philosophers indiscrete, and defined&#xA;as the perfect balance of the materials in it; and it naturally follows&#xA;that in perfect balance there cannot be any motion. In the primal state&#xA;before any manifestation, when there was no motion but perfect balance,&#xA;this Prakriti was indestructible, because decomposition or death comes&#xA;from instability or change. Again, according to the Sankhya, atoms are&#xA;not the primal state. This universe does not come out of atoms: they may&#xA;be the secondary or the tertiary state. The primordial material may form&#xA;into atoms and become grosser and bigger things; and as far as modern&#xA;investigations go, they rather point towards the same conclusion. For&#xA;instance, in the modern theory of ether, if you say ether is atomic, it&#xA;will not solve anything. To make it clearer, say that air is composed of&#xA;atoms, and we know that ether is everywhere, interpenetrating,&#xA;omnipresent, and that these air atoms are floating, as it were, in&#xA;ether. If ether again be composed of atoms, there will still be spaces&#xA;between every two atoms of ether. What fills up these? If you suppose&#xA;that there is another ether still finer which does this, there will&#xA;again be other spaces between the atoms of that finer ether which&#xA;require filling up, and so it will be &lt;em&gt;regressus ad infinitum&lt;/em&gt;, what the&#xA;Sankhya philosophers call the &amp;ldquo;cause leading to nothing&amp;rdquo; So the atomic&#xA;theory cannot be final. According to Sankhya, nature is omnipresent, one&#xA;omnipresent mass of nature, in which are the causes of everything that&#xA;exists. What is meant by cause? Cause is the fine state of the&#xA;manifested state; the unmanifested state of that which becomes&#xA;manifested. What do you mean by destruction? It is reverting to the&#xA;cause If you have a piece of pottery and give it a blow, it is&#xA;destroyed. What is meant by this is that the effects go back to their&#xA;own nature, they materials out of which the pottery was created go back&#xA;into their original state. Beyond this idea of destruction, any idea&#xA;such as annihilation is on the face of it absurd. According to modern&#xA;physical science, it can be demonstrated that all destruction means that&#xA;which Kapila said ages ago — simply reverting to the cause. Going back&#xA;to the finer form is all that is meant by destruction. You know how it&#xA;can be demonstrated in a laboratory that matter is indestructible. At&#xA;this present stage of our knowledge, if any man stands up and says that&#xA;matter or this soul becomes annihilated, he is only making himself,&#xA;ridiculous; it is only uneducated, silly people who would advance such a&#xA;proposition; and it is curious that modern knowledge coincides with what&#xA;those old philosophers taught. It must be so, and that is the proof of&#xA;truth. They proceeded in their inquiry, taking up mind as the basis;&#xA;they analysed the mental part of this universe and came to certain&#xA;conclusions, which we, analysing the physical part, must come to, for&#xA;they both must lead to the same centre.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>083 SANKHYA AND VEDANTA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/083_sankhya_and_vedanta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/083_sankhya_and_vedanta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;sankhya-and-vedanta&#34;&gt;SANKHYA AND VEDANTA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I shall give you a résumé of the Sānkhya philosophy, through which we&#xA;have been going. We, in this lecture, want to find where its defects&#xA;are, and where Vedanta comes in and supplements it. You must remember&#xA;that according to Sankhya philosophy, nature is the cause of all these&#xA;manifestations which we call thought, intellect, reason, love, hatred,&#xA;touch, taste, and matter. Everything is from nature. This nature&#xA;consists of three sorts of elements, called Sattva, Rajas, and Tamas.&#xA;These are not qualities, but elements, the materials out of which the&#xA;whole universe is evolved. In the beginning of a cycle these remain in&#xA;equilibrium; and when creation comes, they begin to combine and&#xA;recombine and manifest as the universe. The first manifestation is what&#xA;the Sankhya calls the Mahat or Intelligence, and out of that comes&#xA;consciousness. According to Sankhya, this is an element (Tattva). And&#xA;out of consciousness are evolved Manas or mind, the organs of the&#xA;senses, and the Tanmātras (particles of sound, touch, etc.). All the&#xA;fine particles are evolved from consciousness, and out of these fine&#xA;particles come the gross elements which we call matter. The Tanmatras&#xA;cannot be perceived; but when they become gross particles, we can feel&#xA;and sense them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>084 THE GOAL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/084_the_goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/practical_vedanta_and_other_lectures/084_the_goal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-goal&#34;&gt;THE GOAL&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in San Francisco, March 27, 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Reprinted from the &lt;em&gt;Vedanta and the West&lt;/em&gt;, May-June 1958. The editors&#xA;of the Magazine published it as it was recorded, adding certain words&#xA;(in square brackets) to maintain the continuity of thought, and periods&#xA;to indicate omissions that might have occurred in recording. — Ed.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We find that man, as it were, is always surrounded by something greater&#xA;than himself, and he is trying to grasp the meaning of this. Man will&#xA;ever [seek] the highest ideal. He knows that it exists and that&#xA;religion is the search after the highest ideal. At first all his&#xA;searches were in the external plane — placed in heaven, in different&#xA;places — just according to [his grasp] of the total nature of man.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
