<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;11 Augustan Statesmanship 30 B C - A D 14 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/11_Augustan_Statesmanship_30_B_C_-_A_D_14/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;11 Augustan Statesmanship 30 B C - A D 14 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/11_Augustan_Statesmanship_30_B_C_-_A_D_14/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 THE ROAD TO MONARCHY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/11_Augustan_Statesmanship_30_B_C_-_A_D_14/01_THE_ROAD_TO_MONARCHY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/11_Augustan_Statesmanship_30_B_C_-_A_D_14/01_THE_ROAD_TO_MONARCHY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FROM Alexandria Octavian passed to Asia and continued the reallotment of kingdoms and provinces. Not till the summer of 29 did he reach Italy. There almost all classes welcomed and feted him as a savior and joined in a triumph that lasted three days. The Temple of Janus was closed as a sign that for a moment Mars had had his fill. The lusty peninsula was worn out with twenty years of civil war. Its farms had been neglected, its towns had been sacked or besieged, much of its wealth had been stolen or destroyed. Administration and protection had broken down; robbers made every street unsafe at night; highwaymen roamed the roads, kidnaped travelers, and sold them into slavery. Trade diminished, investment stood still, interest rates soared, property values fell. Morals, which had been loosened by riches and luxury, had not been improved by destitution and chaos, for few conditions are more demoralizing than poverty that comes after wealth. Rome was full of men who had lost their economic footing and then their moral stability: soldiers who had tasted adventure and had learned to kill; citizens who had seen their savings consumed in the taxes and inflation of war and waited vacuously for some returning tide to lift them back to affluence; women dizzy with freedom, multiplying divorces, abortions, and adulteries. Childlessness was spreading as the ideal of a declining vitality; and a shallow sophistication prided itself upon its pessimism and cynicism. This was not a full picture of Rome, but a dangerous disease burning in its blood. On the sea piracy had returned, rejoicing in the suicide of states. Cities and provinces licked their wounds after the successive exactions of Sulla, Lucullus, Pompey, Gabinius, Caesar, Brutus, Cassius, Antony, and Octavian. Greece, which had been the battlefield, was ruined; Egypt was despoiled; the Near East had fed a hundred armies and bribed a thousand generals; their peoples hated Rome as a master who had destroyed their freedom without giving them security or peace. What if some leader should arise among them, discover the exhaustion of Italy, and unite them in another war of liberation against Rome?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 THE NEW ORDER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/11_Augustan_Statesmanship_30_B_C_-_A_D_14/02_THE_NEW_ORDER/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/11_Augustan_Statesmanship_30_B_C_-_A_D_14/02_THE_NEW_ORDER/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let us study this principate government in some detail, for in many ways it was one of the subtlest political achievements in history.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The powers of the prince were at once legislative, executive, and judicial: he could propose laws or decrees to assemblies or Senate, he could administer and enforce them, he could interpret them, he could penalize their violation. Augustus, says Suetonius, regularly sat as a judge, sometimes till nightfall, “having a litter placed upon the tribunal if he was indisposed. . . . He was highly conscientious and very lenient.”1 Bearing the duties of so many offices, Augustus organized an informal cabinet of counselors like Maecenas, executives like Agrippa, generals like Tiberius, and an incipient clerical and administrative bureaucracy chiefly composed of his freedmen and slaves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 SATURNIA REGNA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/11_Augustan_Statesmanship_30_B_C_-_A_D_14/03_SATURNIA_REGNA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/11_Augustan_Statesmanship_30_B_C_-_A_D_14/03_SATURNIA_REGNA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It could not be said that Augustus had made a desert and called it peace. Within a decade after Actium the Mediterranean knew such economic quickening as no tradition could parallel. The restoration of order was in itself a stimulus to recovery. The renewed safety of the seas, the stability of government, the conservatism of Augustus, the consumption of Egypt’s hoarded treasure, the opening of new mines and mints, the reliability and accelerated circulation of the currency, the easing of congested population into agricultural allotments and colonial settlements—how could prosperity resist so unanimous an invitation? A group of Alexandrian sailors, landing at Puteoli when Augustus was near by, approached him in festal dress and offered him incense as to a deity. It was because of him, they said, that they could voyage in safety, trade in confidence, and live in peace.8&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 THE AUGUSTAN REFORMATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/11_Augustan_Statesmanship_30_B_C_-_A_D_14/04_THE_AUGUSTAN_REFORMATION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/11_Augustan_Statesmanship_30_B_C_-_A_D_14/04_THE_AUGUSTAN_REFORMATION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He destroyed his own happiness by trying to make people good as well as happy; it was an imposition that Rome never forgave him. Moral reform is the most difficult and delicate branch of statesmanship; few rulers have dared to attempt it; most rulers have left it to hypocrites and saints.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Augustus began modestly enough by seeking to check the racial transformation of Rome. Population there was not declining; on the contrary, it was growing by mass and dole attraction and the import of wealth and slaves. Since freedmen were included in the dole, many citizens freed old or sickly slaves to have them fed by the state; kinder motives freed more, and many slaves saved enough to buy their liberty. As the sons of freedmen automatically became citizens, the emancipation of slaves and the fertility of aliens combined with the low birth rate of the native stocks to change the ethnic character of Rome. Augustus wondered what stability there could be in so heterogeneous a population, and what loyalty to the Empire might be expected of men in whose veins ran the blood of subject peoples. By his urging, the &lt;em&gt;lex Fufia Caninia&lt;/em&gt; (2 B.C.) and later measures enacted that an owner of not more than two slaves might free them all, the owner of from three to ten slaves might free half of them, the owner of from eleven to thirty one-third, the owner of from thirty-one to one hundred one-fourth, the owner of from 101 to 300 one-fifth; and no master might free more than a hundred.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 AUGUSTUS HIMSELF</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/11_Augustan_Statesmanship_30_B_C_-_A_D_14/05_AUGUSTUS_HIMSELF/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/11_Augustan_Statesmanship_30_B_C_-_A_D_14/05_AUGUSTUS_HIMSELF/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What sort of man was this who was heir to Caesar at eighteen, master of the world at thirty-one, ruler of Rome for half a century, and architect of the greatest empire in ancient history? He was at once dull and fascinating; no one more prosaic, yet half the world adored him; a physical weakling not particularly brave, but able to overcome all enemies, regulate kingdoms, and fashion a government that would give the vast realm an unexampled prosperity for two hundred years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 THE LAST DAYS OF A GOD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/11_Augustan_Statesmanship_30_B_C_-_A_D_14/06_THE_LAST_DAYS_OF_A_GOD/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/11_Augustan_Statesmanship_30_B_C_-_A_D_14/06_THE_LAST_DAYS_OF_A_GOD/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;His failures and his tragedies were almost all within his home. By his three wives—Claudia, Scribonia, Livia—he had but one child: Scribonia unwittingly avenged her divorce by giving him Julia. He had hoped that Livia would bear him a son whom he might train and educate for government; but though she had rewarded her first husband with two splendid children—Tiberius and Drusus—her marriage with Augustus proved disappointingly sterile. Otherwise their union was a happy one. She was a woman of stately beauty, firm character, and fine understanding; Augustus rehearsed his most vital measures with her and valued her advice as highly as that of his maturest friends. Asked how she had acquired such influence over him, she replied, “by being scrupulously chaste . . . never meddling with his affairs, and pretending neither to hear of nor to notice the favorites with whom he had amours.”38 She was a model of the old virtues, and perhaps expounded them too persistently. In her leisure she devoted herself to charity, helping parents of large families, providing dowries for poor brides, and maintaining many orphans at her own expense. Her palace itself was almost an orphanage; for there, and in the home of his sister Octavia, Augustus supervised the education of his grandsons, nephews, nieces, and even the six surviving children of Antony. He sent the boys off early to war, saw to it that the girls should learn to spin and weave, and “forbade them to do or say anything except without concealment, and such as might be recorded in the household diary.”39&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
