<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;PORTUGUESE-MAHRATTA RELATlONS on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/portuguese-maratta-relations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;PORTUGUESE-MAHRATTA RELATlONS on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/portuguese-maratta-relations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Intro</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/portuguese-maratta-relations/01_Intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/portuguese-maratta-relations/01_Intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Translation of the Book&lt;br&gt;&#xA;“पोर्तुगीज-मराठे संबंध” By Dr. P. S. Pissurlencar&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Translator Shri T. V. Parvate&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MAHARASHTRA STATE BOARD FOR LITERATURE AND CULTURE, BOMBAY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First Edition : June, 1983&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;publisher&#34;&gt;Publisher&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Secretary&#xA;Maharashtra State Board for Literature and Culture Mantralaya, Bombay 400 032&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;© Maharashtra State Board for Literature and Culture, Bombay&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;printer&#34;&gt;Printer&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Manager&#xA;Government Central Press&#xA;Charni Road, Bombay 400 004&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;foreword&#34;&gt;FOREWORD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The State Board for Literature and Culture (Sahitya Sanskriti Mandal) has been set up  by the Government of Maharashtra for the modernisation of the Marathi language and  literature and for encouraging research and publication with a view to protecting the rich  heritage Maharashtra has in the fields of literature, history, culture and fine arts. To attain this  objective, the State Board has undertaken a manifold programme of literary activities, one of these being to initiate, assist or undertake schemes for editing, translating and publishing in  Marathi, relevant important published or unpublished source material which will have a direct  or indirect bearing on the history and culture of Maharashtra. The Board has also the scheme  for the preparation and publication of the socio-political, cultural and literary history of  Maharashtra.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 CH1 SCOPE AND EXTENT OF SOURCE MATERIAL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/portuguese-maratta-relations/02_CH1_SCOPE_AND_EXTENT_OF_SOURCE_MATERIAL/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/portuguese-maratta-relations/02_CH1_SCOPE_AND_EXTENT_OF_SOURCE_MATERIAL/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1510, the Portuguese conquered the city of Goa from Ibrahim Adilkhan as a result of  which the then Goa State extending from Kudal, now in Ratnagiri District, Maharashtra, to  Chita-Kut, now in Mysore State. came under their sway.1 But they were not able to keep  such an extensive territory in their hands for long.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By May 1511, the Portuguese had under their command only Tiswadi and some neighbouring islands and Adilkhan began to rule the rest of the territory of Goa Kingdom. In 1520, the Portuguese again captured Salçette, Bardez and other parts of the Goa Kingdom  and they continued to rule these areas till April 1524, when Adilkhan re-captured them.2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 CH2 DURING SHIVAJI’S TIME</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/portuguese-maratta-relations/03_CH2_DURING_SHIVAJIS_TIME/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/portuguese-maratta-relations/03_CH2_DURING_SHIVAJIS_TIME/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While Shahaji, Shivaji’s father, was in the service of the Nizamshahi, his relations with  the Portuguese were friendly. In a letter from Bijapur reproduced in the daily journal of the  Portuguese Viceroy, Conde de Linhares, it is recorded that the annual income of Shahaji was  20,75,000 hons1and that his private army consisted of 3,000 horsemen.2In the same letter it is also mentioned that the son of Nizam Shah Murtuza was staying at Shahagad  (Xihagadda), i.e. Shahaji’s own residence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 CH3 DURING SAMBHAJI’S REIGN AND AFTER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/portuguese-maratta-relations/04_CH3_DURING_SAMBHAJIS_REIGN_AND_AFTER/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/portuguese-maratta-relations/04_CH3_DURING_SAMBHAJIS_REIGN_AND_AFTER/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After the death of Shivaji, while Sambhaji was at Panhala, he sent a letter to the  Governor of Goa through his envoy, Ramoji Naik Thakur. The tone of the letter was friendly. The envoy reached Goa in May 1680. The Governor sent Sambhaji a friendly reply  accompanied by a draft treaty of friendship with Raiji Pandit whom Sambhaji had appointed to maintain peace in the Konkan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In May 1681, Sambhaji went to Bicholim. While he was there. the Portuguese  Governor sent him a letter reminding him how the Portuguese had behaved with him after  Shivaji’s death, when all was not well with Sambhaji, and requested him to enter into a  permanent treaty of friendship without delay. Consequently, Yesaji Gambhirrao, Sambhaji’s  envoy, went to Goa to negotiate such a treaty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 CH4 DURING PESHWA ADMINISTRATION Ⅰ</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/portuguese-maratta-relations/05_CH4_DURING_PESHWA_ADMINISTRATION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/portuguese-maratta-relations/05_CH4_DURING_PESHWA_ADMINISTRATION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having gained the Konkan territory from the Moghul Emperor as a jagir for Chhatrapati  Shahu, the Mahrattas considered it a rightful and legitimate act to recover tribute from the  Portuguese also. Actually the Moghul Emperor never had any authority over this territory. But  the powerful have always dictated to the weak. Vice-rei Marquez de Alorna said that since  Chhatrapati Shahu of Satara and Chhatrapati Sambhaji of Kolhapur had the Mahratta  Kingdom divided between them and the Konkan passed to Sambhaji, the Mahrattas expected  a tribute from Goa also. But this position was never accepted by the Portuguese, says the  Viceroy, and so they did not pay the tribute.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 CH5 DURING NANASAHEB’S REGIME</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/portuguese-maratta-relations/06_CH5_DURING_NANASAHEBS_REGIME/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/portuguese-maratta-relations/06_CH5_DURING_NANASAHEBS_REGIME/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1740, Balaji Bajirao alias Nanasaheb Peshwa made a treaty with the Portuguese at  Poona but the Bhonsala Savant of Savantvadi did not like it. Jairam Savant was well aware of  the worsened condition of the Portuguese. He decided that before any help from Portugal  reached Goa, he should attack Bardez and capture it. He was of the view that with Mahratta  help he could even capture Salcete and Goa island.1 His councillers said that while formelly  one Portuguese soldier was more than a match for ten of the Savant, the position then was  that one soldier of the Savant was too much for 100 Portuguese.2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 CH6 DURING DECLINE OF PESHWAS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/portuguese-maratta-relations/07_CH6_DURING_DECLINE_OF_PESHWAS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/portuguese-maratta-relations/07_CH6_DURING_DECLINE_OF_PESHWAS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The echoes of the Mahratta disaster at Panipat were heard in contemporary  Portuguese documents. On January 31, 1762, the Viceroy wrote to Portugal that the utter rout  of the Mahrattas at Panipat caused Nanasaheb’s mental disequilibrium and in a few days he  die.1In this battle, a trained military force of the Mahrattas was destroyed and a number of  experienced generals died in action. The ample tributes from the North that the Mahrattas  were getting were stopped. In another letter, the Viceroy wrote that due to the deaths of  Bhausaheb, Vishwasrao and Nanasaheb, the Mahratta State sustained an enormous loss. 2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 CH7 SUMMING UP</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/portuguese-maratta-relations/08_CH7_SUMMING_UP/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/portuguese-maratta-relations/08_CH7_SUMMING_UP/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The history of the Portuguese began in Goa and near Bassein, about a hundred years  before Shivaji the Great was born. They had already established their hegemony in the Indian Ocean. Before the Portuguese power found firm roots in Goa, their principal seat was at  Cochin in Kerala. Goa was honoured with that position from 1521 onwards.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most people in Tiswadi, Salcette and Bardez had been converted to Roman  Catholicism before the rise of Shivaji the Great. The Portuguese had destroyed all Hindu  temples without an exception. On their ruins they erected magnificent churches. They built up the townships in Goa, Daman, Chaul and Bassein in the western style and had their engineers  to construct big fortresses in Gujarat and Konkan. The hospital (espital) that they erected in  Goa was reputed to be the best in the whole world in the sixteenth and the seventeenth century.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
