<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Endemicness and Outbreaks</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/articles/endemicness_and_outbreaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/articles/endemicness_and_outbreaks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1446924989182140419&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1446924989182140419&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like a lot of countries they (Singapore) are shifting to endemic. Going from zero cases to some is going to lead to at least a short-term spike. The graph is expected on some level as ppl normalize behaviorbut overall, YOU NEED TO COMPARE VAX VS. UN-VAX, not vaccination against a perfect ideal pre-covid world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are going into endemic stage for most of the world. I think china will too, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to argue that. Low levels of covid-19 will persist. Reinfection will happen. There are also going to be pockets where people don&amp;rsquo;t vaccinate in mostly vaccinated societies. Herd immunity is hard to achieve with delta due to its infectiousness, and the pockets of un-vaxed are concentrated in ways that make outbreaks (small ones) likely. The issue is to compare unvaxed vs. vaxed societies, and the comparisons that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen are not pretty. We&amp;rsquo;re not going to get perfect situations. But we need to get better and manage this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excess mortality 202203</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/articles/excess-mortality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/articles/excess-mortality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Intelligencer&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What a Single Metric Tells Us About the Pandemic&#xA;By David Wallace-Wells&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A grave in Tehran in March 2020. Photo: Newsha Tavakolian/Magnum Photos&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Live long enough in a pandemic and you will see the entire narrative landscape shift, even flip, sometimes more than once.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As recently as a month ago, Americans of a certain cast of mind could have still looked to China — and indeed all of East Asia, Southeast Asia, and Oceania — with some plausible pandemic envy. Those early lockdowns in Wuhan were brutal, yes; some of the surveillance testing, contact tracing, and quarantine measures imposed in places like South Korea and Singapore were very restrictive, true; closed borders and reentry policies in Australia and New Zealand went further than those of any country in Europe or the Americas; and while the Sinovac vaccines weren’t as effective as those made by Moderna or Pfizer, the success of true “zero COVID” policies through the region meant that in many places, shots got into arms without anything like a major COVID surge ever having taken place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lab origin - summary</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/articles/lab-origin-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/articles/lab-origin-summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1566826229931524096.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;COVID: summary of lab-origin hypothesis:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pandemic caused by a bat SARS-like coronavirus emerged in Wuhan&amp;ndash;a city 1,000 kms from nearest wild bats with SARS-like coronaviruses, but that contains labs conducting world&amp;rsquo;s largest research program on bat SARS-like coronaviruses. In 2015-2017, scientists and science-policy specialists expressed concern that the Wuhan Institute of Virology (WIV) was conducting and contemplating research that posed an unacceptable risk of lab accident and pandemic&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nature.com/articles/nature.2017.21487&#34;&gt;Engineered bat virus stirs debate over risky research  - Nature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
