<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>jAva sepoy conspiracy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/articles/jAva-sepoy-conspiracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/articles/jAva-sepoy-conspiracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/LandOfImmortals/status/1761753509748220340&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The East India Company&amp;rsquo;s army faced a Sepoy Conspiracy in Java (then Dutch East Indies), after the invasion of the island in 1811 by EIC. The Hindu sepoys of The Bengal Army stationed in Yogyakarta in 1815, inspired by the Hindu-Buddhist rituals of the Surakarta court and the glory of the Javanese temples of Prambanan and Borobodur planned a revolt against the British. This plot was conjured with the help of Pakubuwono IV, ruler of Sukarta in Java. The sepoys planned to kill all the British officers, overthrow European power, and install a Bengali administration over the whole island. The ruler of Surakarta took an avid interest in the Hindu sepoys and would attend puja with them, who prayed to Javanese idols, which likely had not seen worship in centuries. The plan never came to fruition as Napoleonic Wars ended and Java returned to the Dutch in 1816.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Little black primitives</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/articles/little-black-primitives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/articles/little-black-primitives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/Paracelsus1092/status/1905531517595431367&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thread by @Paracelsus1092 on Thread Reader App – Thread Reader App&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A thread on the Pacific Dwarf mythology that accompanied the Austronesian expansion - the Primordial Little People Type-Tale&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The dominant hypothesis as to why many Austronesian-Polynesian cultures have a foundational little-people story, is that when the proto-Austronesians arrived in Taiwan they found a short statured Palaeolithic people already living there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This theory was recently strengthened by the discovery of &amp;rsquo;negrito-like&amp;rsquo; human remains in Taiwan, dating back around 6000 years. The skull shows many similarities to other Negrito and African San peoples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post sukarNo bAli slaughter</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/articles/post-sukarNo-bAli-slaughter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/articles/post-sukarNo-bAli-slaughter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;False claim:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In indonesia 90% Muslims &amp;amp; only 2% Hindu. 11000 Temples, but u will never heard any Lynching not they destroyed or harm any temple or Pogrom or inequality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The slaughter in Bali was probably the worst in all of Indonesia. &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In total, at least 5% of the population of Bali was killed - 80,000 people &amp;hellip; the highest proportion in the country.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Balinese had been especially strong supporters of Sukarno&amp;rsquo;s multifaith political project, because it gave Hindus more freedom in a Muslim-majority country.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
