<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Rjrasva on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/rjrasva/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Rjrasva on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/rjrasva/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Arm of Francis</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/rjrasva/arm_of_francis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/rjrasva/arm_of_francis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An ancient; awe-inspiring relic last month took its place in the mounting struggle between pagan- ism and Christianity in Japan. From Rome, where it had been enshrined since the year 1614, the remarkably well-preserved right arm of St. Francis Xavier (above), a historic relic of Catholicism, was returned to one of the scenes of the great evangelist&amp;rsquo;s labors. It was just 400 years since Spanish-born Xavier had come to Japan. While there he had converted hundreds of people to the Catholic faith and had helped to plant the seed of Christianity in a hostile and pagan land. When he died in 1552, on his way to new work in China, his body was buried but was later exhumed, and the right arm was severed and sent to Rome by the Jesuits. The rest of the body now lies in a church in India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holy smoke 1940s</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/rjrasva/holy-smoke_1940s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/rjrasva/holy-smoke_1940s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Missionaries were given extra-legal privileges including army transport, the right to make purchases at subsidized American military base stores and the right to use U.S. Army postal service mailboxes. MacArthur personally asked the American Bible Society to send 10 million Bibles to Japan. The Bibles arrived on military ships, freight paid by American taxpayers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While at first there did seem to be an outburst of Christian conversions, it soon became apparent that many of the converts were out of work and had nothing better to do than attend church meetings. As to the brisk sales of Bibles, they were printed on paper that was a perfect substitute for high-priced cigarette paper. English-speaking Japanese made jokes about Holy Smoke.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan vs Christ</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/rjrasva/japan_vs_christ_rjrasva/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/rjrasva/japan_vs_christ_rjrasva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;source&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Japan - Her first dalliance with West, by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Rjrasva&#34;&gt;Rjrasva&lt;/a&gt; and Ravi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;foreword&#34;&gt;Foreword&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The history of the world since fourth century CE has seen the expansionist monotheistic religions from Middle East stamping out the pagan traditions in one land after another. We, Hindus, have keenly felt the result of this monotheistic Abrahamic onslaught losing more than half of our lands. A thorough reversion of Abrahamic expansion has occurred only in one land - the land of our pagan cousins, the Land of Rising Sun. Japan is a land of Gods (kami) for the Shintoists just as Bharata is a punyabhoomi and karmabhoomi for us. Japanese have digested many Hindu devis and devatas (Sarasvati as Benzaiten, Lakshmi as Kichijo, Ganesha as Kangiten, Garuda as Karura etc.) in their pantheon through the intermediary Buddhists from China. While Japan was spared from any Islamic invasions, she had to face the onslaught of the second Abrahamism from the sixteenth century. Some missionaries even planned to use a Christian Japan to invade and subdue China as we shall see later.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Komura on Christian ed</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/rjrasva/komura_on_christian-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/rjrasva/komura_on_christian-ed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1875, Komura was sent by the Ministry of Education to study abroad in the United States. He spent three years at Harvard Law School and then worked in a New York law firm for another two, acquiring a practical legal education. This Japanese diplomat who is emblematic of the Meiji period was a lifelong self-styled advocate of the “Expel the Barbarians” movement, which supported ridding the country of any foreign presence. During Komura&amp;rsquo;s years overseas, his pride as a Japanese could sometimes be excessive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meiji persuation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/rjrasva/meiji-persuation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/rjrasva/meiji-persuation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christianity was legalized under threat of Western gunboats, not because Meiji leaders had a positive view of it. The opposite was true &amp;amp; the top leadership held a conference on how the new era needed new methods to shield Japan from dead jew worship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In early April 1869, the government had set up within the Dajōkan a bureau for propaganda research, the Kyōdōkyoku. A contemporary diarist reveals that a petition from Ono Jusshin, a Chōshu Confucianist, was behind its creation.34 Ono had been in charge of the Urakami Christians in Chōshū since their deportation there in July 1868.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nagasaki korushu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/rjrasva/nagasaki-korushu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/rjrasva/nagasaki-korushu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christians died disproportionately in the Nagasaki bombing, whose epicentre was the Christian Urakami valley - the heart of Christianity in Japan. 70% of the community that survived centuries of persecution got vaporized in mere minutes by the Americans&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nagasaki residents in the old city center spoke to each other, “Not Nagasaki,but Urakami was bombed [because] the Kuroshu live there”(Treat 1995). The literal translation of“Kuroshu”is “the people of the cross,&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recantation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/rjrasva/recantation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/rjrasva/recantation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;execution-to-recantion&#34;&gt;Execution to recantion&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Initial shogunate policy was to stage public executions which attracted crowds singing xtian prayers &amp;amp; sites became pilgrimage places. Japanese realized martyrdom fetish of Xtians &amp;amp; changed strategy. First they began cremating &amp;amp; scattering everything into ocean so nothing remained of the &amp;ldquo;martyr&amp;rdquo; to congregate around. Then someone realized the whole strategy they were pursuing was flawed. Fujihiro&amp;rsquo;s (in charge of Nagasaki) comments show this shift.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most active persecutors of the Christians was Hasegawa Sahioye Fujihiro, the chief Governor of Nagasaki. In that city he was somewhat restrained by various privileges that had been granted to the Portuguese, by fear of an insurrection, and by the apprehension that he might be blamed if his acts put an end to foreign commerce. He had for a long time desired to be put in possession of Arima. He had already been given some oversight of the apostate Daimyo of that fief and it was partly because of this that the persecutions that had been particularly severe. He now succeeded in getting that daimyo transferred to Hyuga, while he himself obtained the coveted territory. He determined to purge it from the hated religion. For this purpose he made use of a large force of soldiers from Satsuma and Hizen. He is said to have issued the following directions to his subordinates:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rome visit</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/rjrasva/rome-visit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/rjrasva/rome-visit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most interesting character of band sent to Rome by Valignano was Miguel Chijiwa who saw things Valignano didn&amp;rsquo;t intend for him to see&amp;amp; ended an apostate. He wrote a fictional story abt Christian plot to take over world in Japanese &amp;amp; gave warnings lyk below&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Omurake hiden, or &amp;ldquo;Secret History of the Omura Houser&amp;rdquo; reports that it was Miguel who advised Yoshiaki in 1605 that Christianity was nothing but a device for the conquest of foreign lands: &amp;ldquo;From his youth he had been a student of that sect, and he went all the way to Rome, where through his diligence he reached the innermost recesses [of the doctrine]. After he returned home, he told Lord Yoshiaki in secret: &amp;ldquo;That faith is extremely pernicious. Outwardly, it purports to deal with the afterlife and salvation, but in reality it represents a plot to grab foreign lands.&amp;ldquo;50 The document concludes: &amp;ldquo;When we explore the inner doctrine, with Seizaemon as our indispensable guide, [we see that] the Christians reject the customs we practice at home and the laws issued by the authorities. They make light of their official duties and work only for the church.&amp;ldquo;51&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
