<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>shilAhAra arab intrigue</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/shilAhAra-arab-intrigue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/shilAhAra-arab-intrigue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://unrollthread.com/t/1328029374696755200/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we know the Shilaharas were lords of North Konkana ruling from their capital Sthanaka (Thana). It was a very rich Dukedom based on Trade tariffs and coconut , banana plantations. It had big Merchants both Indians and Foreign(Arabs mostly) . Duke and his ministers also dabbed in trade ,owned multitude of Ships . Imagine a prosperous trade derived Principality with many rich sister cities ( Thana , Chaul , Puri ) and a small hinterland of 1400 villages owing allegiance to Deccan Imperium.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Southern Jihad</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/southern-jihAd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/southern-jihAd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Swarajya&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Southern Jihad - Aravindan Neelakandan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The night watchman said that they were three youths in their twenties. He said they calmly walked around. One held the watchman while the two others zeroed in on their target. Their target was Mr. Ramesh – a leading auditor and state general secretary of Tamil Nadu BJP. They twisted his hand in an impossible angle breaking it. Then they slammed his head against the wall. Then in the perfect tradition of Islamist terror, they started to slit his throat even as they were raining cuts against the struggling body of the fifty three year old man. And when it was all over the lifeless body lay down in a pool of blood with 23 cuts and a disfigured head. The killers did not run away. They simply walked and dissolved into the night of Salem – a prominent city in Tamil Nadu. And the night was still young when the auditor was no more: 9.30 pm. It was a Friday in the Islamic holy month of Ramadan- 19-07-2013. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tamil-qAdiris</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/tamil-qAdiris/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/tamil-qAdiris/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/in.ernet.dli.2015.15955/page/n77/mode/2up&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A R Rahman&amp;rsquo;s peer is Syed Karimullah Shah Qadri. Some interesting stories of the Qadiriyya peers at Vellore&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sayyid-shah-modin-qadiri&#34;&gt;Sayyid Shah Modin Qadiri&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ali Sahib was a police peon employed at Vellore, a prominent South Indian garrison town. During the month of Ramadan in 1839, he visited a mosque located on the grounds of the huge military fort complex at Vellore. It was at that time, he claimed, that he heard a maulvi (teacher of Islamic law) denouncing the British as kafirs (infidels) and exhorting Muslims to wage jihad against them. The maulvi, Sayyid Shah Modin Qadiri came from a family of clerics who had presided over the same mosque for generations. Ali Sahib was one of twenty-nine Muslims who reported to Vellore officials that they had heard Modin&amp;rsquo;s seditious messages. He recounted being seated in Modin&amp;rsquo;s mosque amongst Muslim sepoys, government workers, and other persons of rank. He then heard what was widely referred to as Modin&amp;rsquo;s jihad wa&amp;rsquo;z (sermon or exhortation):1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
