<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Army under congress vs BJP</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/army_under_bjp_vs_congress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/army_under_bjp_vs_congress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How things changed at the border -&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2001 when Operation Parakram was launched I was travelling to the Pakistan border. In the train I met a soldier belonging to the Madras Regiment. He started the conversation: &amp;ldquo;Are you an air force pilot?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I laughed. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m flattered you think I&amp;rsquo;m a pilot, but I&amp;rsquo;m just a journalist. He replied: &amp;ldquo;Because of your crew cut I thought you were with the IAF.&amp;rdquo; We talked for over an hour. He told me:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nehru-indira-buildup</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/nehru-indira-buildup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/nehru-indira-buildup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(durga das wrote in 1957)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In fact, I disclosed Nehru&amp;rsquo;s succession plan in my weekly Diary in the Hindustan Times as early as 18th June, 1957. I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is wrong to suggest that Mr. Nehru is trying to build up Mr. Menon, or anyone else, as his successor. If Mr. Nehru is consciously building up anyone, he is building up his daughter.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That was shortly after Nehru had gone to London for the Commonwealth Prime Minister&amp;rsquo;s Conference and taken Menon along. Menon was then a member of the Cabinet and the fact that a Minister was accompanying the Prime Minister for the first time to the Conference had encouraged talk that Nehru was building up Menon for succession.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear-state</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/nuclear-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/nuclear-state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/arya_amsha/status/1628820264107782144&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important for people to understand that Smiling Buddha didn&amp;rsquo;t make us a nuclear weapons state; it was not a bomb but simply a controlled peaceful nuclear explosion. Big difference in the two things. Nuclear states can successfully deliver warheads, the actual military use.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;India became a nuclear weapon state in 1994 but we could&amp;rsquo;ve become one at least 25-30 years earlier. India was a nuclear weapons state by 1994 at the latest. Narasimhan Rao delayed showing off our bomb because India was economically screwed and everyone knew we will face sanctions the moment the world knows, and we couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford them then.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sacks - us trade tactics</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/sacks_us-trade-tactics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/sacks_us-trade-tactics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sachs warns India against U.S. tactics, urges strategic independence&lt;br&gt;&#xA;April 27, 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jeffrey Sachs shared insights on India’s global role, U.S. ties, and navigating multipolar geopolitics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NEW DELHI: Jeffrey Sachs, a renowned economist and director of the Center for Sustainable Development at Columbia University, is a leading voice on global economic policy and multilateralism. His extensive work on sustainable development, poverty reduction, and critiques of U.S. foreign policy make him a critical commentator on India’s strategic choices in a multipolar world. He spoke to The Sunday Guardian and shared his insights on India’s global role, U.S. relations, partnerships with China and BRICS, and offered timely guidance for navigating today’s geopolitical challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Securing Tawang</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/securing-tawang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/securing-tawang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tawang, the name, is on everyone&amp;rsquo;s mouth after a skirmish in the Yangtze. It is worth recalling how a brave officer of the Second Assam Rifles played a key role in taking over Tawang in 1951. Let&amp;rsquo;s remember Major Ralengnao Bob Khathing, MC, MBE.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Jan 1951, then-the governor of Assam, Jairamdas Daulatram summoned Major Khathing and entrusted him with a top-secret mission: &amp;lsquo;To go and integrate Tawang into India&amp;rsquo;. Major Khathing afterwards transferred on deputation as an assistant political officer, to the Indian Frontier Administrative Service. (to maintain the secrecy of the mission).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine vs India protests</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/ukraine-india-protests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/ukraine-india-protests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1503006600935600131.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have just been watching &amp;ldquo;Ukraine Under Fire&amp;rdquo; and I must say that it is a revelation.&#xA;The parallels to the Maydan protests in Ukraine in 2014 and our own &amp;ldquo;Farm Laws&amp;rdquo; protests are eerily similar. Ukraine - Across its eastern border is Russia and to its west-Europe. For centuries, it has been at the center of a tug-of-war between powers seeking to control its rich lands and access to the Black Sea. The show talks about how there were three main pieces of any of these color revolutions&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VidyAsAgar on talbott book</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/vidyAsAgar_talbott-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/vidyAsAgar_talbott-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://people.iith.ac.in/m_vidyasagar/engaging.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;**Review of Strobe Talbott&amp;rsquo;s Book&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Engaging India: Diplomacy, Democracy and The Bomb&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Copyright: The Brookings Institution, 2004&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nostalgia for days gone by&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had found out about this book through the book reviews column of some Indian newspaper (I can&amp;rsquo;t remember which one). Normally books that are copyrighted in 2004 would have been published in late 2003. In contrast, the present book was published during the second half of 2004, because it mentions recent events such as the surprising defeat of the NDA in the 2004 general elections. Though book ends in 2004, its focus is on the two-year period between May 1998 when India conducted its shakti series of nuclear tests, and February 2000 when Bill Clinton visited India, thus signalling a &lt;em&gt;de facto&lt;/em&gt; acceptance by the USA of India&amp;rsquo;s nuclear status. Since the author went out of the US State Department in January 2001 after the changing of the party in power, his description of the events after Clinton&amp;rsquo;s visit are pale and impersonal, in contrast to his vivid and personal portrayal of the events between 1998 and 2000. Reading the book brought back many pleasant memories of the eleven years I had spent serving India&amp;rsquo;s Ministry of Defence, during the last eight of which I had the distinct privilege of reporting directly to the charismatic Dr. A. P. J. Abdul Kalam, our current President. (For a highly personal reminiscence about Dr. Kalam, please &lt;a href=&#34;http://atcweb.atc.tcs.co.in/~sagar/kalam.html&#34;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
