<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Ukraine invasion on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Ukraine invasion on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting a sense of the</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/2022-03-21_Getting_a_sense_of_the_Russian_soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/2022-03-21_Getting_a_sense_of_the_Russian_soul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://razib.substack.com/p/getting-a-sense-of-the-russian-soul&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Getting a sense of the Russian soul&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Share this post&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Getting a sense of the Russian soul&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;razib.substack.com&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copy link&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Twitter&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Facebook&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Email&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;getting-a-sense-of-the-russian-soul&#34;&gt;Getting a sense of the Russian soul&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;looking-into-russian-genetics-and-history-not-through-putins-eyes&#34;&gt;Looking into Russian genetics and history (not through Putin’s eyes)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[TABLE]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F0759ea5d-0ade-416e-9aef-567ccaa0a1eb_645x405.jpeg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F0759ea5d-0ade-416e-9aef-567ccaa0a1eb_645x405.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subscribe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://razib.substack.com/subscribe?&amp;amp;gift=true&#34;&gt;Give a gift subscription&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://razib.substack.com/p/getting-a-sense-of-the-russian-soul?utm_source=substack&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=share&amp;amp;action=share&#34;&gt;Share&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For many of us actual Cold War kids, the Soviet Union, the Eastern Bloc and the battle between capitalism and global communism were just background conditions of our youth. But at least in the United States, what we really talked about wasn’t the Soviets or the communists so much as the “Russians,” conflating the dominant Soviet ethnicity with the whole nation. Though Russians were only 50% of the population of the Soviet Union, Russian language and culture dominated the USSR. Despite being the bulwark of international communism, by the time Josef Stalin led it in the 1930’s, the Soviet Union was for all practical purposes the heir of the Russian Empire. This is how a prominent Stalin expert could refer to his subject as the “&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B004ZDH10A/geneexpressio-20&#34;&gt;Red Tsar&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>202203 sanctions effect</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/202203-sanctions-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/202203-sanctions-effect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: TW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The West thinks sanctions are hurting Putin. They have it backwards: His power inside Russia is surging. Objectively, Putin&amp;rsquo;s poll numbers have improved since the lead-up to and onset of the war. This was predictable – a &amp;ldquo;rally &amp;lsquo;round the flag&amp;rdquo; effect is common for wartime president. In less than 2 weeks, his approval rating spiked 10 points – from 61% to 71%.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many in the West are predicting that this effect will be short lived. Analysts think that Russians will sour on Putin if the economic situation in the country continues to worsen. But there&amp;rsquo;s a gaping hole in their theory: Russians don&amp;rsquo;t think the war was Putin&amp;rsquo;s fault. This is difficult for people in the West to understand. Here, we see the invasion of Ukraine as a war of choice. In Russia, the average citizen sees the conflict as a war of necessity – one forced onto Russia by NATO and Ukraine. This was confirmed before the war in research by the Levada Center, a non-governmental polling firm widely trusted in the West. More than 66% of Russians blamed the conflict on America, NATO, or Ukraine. Only 4% said the conflict was Russia&amp;rsquo;s fault.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>202402 putin - carlson</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/202402_putin-carlson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/202402_putin-carlson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Full Text Transcript of Tucker Carlson Putin Interview&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Russian President Vladimir Putin sat down in the Kremlin for a two-hour one-on-one interview with former Fox News host-turned Tucker Carlson in his Western media conversation since the full-scale invasion of Ukraine began two years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Below is the full text transcript in English of the interview translated from the original conversation in Russian.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: This transcript presents what Putin said and as he said - it may contain a selective view of history and information to argue Russia’s case for its invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 econoist assessment</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/2025_econoist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/2025_econoist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Russia&amp;rsquo;s latest big Ukraine offensive gains next to nothing, again&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of thousands of Vladimir Putin&amp;rsquo;s troops are losing their lives for barely any land&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oct 17th 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tracked fires, since May 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;War-related fires&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Other fires&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In May, Russia launched an enormous offensive aimed at breaking Ukrainian lines. Its furious attacks in the following months set the entire front line ablaze.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, our calculations suggest it has seized just 0.4% of Ukrainian land&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azov history</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/azov-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/azov-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1528023220225466374.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A thread on “Azov”. A lot of people are talking about them these days, the New York Times &amp;amp; the Pope call on them to be saved, they are being presented as glorious heroes. So, let&amp;rsquo;s take a short look at their history:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The roots of “Azov” can be found in the Neonazi soccer hooligan scene of Kharkov. Andrei Biletsky was the central figure of the nascent movement for the longest time. A Kharkov native, he joined numerous nationalist organizations, e.g. the Lvov-based “Tryzub”. He also actively supported the Kharkov cell of the “Social-National Party of Ukraine” (nowadays “Svoboda”).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chatter</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/chatter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/chatter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An interesting post by a Russian volunteer reveals how 🇺🇦listen to radio/cellular comms. It alleges 🇺🇦 hear almost everything and can act on it very effectively:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post applies primarily to the mobilised and their relatives. There are people who will continue chatting regardless of anything, and there are also reasonable people, who simply have not encountered such things before and do not know how to behave. The post is for them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clint-RWA interview</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/clint-rwa-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/clint-rwa-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Details&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clint Ehrlich is a foreign-policy analyst and attorney. He was a Visiting Researcher at the Moscow State Institute of International Relations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Russians With Attitude are two podcasters manoeuvring the globe-spanning American monoculture, currently reporting on Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clint Ehrlich &amp;amp; RWA: The War Dialogues&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clint Ehrlich: When Russia invaded, I notoriously predicted a “Sputnik moment”. I was confident that Russia’s modernized military would win a Gulf War-style victory against Ukraine. I’ve caught a lot of deserved flak for that, but my belief was mirrored by the U.S. intelligence community, which projected that Kiev could fall within the first 72 hours of a Russian invasion, as the Ukrainian military surrendered en masse. Whether the Kremlin itself also planned for a swift victory in Ukraine is of more than academic interest. It may have a significant effect on the course of the war, since if Russia did not anticipate prolonged combat, it may have underestimated the strategic consequences of Western sanctions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filatyev diary excerpts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/filatyev-diary-excerpts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/filatyev-diary-excerpts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rattibha.com/thread/1560022545356791810?lang=en&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A 34-year-old former Russian paratrooper, Pavel Filatyev, has published a remarkable in-depth account of his experiences of the Ukraine war. He served with the Feodosia-based 56th Guards Air Assault Regiment and fought in southern Ukraine for two months. A 🧵 follows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Filatyev was part of the force that captured Kherson in February and was hospitalised with an eye injury after spending more than a month under heavy Ukrainian artillery bombardment near Mykolaiv. By that time, he was completely disillusioned with the war. While recuperating, Filatyev wrote a scathing 141-page memoir titled &amp;lsquo;ZOV&amp;rsquo; (after the recognition symbols painted on vehicles of the invasion force) and published it on VKontakte (Russian Facebook). Not surprisingly, he&amp;rsquo;s now been forced to flee Russia for his own safety.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girkin overview 04-21</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/girkin-overview-2022-04-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/girkin-overview-2022-04-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: TW, translation by @mdmitri91)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of my comrades who came back from the frontline for reorganisation asked to briefly and clearly (without going into depths of warfare science) to sum up and express my thoughts that I listed in a discussion with him, revolving around my &amp;lsquo;pessimism&amp;rsquo; towards the success of the &amp;lsquo;second stage&amp;rsquo; of this SMO (Special Military Operation). - He believes someone might find this useful. I think that no one from those making decisions will pay any attention, but I made a promise, so here it is. In short, let&amp;rsquo;s evaluate the operational situation:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moscow conditions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/moscow-conditions-20220312/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/moscow-conditions-20220312/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: TW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;protests&#34;&gt;Protests&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t say much about people&amp;rsquo;s feelings because now you can get up to 15 years in jail for criticizing this &amp;lsquo;special operation&amp;rsquo;, calling it a war (yes, you can&amp;rsquo;t), &amp;lsquo;spreading fakes&amp;rsquo;, supporting sanctions or calling for protests. Have to blink twice. Can&amp;rsquo;t really protest because everyone gets instantly detained, even random people. See what happened on Bolotnaya Square +++(←2012 government allegations against several people)+++, protests after Nemtsov was killed +++(supposedly at government&amp;rsquo;s behest)+++, or what happened in Belarus +++(← 2021 post election protests, arrests, torture)+++. These governments are good at shutting down protests. Anti-riot police is everywhere now. Not only they control TV channels and websites, they control ALL the media. Social media networks get fines for not cooperating. FB and Google got fined for &amp;rsquo;not removing fakes&amp;rsquo;, gov limits speed and then bans them. Already happened before. VPN helps.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nimitz on leaving ukraine</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/nimitz_on_leaving_ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/nimitz_on_leaving_ukraine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/Peter_Nimitz/status/1892304769852600349&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reasons that it is in our interests for Russia to fully conquer Ukraine:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s supporters have been extremely explicit that her cause is part of a greater struggle against populist forces in America and Europe. Per her own beliefs, our support for her is against our own self-interest.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s supporters have tried to overthrow (the Vindman brothers 2019/20) and kill (Ryan Routh 2024) President Trump. Russia has never tried to either overthrow or assassinate President Trump.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ukraine is second only to the United Kingdom as an anti-democratic force in the West. While the United States and the Confederacy both held elections in wartime, Ukraine cancelled hers. Ukraine (Myrotvorets), unlike Russia, has called for the murder of US citizens abroad, including Elon Musk, and has had a number of US citizens detained abroad. Ukraine also supported the annulment of Romania&amp;rsquo;s election. Russia has never pushed for the cancellation of a Western election.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ukraine is the host of the largest neo-Nazi organization in the world, Azov. Azov is two-hundred times as large as the largest Russian neo-Nazi organization Rusich.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ukraine has been supportive of Western pushes for internet censorship. These pushes have led to the arrests of more than ten thousand people in the United Kingdom for internet posts. Russia has not advocated for internet censorship or speech codes in the West, and has fewer political prisoners than countries like the UK despite a considerably larger population.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Paid propagandists of the Ukrainian government celebrate sadism and murder to a degree not seen since ISIS was on this site, demonstrating the wickedness of her cause.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Our involvement in this war, like every war since 1917, has eroded our sovereignty by granting more authority to democratically-unaccountable international institutions. Those institutions universally opposed President Trump and have worked hard to subvert his cause.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Pivot to Asia strategy encourages us to permanently end the conflicts in the Middle East and eastern Europe. The continued existence of the Ukrainian state will force military commitments in Europe that could otherwise be avoided. Russia&amp;rsquo;s territorial ambitions are limited to lands inhabited by East Slavs, so she will certainly seek a gradual draw down of military forces in agreement with Poland, Hungary, and Romania. While it is unlikely that Russia will join an anti-Chinese axis, she can be turned into a true neutral for the rest of the century with the satiation of her territorial ambitions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The defeat of Ukraine will embolden pro-democracy forces in Europe like Alternative for Germany &amp;amp; UK&amp;rsquo;s Reform Party who have been suppressed by the security forces. Pro-Ukrainian parties in Germany have publicly called for outlawing of Alternative for Germany, and have imprisoned hundreds of people for social media posts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The abandonment of Ukraine will shift the costs of reconstruction onto Russia, saving the West several hundred billion dollars.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Even a rump Ukraine will continue to advocate for the repression of pro-democracy movements in the West. Her intelligence services will continue to undermine democracy through claims of &amp;ldquo;disinformation&amp;rdquo; (see the 2024 Romanian election annulment), and spy on pro-democracy and populist parties without due process. She will work closely with elements of the deep state deeply hostile to the Republican Party.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It should be added that this &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; come with the compensated repatriation of the Baltic Russians. The actual reason that the Russians want to expand is to unify their people. Remove the Russians from the Baltic, and the threat to Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania disappears.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Old recruits</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/old-recruits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/old-recruits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1978498606656057720.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thread by @ChrisO_wiki on Thread Reader App – Thread Reader App&#xA;416 views&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;elders&#34;&gt;Elders&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1/ Large numbers of elderly Russian men are being attracted by fat recruitment bonuses to join the war in Ukraine for the financial benefit of their families. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve lived my life, we&amp;rsquo;ll get an apartment for my son now, so what if I get killed?&amp;rdquo;, asks one. ⬇️&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2/ The independent Russian media outlet Verstka reports that men over 50 from all over Russia are travelling to Moscow to join the army there, enticed by what have until recently been the highest military recruitment salaries in Russia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rus-thrusts-202302</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/rus-thrusts-202302/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/rus-thrusts-202302/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1640426102043623451.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the last 2 months, Russia has undertaken a series of thrusts in eastern #Ukraine to capture territory &amp;amp; weaken Ukraine’s armed forces. Soon, it will be the turn of the Ukrainians to resume their offensive operations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is important to explore the purpose of these offensives because those planning them will have to balance multiple political, strategic and military imperatives for the coming attacks against Russian forces.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s new offensives will be heartbreakingly bloody, but may mark the beginning of the end of the war. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.abc.net.au/news/2023-03-28/ukraine-2023-offensives-russia-retake-territory-west-war/102148638&#34;&gt;abc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Todd-interview</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/todd-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/todd-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Emmanuel Todd comments on the Russian-Ukrainian war – Jürg Altwegg&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Posted on Feb 12, 2023 by VOI&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Emmanuel Todd&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;French historian Emmanuel Todd predicted the collapse of the Soviet Union. Today he sees the United States in decline. France is laughed at and the British act headlessly. Worst of all are the Germans, who have become targets for the Americans. Russia, on the other hand, is doing better than many Western observers would like to think. – Jürg Altwegg&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine Belarus Rus</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/ukraine_belarus_russia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/ukraine_belarus_russia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tressel.xyz/threads/1498960220428529674&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What the West fails to Understand in the Russia-Ukraine War&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A primary problem of the West is that it denies existence to any other epistemology than its own. What is not real according to their current ideological standards does not exist at all. So they will deny agency to religion in each and every case, attributing it to some economic or political reason. But they will refuse any religious motivation. The global media is demonizing Putin, again and again claiming, ‘it is the rapaciousness of one man’. Even great intellectuals like Harari and Taleb are playing into this false narrative that it is the political hunger of one dictator which is leading so many individuals down the violent road.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine history</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/ukraine-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/ukraine-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rattibha.com/thread/1485394436926308352?lang=en&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thread with excerpts from “A History of Ukraine: The Land and Its Peoples” by Paul Magocsi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ukraine is a very flat country, with few natural defenses. Most rivers in Ukraine empty into the Black Sea, but in the west the Bug &amp;amp; San River flow into the Vistula &amp;amp; eventually the Baltic. This put western Ukraine in a different trade network.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ukraine is a very fertile land due her black earth (chernozem). She dominated the agricultural exports of the late Russian Empire for this reason.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine provocations</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/ukraine-provocations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/ukraine-provocations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On Feb 15, the OSCE recorded 41 ceasefire violations as Kiev’s forces began shelling Donbas.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Feb 16: 76 violations&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Feb 17: 316&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Feb 18: 654&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Feb 19: 1,413&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Feb 20-21: 2,026&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Feb 22: 1,484&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;…virtually all by the Kiev side.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Feb 24: Russian forces intervene&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian neo-nazis 2022</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/ukrainian-neo-nazis_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/ukrainian-neo-nazis_2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1501149096949608451.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ukrainian Nationalist Volunteers Committing &amp;lsquo;ISIS-Style&amp;rsquo; War Crimes: Amnesty International&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Right-wing Ukrainian ultra nationalists are committing war crimes in rebel-held territories of Eastern #Ukraine, evidence of militias beheading their victims. Images of what appeared to be the severed heads of two hostages circulated on social media, after a report by Amnesty International &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newsweek.com/evidence-war-crimes-committed-ukrainian-nationalist-volunteers-grows-269604&#34;&gt;accused&lt;/a&gt; both sides of war crimes. Armed volunteers who refer to themselves as the Aidar battalion &amp;ldquo;have been involved in widespread abuses, including abductions, unlawful detention, ill-treatment, theft, extortion, and possible executions&amp;rdquo;, Amnesty said. Kiev-based Pravilnoe TV reported that it had spoken with one of the mothers who confirmed her son was a rebel, captured during fighting in Donetsk. She said she had received her son&amp;rsquo;s head in a wooden box in the post, blaming nationalist volunteers for her son&amp;rsquo;s death.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US investment</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/us-investment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/us-investment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1895523555418522039.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Based on actual disbursed funds through October 2024, the United States had delivered approximately $61-68 billion in aid to Ukraine since Russia&amp;rsquo;s full-scale invasion began. This disbursed aid breaks down approximately as:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Military assistance: ~$44-47 billion in equipment, ammunition, training, and related support that was physically delivered or services rendered&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Economic support: ~$13-15 billion in direct budgetary assistance and other economic aid that was transferred&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Humanitarian assistance: ~$4-6 billion in delivered humanitarian supplies and services&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The disbursed figures are lower than commitment totals because:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>गद्य-विवादः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/gadya-vivAdaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/gadya-vivAdaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;त्रिविक्रमदासाख्यस्य +ऊक्रैनदेशसमर्थकस्य &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/trivikramdas1990/posts/5597223840311750&#34;&gt;गद्यस्योत्तरे&lt;/a&gt; -&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;भारतान् कृष्णान् अखिलान् चीनांश् च मूढान् मन्यमानो ऽपि भवान्, त्रिविक्रमदास, ऊक्रैननागरीकः?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;भारतीयकृष्णादींश् छात्रान् यदोक्रैनराजभटास् सनागरीका वाहनेभ्यो नुत्त्वा देशसीमसु हिमय् उपवेश्य वाहनादिभिः पशून् इव ताडयन्तो ऽपनुदन्ति स्म, तदा क्वासीदियम् अनुकम्पा? सूमि-खार्कीवादिभ्य आत्मरक्षणार्थं भारतीयविधार्थिनौ जीवद्वर्मरूपेण प्रयुञ्जानान् अवीरान् दुष्टान् वा विस्मरति भवान्?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;दॊन्बासादिष्व् आसप्ताधिकवर्षेभ्यो निरन्तरासह्यदुष्टयुद्धम् निगूहयन् बलमित्रं पूतिनं राक्षसीकुर्वते भवते कथं न भवेल्लज्जा?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;प्रजातन्त्रं विरुद्ध्य मैदानाख्यविक्षोभेणाङ्ग्लम्लेच्छप्रेरितेन रूस्कमित्र-राजनेतॄन् उत्पाट्य विधाव्य रूस्क-भाषिणां दलने रतान् सुरतम् इवानन्दम् आसुरं कञ्चनानुभवन्तो दृष्ट्वा तूष्णीं स्थितो भवान्, कथम् अधुना विभाषते?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;बन्देरोपाख्य-स्तीफ़ानं हित्लरासुर-प्रियं देवीकृत्य विविधासुरकर्मकृताम् आज़ोवैदरादीर् दैत्यचमूर् दृष्ट्वा कथम् अधर्मोत्पाटनैकदीक्षाप्रदानुयायिनस् ते रक्तं न क्वथति? अथ लोकविनाशाय तद्देशे कृमिवर्धनतत्परान् महाम्लेच्छान् सहमानैर् महारूस्कैर् भाव्यम् इत्य् अभिप्रैति?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;भो तन्मिथ्यवादः किल। भारते या वार्ताः प्रकाशन्ते ते प्रायः रूषदेशानुकुला यतो हि भारतदेशश्चिरात्कालात् रूषदेशस्य मैत्रिभावेन प्रवर्तते। रूषदेशेन donbas स्थाने युद्दं प्रारब्धम्, पूर्वं Chechnya प्रान्ते अपि ते युद्धं चक्रुः, स्वेतिहासे रूषदेशः सदा युद्धेन नूतनभूमी गृह्णति। अत एव यन्मया उक्तं तदेव श्रूयतां न तू यत् रूषीभिः प्रसर्यते।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
