<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some notes on the</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/2022-07-05_some-notes-on-the-runiform-altaic-inscriptions-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/2022-07-05_some-notes-on-the-runiform-altaic-inscriptions-and/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2022/07/05/some-notes-on-the-runiform-altaic-inscriptions-and-the-early-turk-khaghanates-orkhon-and-beyond/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some notes on the runiform “Altaic” inscriptions and the early Turk Khaghanates: Orkhon and beyond&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-early-turkic-inscriptions-from-mongolia-and-their-discovery&#34;&gt;The early Turkic inscriptions from Mongolia and their discovery&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;kül-tegin-funerary-stele&#34;&gt;Kül Tegin funerary stele&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On February 27th, 731 CE (17th day of the Year of the Sheep), Kül Tegin, the great hero of the second Gök Türk (Blue Turks) empire, passed away in his 47th year (literally flew away to the realm of Tengri). He was greatly mourned by his clansman — his elder brother, Bilge Khaghan, the ruler of the Turks, had his elegy inscribed on the now-famous Kül Tegin funerary stele. On the northern face of the stele, we read:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The epic on stone</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/2010-03-06_the-epic-on-stone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/2010-03-06_the-epic-on-stone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2010/03/06/the-epic-on-stone/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While historians of certain brands have often disregarded epics as a source of history, their value in reconstructing the past cannot be underrated. The great Turko-Mongol empire of Blue Turks or the Tu-Chueh set their entire epic down in stone and it remains one of the most valuable sources of the early medieval history of Central Asia. The history of the Blue Turks was inscribed on the funeral steles of their great warrior Kultegin in the heart of Mongolia at Kosho-Tsaidam, on the banks of the Orkhon river, in the old Turkic language in the Runic script. Several parts of it survive and its translation gives a dramatic glimpse of one of the early Altaic empires. We present the translation as made by Thomsen in his work: “Alttuerkischen Inschriften aus der Mongolei”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The rise and fall of the Uighur Empire</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/2009-07-09_the-rise-and-fall-of-the-uighur-empire/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/2009-07-09_the-rise-and-fall-of-the-uighur-empire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2009/07/09/the-rise-and-fall-of-the-uighur-empire/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the Uighurs in the news some people asked me about them. I decided to salvage one of my writings on their history, which I suspect is one of the more complete ones which I compiled from some obscure sources that very hard to even lay hands on these days.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;…&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Uighurs were the most powerful members of the Turkic Oghuz confederation, which included other clans such as the Khaljis. The yabghu of the Uighurs, Etmish Qutlugh Bilge, was a vassal of the Blue Turks when they were at the height of their glory under Kul Tegin and Bilge Kha’Khan. The pretender Özmish Khan seized the Blue Turk throne, three Altaic tribes, namely the Basmils from the region around modern Kucheng, the Uighurs from the region between the Kobdo and Selenga, and the Qarluqs from Eastern end of the Balkash Lake, tried to seize the empire of Mongolia. The Basmil made the first attempt by marching on Özmish Khan in 744 CE; they killed him in the battle and his capital Ötuegen was captured. They sold his severed head to the Chinese Emperor Hsuan Tsung hoping to obtain patronage from China. Confident of Chinese aid the lord of the Basmil Turks declared himself Kha’khan and the supreme ruler of all Mongolia. However, the Chinese governor Shuo Fang betrayed him when the yabghus of the Uighurs and Qarluqs made common cause with each other. This huge Uighur-Qarluq horde marched on Basmils in late 744. The Basmil army was beaten thoroughly by this coalition and its Kha’Khan was beheaded. The survivors were distributed as naukers amidst the victors or sold to the Chinese, and Basmil tribe was erased off the slate of Mongolian history. The Uighurs seized Mongolia and allowed the 3 Qarluq tribes to keep the western reaches of the original Blue Turk empire. The lord of the Uighurs crowned himself as Etmish Qutlugh Bilge Köl Kha’Khan, the supreme ruler of all Altaic tribes. He founded his capital, Ordu Baligh, some distance away from Ötuegen, and close to the original capital of the first Hun Kha’Khan, Motun Tegin. The lord of Qarluqs was asked to retain the junior title, Yabghu, in deference to the dominance of the Uighurs. Soon after this, Qutlugh Bilge ratified a treaty of peace and cooperation with the Chinese Emperor. Soon after this he died (747) and the empire passed to his youngest son, Kul Mayanchur Kha’Khan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The rise of the Kirghiz Khaganate</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-09-01_the-rise-of-the-kirghiz-khaganate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-09-01_the-rise-of-the-kirghiz-khaganate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/09/01/the-rise-of-the-kirghiz-khaganate/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Kirghiz Khaganate came to the fore after Uighurs were destroyed by the Kirghiz in the 840 AD. The rise of the Kirghiz was shrouded in mystery. All we knew was that a Uighur general defected to the Kirghiz with critical information. The Kirghiz were in rebellion to avenge the Uighur campaign of 740 AD, where the latter had demolished the Kirghiz completely and conquered their lands on the Ob and Yennesei. Before that the Blue Turks had also suppressed the Kirghiz and subjugated them, in course of the breath-taking campaigns of the great Blue Turk warriors Kueltegin and Bilge Kha’Khan. Kirghiz suddenly rebounded in 840 AD and having routed the Uighur Khaganate, seized the empire of Mongolia for about a 100-120 year period. How did this happen?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turning of the Turkic wheel</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-08-16_turning-of-the-turkic-wheel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-08-16_turning-of-the-turkic-wheel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/08/16/turning-of-the-turkic-wheel/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;nasr&#34;&gt;Nasr&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 914 CE, Nasr ibn Ahmed II raised the Samanid Moslems to their peak. They were the first Iranians who had been converted to Sunnism and pursued their zealous Jihad on central Asia with a large army of Iranian Moslems and Arab mercenaries to convert Turkic pagans, the Hindu Vijayas and Iranian fire worshipers to Islam.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nasr converted to Shi’aism and this sparked off a rebellion in the Samanid kingdom, as the Sunni and Shia factions went to war on each other. The Shias were aided by the Buyids another dynasty of Iranian Shia warlords and there were pitched battles fought around the Tehran region. Nasr was succeeded by his son Sultan Noah ibn Nasr, who converted back to Sunnism and led a Jihad agains the Buyids in 943 CE. He also led a great Jihad on the pagan Turks in the Steppes north of Khorasan. In this battle the shamanist Turkic tribes of Cuman and Qarluq clans were beaten by the ghazis and taken as slaves in the condition they would forefeit their foreskins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The battle of Talas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-12-24_the-battle-of-talas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-12-24_the-battle-of-talas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/24/the-battle-of-talas/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reviewing the battle of Talas one of the most defining moments in Asiatic history is worthwhile because the same explosive mix continues to dominate Central Asia. We have to learn many military lessons from the battle of Talas for a scenario like that is still likely to be useful to unravel Chinese war machine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the space of 740-750 CE a numbers of events of importance transpired in Central Asia. The Moslems from Merv and Khorasan grouped under Abu Muslim and marched on the Umayyad Kalif and having routed him placed the Abbasid Kalif as the head of the Moslem world. Shortly after that, Abu Muslim was commissioned to conduct Jihad in Central Asia to exterminate the Kaffirs once and for all. It was a great low point for the Western branch of the Blue Turks. Their great Khan Su-lu who was a bulwark against the Moslems and the Chinese in the wars of 720 and 723, was killed in an internecine conflict. The pagan Turkic rulers of Samarqand and Bokhara came under a heavy assault from the ghazis after the fall of Su-lu when the Arabs with 300 giant trebuchets stormed the cities and forcibly imposed Islam with the destruction of the pagan places of worship. Archaeological evidence shows that these Turkic cities were cosmopolitan with Buddhism, Hinduism, Zoroastrianism and the Tengri cults of the Altaics being practiced.+++(5)+++ The Chinese in the meantime eliminated a major rival of the Moslems, the Tibetans in a combined operation with the Hindu led by lalitAdiya by smashing them in a 749 CE and reducing them to vassalage.+++(4)+++ The pagan Turkic ruler of Tashkent, known as the Tudun, was repeatedly pressured by the Chinese to pay tributes to the T’ang emperor of China. The Uighurs in the mean time became the most powerful Turko-Mongol group in the east and pushed the Qarluq turks westwards. The Qarluqs remained the masters of the territory just west of the Balkash lake.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BMAC-hypothesis</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/bmac-hypothesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/bmac-hypothesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1608679161253736449.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TLDR: A speculative hypothesis: Turkic language originated in the Eastern BMAC populations. Warning: what follows is a long thread on this matter. What was the origin of the Turkic languages?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the early days, buoyed up by the success of Indo-European it was proposed that Turkic, Mongolic &amp;amp; Tungusic were a monophyletic language family &amp;ndash; Altaic &amp;ndash; which originated somewhere close to the Altai region. The early formulations also unified it with Uralic making the large Uralo-Altaic grouping. Since then, Uralo-Altaic has been seen as an artificial group, perhaps with some similarities arising from borrowings. However, Altaic was still believed to hold and even expanded into a ``Macro-Altaic&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; formulation which came to include Koreanic &amp;amp; Japonic. More recently, this formulation has been rebottled as the &amp;ldquo;Trans-Eurasian&amp;rdquo; family.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fromo kesar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/fromo_kesar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/fromo_kesar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A coin from udbhANDapura of Fromo Kesar, the turk shAhIya ruler of gandhAra who fought the Mohammedans with much distinction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some believe that he lent his name to the hero of the Tibeto-Mongolian epic of Gesar Khan. He is name is interpreted as Kaiser of Roman: an odd name for a turk shAhIya ruler of gandhAra. It has been suggested that it was inspired by a Byzantine embassy that came to the region during the reign of his father Tigin to announce their victory over the Mohammedans in 719 CE and form a transnational alliance to contain the rampaging army of Islam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kirghiz</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/kirghiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/kirghiz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1840913545921220631&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jiānkūn 堅昆 is not of wolf descent. Their ancestors were born in a cave north of the Kögmän Mountain (曲漫山 Sayan) as the offspring of a god and a cow (神與牸牛). They have yellow hair, green eyes, red beards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The (green) color of the Kirghiz eyes was noted in manuscript PT 1283 by the Turkic agents. This indicates Western Eurasian ancestry. This taken with the Indo-Iranian type R1a1 among them indicates that they did descend from an Aryan population on the steppe that was Turkicized.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orkhon inscriptions and balbal</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/orkhon-inscriptions_and_balbal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/orkhon-inscriptions_and_balbal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: TW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;image-descriptions&#34;&gt;Image descriptions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The holy site on the steppes on the banks of the Orkhon river in Mongolia where the first Turkic empire originated. The stone epic of the Blue Turks is carved on rock steles in the vicinity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An etching of the Kueltegin Inscription, Orkhon, Mongolia. Part of the great Blue Turk epic on stone.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The headless statue of the great Blue Turk Khan: Tengrida Bilge. Was it beheaded by the chIna-s or the Soviets?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The graves of two unknown Hun Khans in the vicinity of the famous Orkhon steles.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An etching of the Blue Turks with lamellar armor and horse armor riding forth on a campaign with the characteristic Altaic reindeer motif still seen among the only heathen Turks surviving in the region.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The inscription of the Blue Turk Tonyuquq the prime minister of Bilge Khan and brother Kul Tegin.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;language&#34;&gt;Language&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The noun of old Turkic in these inscriptions had 9 cases: 4 of which nominative, accusative, instrumental and genitive are also found in IE. The verbal atmanepada-parasmaipada distinction of IE is achieved by a special case called directive. bahuvrIhI &amp;amp; tatpuruSha samAsa-s both prominently exist in the old Turkic of these inscriptions. Notably unlike IE most nouns do not inflect to indicate dual/plural. However a suffix &amp;ldquo;-lar/laer&amp;rdquo; can be added to make a noun collective:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Return offer</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/turkik-return-offer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/turkik-return-offer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the Khitan Khan Yelü Dashi (1124–1143) wrote to the Uighur ruler Bilge mentioning how his ancestor Abaoji, the founder of the Khitan empire, on conquering Mongolia had taken the sites of the Turkic royal steles &amp;amp; offered to the Uighurs to return to those lands. The Uighurs had been driven out of those lands in the great war they fought with the Kirghiz in 840 CE. Yenisei (Uibat VI) funerary inscription commemorates a certain Turkic hero named Tirig-beg who is said to have fought like a wild boar when the mighty Uighurs were overthrown.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TArAnAtha asanga qarluqs</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/tArAnAthA-asanga-qarluqs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/tArAnAthA-asanga-qarluqs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1823206414497591771&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The lama tAranAtha gives a curious tale regarding the bauddhAchArya asa&lt;del&gt;Nga from puruShapura. He says that during his time, there was a settlement of a force of Qarluq Turks (!!) near the &amp;ldquo;non-bauddha&amp;rdquo; city of ayodhyA. The Qarluqs are said to have attacked him and his disciples when he was giving a sermon. He asked them to remain in meditation, and the Qarluq arrows are said to have &amp;ldquo;turned to dust&amp;rdquo;. When they struck asa&lt;/del&gt;Nga with a sword it broke into a hundred pieces. Seeing them immune and unmoved the Qarluqs &amp;ldquo;bowed down in great reverence and went away.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ughur title</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/ughur-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/articles/MT_lekhAH/ughur-title/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://unrollthread.com/t/1588747232878428161/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The grandiose title with which the Uighur khan was addressed:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;kün ay tengride qut bulmısh ulugh qut ornanmısh alpın erdemin el tutmısh alp arslan qutlugh kül bilge tengri khaanımız&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My khan, the wise kül (also found in the name Kül-tegin of the türk-s).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3 deities are mentioned as conferring the qut -heavenly fortune or the royal power: Tengri, the solar and lunar deities. He is also called &amp;ldquo;the brave lion who has taken the realm by bravery and virtue&amp;rdquo;. Some of these titular elements also appear post-conversion to marUnmAda in the regnal names of various tyrants from mUjavant to dilli.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
