<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;26 Jesus 4 B C -A D 30 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/26_Jesus_4_B_C_-A_D_30/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;26 Jesus 4 B C -A D 30 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/26_Jesus_4_B_C_-A_D_30/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 THE SOURCES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/26_Jesus_4_B_C_-A_D_30/01_THE_SOURCES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/26_Jesus_4_B_C_-A_D_30/01_THE_SOURCES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DID Christ exist? Is the life story of the founder of Christianity the product of human sorrow, imagination, and hope—a myth comparable to the legends of Krishna, Osiris, Attis, Adonis, Dionysus, and Mithras? Early in the eighteenth century the circle of Bolingbroke, shocking even Voltaire, privately discussed the possibility that Jesus had never lived. Volney propounded the same doubt in his &lt;em&gt;Ruins of Empire&lt;/em&gt; in 1791. Napoleon, meeting the German scholar Wieland in 1808, asked him no petty question of politics or war, but did he believe in the historicity of Christ?1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 THE GROWTH OF JESUS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/26_Jesus_4_B_C_-A_D_30/02_THE_GROWTH_OF_JESUS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/26_Jesus_4_B_C_-A_D_30/02_THE_GROWTH_OF_JESUS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Both Matthew and Luke assign Jesus’ birth to “the days when Herod was king of Judea”27—consequently before 3 B.C.. Luke, however, describes Jesus as “about thirty years old” when John baptized him “in the fifteenth year of Tiberius”27a—i.e., A.D. 28-29; this would place Christ’s birth in the year 2-1 B.C. Luke adds that “in those days there went out a decree of Caesar Augustus that all the world should be taxed . . . when Quirinius was governor of Syria.” Quirinius is known to have been legate in Syria between A.D. 6 and 12; Josephus notes a census by him in Judea, but ascribes it to A.D. 6-7;28 we have no further mention of this census. Tertullian29 records a census of Judea by Saturninus, governor of Syria 8-7 B.C.; if this is the census that Luke had in mind, the birth of Christ would have to be placed before 6 B.C.. We have no knowledge of the specific day of his birth. Clement of Alexandria &lt;em&gt;(ca.&lt;/em&gt; 200) reports diverse opinions on the subject in his day, some chronologists dating the birth April 19, some May 20; he himself assigned it to November 17, 3 B.C. As far back as the second century the Eastern Christians celebrated the Nativity on January 6. In 354 some Western churches, including those of Rome, commemorated the birth of Christ on December 25; this was then erroneously calculated as the winter solstice, on which the days begin to lengthen; it was already the central festival of Mithraism, the &lt;em&gt;natalis invicti solis,&lt;/em&gt; or birthday of the unconquered sun. The Eastern churches clung for a time to January 6, and charged their Western brethren with sun worship and idolatry, but by the end of the fourth century December 25 had been adopted also in the East.30&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 THE MISSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/26_Jesus_4_B_C_-A_D_30/03_THE_MISSION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/26_Jesus_4_B_C_-A_D_30/03_THE_MISSION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When John was imprisoned Jesus took up the Baptist’s work, and began to preach the coming of the Kingdom.45 He “returned to Galilee,” says Luke, “and taught in the synagogues.”46 We have an impressive picture of the young idealist taking his turn at reading the Scriptures to the congregation at Nazareth, and choosing a passage from Isaiah:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The spirit of the Lord is upon me, because he hath anointed me to preach glad tidings to the poor; he hath sent me to heal the brokenhearted, to preach deliverance to captives, and recovery of sight to the blind, to set the down-trodden free.47&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 THE GOSPEL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/26_Jesus_4_B_C_-A_D_30/04_THE_GOSPEL/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/26_Jesus_4_B_C_-A_D_30/04_THE_GOSPEL/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He taught with the simplicity required by his audiences, with interesting stories that insinuated his lessons into the understanding, with pungent aphorisms rather than with reasoned argument, and with similes and metaphors as brilliant as any in literature. The parable form that he used was customary in the East, and some of his fetching analogies had come down to him, perhaps unconsciously, from the prophets, the psalmists, and the rabbis; 64 nevertheless, the directness of his speech, the vivid colors of his imagery, the warm sincerity of his nature lifted his utterances to the most inspired poetry. Some of his sayings are obscure, some seem at first sight unjust,65 some are sharp with sarcasm and bitterness; nearly all of them are models of brevity, clarity, and force.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 DEATH AND TRANSFIGURATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/26_Jesus_4_B_C_-A_D_30/05_DEATH_AND_TRANSFIGURATION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/26_Jesus_4_B_C_-A_D_30/05_DEATH_AND_TRANSFIGURATION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Feast of the Passover was at hand, and great numbers of Jews were gathering in Jerusalem to offer sacrifice in the Temple. The outer court of the shrine was noisy with vendors selling doves and other sacrificial animals, and with money-changers offering locally acceptable currency for the idolatrous coins of the Roman realm. Visiting the Temple on the day after his entry into the city, Jesus was shocked by the clamor and commercialism of the booths. In a burst of indignation he and his followers overthrew the tables of the money-changers and the dove merchants, scattered their coins on the ground, and with “a scourge of rods” drove the traders from the court. For several days thereafter he taught in the Temple, unhindered; 122 but at night he left Jerusalem and stayed on the Mount of Olives, fearing arrest or assassination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
