<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Hindu Muslim Riots 1947-86 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Hindu Muslim Riots 1947-86 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>0 INTRODUCTION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/0_INTRODUCTION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/0_INTRODUCTION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Short biographical notices and background information are provided through hyperlinks for the most important personalities and organizations mentioned in the text that follows. The reader might refer to them for further understanding.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All along the years when the fight for an independent India was at its peak, a number of Congress personalities, led by an already well-known leader - a brilliant man who hailed from the historically famous United Provinces (now Uttar Pradesh, UP) - Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru, carried a dream: once India was freed from the British rule, a modern state would be built, a state that would see that its caste and communal ancestral traditions were forgotten. A secular state that would bring people together. A new Socialist order would be built. New Temples - i.e. heavy industries–would appear which would bring the new India into modernity (Parry and Struempell 2008). Some of these dreams would take shape indeed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 CONCLUSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/4_CONCLUSION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/4_CONCLUSION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Indian subcontinent acquired independence in 1947. However, the inability of the Indian National Congress (INC) and of the Muslim League to reach an agreement before the required deadline brought about a precipitous partition of the country, and with the ensuing massacres and exchange of populations, the event has had heavy long-term consequences. To their mutual detriment, both India and Pakistan continue to defy each other dangerously. For India, the secular model, advocated by Nehru and which was meant to ensure peaceful coexistence between religious communities, seemed to have worked. However, after some fifteen years, the situation deteriorated. Local economic rivalries, political games, and international tensions brought a new awareness of difficulties and discriminations. Violence erupted in many places and each successive prime minister had his or her own approach to events. In 1986, religion invaded the political field. Efforts were made by the government to &amp;ldquo;appease&amp;rdquo; both Hindus and Muslims, which brought about disaster. Various groups became vociferous. Hindus felt besieged. Minorities felt threatened. The next decade would be one of blood and tears.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 BIBLIOGRAPHY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/5_BIBLIOGRAPHY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/5_BIBLIOGRAPHY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;SOURCES&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ABOU - ZAHAB, Mariam, ROY, Olivier, 2004, Islamist Networks: the Afghan - Pakistan Connection, London: Hurst&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AGWANI, M.S., 1986, Islamic Fundamentalism in India, Chandigarh: Twenty - First Century India Society&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AHMAD, Imtiaz, 1997, «The Political Economy of Places of Worship», in SHAH, Ghanshyam Shah (ed.), Social Transformation in India, vol. 2, Jaipur: Rawat Publications&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AHMAD, Imtiaz, 1984, «Political Economy of Communalism in Contemporary India», Economic and Political Weekly, vol. 19, n°22/23, June 2 - 9, 1984, pp 903 - 906&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
