<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;2 PHILOSOPHY on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/2_PHILOSOPHY/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;2 PHILOSOPHY on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/2_PHILOSOPHY/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 PRELIMINARY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/2_PHILOSOPHY/1_PRELIMINARY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/2_PHILOSOPHY/1_PRELIMINARY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER I.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PRELIMINARY.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abhinava wrote on a number of subjects and was recognized to be a reliable authority on each one of them. He worked on poetics, only during the short period of transition from the Tāntrika to the Philosophical period. The number of his works on poetics is, therefore, much smaller than that of his philosophical treatises. The value, however, attributed to the former, has overweighed that which scholars in general have attached to the latter. Hence he is better known as an able exponent of the theories of Rasa and Dhvani than as the greatest authority on the &amp;ldquo;Realistic Idealism&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Trilca&amp;rdquo; as the system is technically called.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 ĀBHĀSAVĀDA or &#34;REALISTIC IDEALISM &#34;</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/2_PHILOSOPHY/2_REALISTIC_IDEALISM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/2_PHILOSOPHY/2_REALISTIC_IDEALISM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2 ĀBHĀSAVĀDA or &amp;ldquo;REALISTIC IDEALISM &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ĀBHĀSAVĀDA. or &amp;ldquo;REALISTIC IDEALISM.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The aim of every system of philosophy is to explain the why, the what and the wherefrom of the knowable. Every system bases its conclusions on a careful study of facts of experience and the comparative importance of each depends upon how far it satisfactorily accounts for these facts. Abhinava claims this basis of facts for his system, the Trika. To the facts of experience, as has already been stated, he gives the first, to reason the second, and to a scriptural authority only the last place as the basis of his theories.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 CATEGORIES OF ABHĀSAVĀDA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/2_PHILOSOPHY/3_CATEGORIES_OF_ABHASAVADA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/2_PHILOSOPHY/3_CATEGORIES_OF_ABHASAVADA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;3 CATEGORIES OF ABHĀSAVĀDA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the preceding chapter we have dealt with the Abhāsavādin&amp;rsquo;s concept of the Universal Consciousness as the manifestor. In this chapter, therefore, we propose to give &amp;amp; brief exposition of the Manifested.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Abhāsavāda divides the manifested into thirtysix categories. This division, as Abhinava very clearly states, is based, neither wholly on the scientific observation, nor purely or exclusively on the logical inference. The authority of the Agamas? is its sole basis. This, however, does not mean that it has no support of the facts of experience and that it is simply a matter of belief. It means only this that it is not within the reach of the ordinary means of perceptional or inferential knowledge to fully reveal the essential nature and the full implication of each one of the tattvas. It does not deny that it is a result partly of long intuitive (yogic) experiments and partly of a careful study of mind and matter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 ABHĀSAVĀDA AS THE BASIS OF THE TRIKA THEORY OF KNOWLEDGE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/2_PHILOSOPHY/4_ABHASAVADA_AS_THE_BASIS_OF_THE_TRIKA_THEORY_OF_KNOWLEDGE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/2_PHILOSOPHY/4_ABHASAVADA_AS_THE_BASIS_OF_THE_TRIKA_THEORY_OF_KNOWLEDGE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;4 ABHĀSAVĀDA AS THE BASIS OF THE TRIKA THEORY OF KNOWLEDGE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ABHĀSAVĀDA AS THE BASIS OF THE TRIKA THEORY OF KNOWLEDGE.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Preliminaries and Presuppositions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ĀBHĀSAVĀDA AND PRACTICAL LIFE.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abhinava very clearly says, as has already been stated in the first chapter, that the practical utility of this system is that it explains the real nature of phenomenal existence and so enables its followers to recognise the Ultimate Reality. It is, therefore, meant for only those who are seeking the truth, who want to understand the real nature of the &amp;lsquo;apparent&amp;rsquo;. As for those, who are completely engrossed in the worldly activities of momentary interest and, therefore, seek the explanation only of the apparent nature of the apparent, the view point and the method of the Naiyāyikas is the best. The Abhāsavāda holds that each object, as we perceive it, is a momentary collocation of a certain number of abhāsas; that the individual is in reality identical with the Universal Self and as such has no independent will of its own, but acts and moves as the latter makes it do; that whatever is, is ever one with the Universal Self and even when a thing appears to have a separate existence, it is as little independent of the Ultimate as the objects of a dream are of the dreaming self and that the difference between the real and the illusory i. e. between the silver appearing at the sight of a mother-of-pearl and the real silver or between the objects of a dream and those of the wakeful state, is purely conventional; both of them are equally real or unreal; the difference between them is of&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 EFFECTABILITY CAUSAL AND KARMA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/2_PHILOSOPHY/5_EFFECTABILITY_CAUSAL_AND_KARMA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/2_PHILOSOPHY/5_EFFECTABILITY_CAUSAL_AND_KARMA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;5 EFFECTABILITY CAUSAL AND KARMA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER V. THE THEORIES OF EFFECTABILITY CAUSAL AND KARMA.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE ABHĀSAVĀDA AND THE PHYSICAL PHENOMENA.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The two powers of the Maheśvara, namely, the powers of knowledge and action (jñāna and kriyā sakti) are most prominently mentioned in the Saiva literature. The Pratya bhijña Vimarsinī, for instance, is primarily concerned with the exposition of these two powers in its first two voluminous adhikāras. In the preceding chapter we have dealt with the power of knowledge. In this, therefore, we propose to give a brief idea of the power of action.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
