<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/bantu/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/bantu/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Haiti</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/bantu/articles/haiti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/bantu/articles/haiti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Haiti was founded by plantation slaves who fought for independence against the colonial French, defeating Napoleon&amp;rsquo;s army. The slaves were originally kidnapped from Africa &amp;amp; formed 90% of the population.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;France demanded 150 million Francs for the &amp;rsquo;loss&amp;rsquo; of its plantations to the slaves. In contrast, USA paid France 1/10 this amount for Louisiana. The French demand was supported by USA under President Jefferson (fearing slave rebellion in USA), helping enforce an embargo on Haiti with other European powers. Haiti was forced to take a loan at a massive interest from a French bank. In today&amp;rsquo;s terms, Haiti was extorted $30 billion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nemets on expansion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/bantu/articles/nemets_on_expansion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/bantu/articles/nemets_on_expansion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three broad divisions of Bantus - the Southwestern, the West-Central, &amp;amp; the Eastern.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;urewe-kalundu-and-luangwa&#34;&gt;Urewe, Kalundu, and Luangwa&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Urewe was an early Bantu group that reached northern Zambia in 7th century BC. There were related groups in Great Lakes, Tanzania, &amp;amp; Kenya. There were invasions from Bantu groups to west of Urewe in 5th century AD and to east of Urewe in 9th century AD. Urewe were first Bantu group to settle the Zambezi River all the way to Sesheke (red dot on map).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South-iraq settlement</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/bantu/articles/south-iraq-settlement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/bantu/articles/south-iraq-settlement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After centuries of cruel chattel slavery, African slaves rise up to massacre their oppressors. A protracted &amp;amp; bitter war ensues, the rebels taking refuge in the marshes &amp;amp; rivers that surround the now-charred plantations. This is Iraq.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After the Arab conquest of Mesopotamia a military camp was established in the marshlands of southern Iraq. This camp soon grew into the wealthy port city of Basra, the link between Baghdad &amp;amp; the rich lands that lay on the Arabian Sea &amp;amp; beyond. Southern Iraq was once a fertile region, the cradle of the first cities &amp;amp; Sumerian civilization, but flooding &amp;amp; poor upkeep reverted the land to marshes. The wealthy residents of Basra were given ownership of these marshlands on the condition they brought them under cultivation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
