<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Rob Lee on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/rob-lee/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Rob Lee on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/rob-lee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Attrition factor</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/rob-lee/attrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/rob-lee/attrition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rob Lee on why attrition will be a critical factor in the battle for Donbas&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The expert on Russia’s armed forces says Vladimir Putin will struggle to achieve his goals&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apr 23rd 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TWO MONTHS into the war in Ukraine, Russia is still struggling to achieve its goals. Its attempts to take or even surround Kyiv and Odessa have failed. Now it is refocusing its efforts on encircling Ukrainian forces around the Donbas region of eastern Ukraine. But mounting attrition is threatening its ability to achieve even this secondary aim. As the war enters its next stage, who has the upper hand?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Force design</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/rob-lee/force-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/rob-lee/force-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;National security.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For insiders. By insiders.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;RUSSO-UKRAINIAN WAR ABOUT SIGN IN BECOME A MEMBER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NOT BUILT FOR PURPOSE: THE RUSSIAN MILITARY’S ILL-FATED FORCE DESIGN&lt;br&gt;&#xA;MICHAEL KOFMAN AND ROB LEE JUNE 2, 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Summary&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Michael Kofman is director of the Russia Studies Program at CNA and a fellow at the Center for New American Security.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rob Lee is a senior fellow in the Foreign Policy Research Institute’s Eurasia Program. He is a Ph.D. student researching Russian defense policy at King’s College London’s War Studies Department and a former Marine infantry officer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rob Lee notes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/rob-lee/rob-lee-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/rob-lee/rob-lee-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Rob Lee on TW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-and-drones&#34;&gt;2024 and drones&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Without the development and integration of commercial UAVs into a strike role (e.g. FPVs, Mavics, night bomber, etc.) in the Ukrainian military, I think Ukraine could have lost the war in 2024. Russia&amp;rsquo;s recent improvements in its strike drone capabilities is currently one of the most significant and concerning factors on the battlefield. Unclear if they will prove to be a determinant of victory, but drones have played a key role in avoiding defeat so far.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rus contracts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/rob-lee/rus-contracts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/rob-lee/rus-contracts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bbc.global.ssl.fastly.net/russian/features-61848550&#34;&gt;Report&lt;/a&gt; from the BBC on Russian volunteers in Ukraine. They say volunteers can either sign a contract with the Russian military, with Rosgvardia in Chechnya, with LNR/DNR forces (less common because the pay is worse), or join Wagner.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The BBC says that volunteer units are taking part in fighting in some of the most kinetic areas in Ukraine and volunteers generally receive 3-7 days of training. One of the volunteers interviewed said there was no training in tactics and that many volunteers are over 45. Volunteers who join Rosgvardia in Chechnya were provided better training at the Spetsnaz University in Gudermes and signed 3-month contracts. The Rosgvardia volunteer fought in Rubizhne and around Severodonetsk and said Ukrainian mortar and MLRS fire was effective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Warfare changes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/rob-lee/warfare-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/ukraine-invasion/rob-lee/warfare-changes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1531733871850553344.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I completely disagree with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2022/05/ukraine-russia-putin-war/638423/&#34;&gt;this article&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; conclusions, and I think it stems from a misinterpretation of the data. Tanks, fighters, and ships are not &amp;ldquo;being pushed into obsolescence&amp;rdquo; and we are mostly seeing incremental changes in warfare. If you are going to make a bold claim like &amp;ldquo;we are seeing the very nature of combat change&amp;rdquo; you need extraordinary evidence, which this article lacks. Instead, the successes and failures of the Russian and Ukrainian militaries can be explained by well-known principles of war.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
