<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MMP on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/items/articles/mmp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MMP on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/items/articles/mmp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Carb rich - diabetes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/items/articles/mmp/carb-rich_diabetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/items/articles/mmp/carb-rich_diabetes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Body maintains Blood Glucose Homeostasis (balance) with the help of Hormones like Insulin, Glucagon &amp;amp; few others (as shown in the pic). When someone eats a diet dominant in Carbohydrates, more glucose is produced &amp;amp; body is forced to overproduce Insulin to maintain Homeostasis. More Insulin production = More Fat storage. This increased Insulin production eventually leads to Insulin Resistance, due to which the action of the Hormone Insulin gets inhibited to an extent. It is basically like Insulin hijacked the whole Glucose regulation process &amp;amp; made Glucagon a minor player.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coconut-oil</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/items/articles/mmp/coconut-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/items/articles/mmp/coconut-oil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coconut oil is extracted from the dried flesh of the coconut.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is made up of 86 percent saturated fat, 6 percent monounsaturated fat, and 1.4 percent polyunsaturated fat. About half of the saturated fat in it is a rare, special type of saturated fat called lauric acid. It is known as a medium-chain triglyceride or MCT.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;mct&#34;&gt;MCT&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the body, lauric acid converts to monolaurin, one of the compounds found in breast milk that boost a baby’s immune system. It is like superfuel for your cells, your metabolism, your bones, and your brain. MCTs also have been shown to possess antioxidant and antimicrobial properties.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soy - MMP</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/items/articles/mmp/soy_mmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/items/articles/mmp/soy_mmp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1673019793992196096.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;𝗦𝗢𝗬 𝘁𝗿𝘂𝘁𝗵&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Soy is seen by many as a cheap vegetarian/vegan alternative source of Protein &amp;amp; a health food. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at Soy &amp;amp; debug some of these claims.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;protein&#34;&gt;PROTEIN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Unlike other sources of Plant protein, Soy is a complete one.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It has all the 9 essential Amino acids&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;But Soy has less amounts of Sulfur containing Amino acids; Methionine &amp;amp; Cysteine.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Almost half the amount as in eggs (Amino acid profile of Tofu in Pic)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;protease-inhibitors&#34;&gt;PROTEASE INHIBITORS&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Protease is a enzyme that breaks down proteins into amino acids.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beans &amp;amp; many other foods contain Protease Inhibitors. They mess with the action of Proteases.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The 2 main types of protease inhibitors found in soybeans are Kunitz-type trypsin inhibitors and Bowman-Birk inhibitors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The level of protease inhibitors in soybeans can vary depending on the variety of soybean, the processing method, and the storage conditions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heat deactivates most, but not all of the Protease Inhibitors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-flatulence&#34;&gt;❌ FLATULENCE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy, like other beans, are rich in 2 Oligosaccharides (carbs) called Raffinose &amp;amp; Stachyose.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Humans don&amp;rsquo;t have enzyme to digest these properly.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once they reach the large intestine the bacteria ferments it, resulting in production of Gas.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They are heat stable &amp;amp; hence cooking has less effect on them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fermentation can reduce the amount of these sugars, which is why Fermented soy like Tempeh, Natto, Miso etc are less of an issue in this regard.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;phytates&#34;&gt;PHYTATES&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Phytates are compounds found in beans, grains etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;🔴 They prevent premature germination &amp;amp; acts as a phosphorus store.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The problem with phytates is that they bind with minerals like Zinc, Calcium, Magnesium, Iron etc &amp;amp; hinder their absorption.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soybeans contain more phytates than other legumes. 3 times more than Mung beans &amp;amp; 4 times as Chickpea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This is especially problematic for Vegetarians as their diet contains less of Iron, Zinc etc in the first place.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;lectins&#34;&gt;LECTINS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lectins are carbohydrate-binding proteins which are commonly found in plants&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They can attach to specific sugars on the surface of cells, often causing immune system reactions and blood clotting.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy lectins bind to the villi and crypt cells of the small intestine.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This contributes to diminished capacity for digestion and absorption &amp;amp; a shift in the gut microbiome.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lectins when they enter the bloodstream via a leaky gut can cause an immune response.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;phytoestrogens&#34;&gt;PHYTOESTROGENS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Phytoestrogens are compounds in plants that are structurally similar to Estrogen&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Isoflavones are the most common of the Phytoestrogens &amp;amp; its concentration is highest in Soy.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Actual Isoflavone content depends on variety &amp;amp; processing technique&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy phytoestrogens such as genistein can inhibit 17-hydroxysteroidoxido reductase, an enzyme that is required for the synthesis of testosterone.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If consumed in high enough doses or during critical stages of development, they can cause several reproductive disorders.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;goitrogens&#34;&gt;GOITROGENS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Goitrogens are substances that block the synthesis of thyroid hormones.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In Soy, Isoflavones are the main Goitrogen.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They are potent inhibitors of thyroid peroxidase (TPO), an enzyme involved in the synthesis of T3 &amp;amp; T4.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This can cause a drop in the Thyroid hormone levels &amp;amp; an increase in TSH.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Goitrogens also damage thyroid function is by increasing concentrations of thyroid binding globulin (TBG), a plasma protein involved in the inactivation &amp;amp; transport of T3 &amp;amp; T4.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To Summarise:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>uric-acid &amp; gout</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/items/articles/mmp/uric-acid_gout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/items/articles/mmp/uric-acid_gout/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1654841810852941824.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Uric acid is a compound of Carbon- Nitrogen- Hydrogen- Oxygen, that is a product of Metabolism (more later). It is largely excreted through Urine &amp;amp; some of it is broken down by Gut Bacteria.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;biological-role&#34;&gt;Biological role&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is commonly believed that is a waste with no use. that is absolutely NOT true. Uric Acid is biologically active. Uric acid is an important antioxidant &amp;amp; also a marker of tissue injury that acts as one of the regulators of our immune system. It has the highest concentration of any water soluble antioxidants found in our blood(50x powerful thn VitC). When our body is under assault &amp;amp; confronted by an imbalance of free radicals &amp;amp; damaged cells, our body&amp;rsquo;s antioxidant defences &amp;amp; our immune system swing into action in order to put things right.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
