<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Banking on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Banking on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>01 Operation</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/01_Operation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/01_Operation/</guid>
      <description>Capital Bank owners make an investment - this is called the capital. A part of the bank’s capital goes towards increasing the size of the capital.
Liabilities/ Borrowed money They also borrow money from investors - in other words, investors deposit money in a bank. The bank promises a return on investment to the depositor, but this return on investment is but a part of the profit the bank makes using that money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Defaulters</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/02_Defaulters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/02_Defaulters/</guid>
      <description>Banks initially often may try to restructure the debt - allow later payment, increase installments, reduce interest etc..
Recovery attempts Defaulters borrow money from banks but fail to pay back. THen, the bank employs various means - seizing assets of defaulters or better yet those who guaranteed payment, shaming and illegal coercion in some cases to recover the money. Defaulters with political power often get their debts written off.
Collateral [Incomplete]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 Insolvency consequences</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/03_Insolvency_consequences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/03_Insolvency_consequences/</guid>
      <description>An insolvent bank, having made bad investments, is incapable of repaying depositors.
Guarantees Small depositors are guaranteed to get their money back, up to a certain limit- usually by government agencies. But, such guarantees do not protect big investors.
Economic consequences Bad money lending leads to ruin of the lender; sometimes selling ownership of these loans on the stock market, they bring ruin to others: 2008 financial crisis resulted from bad housing loans in USA, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 Foreign deposit accounts in India</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/05_Foreign_deposit_accounts_in_India/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/05_Foreign_deposit_accounts_in_India/</guid>
      <description>Higher interest rates make opening savings account in foreign banks attractive. Repatriability and taxation should be considered.
FCNR Deposits These accounts are held in foreign currency - usually $. They yield a lower interest rate.
NRE rupee Accounts Funds held in the account, interest earned on them and returns from investments using them are fully repatriable. NRE accounts are not taxable in India.
These may be term deposits or savings accounts (yielded 3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>