<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Banking on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Banking on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Operation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/01_Operation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/01_Operation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;capital&#34;&gt;Capital&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bank owners make an investment - this is called the capital. A part of the bank’s capital goes towards increasing the size of the capital.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;liabilities-borrowed-money&#34;&gt;Liabilities/ Borrowed money&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They also borrow money from investors - in other words, investors deposit money in a bank. The bank promises a return on investment to the depositor, but this return on investment is but a part of the profit the bank makes using that money.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Defaulters</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/02_Defaulters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/02_Defaulters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Banks initially often may try to restructure the debt - allow later payment, increase installments, reduce interest etc..&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;recovery-attempts&#34;&gt;Recovery attempts&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Defaulters borrow money from banks but fail to pay back. THen, the bank employs various means - seizing assets of defaulters or better yet those who guaranteed payment, shaming and illegal coercion in some cases to recover the money. Defaulters with political power often get their debts written off.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;collateral&#34;&gt;Collateral&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;Incomplete&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Insolvency consequences</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/03_Insolvency_consequences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/03_Insolvency_consequences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An insolvent bank, having made bad investments, is incapable of repaying depositors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;guarantees&#34;&gt;Guarantees&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Small depositors are guaranteed to get their money back, up to a certain limit- usually by government agencies. But, such guarantees do not protect big investors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;economic-consequences&#34;&gt;Economic consequences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bad money lending leads to ruin of the lender; sometimes selling ownership of these loans on the stock market, they bring ruin to others: 2008 financial crisis resulted from bad housing loans in USA, for example.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 Foreigner accounts in India</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/05_Foreigner_accounts_in_India/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/financial_services/banking/05_Foreigner_accounts_in_India/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Higher interest rates make opening savings account in foreign banks attractive. Repatriability and taxation should be considered.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;regular-accounts&#34;&gt;Regular accounts&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eligibility&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Foreign Nationals who are employed in India can open domestic bank accounts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Non residents can&amp;rsquo;t have this. Once you are an NRI, you must redesignate your resident bank accounts as NRO accounts or NRE accounts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When OCI comes to India with an intention to stay for an indefinite period and stays more than 182 days, he/she loses the privileges available to NRIs/PIOs/OCIs. Such OCI is required re- designate / convert his/her NRE/NRO/FCNR Accounts to resident account, or NRE/FCNB account to RFC account as the case may be.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;nro-rupee-accounts&#34;&gt;NRO rupee Accounts&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eligibility&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Non-resident (including OCI, NRI), International students, Foreign tourists&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;can be opened as a joint account with other Non-Resident Indian(s) and Resident Indians. However only resident close relative can be added as joint account holder in NRO accounts on &amp;ldquo;Former or Survivor&amp;rdquo; basis only.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Funds in this account can be repatriated subject to documentation upto USD 1 Million per financial year.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Credits&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;purpose of depositing income earned in India.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;legitimate dues in India of the account holder like current income like rent, dividend, pension, interest, etc., sale proceeds of assets including immovable property acquired out of rupee/foreign currency funds or by way of legacy/ inheritance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;transfers from rupee accounts of non-resident banks, remittances received in permitted currency from outside India through normal banking channels&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Interest&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;30.9% TDS is levied on the interest earned on NRO accounts. Customers can avail of DTAA benefits on their NRO accounts thereby lowering the TDS on their interest earned (valid Tax Residency Certificate (TRC) for the current year, Form 10F ,PAN &amp;amp; DTAA application letter need to be submitted every financial year)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Debit&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eligible debits include all local payments in rupees&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remittance&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Funds up to USD 1 million (or equivalent) per financial year.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;fcnr-deposits&#34;&gt;FCNR Deposits&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These accounts are held in foreign currency - usually $. They yield a lower interest rate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
