<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;१० on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/10/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;१० on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The other side of the guillotine and other musings</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/10/2005-10-26_the-other-side-of-the-guillotine-and-other-musings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/10/2005-10-26_the-other-side-of-the-guillotine-and-other-musings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/10/26/the-other-side-of-the-guillotine-and-other-musings/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What ever happened after we passed on to the other side of the&#xA;guillotine we were not sure. Evidentally at that point we did not know&#xA;if the guillotine had fallen or not. In reality the English encounter&#xA;was the begining of the troubles. We got past the deployer of the ghora&#xA;dUradR^iShTi vidyA and were resting silently. We then wandered on the&#xA;Deccan plains in the year 2002, when are our armies were still&#xA;unstoppable, and had a brief wandering with the muni who was declining&#xA;towards the abyss. The muni then saved himself and proceeded to the&#xA;central plains. After that the amAtya spotted what may be termed the&#xA;English agent S in the horizon. We encountered S in the context of a&#xA;SNF2/SWI2 proteins with a PHD finger. Agent S’s progress was remarkably&#xA;lackluster and took things very lightly. But soon S captured us with the&#xA;indrajAla and on Nov 6th 2001 around 6.30 PM we had a dramatic showdown.&#xA;We were using a ricketty old SUN workstation and the machine crashed&#xA;mysteriously 3 times when we were composing something important, yet we&#xA;failed to get the signal. In the bind of indrajAla we were neither&#xA;communicating with the muni nor R, so the message of the jAnashruteya&#xA;birds did not reach us. So we were taken by surprise and hit by the&#xA;tAmasa-dhUma at that time. For 6 days we did not known what had seized&#xA;us. Then gradually with atharvaNa hR^idaya we emerged out of the pAshas&#xA;of agent S and completely overcame S. We then wandered on the Deccan&#xA;plains in the year 2002, when are our armies were still unstoppable, and&#xA;had a brief wandering with the muni who was declining towards the abyss.&#xA;The muni then saved himself and proceeded to the central plains. We then&#xA;faced the duSTa rAkShasi in the battle of chaitya and were again pinned&#xA;down for 6 days in August of 2002, but wriggled our way out of the&#xA;trouble. We were advancing towards the great swell of the AAA+ ATPases&#xA;(codenamed project POSTBOX) when agent Auriga was sighted by the AmAtya&#xA;and shachIva. We wriggled out of the Auriga trap but were ambushed at&#xA;the most fierce battle of the pAShaNDa hill of which we have spoken many&#xA;times. At that point we mused about the fall of the guillotine.&#xA;Subsequent to that there was a period of silence as the shachIva and&#xA;amAtya were fooled by the dreadful grAhi. Then due to the fateful slip&#xA;we faced the dhumAvatI prayoga. In the mean time Jx had already been&#xA;shattered by the dhUmavatI and became unmatta. Mn of greatest power and&#xA;intelligence was subdued by the uchChuShma. The piShAchi was sucking us&#xA;dry, and it looked as though we were hanging as though from a spider’s&#xA;web.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The last journey</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/10/2005-10-24_the-last-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/10/2005-10-24_the-last-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/10/24/the-last-journey/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.intratext.com/IXT/SAN0010/LM.HTM&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Having completed his&#xA;existence as he has passed into the lists of pitR^is, joining the line&#xA;of AN^girasas and ikShvAkus of yore (Ardra kR^iShNa ShaShTi; Ashvina&#xA;mAsa; kali yuga 5106).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;imaM yama prastaramA hi sIdAN^girobhiH pitRbhiHsaMvidAnaH /&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A tvA mantrAH kavishastA vahantvenA rAjanhaviShA mAdayasva //&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Come, sit on this bed of grass, O yama, along with the AN^girasas, the&#xA;fathers.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;let the mantras recited by the kavis bring you O king yama, let this&#xA;oblation make you happy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the pits of khANDava</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/10/2005-10-20_in-the-pits-of-khandava/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/10/2005-10-20_in-the-pits-of-khandava/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/10/20/in-the-pits-of-khandava/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The amAtya’s spells had provided a temporary respite by completely smothering the sapatna’s fury. But finally the amAtya’s charms were broken by the counter-attack and the sapatna advanced right to our most critical fort. We felt that the capital could last only a matter of days in the worst case and we were also besieged by an army of mlechChas. We had gathered our last reserves in our defensive line of forts for the long struggle and then decided to make a surprise sally on the mlechCha as soon as the first chance availed itself and tried to break past their cordon to reach the defensive forts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The full moon rambling</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/10/2005-10-20_the-full-moon-rambling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/10/2005-10-20_the-full-moon-rambling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/10/20/the-full-moon-rambling/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the past fullmoon several years ago when we were still young we were seated in the pleasant company of the apsaras and drinking the wonderful pAyasa. We were yarning about the events in the mundane plane of existence, when the foremost of the sutanUs asked what was the simplest chaturti vrata to the terrible ulka and how may it be performed. We found the appropriate answer for the same after some thought. It is the ulka vrata of oM gaH svAhA. It may be done by all to attain release from vighnas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>eko mAnusha AnandaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/10/2005-10-16_eko-manusha-anandah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/10/2005-10-16_eko-manusha-anandah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/10/16/eko-manusha-anandah/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With almost an year passing since the Great Fall we reflect upon him who&#xA;acquired “eko mAnuSha AnandaH” that is alluded to in the texts. He lived&#xA;once upon a time beside the swamp with snakes and crocodilians in it. He&#xA;was of immense intelligence and physical abilities, and he was capable&#xA;of performing complex rites. He was set on the path of knowing the&#xA;truth. He was recognized for his speed and agility and was recruited&#xA;amongst the able ones. But in his quest for the truth he decided to&#xA;understand the universe. He then was given a wife by the gods who was a&#xA;female mirror image of his in intellect and ability. Together they&#xA;understood many higher truths over a range of most fundamental matters.&#xA;He was given a good mansion by the rAjan, and placed in a wonderful&#xA;village with his family, along with several sacks of gold. He lived&#xA;surrounded by the greatest intellectuals of his time constantly&#xA;discussing the most profound topics and enjoying pleasant conversation.&#xA;He was exceedingly virile and sired several kids, who were also high in&#xA;intellectual accomplisment. The resources showered on him by the rAjan,&#xA;and the intellectual abilities of himself, his wife and children allowed&#xA;him to uncover the greatest mysteries of existence. He knew all of&#xA;stars, galaxies, quasars, planets, organisms, molecules and particles.&#xA;The rAjan used to personally invite him to his palace along with his&#xA;clan and bestow favors upon them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>yakShiNi and R^ikShakarNi … the journey continues</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/10/2005-10-15_yakshini-and-rikshakarni-the-journey-continues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/10/2005-10-15_yakshini-and-rikshakarni-the-journey-continues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/10/15/yakshini-and-rikshakarni-the-journey-continues/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having been trapped with the ghoraprakR^iti we sought to escape on that rainy day. After the passage through the kAlaChidras and the many paths had been sealed there was a single path winding through naraka. The old bystanders such as Dom, Vidrum, Damar and Blackie were all faintly heard from behind an oppressive screen of darkness. Some were crying as though being tortured by a turushka, others were laughing uncontrollably, as though they had imbibed bhang, others were yelling as though they were jostling in kAma. On the sides of the path were rotting corpses and dermestid beetles making short work of them. There were skulls and femurs scattered around. There were jackals and hyaenas yelling out their moans. We kept walking like a pAshupata had shut off his senses to the surroundings. There we saw a corpse of the most beautiful lolanayanA and then we passed the carcass of shvetamohinI which was being consumed by a varAha. Then we saw a crooked stump on which sat a vetAla which laughed horribly. Shortly after that the great gandharva vishvAvasu passed our path. He pointed to the crooked stump and laughed and flew away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>yakShiNi and R^ikShakarNi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/10/2005-10-14_yakshini-and-rikshakarni/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/10/2005-10-14_yakshini-and-rikshakarni/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/10/14/yakshini-and-rikshakarni/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having been trapped with the ghoraprakR^iti we sought to escape on that rainy day. After the passage through the kAlaChidras the many paths and had been sealed and there was a single path winding through naraka. The old bystanders such as Dom, Vidrum, Damar and Blackie were all faintly heard from behind an oppressive screen of darkness. Some were crying as though being tortured by a turushka, others were laughing uncontrollably, as though they had imbibed bhang, others were yelling as though they were jostling in kAma. On the sides of the path were rotting corpses and dermestid beetles making short work of them. There were skulls and femurs scattered around. There were jackals and hyaenas yelling out their moans. We kept walking like a pAshupata had shut off his senses to the surroundings. There we saw a corpse of the most beautiful lolanayanA and then we passed the carcass of shvetamohinI which as being consumed by a varAha. Then we saw a crooked stump on which sat a vetAla which laughed horribly. Shortly after that the great gandharva vishvAvasu passed our path. He pointed to the crooked stump and laughed and flew away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
