<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hindus Abroad on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hindus Abroad on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fiji</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/fiji/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/fiji/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;In Fiji, H mistake was family planning + not joining army during ww2, at 1 pt it was 51% Indian. Indians had a higher TFR. During WW2 Brits opened up army but these idiots demanded equal pay where as natives joined up &amp;amp; gained full ctrl of army. Also Indian TFR fell below Fijian &amp;quot; -SP17 &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Prior to World War II, soldiers served voluntarily and were paid &amp;ldquo;capitation grants&amp;rdquo; according to efficiency ratings without regard to race. In 1939, during the mobilisation of the Fiji Defence Force, the British Royal Military changed its payment system to four shillings per day for enlisted men of European descent while enlisted men of non-European descent were paid only two shillings per day. Indian platoon readily disputed this disparity in pay. The British, fearing this dissidence would eventually be shared by the Native Fijians, decided to disband the Indian platoon in 1940 citing lack of available equipment, such as military armour, as their reason.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mittani</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/mittAni/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/mittAni/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Mitanni kingdom was referred to as the &amp;ldquo;Maryannu&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Nahrin&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Mitanni&amp;rdquo; by the Egyptians, the &amp;ldquo;Hurri&amp;rdquo; by the Hittites, and the &amp;ldquo;Hanigalbat&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Hani-Rabbat&amp;rdquo; by the Assyrians.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Hittite conquest of Aleppo (Yamhad), the weak middle Assyrian kings who succeeded Puzur-Ashur III, and the internal strife of the Hittites had created a power vacuum in upper Mesopotamia. This led to the formation of the kingdom of Mitanni.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;ia-identification&#34;&gt;IA identification&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A treatise on the training of chariot horses by Kikkuli, a Mitanni writer, contains a number of Indo-Aryan glosses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pAkistAn</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/pAkistAn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/pAkistAn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Caste of Pakistani Hindus based on the 2017 Census. 81% (3.6 million) of all Pakistani Hindus are from &amp;lsquo;Upper Caste&amp;rsquo; backgrounds while 19% (850k) are from Scheduled Caste backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Through network of clerics, word is spreading fast across villages in Sindh province to not buy house of Hindu family because they are going to go anyway as migration to India has increased. In villages where 1 or 2 Hindu families are left, it’s become particularly tough to sell. - Swati 2023&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roma/ Gypsy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/roma_gypsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/roma_gypsy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;genetics&#34;&gt;Genetics&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The roma are 50% non indian in romania. once you get to a place like england or finland the s. asian component is small.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steppe remnants</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/steppe_remnants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/steppe_remnants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;kurus&#34;&gt;Kurus&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There were people with uniquely Indian admixture operating even in Central Asia around the time of the Aryan transition. This suggests that Indo-Aryan power was actually straddling their steppe base &amp;amp; northern India. I believe the memory of the former is that of the uttara-kuru-s. &amp;hellip; [I] hold that a branch of these steppe kuru-s re-emerged with another allied clan the kamboja much later on the Iranians side to form the elite of the hAkamAnashIya dynasty. - MT&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
