<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Bad neo-pagans on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/bad-neo-pagans/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Bad neo-pagans on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/bad-neo-pagans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aliakai on Indica</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/bad-neo-pagans/aliakai_on_indica/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/bad-neo-pagans/aliakai_on_indica/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mythoughtsbornfromfire.wordpress.com/2021/12/08/on-indica-and-edward-butler/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On Indica and Edward Butler&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There were a few topics relating to the Pagan community that I thought of talking about here, and it seems that the most pressing concerns a controversy relating to an organization known as Indica, an umbrella of apparent polytheist organizations including the Indic Academy, of which Edward Butler, a polytheist academic and the proprietor of a website about Neoplatonic polytheism called Henadology, is a director. Indica bills themselves as “an institute for global study of indigenous knowledge, seeking to bring about a renaissance of indigenous wisdom”. We might infer from this that they are, at least in theory, advocates for indigenous religious belief systems, and thereby for polytheism, though they actually seem to focus particularly on Hinduism, so I’m theory at least you might think of them as a Hindu advocacy group. In any case, Indica recently hosted a conference entitled Conference on Polytheism Today &amp;amp; Tomorrow: Dialogues on Pluralism and Polytheist Art, hosted by Edward Butler and consisting of a series of discussions from different polytheist voices coming from a variety of traditional backgrounds. It was honestly a very good opportunity to hear perspectives from the world of modern polytheism. That’s why it’s such a shame to report that, some time after that conference, a problem emerged when apparent connections between Indica and the Hindutva movement were brought to everyone’s attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chelydoreus on Indica</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/bad-neo-pagans/chelydoreus_on_indica/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/bad-neo-pagans/chelydoreus_on_indica/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://hellenicmagicalpath.blogspot.com/2021/12/a-statement-on-indica-controversy.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A statement on the Indica controversy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you know, last May I was awarded a fellowship grant for the development of my project “The New Mysteries of Hekate-Despoina” from Indic Academy’s Center for Global Polytheist and Indigenous Traditions led by Dr. Edward Butler. As part of my contractual obligations relating to that grant, I also participated in the online Conference for Polytheism Today and Tomorrow: Dialogues on Pluralism and Polytheist Art, alongside many others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ptahmassu on Indica conference</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/bad-neo-pagans/ptahmassu_on_indica-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/bad-neo-pagans/ptahmassu_on_indica-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scribe.iconsofkmt.com/post/words-on-the-indica-controversy&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Words On the Indica Controversy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although I have very succinctly addressed this issue in a thread on Twitter, I realize that my statement did not have the clarity or strength I intended, and that something more substantial is required. With such a weighty issue touching many people in the Pagan and polytheist communities at this time, the last thing I wish to do is cause further distress or harm to anyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
