<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Eating on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/eating/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Eating on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/eating/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Elimination diet</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/eating/elimination_diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/eating/elimination_diet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-meat-base&#34;&gt;A meat base&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main reason a Carnivore Diet heals is that it cuts out all food sensitivities in the diet, not that all non-ASF (animal sourced food) is bad. People who have a wide sensitivity to plants benefit because it cuts out all potential food triggers. Meat is the least problematic food group. Carnivory works to reduce inflammation, autoimmune conditions and gut issues. Essentially, only eating meat is an elimination diet – and elimination diets work. Take the base diet &amp;amp; expand from there. There is no need to personalise the base. - GA&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fasting</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/eating/Fasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/eating/Fasting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;exclusions&#34;&gt;Exclusions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pregnant women beware:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Muslim children exposed to Ramadan fasting in utero during first trimester had significantly lower scores in maths, reading, and writing tests (taken at the age of 7 years) than Muslim children who were not exposed to Ramadan fasting in utero.&amp;rdquo; /&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another extensive census-based study of Muslim populations in Uganda (n = 80,000) and Iraq (n = 250,000) demonstrated that exposure to Ramadan fasting during the first month of pregnancy increased the risk of mental or learning disability in offspring by 50% and psychological disability by 63%! Additionally, a large study on Indonesian women indicated that exposure to Ramadan during pregnancy resulted in smaller statures and thinness in adulthood. Lower birth weight is directly linked to impaired cognitive function. For example, research has shown that Muslim children exposed to Ramadan fasting in utero during the first trimester had significantly lower scores in maths, reading, and writing tests (taken in primary schools at the age of 7 years) than Muslim children who were not exposed to Ramadan fasting in utero.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hunger management</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/eating/hunger-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/eating/hunger-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;glycemic-index&#34;&gt;Glycemic index&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;..postprandial glucose dips are common &amp;amp; lead to increased hunger and energy consumption in real-world conditions&amp;rdquo;. i.e. Rebound Hypo - one of the negatives effect of a high carb meal (breakfast/lunch) is it makes you more hungry.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pple have different responses to the same amount of calories (big dipper and little dippers).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/eating/Quantity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/eating/Quantity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Around 2240.7 calories per day required to maintain 125 lb weight in 68 inch body.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ati-bhakShaNAt prAptA nidrAvasthA.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;eating-out&#34;&gt;Eating out&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most restaurants and food venues give more than enough food for one meal. Don’t eat it all at once. When eating out, take home leftovers have 2 meals for the price of 1.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
