<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;1 The Genesis of the Question on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/1_The_Genesis_of_the_Question/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;1 The Genesis of the Question on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/1_The_Genesis_of_the_Question/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/1_The_Genesis_of_the_Question/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/1_The_Genesis_of_the_Question/1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before the Southern Question: &amp;ldquo;Native&amp;rdquo; Ideas on Backwardness and Remedies in the Kingdom of Two Sicilies, 1815–1849&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Marta Petrusewicz *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently, a historian wrote that &amp;ldquo;the Southern Question was not born with the political unification of Italy; it had its roots in the history of the Mezzogiorno&amp;rdquo; (De Rosa 1993: v). But this is an unusual position. For most scholars today, the &amp;ldquo;Question,&amp;rdquo; understood as a global representation of the Mezzogiorno&amp;rsquo;s people and heritage, was born after 1860, in the wake of the Risorgimento. The arguments are mainly about what there was in the process of Unification that caused the &amp;ldquo;Question&amp;rdquo; to crystallize as a discourse. Some scholars, following the well-known thesis of Emilio Sereni (1974), claim that, by broadening the market, unification simply exposed what was already there — namely the structural &amp;ldquo;backwardness&amp;rdquo; of the southern economy. Others, in the Gramscian tradition, see Unification and its aftermath as having provided an opportunity for southern agrarian conservative interests to strike a mutually advantageous alliance with northern industrialists; this so-called &amp;ldquo;historical bloc&amp;rdquo; in turn caused the economic dualism that condemned the South to the role of a permanent periphery. Yet others, influenced by the dependency school, interpret unification as straightforward colonization. In one, economically-oriented, version of this scenario, northern colonizers forcibly destroyed the existing industries of the South in order to turn the Mezzogiorno into an outlet for northern commodities and a source of cheap and compliant labor. In a second, more political version, the emphasis is placed on the &amp;ldquo;conquest of the South,&amp;rdquo; the conqueror overthrowing, &lt;em&gt;manu militari&lt;/em&gt;, a legitimate southern dynasty and pillaging the territory that was defeated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/1_The_Genesis_of_the_Question/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/1_The_Genesis_of_the_Question/2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Emergence of the Southern Question in Villari, Franchetti, and Sonnino&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Nelson Moe *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the second half of the 1870s, Pasquale Villari, Leopoldo Franchetti, and Sidney Sonnino elaborated a new vision of southern Italy. Their writings articulated for the first time the regional specificity of the social, political, and economic conditions of the South, inaugurating both the Southern Question and the field of &lt;em&gt;meridionalismo&lt;/em&gt;. While these three men were pioneers in setting the terms of a question and a field &amp;ldquo;that situates the South at the center of its analysis and, even more importantly, at the center of national political life&amp;rdquo; (Barbagallo 1979: 7), it is important to note that their work formed part of a broader cultural trend. Over the course of the 1870s, the South increasingly attracted the attention of folklorists, visual artists, and writers, most notably Giovanni Verga. What marks this decade is the proliferation of discursive and pictorial representations of the South in a variety of fields. While this essay does not explore the relations between the emergence of &lt;em&gt;meridionalismo&lt;/em&gt; and the representation of the South in these other domains, this is the broader context in which the Meridionalist writings of Villari, Franchetti, and Sonnino can be framed.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/1_The_Genesis_of_the_Question/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/1_The_Genesis_of_the_Question/3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How Many Italies? Representing the South in Official Statistics&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Silvana Patriarca *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the introduction to a collection of essays significantly titled &lt;em&gt;Mezzogiorno senza meridionalismo&lt;/em&gt;, Giuseppe Giarrizzo has recently recalled the circumstances in which a &lt;em&gt;meridionalista&lt;/em&gt; discourse first emerged. The first articulation of the &amp;ldquo;Southern Question&amp;rdquo; was the work of some representatives of the Historic Right who were reacting to the defeat of their party in the southern regions in the elections of 1874, a defeat that paved the way for the Historic Left to attain power in 1876. Far from being a realization of the socio-economic &amp;ldquo;backwardness&amp;rdquo; of the South, the descriptions and denunciations of the conditions of the South produced by conservative reformers such as Pasquale Villari, Leopoldo Franchetti, and Sidney Sonnino in the mid-1870s would essentially represent a political indictment of the southern élites (too corrupt, in their views, to be able to ensure a good government of the country). According to Giarrizzo, there was indeed no perception of a fundamental economic and social dualism of North and South in the 1860s and early 1870s; this perception appeared only later, and was then read back into this earlier period (Giarrizzo 1992: xv). The Southern Question in its beginning would thus be a largely political construct. In this discourse the South was a symbol, a signifier whose referent is to be found essentially in the politics of its makers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/1_The_Genesis_of_the_Question/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/1_The_Genesis_of_the_Question/4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Biology or Environment? Race and Southern &amp;ldquo;Deviancy&amp;rdquo; in the Writings of Italian Criminologists, 1880–1920&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Mary Gibson *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Mafia is a Sicilian variant of the ancient &lt;em&gt;Camorra&lt;/em&gt;, a variant shaped perhaps by a more tenacious adherence to secrecy, typical of the Semitic race (Lombroso 1896—7, Vol. 1: 621).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is to the African and Eastern elements (except the Greeks), that Italy owes, fundamentally, the greater frequency of homicides in Calabria, Sicily and Sardinia, while the least occur where the Nordic races predominate (Lombardy) (Lombroso 1896-7, Vol. 3: 30).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/1_The_Genesis_of_the_Question/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/1_The_Genesis_of_the_Question/5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Homo Siculus: Essentialism in the Writing of Giovanni Verga, Giuseppe Tomasi Di Lampedusa, and Leonardo Sciascia&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Frank Rosengarten *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this essay is to shed critical light on the forms of essentialism and fatalism that inhere in the writing of three Sicilian novelists, Giovanni Verga, Giuseppe Tornasi di Lampedusa, and Leonardo Sciascia. I shall be looking at the two twentieth-century novelists mainly through the prism of their nineteenth-century predecessor, in order to highlight themes present in Verga that will be taken up again but in rather different ways, by Sciascia and Lampedusa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
