<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;१२ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2003/12/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;१२ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2003/12/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Melancholy Eve</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2003/12/2003-12-08_melancholy-eve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2003/12/2003-12-08_melancholy-eve/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/12/08/melancholy-eve/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The yellow autumn had slipped by silently. The white cover brought with&#xA;it the short days of diablerie, and the old curse of another shivarAtri&#xA;passing by was apparent. A coin fell without any apparent reason, but&#xA;the omen was hardly understandable. Four roads crossed at a certain&#xA;point in the southern boundary of the kingdom of the Assakas of yore. On&#xA;side of one of those roads was a buffalo shed and on the other the&#xA;shrine of the tribal buffalo lord, Mahsoba. At the crossing of the four&#xA;roads was the shrine of The deva. With respect to The deva one is not&#xA;sure if one has commited a mistake. In any case the periodic curse of&#xA;the gods fell on the victim. The curse drew the power of the victim in&#xA;the tenth battle after two. In the 15th battle too it blunted the&#xA;strength of the victim.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The wonder house</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2003/12/2003-12-01_the-wonder-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2003/12/2003-12-01_the-wonder-house/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/12/01/the-wonder-house/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was late summer or early autumn in the year of dvAdashAnta. R and I&#xA;went to that house in the afternoon. Our acquaintences were busy trying&#xA;to prepare for some exam, which at least to us seemed distant. They were&#xA;chattering about text books, tuitions and other quintessentially Indian&#xA;fascinations. We suddenly broke away from the chatter of the plebeians.&#xA;The dark one who tended to be with me decided to go away to immerse&#xA;himself in this more mundane business. So R and I set up the microscope&#xA;and observed the drop of water we had obtained from the Hydra pond.&#xA;There was a large Euglenozoan flagellate going its way that caught our&#xA;attention. There was the usual crowd of Bodoid flagellates and the&#xA;occasional ciliate. That large Eugelenozoa with its starch granules&#xA;continues to fascinate us after many years. This went on for a while.&#xA;Then we walked out of the house moved over the curving road with our&#xA;scooters. We stopped at high point. Then we walked past the temples of&#xA;The god’s fierce son and wife on the hill facing the setting sun. We&#xA;came to a circlet of stones laid there by the megalithic mourners of&#xA;yore. We looked at the yonder mists and could faintly discern the dark&#xA;outline left behind from Tughlaq’s invasion. To match the ambience R&#xA;narrated to me Conan Doyle’s tale about the Roman woman and the&#xA;barbarian in England. I asked her if she felt something like that may&#xA;happen. She did not want to confess it but seemed to tacitly admit&#xA;belief in such things. We sat on stones of the megalithic cairn and to&#xA;my mind came the thought of auvvaiyAr’s poem to the dead tamil warlord&#xA;adiyamAn neDuman anchi after he was placed under such a vIra kallu. We&#xA;then returned to seeing leafhoppers and salticids and the like.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
