<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०८ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/08/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०८ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/08/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The hand of fate</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/08/2006-08-29_the-hand-of-fate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/08/2006-08-29_the-hand-of-fate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/08/29/the-hand-of-fate/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After much struggle our forces fought their way to a strong position on&#xA;the front of the dvayaM daNDakAH. We were close to taking this much&#xA;desired and important outpost after a really long drawn conflict. But,&#xA;just then the news reached us on the khANDavan front that something we&#xA;always suspected from the fateful day of Nov 30, 2004 was true. It put&#xA;us in an even more complicated mess on that front. What struck us in&#xA;hindsight was that how despite knowing everything fairly accurately&#xA;before hand we kept committing mistake after mistake in our actions. We&#xA;could today clearly see what the Hindus call the hand of fate dragging&#xA;us into the morass, despite us having seen the bog from a over a mile&#xA;away. It taught us that foresight and rational decisiveness does&#xA;necessarily translate into the right path if the flow of fate is against&#xA;it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Injun’s revenge</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/08/2006-08-20_the-injuns-revenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/08/2006-08-20_the-injuns-revenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/08/20/the-injuns-revenge/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a long time we spoke and she had much to say. She had given up&#xA;active science, had been on travels to far of places, then worked as a&#xA;clerk in her ancestral confectionary business and finally settled as a&#xA;village school teacher in sublimely desolate expanse in the depths of&#xA;Texas.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;….&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Charlotte had an impressive collection of stone weapons and tools made&#xA;by the ancient Americans, which she had showed during expedition we had&#xA;made to the expanses that lay beyond Lubbock. She had pointed many heaps&#xA;and tumuli and mentioned that they housed the ghosts of long dead&#xA;Injuns, who had been killed by the Whites or had died of their own. She&#xA;expressed considerable fear about them. Later when R and me had made the&#xA;great Texan expedition by road we halted to rest in Charlotte’s mansion.&#xA;Charlotte’s people were of Germanic origin who still retained vestiges&#xA;of their old Tongue and more prominently vestiges of their pre-Christian&#xA;past. Some gifts were exchanged: Charlotte gave us sweets and jams from&#xA;her clan’s confectionary. R duely presented to Charlotte a North Indian&#xA;dress which she wanted. Charlotte also gave me a bicycle. Sadly, I alone&#xA;did not give her anything despite enjoying her hospitality and largess.&#xA;I thought I might have offended her, but luckily she did not mistake me.&#xA;For some reason R told me that it was a HUGE mistake I was making by not&#xA;giving Charlotte anything in return and that I must buy something and&#xA;give her in return. Charlotte, me and R were eating icecream after&#xA;dinner in their porch on the bright fullmoon night when she asked about&#xA;the 3 questions. R was highly embarassed and blushing like crazy then,&#xA;but Charlotte nodded her head in approval and said if you fail to use&#xA;the 3 questions you might have a terrible fate like digging up the&#xA;Injun’s grave.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The circle of yakShiNI-s</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/08/2006-08-17_the-circle-of-yakshini-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/08/2006-08-17_the-circle-of-yakshini-s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/08/17/the-circle-of-yakshini-s/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We bow to the great goddess of the trotalottaraM and pay worship to the&#xA;great throng of yakShiNI-s that emerge from her. The yakShiNI-s are of&#xA;diverse forms, all very wonderful and amazing. They bear many diverse&#xA;facets of knowledge — he who can acquire them all becomes sarva-vyApin.&#xA;But the knowledge is not easily acquired from the yakShiNI. There are so&#xA;many ways in which they slip away after it has been shown to you by her.&#xA;After you land from the flight of the yakShiNI, it may evaporate from&#xA;you. Or in the delusion of the wonderous form of the yakShiNI, the&#xA;knowledge might escape from you. Some wonderous yakShiNI-s carry what&#xA;may be called “useless knowledge”. It can be endlessly fascinating but&#xA;cannot be acquired by those not fit for it, or knowing it takes you down&#xA;a path a failure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jIvamUlIya pa~ncha-koNaM cha shulbArIya halaM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/08/2006-08-12_jivamuliya-pancha-konam-cha-shulbariya-halam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/08/2006-08-12_jivamuliya-pancha-konam-cha-shulbariya-halam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/08/12/jivamuliya-pancha-konam-cha-shulbariya-halam/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We were ruing the crushing defeat on the field code-named jIvamUlIya&#xA;pa~ncha-koNaM cha shulbArIya halaM by the five mlechCha attackers. We&#xA;felt like Shivaji after the great fort of Purandar was taken by the&#xA;ghazis. While we sat ruing our defeat and the loss of the small but&#xA;strong force sent to wrest the pa~nchakoNa and shulbArIya hala that we&#xA;much desired, we wished that indra give us victory here. We knew that GS&#xA;of boundless energy, the descendent of the great dIkshita, was a man who&#xA;had attained eko-mAnuSha AnandaH. He was never happy though constantly&#xA;seeking new gaviShTi-s for dhana. We hence thought of our shiShya of&#xA;great wealth again and hatched a plan for revenge. We told him that all&#xA;wealth in the gaviShTi was deservedly his, though we wanted the yasha of&#xA;jayam and more importantly the coveted pa~nchakoNa and ekakoNa. We&#xA;arranged for a secret force, small but fierce, to be gathered again. We&#xA;were suffering from the crane-arrow plowing through us as a result of&#xA;the disasterous khANDavan battle, but GS promised to fight on our&#xA;pakSha. We equipped him with astra-s as we did before the gaviShTi-s in&#xA;which he gained his mahAdhana and asked him to boldly advance with a&#xA;raiding party of his own. His dauntless cousin of droNa-like tenacity&#xA;joined him in the raid with another small raiding party. We then waited&#xA;till GS and his troops surprised the mlechCha enemies, who had nothing&#xA;but deep hate and contempt for us. mlechCha who thought we were&#xA;completely annihilated laughed at first, but seeing GS and his cousin&#xA;shake their ranks, were taken aback. At that critical point we&#xA;dispatched our hidden force to join the fray in a merciless assault.&#xA;bhImadviSha, the mlechCha chief was killed right away and two more were&#xA;slain after him. GS closed in capture the rest and we hope to seize the&#xA;pa~nchakoNa and ekakoNa from them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The links in the chain</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/08/2006-08-02_the-links-in-the-chain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/08/2006-08-02_the-links-in-the-chain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/08/02/the-links-in-the-chain/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our ancestors went to the great asura medhira when they were in such a&#xA;state. But this time we went to deva indra. We extolled the great&#xA;vR^itrahan: you who gave the yati-s to hyaenas, you who smashed the&#xA;forts of the dAsas, you who slaughtered the arurmaghas, you who&#xA;extirpated prahlAda and the pulomas, we offer sacrifice to you. We wish&#xA;to know what happended after we moved beyond the battle pAShaNda&#xA;parvata. maghavan said you shall know thus:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
