<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;2 The Mongol World War: 1211–1261 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/2_The_Mongol_World_War_12111261/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;2 The Mongol World War: 1211–1261 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/2_The_Mongol_World_War_12111261/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>4 Spitting on the Golden Khan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/2_The_Mongol_World_War_12111261/4_Spitting_on_the_Golden_Khan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/2_The_Mongol_World_War_12111261/4_Spitting_on_the_Golden_Khan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The hooves of our Mongol horses go everywhere.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;They climb to the heaven and plunge into the sea.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;YELÜ CHUCAI, 1237&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IN 1210, THE YEAR of the Horse and the forty-eighth year of the life of Genghis Khan and the fourth year of his new nation, a delegation arrived at the Mongol encampment to proclaim the ascension of a new Golden Khan to the Jurched throne and demand the submission of Genghis Khan and the Mongols as a vassal nation. From their capital city of Zhongdu, where modern Beijing now rises, the Jurched dynasty, founded nearly a century earlier in 1125, ruled Manchuria and much of modern-day Inner Mongolia and northern China. As a tribal people themselves from the forests of Manchuria, they claimed sovereignty over all the tribes of the steppe. Ong Khan had offered allegiance to them in the past, and the Jurched seemed eager to reassert their superiority over Genghis Khan, who had replaced Ong Khan as the dominant figure among the nomads of the steppe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Sultan Versus Khan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/2_The_Mongol_World_War_12111261/5_Sultan_Versus_Khan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/2_The_Mongol_World_War_12111261/5_Sultan_Versus_Khan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;War for the nomadic people was a sort of production.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For the warriors it meant success and riches.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SECHEN JAGCHID,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Essays in Mongolian Studies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GENGHIS KHAN SET OUT to the west, heading for Khwarizm in 1219, the Year of the Rabbit, and arrived with the following spring in the Year of the Dragon, when he crossed the desert to suddenly appear deep behind enemy lines at Bukhara. Before the year ended, the Mongols had taken every major city in the Khwarizm empire, and its sultan lay abandoned and dying on a small island out in the Caspian Sea where he had sought refuge from the relentless hounding by Genghis Khan’s warriors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 The Discovery and</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/2_The_Mongol_World_War_12111261/6_The_Discovery_and/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/2_The_Mongol_World_War_12111261/6_The_Discovery_and/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Conquest of Europe&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For our sins, unknown tribes came.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CHRONICLE OF NOVGOROD, 1224&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IN THE SPIRIT OF inebriated generosity at the celebration of his installation as Great Khan, Ogodei threw open his father’s treasury and riotously distributed all the riches stored there. He passed out pearls, the gem most admired by the Mongols, by the casket loads. Bolts of silk cloth were thrown out among the people. Horses and camels were decorated in great finery, and all the Mongols had new silk &lt;em&gt;deels&lt;/em&gt; embroidered with golden threads. They had so many beautiful colors that each day the courtiers could all wear the same color, and then the next day a different color was prescribed. They drank, feasted, and played games throughout the summer of 1229 at Avarga, where storehouses had been erected to serve as a treasury for some of the tremendous amount of loot sent back from Genghis Khan’s campaigns. The days of blue and green and white and yellow silks rolled one into the other, as the most powerful family in the world celebrated itself. To lubricate the event, the alcohol flowed without pause. Men and women drank until they passed out; they slept a while, and then resumed drinking when they awoke.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Warring Queens</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/2_The_Mongol_World_War_12111261/7_Warring_Queens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/2_The_Mongol_World_War_12111261/7_Warring_Queens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just as God gave different fingers to the hand so has&lt;br&gt;&#xA;He given different ways to men.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MONGKE KHAN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WHILE THE MONGOL men stayed busy on the battlefield conquering foreign countries, women managed the empire. Among the herding tribes, women traditionally managed the affairs at home while men went off to herd, hunt, or fight, and although the war campaigns now lasted for years rather than months and the home consisted of not merely a collection of &lt;em&gt;ger&lt;/em&gt; camps but a vast empire, women continued to rule. Aside from Russia and eastern Europe, where the fighting continued the heaviest during Ogodei’s reign, women assumed administration of all remaining parts of the Mongol Empire. Despite the rivalry with Ogodei Khan, Sorkhokhtani, the widow of Genghis Khan’s youngest son, Tolui, ruled northern China and eastern Mongolia, including the family homeland where Genghis Khan grew up. Ebuskun, the widow of Genghis Khan’s second son, Chaghatai, ruled Central Asia or Turkestan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
