<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AfghAn rAjesh kumAr</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/afghAn-rAjesh-kumAr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/afghAn-rAjesh-kumAr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Hindu of Kabul, Pandit Rajesh Kumar of Rattan Nath Temple, refuses to leave amid Taliban takeover&lt;br&gt;&#xA;August 16, 2021&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The Commune&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the Afghanistan government of Ashraf Ghani capitulated to the Taliban on Sunday (August 15), one Hindu priest whose family has been in charge of the Rattan Nath temple has refused to be evacuated from Kabul.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pandit Rajesh Kumar, the priest of Rattan Nath Temple in Kabul said, “Some Hindus have urged me to leave Kabul and offered to arrange for my travel and stay.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brit age colonization pattern</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/brit-age-colonization-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/brit-age-colonization-pattern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In trinidad u will find more douglas (products of indian male &amp;amp; black female).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;language&#34;&gt;Language&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In guyana &amp;amp; trinidad they switched to english completely due to brit policy being harsh, in suriname they have retained sarnami hindi even today, similar in mauritius (which became 68% &amp;ldquo;indian&amp;rdquo;). the dutch in suriname were more relaxed &amp;amp; gave more freedom than brits&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dehinduization rates</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/dehinduization-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/dehinduization-rates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2025-pew&#34;&gt;2025 Pew&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/hIoWpfxTVY&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-Of the countries surveyed, the highest shares of people raised Hindu who no longer identify as Hindu are in the U.S. (18%) and Sri Lanka (11%).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-In Sri Lanka, most who have left Hinduism now identify as Christians. In the U.S., 11% of people who were raised Hindu are now religiously unaffiliated (i.e., they identify religiously as atheist, agnostic or “nothing in particular”) and 6% are Christians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>dilip-amin on malaysia</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/dilip-amin_malaysia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/dilip-amin_malaysia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.indiafacts.org.in/the-status-of-hindus-in-malaysia-a-travelogue/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Malaysian Hindus are fearful of speaking out against atrocities against them, frightened that the Muslim authorities may incriminate them and give them a hard time. The author and his wife at Kuan Yin Buddhist temple in Penang.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Image Courtesy: Dilip Amin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hindus in Malaysia are treated as second class citizens even though many of them have been there for at least four generations. This is not merely a subjective or biased opinion but there are statistical data to corroborate it:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GA siMhapura hindukAH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/GA_siMhapura-hindukAH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/GA_siMhapura-hindukAH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vaishnavah&#34;&gt;vaiShNavAH&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a Vaikhānasāgama Viṣṇu temple and 2 Pāñcarātrāgama temples—one for Rāma and another for Kṛṣṇa. There are 3 Āgama temples for Viṣṇu out of the 20+ Āgama temples. And a North-Indian temple for Lakṣmīnārāyaṇa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guyana adaptation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/guyana-adaptation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/guyana-adaptation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Practice and methodology changed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sunday-satsangh&#34;&gt;sunday satsangh&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most obvious was the adopting of &amp;ldquo;Sunday Satsangh&amp;rdquo; a foreign concept in India when it relates to Sanatana Dharma. But when living outside of India, it has its place.  It provides community, shared identity and a way to keep together.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;standardization&#34;&gt;Standardization&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The more complicated answer was the unifying of Hindu practices through the formation of the Sanatana Dharma Mahasabha.  They codified practices and created Mandir&amp;rsquo;s into &amp;ldquo;branches&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India migration</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/india-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/india-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cm23n23dwx3o&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What migration reveals about religion in India&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Soutik Biswas&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The religious composition of Indians who emigrate differs significantly from those who stay in India, analysis by the US-based Pew Research Center has found.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hindus-stay-more&#34;&gt;Hindus stay more&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;About 80% of people in India are Hindu, but they form only 41% of emigrants from the country, the survey on the religious composition of the world&amp;rsquo;s migrants says.+++(5)+++&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In contrast, about 15% of people living in India are Muslim, compared with 33% of those who were born in India and now live elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jyotiSha in china</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/jyotiSha_in_china/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/jyotiSha_in_china/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/maitra_varuna/status/1709423410294509573&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Tang dynasty capital was home to 3 major clans of Indian astronomers:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;瞿曇 - Gautama , 拘摩羅 - Kumāra , 迦 葉 - Kāśyapa&#xA;some of whom were settled in China for multiple generations while maintaining their Indian identities  &amp;amp; translating key Indian astronomical works .&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most famous such astronomer was Gautama Siddha (瞿昙悉达), a 3rd gen Sino-Indian. The Book of Tang records that Siddha was ordered to translate the Navagraha system (九執曆) into Chinese. His work - 开元占经 survives and includes explanations of Indian numerals &amp;amp; place-value. n 1977 a stele was found in Xi&amp;rsquo;an documenting the Gautama family&amp;rsquo;s presence in Tang China for at least 110 years, serving the Tang court for 4 generations. Siddha&amp;rsquo;s grandfather (瞿昙逸) was likely a Brahmin immigrant, while his father and brothers also served in the Tang Court. Gautama Siddha is also recorded as having worked on repairing an iron armillary sphere made by Chao Chong(晁崇) of the Northern Wei Dynasty (713). Perhaps the earliest Indians to work on such a machine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>majapahit-vijayanagara</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/majapahit-vijayanagara/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/majapahit-vijayanagara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/convos/1645945300048318464&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always wondered why the Hindu Majapahit Empire never appealed to the Vijayanagara Empire for help during its fatal conflicts with the Malacca Sultanate. The 2 Hindu empires could have easily countered the Ming-backed Sultanate. But I think I&amp;rsquo;ve figured-out why&amp;hellip;🧵&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Firstly, let&amp;rsquo;s clarify that Vijayanagara maintained both cultural and trade relations with the empires of South-East Asia. The trade relations are almost trivially obvious so I won&amp;rsquo;t bother with the details. But we see Hindu religious exchange even as late as the 1480s. A Javanese text from the late 1400s called the Śiwarātrikalpa (ꦯꦶꦮꦫꦴꦠꦿꦶꦏꦭ꧀ꦥ) introduces the practice of Mahā Śivarātri which was previously unknown in Indonesian Hinduism. Scholars suspect that this ritual was transmitted from Vijayanagara to a dying Majapahit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mittani-suffixes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/mittani-suffixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/mittani-suffixes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Supposedly from Srikant Taligeri)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The common names consist of names having the following prefixes and suffixes:   -aśva, -ratha, -sena, -bandhu, -uta, vasu-, ṛta-, priya-, and (as per the analysis of the Indologist P.E.Dumont), also bṛhad-, sapta-, abhi-, uru-, citra-, -kṣatra, yam/yami-:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the Non-redacted Hymns in the five Old Books (2,3,4,6,7):&#xA;NONE.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the Redacted Hymns in the five Old Books (2,3,4,6,7):&#xA;NONE.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the five New Books (5,1,8,9,10): 108 hymns:&#xA;V. 3-6, 24-26, 46, 47, 52-61, 81-82 (21 hymns).&#xA;I. 12-23, 100 (13 hymns).&#xA;VIII. 1-5, 23-26, 32-38, 46, 68-69, 87, 89-90, 98-99 (24 hymns).&#xA;IX. 2, 27-29, 32, 41-43, 97 (9 hymns).&#xA;X. 14-29, 37, 46-47, 54-60, 65-66, 75, 102-103, 118, 120, 122, 132, 134, 135, 144, 154, 174, 179 (41 hymns).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reunion hindus</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/reunion-hindus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/reunion-hindus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1379095902896451592&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1379095902896451592&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hinduism in Réunion island, France 🇫🇷&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First Indian labourer arrived in the French overseas island on 25th July 1860, when slavery was abolished in 1848. First Indians were numbered around 6000. This significantly increased to 38,000.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overwhelming majority of these Indians were Tamils from French territory in India. They were brought to Grenade Chaloupe lazaret. They were quarantined here. These Indian were prosecuted and striped off their basic rights and forcefully made to convert to christianity. They were forced to assimilate to Frence identity. (Some of the early souvenir, the documents related to the agreements between the French and British for providing labourers to the island.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silent diaspora shashi tar Ur</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/silent-diaspora-shashi-tarUr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/silent-diaspora-shashi-tarUr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can diaspora please stand up?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As Washington’s stance on India shifts, Indian-americans find themselves caught between assimilation and allegiance. But silence has its costs&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Indian Express (Delhi Edition) 2 Oct 2025The writer chairs the Parliamentary Standing Committee on External Affairs by Shashi Tharoor&lt;br&gt;&#xA;C R Sasikumar&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IN THE PANTHEON of immigrant success stories, few shine as brightly as those of the Indian-american community. With the highest median household income of any ethnic group in the United States, a constellation of CEOS helming Fortune 500 companies, six members of Congress, two former governors, and senior officials at the top of federal agencies, including the FBI and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the community is often held up as a model of integration, achievement, and influence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suriname return refusal</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/suriname-return-refusal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/suriname-return-refusal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://indianexpress.com/article/research/in-the-land-of-sri-ram-why-indian-indentured-labourers-in-suriname-refused-to-come-back-7147231/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the land of ‘Sri Ram’: Why Indian indentured labourers in Suriname refused to come back&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The fact that two-third of the more than 34,000 Indian immigrants settled down in Suriname and gave up their free passage back to India is to some extent proof of the fact that life in Suriname was perhaps better than in British India.&#xA;Written by Adrija New Delhi | January 15, 2021 15:23 IST&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>trinidad aryamsha 23</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/trinidad_aryamsha_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/trinidad_aryamsha_23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trinidad is a good example of the ceiling of Indian capacity to build a successful country. It became an industrialized nation off its natural gas/petroleum and agricultural exports. Indians are 35% of the population, followed by Africans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HDI is 0.800+&lt;br&gt;&#xA;PCI $30K (ppp)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;India wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been so rich even if we had oil/gas. We&amp;rsquo;re too factionalized and too diverse to become a rich democratic country. Trinidad received indentured laborers mostly from Hindi belt, and sometimes even entire villages moved together. Mostly middle caste ones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trinidad gangA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/trinidad-gangA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/articles/trinidad-gangA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.triniview.com/blog/?p=575&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.triniview.com/gallery/main.php?g2_itemId=764334&#34;&gt;www.triniview.com/gallery/main.php?g2_itemId=764334&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ganga Dhaaraa Teerath: Water is Life&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Posted by TriniView Reporters on July 4, 2014 ·&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By TriniView Reporters&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the early pre-dawn hours, the temporary camp stirred near the 18¾ mile post to Blanchisseuse on the North Coast of Trinidad. The air was heavy with dew and the promise of rain seemed imminent as mist whorled whitely across the surrounding forest canopy under a clouded sky. Undaunted, the volunteers of the Ganga Dhaaraa Teerath Committee seemed energized. In the shadowy confines of a makeshift bamboo shed, under corrugated galvanized roofing, preparations were already bustling for the day’s festivities. In the dark, peeled potatoes already lay in large silver basins of water ready for cooking as pots of coffee and tea steamed nearby. Though the sun had yet to make an appearance, the morning had already begun, for this was the day the annual Ganga Dhaaraa Teerath would be made. The faithful from all paths of life in Trinidad would already be wending their way through the dark and from far-flung parts of the country to meet and honour Mother Ganga at this spot as they have been doing for the last twenty-one years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
