<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Tradeables on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/assets/goods/tradeables/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Tradeables on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/assets/goods/tradeables/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Commodities</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/assets/goods/tradeables/Commodities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/assets/goods/tradeables/Commodities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Excluding precious metals used as currency)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;price-trends&#34;&gt;Price trends&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Commodity prices are highly sensitive to (speculation about) the supply situation (relative to demand). This leads to great volatility.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;long-term-investment-suitability&#34;&gt;Long term investment suitability&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Historically, most commodities have only keep up with inflation. In the long term, Investing in commodities is essentially betting against inflation (and to an extant human ingenuity given war, disease etc).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;oil&#34;&gt;Oil&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oil is used in distribution of goods and services. Only a few nations produce it, and they form a cartel - OPEC - which can often arbitrarily increase price as a way to bargain for concessions from their buyers. But, the cartel is slightly inefficient because various producers often violate agreements due to self interests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Currency</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/assets/goods/tradeables/Currency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/assets/goods/tradeables/Currency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;precious-metals&#34;&gt;Precious metals&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are mainly used as a store of value. Though they may have industrial use, their demand is dominated by the former. It is often difficult to get the fundamental value of precious metals. For example, Gold is in a 400 year price increase: but since its fundamental value is unknown, it can’t be easily said to be a boom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;crypto-currency&#34;&gt;Crypto-currency&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Negotiable instruments</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/assets/goods/tradeables/Negotiable_instruments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/assets/goods/tradeables/Negotiable_instruments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aka Securities. These are objects which promise payment to whoever holds the object. They include: stocks/ equities (which represent ownership in various businesses/ funds), bonds (loans), derivatives (whose value is determined based on the value of other instruments).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-securities&#34;&gt;Creating securities&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Investment bankers help raise capital for various businesses by creating bonds and stocks. They get big fees for it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;underwriting&#34;&gt;Underwriting&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They often take the responsibility of selling such securities by purchasing it from the business and holding on to them - usually until they can sell it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
