<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;3 Becoming the World Conqueror on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/3_Becoming_the_World_Conqueror/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;3 Becoming the World Conqueror on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/3_Becoming_the_World_Conqueror/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>09 Two Wings of One Bird</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/3_Becoming_the_World_Conqueror/09_Two_Wings_of_One_Bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/3_Becoming_the_World_Conqueror/09_Two_Wings_of_One_Bird/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the start of the thirteenth century, China consisted of more than a dozen kingdoms, some large enough to claim to be an empire and others too restricted to be concerned about anything beyond petty rivalries and local strife. Northern China was in political turmoil while southern China was in a protracted period of decadent decay. A so-called barbarian group, the Jurched of Manchuria, ruled the north as the Jin, or Golden, dynasty. Farther south, the Sung dynasty, which had once ruled a united China, continued as a truncated empire teetering on the brink of collapse. In what are now Tibet and Yunnan, a handful of isolated Buddhist kingdoms drifted along with none successfully dominating the others for long.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 God’s Omnipotence</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/3_Becoming_the_World_Conqueror/10_Gods_Omnipotence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/3_Becoming_the_World_Conqueror/10_Gods_Omnipotence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Soon after the success of his campaign against the Jin, Genghis Khan received an urgent and unusual request from a group of Muslims living in the Kara Khitai Empire, along the eastern shadow of the Tien Shan Mountains, bridging modern-day China and Kyrgyzstan. Having seen the Uighurs and Karluks, both fellow Muslims, break away from the Kara Khitai to join Genghis Khan, the group beseeched him to come liberate them from their current master and to rule over them. They appealed to the Mongol leader in part because their current ruler happened to be an old nemesis. He was Guchlug, the son of Tayang Khan of the Naiman.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 The Thumb of Fate</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/3_Becoming_the_World_Conqueror/11_The_Thumb_of_Fate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/3_Becoming_the_World_Conqueror/11_The_Thumb_of_Fate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Genghis Khan showed no sign of doubting his mission on Earth and his right to decide life and death for whole nations. His conquests were harsh and brutal, but harshness and brutality were typical of his era. Although he showed a remarkable ability to think outside of his time and context about many issues, no evidence suggests that he regretted killing so many men or questioned the morality of his conquests. People who died in war were fulfilling their destiny assigned by heaven; this meant that they deserved to die. In killing them, he was simply fulfilling his own destiny and following the Will of Heaven.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Wild Man from the Mountain</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/3_Becoming_the_World_Conqueror/12_Wild_Man_from_the_Mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/3_Becoming_the_World_Conqueror/12_Wild_Man_from_the_Mountain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Genghis Khan was beginning to feel what the Mongols call *nasand daragdax—*the inevitable triumph of age over body. Although he had defeated the last holdout leader of the Khwarizm army, he had little cause to celebrate. His army had lost only one battle, but combined with the loss of his grandson, the year 1221 marked a turning point in his life. He was tired and very far from home. His eldest son, Jochi, had ignored his summons and stayed as far away as he could, and his other sons continued squabbling among themselves as though their father had already died and they had taken charge of the empire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 The Confucian and the Unicorn</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/3_Becoming_the_World_Conqueror/13_The_Confucian_and_the_Unicorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/3_Becoming_the_World_Conqueror/13_The_Confucian_and_the_Unicorn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mongol nomads rarely returned along the same route by which they came. Because Genghis Khan had entered Afghanistan from the northeast, he planned to return to Mongolia via another route, going south, crossing the Indus River, turning east, and making his way through the Himalayas or around them and across Bengal and Assam, and then turning north through China. If he took this route, he could continue to expand his empire along a course that would bring him back to the Tangut kingdom, where he could exact revenge on their ruler who had surrendered to him but then reneged on his promise and refused to send warriors for his campaign against the Khwarizm shah.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
