<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Human retroviruses,</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/articles/MT/2022-03-23_human-retroviruses-sociology-of-science-and-biogra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/articles/MT/2022-03-23_human-retroviruses-sociology-of-science-and-biogra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2022/03/23/human-retroviruses-sociology-of-science-and-biographical-ruminations/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Human retroviruses, sociology of science, and biographical ruminations&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We learnt via a recent obituary that the French researcher Luc Montagnier died a month or so ago after living for nearly 90 years. He along with his compatriot and erstwhile colleagues, Françoise Barré-Sinoussi and Jean-Claude Chermann discovered HIV-1. Subsequently, his lab also discovered HIV-2, the second virus that causes AIDS. It was around the time of the discovery of HIV-2 and the naming of the original AIDS virus as HIV-1 that we made our own first foray into studying evolution and biochemistry in the language of the genes. Soon thereafter, we realized that the study of the biochemistry of the endless war between viruses and their hosts offered some of the deepest insights into the evolutionary process after Darwin’s work. Thus, the path for our primary investigations in the coming years “crystallized” out of these early meditations. Not being an entirely autistic type of scientific enthusiast, we also started observing the sociology of science, if anything for the selfish reason of understanding better the social systems that we would become a part of due to our chosen course. We cannot say that we saw or understood things clearly in those early days, but the germs of the realization that the heroic hagiographies of science are far from the truth dawned on us then. One early introduction to this was the drawn-out conflict between the Frenchman Montagnier and his American rival Robert Gallo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lumpy pox 2022</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/articles/MT/lumpy-pox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/articles/MT/lumpy-pox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://unrollthread.com/t/1573922457349771264/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The wide and rapid spread of the Lumpy skin poxvirus in cattle across the desh is rather puzzling.There seem to be lacunae in understanding its spread.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, there are multiple reports that quarantines to restrict spread widely fail. That seems to be borne out here too. That has led proposal that factors other than contact with saliva or pustules might be in play. This is keeping with the spread in multiple states where the cattle simply could not have come in direct contact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
