<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;जमदग्निः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;जमदग्निः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>अर्वाचीनाः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/arvAchInAH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/arvAchInAH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;बणभटट&#34;&gt;बाणभट्टः&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was pleased to note that bANa-bhaTTa was a sagotra and his ancestors were practitioners of the cult of rAjarAja. He preserves a peculiar legend of the early settlement of the bhArgava-s, i.e., that the vatsa bhArgava-s&amp;rsquo; original center was on the banks of the shoNa river. - MT&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;वरमशव&#34;&gt;वर्मशिवः&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He also was widely&#xA;respected for his tAntric abilities in the KShudra vidyA-s acquiring the&#xA;yakShiNi, chUrNa, chetaka, DAmarikA and DAvI prayoga-s (latter for&#xA;invoking terrifying agents that can cause a variety of rogas in course&#xA;of uchChATana prayoga-s). varma then settled in the temple of&#xA;vodAmayUtA, where he was appointed as the head of a shaiva maTha. There&#xA;he acted in un-orthodox ways. He took as his primary student, a&#xA;brilliant shUdra named mUrtigaNa. mUrtigaNa was initiated into all the&#xA;tantric rahasya-s by varmashiva and became a great tantric himself. He&#xA;was made the preceptor of the Rathod king shUrapAla, despite being&#xA;shUdra on account of his learning. He succeeded varMashiva as the lord&#xA;of the maTha. At that time a nambUthiri from the chera country,&#xA;ishAnashiva, journeyed to vodamayUtA and impressed by mUrtigaNa became&#xA;his student. He then succeeded mUrtigaNa and became an illustrious&#xA;shaiva tantric himself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>नीलमेघाचार्यः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/nIlameghAchAryaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/nIlameghAchAryaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Vidvat Varishta&amp;rsquo; Nilameghacharya&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;उत्तमूरु-वीरराघव-सतीर्थ्यः, किन्तु +उप-२०-वर्षैर् ज्यायान्।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;अधीत-वेदः, चतुश्-शास्त्र-पण्डितः, द्राविड्याम् अपि, महामेधावी।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;पल्लव-देशोद्भवः।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;२५तमे वयसि प्रायेण वाराणासीम् प्रत्य् आहूतः - तत्र शास्त्राण्य् अपाठयत्।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;तत्रत्य-प्रयोजनाय नैके विशिष्टाद्वैतग्रन्था आप्राथमिका आप्रौढा हिन्द्या ऽनूद्य प्रकाशिताः।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;पलवेरि-राजगोपालस् तत्-पुत्राय - &amp;ldquo;तदीय-ग्रन्थान् पठितुं त्वया हिन्दी शिक्षणीये&amp;quot;ति प्रेरयति स्म।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;सायं कालेषु पामरान् उद्दिश्य प्रवदति स्म गङ्गा-तीरे।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;अहोबिलम् आगते तत्रत्य आचार्यः (४४-तमः) कम्बलक-द्वयेन सम्मानयति स्म।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hindi translations&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;nyAya-siddhANjana&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;vedArtha-sangraha&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;vedAnta-dIpa&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;sanskrit&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;rahasyatrayasAra translation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For NyAya-SiddhAn&lt;del&gt;janam, VaikuNThavAsi SrI NIlamEghAchArya has written an excellent Hindi anuvAdam - Again published by the chowkhamba group. He was a scholar of very high merit and was colleague of SrI UtthamUr SwAmi at SrI VE&lt;/del&gt;nkatESwara Oriental University,Tirupathi, and later moved over to KAsi.He was an authority in VyAkaraNa and very well-versed in VEdAnta. His another celebrated contribution is the full-length Sanskrit version of SrImad Rahasya-Traya-SAram +++(published)+++ by SrI UtthamUr SwAmi through Ubhaya-VEdAnta GranthamAlA, for the benifit of non-tamil speaking scholars. This book is out-of-print.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>भार्गवो रामः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/bhArgavo_rAmaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/bhArgavo_rAmaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;यस् स्वपरशुना हत्वा मातरं भ्रातॄन् पित्राज्ञया, तद्वरेणैव तान् उज्जीवयामास।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;धनुर्विद्यां प्राप्य शिवप्रेरणया ऽसुरान् जित्वा परश्वादिदिव्यास्त्राणि शिवाल् लेभे। ततो ऽकृतव्रणं शिष्यं लब्ध्वा धनुर्वेदाचार्यो बभूव। कर्णद्रोणौ तच्छिष्यौ पश्चाद् बभूवतुः। असत्यवादिनं कर्णं ब्रह्मास्त्रविस्मृत्या शशाप।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;कामधेन्वपहर्ता कार्तवीर्यार्जुनो मन्त्रिहस्तेन जघान जमदग्निम्। किञ्च शुक्रेण जीवितः। धेनुः प्रत्यागता। धेनुवत्सप्रत्यानयने कार्त्तवीर्यार्जुनं हैहयं जघान। तत्पुत्रैस् तदाश्रममागत्य जमदग्निश् च हतः। रेणुकाऽपि प्राणान् तत्याज।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ततस् स हि पितृहत्याप्रतीकारं लेभे दुष्टक्षत्रियान् हत्वा (१८ वारं वा, २१ वारं वा), तद्रुधिरसरोभ्यस् सप्तभ्यस् तर्पणान्य् अर्पयित्वा। प्रीताः पितरस् तत् क्षेत्रं समन्तपञ्चकं पुण्यं चक्रुः। पापान् मोचयाञ्चक्रुश्च। ततो यागदानादयः कृता अनेन। काश्यपाय भूमिं दत्त्वा दक्षिणसमुद्रप्रान्ते वासाय चोदितः, तदर्थं वरुणेन नूतनभूमिर्दत्ता।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;राघवेण रामेन हतदर्पः पितृकृपया तपᳶप्रभावेन च स्वतेजसं पुनराप।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;अम्बाप्रार्थनया सकृद् भीष्मेण युयोध।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;[p= &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sanskrit-lexicon.uni-koeln.de/scans/PEScan/2014/web/webtc/servepdf.php?page=568&#34;&gt;568&lt;/a&gt;,2]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sukthankars-criticism&#34;&gt;Sukthankar&amp;rsquo;s criticism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is only one explanation of the childish exaggeration and this repeated mention on the annihilation of the Ksatriyas by the Bhargava Ráma. A deep analysis of the motives underlying this phenomenon) would suggest that these fabrications are only a form of over-compensation, and endeavour to make the Bhrgus feel important and &amp;lsquo;worth while&amp;rsquo;, after the disastrous blow to their egoideals. It is the psychological revenge of the Bhrgus who were all but exterminated by the Ksatriyas. The slaughter of the Bhrgus admitted by the Bhrgus themselves in the Aurva legend deserves all the credence which unfavourable evidence by a witness against one&amp;rsquo;s own self ordinarily does what the Bhrgus in turn did to the Ksatriyas &amp;ndash;namely, the annihilating the Ksatriyas by Bhargava Räma 3X7 is known to us only from the account of the event from Brahmin sources. This myth the dream of the Bhrgus—is the sublimation of that intolerable inferiority feeling which had been repressed, but which was clamouring for expression.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>वाल्मीकिः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/vAlmIkiH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/vAlmIkiH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;भृगूणाम् एवादितो व्याख्यास्यामो - … वाल्मीकिः … भार्गव च्यावनाप्नवानौर्व जामदग्न्येति होता।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;इति बोधायनः।&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;महर्षेर् वल्मीकेश् चावनेः&lt;br&gt;&#xA;7th-century Trà Kiĕu pedestal inscription of King Prakāśadharman of Campā (Vietnam)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://shs.hal.science/halshs-01909934/document&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;वलमकदभव&#34;&gt;वल्मीकोद्भवः&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;वल्मीकः इति तु पुत्तिकाभिधैः क्षुद्रकीटैः कृतः मृत्स्तूपविशेषः । तस्य अचेतनत्वात् अपत्यस्य असम्भवः ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;तर्हि वल्मीकस्य अपत्यं इति कथम् —‌ इति चेत्,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;वस्तुतस्तु ऋक्षः इत्याख्यः कश्चन भृगुपुत्रः यदा दीर्घकालं यावत् तपः कृतवान्,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;तदा तं परितः वल्मीकस्य निर्माणं जातम् ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;तदनन्तरम् वरुणेन (प्रचेतसा) निरन्तरं वर्षणं कृत्वा वल्मीकस्य भेदे कृते सः बहिः आगतः,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;अतः गौणत्वेन (वल्मीकस्य पुत्रः =) वाल्मीकिः,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;किञ्च (प्रचेतसः पुत्रः = ) प्राचेतसः इत्यपि नामद्वयेन सः प्रसिद्धः ।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
