<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The brahmin brain-drain</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/MT/2004-08-26_the-brahmin-brain-drain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/MT/2004-08-26_the-brahmin-brain-drain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/08/26/the-brahmin-brain-drain/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For particular unstated reasons, I shall concentrate on the brahmins of the southern state of Tamil Nad for a case study. We have earlier discussed how the brahmins might face number of problems in the immediate future, which may destroy them and in the process damage India. We shall now look into the problem of the brahmin brain-drain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;migrations&#34;&gt;Migrations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The brahmins of Tamil Nad are a diverse group.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Their earliest migrations from North India seem to have started after bAvari, the early colonizer of dakShiNA patha. Their presence in attested in the form of their role in formalizing the Dravidian language Tamil along the lines of Sanskrit in the Tolkappiyam and as composers of early Tamil poetry (eg. Kapilar).+++(5)+++&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Subsequently several great waves of brahmin immigrants moved into the southern state from North India, during the Pallava period, the imperial Chola period and the Vijayanagara-Maharatta period.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Specimens of the earliest wave of brahmins entering Tamil Nad appear to now be restricted within the groups of the Cholians and the Dikshitars of Chidambharam. They are closest to the Nambuthiris of the Chera country and like them maintain an frontal shikha (in contrast to the rear shikha of the later brahmin groups). The Nambuthiris through their selective mating practices retained a considerable degree of closeness to the ancestral Indo-Aryan stock from the north within the brahmin fold.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brooding over Hindu woes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/MT/2004-03-02_brooding-over-hindu-woes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/MT/2004-03-02_brooding-over-hindu-woes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/03/02/brooding-over-hindu-woes/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Though I have no personal liking for Malhotra nor agree with him in entirity, I appreciate his efforts in the recent efforts to raise the awareness of the Hindus regarding the ongoing attempts by the Anglosphere to subvert and demonize the Hindus. Sankrant Sanu, Narayanan and Ramesh Rao’s efforts in this direction are also commendable. Some present well-reasoned critiques, while others humorous satires of these Anglospheric attempts. Hindus are angry and that is a good sign. It is unlikely they will take things lying down. But the question repeatedly raises itself as to whether the Hindus will successfully counter the newest assaults. Many Hindus take history for granted. They say we defeated the British, we defeated the Moslems, so we will also over come this most recent assault. Yes it is good to be optimistic but we need to see if the case is really that water-tight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The fall of brahmins</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/MT/2003-11-30_the-fall-of-brahmins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/MT/2003-11-30_the-fall-of-brahmins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/11/30/the-fall-of-brahmins/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Brahmins, the metaphorical head of the Indo-Aryan society are now facing a major crisis. They have always contributed to Hindu society, way more than what it suggested by their numbers. Their main pioneering areas of activity included the sciences, philosophy and grammar. Even, in the times of national crises like the Macedonian invasion and the blood-curdling Mohammedan violence they contributed as demanded by the occassion by taking to arms or inciting the kshatriyas to defend the land.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Degeneration</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/MT/degeneration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/MT/degeneration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Going by conversations with my grandfather&amp;rsquo;s generation when they were alive, and the writings of kAmeshvara ayyar, I think by the late 1800s a large fraction, &amp;gt;50% had degenerated to know 0-few sUkta-s. We may infer that when traditional v1 education existed they learnt more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fan poluomen</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/MT/fan_poluomen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/MT/fan_poluomen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1652495008157642752.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://bharadvajatmaja.substack.com/p/journey-to-the-east&#34;&gt;good note&lt;/a&gt; on brAhmaNa-s in Central Asia &amp;amp; the sinosphere. I mostly agree with their presence in the Hunnic world &amp;ndash; something I&amp;rsquo;d independently talked about inspired by Golden&amp;rsquo;s observation of the said ethnonym. I&amp;rsquo;m also adding a few assorted comments in no particular order as the author of the above asked me to comment &amp;amp; something came to mind. I&amp;rsquo;d have to preface it by noting I&amp;rsquo;m no sinologist&amp;amp; am primarily interested in Indic&amp;amp; Turko-Mongolic matters but gathered a bunch of things at the interface.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>V1 admin role</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/MT/v1-admin-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/MT/v1-admin-role/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1452126782640082954&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1452126782640082954&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This idea that somehow the marAThA v1s were doing something special, namely &amp;ldquo;secular v1ism&amp;rdquo; that was later emulated by other v1s in the peninsula is indeed a poorly supported idea coming out of &amp;ldquo;white indologists&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; their fellow travelers. They have long spouted misconceptions like :&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the v1s dispersed throughout the subcontinent &amp;amp; beyond by earlier rulers being purveyors of a purely non-secular &amp;ldquo;vedism&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;tantrism&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any serious student will note that the v2s (real or honorary) were not doing this for some idealism like that which permeates occidental academe (e.g. critical theories).+++(5)+++ Rather, it had a very practical function of utilizing v1s in a secular capacity as administrators.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
