<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Health on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Health on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aging</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/aging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/aging/</guid>
      <description>Silent risk  &amp;ldquo;Youth is health more so than strength. The strong 50yr old is &amp;lsquo;healthy&amp;rsquo; in one metric but silent risk is increasing. This is why big powerlifters can die instantly.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t believe a superfit 60yr old can ever be as healthy as the average teenager. But they can be &amp;lsquo;fitter&amp;rsquo; - so we have to define the difference between fitness and health.&amp;rdquo;  Variation  Aging is diminishing variation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blood vessels</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/blood_vessels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/blood_vessels/</guid>
      <description>Chemical determinants Cholesterol One important determinant of blood vessel health is cholesterol levels, with the LDL subtype of cholesterol being bad for your arteries and HDL being good.
Smoking reduces HDL.
Trans fats Explained in poison page.
Oxidative damage Since the brain uses about 25% of the body’s oxygen, the brain is highly susceptible to oxidative damage.
Diabetes Diabetes damages the small blood vessels in the brain, and eventually rots these vessels to the point where they entirely close off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death causes</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/death_causes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/death_causes/</guid>
      <description>Consider the health map to track epidemics.  Temperate Leukosphere   Leading causes of death in developing countries according to [Ref]:
  HIV/AIDS
  Lower respiratory infections
  Ischaemic heart disease
  USA Most common conventional causes of death in the USA, according to [Ref]:
 Heart disease : 30%. Cancer: 24%. Stroke, respiratory diseases and accidents contribute around 5% each.  Heart disease  12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fertility</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/fertility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/fertility/</guid>
      <description>Age  A study published in the Archives of General Psychiatry reveals that men over 40 are six times more likely to father a child with autism than men aged 15 to 29. [Ref] A French study of over 12,200 couples having fertility treatment suggests the chance of a successful pregnancy falls when the man is aged over 35. It adds that the chance is significantly lower if he is over 40.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surgery</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/surgery/</guid>
      <description>Downsides  Invasive surgery can cause more harm than good - and should be elected with care.  Examples  An artificial knee may get infected, leading to pus discharge, swelling and pain. Immune system cells have a harder time getting there and cleaning up. Myopes considering refractive surgery are advised that surgically correcting their nearsightedness may actually be a disadvantage after the age of 40 when the eyes become presbyopic and lose their ability to accommodate or change focus because they will then need to use glasses for reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>व्यायामः</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/vyAyAmaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/vyAyAmaH/</guid>
      <description>Target/ ध्येयम्  Stay at the lighter end of your body&amp;rsquo;s frame  Over-muscled, fueled by constantly eating, is not healthy    Physical Standards Via Guru Anaerobic:
 1 Deadlift: One-rep max of 2 x body weight (general strength) 2 Chin-ups: 20 (usable upper body strength) 3 100m sprint: Under 13 seconds (speed) 4 One mile: Under 6 minutes (endurance) 5 Body-fat: 10-12% - a six-pack is just visible (health)  These are not elite standards, but achieving all five would likely take you into the top 1% of the population.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>