<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Analysis</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/articles/2012-04-08_strategic-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/articles/2012-04-08_strategic-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.wordpress.com/2012/04/08/strategic-analysis/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Strategic Analysis&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have been asked to discuss Iran’s nuclear weapons potential – and I&#xA;will, but I’m going to take a broader look.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;products-and-difficulty&#34;&gt;Products and difficulty&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The short answer is that the centrifuge approach that Iran is pursuing&#xA;is capable (when mature) of producing either low-enriched uranium(LEU),&#xA;useful for power reactors, or HEU, highly-enriched uranium, which can be&#xA;used to make a fission bomb, among other things. Just for general&#xA;information, natural uranium is about 0.7% U-235. LEU means that the&#xA;fraction of U-235 is somewhere under under 20% (3%-5% in light water&#xA;reactors) , while HEU is more highly enriched. Typical uranium nuclear&#xA;weapons are usually &amp;gt;85% U-235, although the real nuclear players use&#xA;plutonium cores nowadays . You can make a gun-type fission bomb with&#xA;highly enriched HEU, which is simpler to develop than implosion,&#xA;although less efficient.+++(4)+++&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ballad of Bahram</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/articles/ballad_of_bahram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/articles/ballad_of_bahram/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/g/FriendOfCAHC/c/PiJ6-nuWYLk&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/AmitMajmudar/status/1833264554077524377/photo/2&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;videoEmbed&#34;  caption=&#34;Video&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aJvVKzbMBk4&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A composition by Farya Faraji. The lyrics are in Middle-Persian, the chronological variety of the Persian language spoken in the Sasanian Era, and they are taken from a rhymed ballad dating to the time following the fall of the Sasanian Empire at the hands of the Arabic Rashidun Caliphate. According to J. C. Tavadia from &amp;ldquo;The Journal of the Royal Asiatic Society of Great Britain and Ireland&amp;rdquo; in 1955, while the exact date of the poem cannot be pinpointed, some estimates can be made.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pahlavi script defects</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/articles/pahlavi-script-defects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/articles/pahlavi-script-defects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1666585955107520518.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I often describe Pahlavi as the worst writing system ever invented.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a perfectly-serviceable writing system for a completely different language (Aramaic) and adapt it for our language (Middle Persian). We&amp;rsquo;ll call this new script &amp;ldquo;Pahlavi&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aramaic doesn&amp;rsquo;t really write all the vowels, only consonants, but that&amp;rsquo;s OK for Aramaic, because through a quirk of Semitic grammar, consonants carry most of the semantics.+++(4)+++ But our language, Middle Persian, is Indo-European and &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; carry a lot of semantic weight in vowels. This is why when Greek (IE) borrowed writing from Phoenician (Sem.), it repurposed a bunch of the consonants that Greek didn&amp;rsquo;t have to use as vowels.+++(5)+++&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sassanian-myths</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/articles/sassanian-myths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/articles/sassanian-myths/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Foreign claims of Alexander the Great go way back - Sassanids claimed that he had a Persian father and a Macedonian mother.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sassanid founding myth involves an episode where they defeated a warlord whose power derived from the possession of a giant worm, which the Sassanids killed along with the warlord.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interesting theory that Sassanid dynasty may have been descended from a branch of the previous Parthian Arsacid dynasty which had been in Sindh or Bactria for a couple of generations - and been influenced by Indic culture. A medieval Zoroastrian text prophesies the liberation of Iran by a Kayanid prince Vahram-i Varzavand who would arrive from India. Wonder if Sasan&amp;rsquo;s India connection had any influence on the myth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
