<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;discourses on jnana-yoga on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;discourses on jnana-yoga on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>795 JNANA YOGA - I</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/795_jnana-yoga_i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/795_jnana-yoga_i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jnana-yoga---i&#34;&gt;JNANA YOGA - I&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(These were originally recorded by a prominent American disciple of the&#xA;Swami, Miss S. E. Waldo. Swami Saradananda, while he was in America&#xA;(1896), copied them out from her notebook — &lt;em&gt;Ed&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Om Tat Sat! To know the Om is to know the secret of the universe. The&#xA;object of Jnāna-Yoga is the same as that of Bhakti and Rāja Yogas, but&#xA;the method is different. This is the Yoga for the strong, for those who&#xA;are neither mystical nor devotional, but rational. As the Bhakti-Yogi&#xA;works his way to complete oneness with the Supreme through love and&#xA;devotion, so the Jnāna-Yogi forces his way to the realisation of God by&#xA;the power of pure reason. He must be prepared to throw away all old&#xA;idols, all old beliefs and superstitions, all desire for this world or&#xA;another, and be determined only to find freedom. Without Jnana&#xA;(knowledge) liberation cannot be ours. It consists in knowing what we&#xA;really are, that we are beyond fear, beyond birth, beyond death. The&#xA;highest good is the realisation of the Self. It is beyond sense, beyond&#xA;thought. The &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo; cannot be grasped. It is the eternal subject and&#xA;can never become the object of knowledge, because knowledge is only of&#xA;the related, not of the Absolute. All sense-knowledge is limitation, it&#xA;is an endless chain of cause and effect. This world is a relative world,&#xA;a shadow of the real; still, being the plane of equipoise where&#xA;happiness and misery are about evenly balanced, it is the only plane&#xA;where man can realise his true Self and know that he is Brahman.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>796 JNANA YOGA - II</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/796_jnana-yoga_ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/796_jnana-yoga_ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jnana-yoga---ii&#34;&gt;JNANA YOGA - II&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(These were originally recorded by a prominent American disciple of the&#xA;Swami, Miss S. E. Waldo. Swami Saradananda, while he was in America&#xA;(1896), copied them out from her notebook — &lt;em&gt;Ed&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The greatest teacher of the Vedanta philosophy was Shankārachārya. By&#xA;solid reasoning he extracted from the Vedas the truths of Vedanta, and&#xA;on them built up the wonderful system of Jnāna that is taught in his&#xA;commentaries. He unified all the conflicting descriptions of Brahman and&#xA;showed that there is only one Infinite Reality. He showed too that as&#xA;man can only travel slowly on the upward road, all the varied&#xA;presentations are needed to suit his varying capacity. We find something&#xA;akin to this in the teachings of Jesus, which he evidently adapted to&#xA;the different abilities of his hearers. First he taught them of a Father&#xA;in heaven and to pray to Him. Next he rose a step higher and told them,&#xA;&amp;ldquo;I am the vine, you are the branches&amp;rdquo;, and lastly he gave them the&#xA;highest truth: &amp;ldquo;I and my Father are one&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;The Kingdom of Heaven is&#xA;within you.&amp;rdquo; Shankara taught that three things were the great gifts of&#xA;God: (1) human body, (2) thirst after God, and (3) a teacher who can&#xA;show us the light. When these three great gifts are ours, we may know&#xA;that our redemption is at hand. Only knowledge can free and save us, but&#xA;with knowledge must go virtue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>797 JNANA YOGA - III</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/797_jnana-yoga_iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/797_jnana-yoga_iii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jnana-yoga---iii&#34;&gt;JNANA YOGA - III&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(These were originally recorded by a prominent American disciple of the&#xA;Swami, Miss S. E. Waldo. Swami Saradananda, while he was in America&#xA;(1896), copied them out from her notebook — &lt;em&gt;Ed&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jnāna teaches that the world should be given up, but not on that account&#xA;to be abandoned. To be &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; the world, but not &lt;em&gt;of&lt;/em&gt; it, is the true test&#xA;of the Sannyāsin. This idea of renunciation has been in some form common&#xA;to nearly all religions. Jnana demands that we look upon all alike, that&#xA;we see only &amp;ldquo;sameness&amp;rdquo;. Praise and blame, good and bad, even heat and&#xA;cold, must be equally acceptable to us. In India there are many holy men&#xA;of whom this is literally true. They wander on the snow-clad heights of&#xA;the Himalayas or over the burning desert sands, entirely unclothed and&#xA;apparently entirely unconscious of any difference in temperature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>798 JNANA YOGA - IV</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/798_jnana-yoga_iv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/798_jnana-yoga_iv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jnana-yoga---iv&#34;&gt;JNANA YOGA - IV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(These were originally recorded by a prominent American disciple of the&#xA;Swami, Miss S. E. Waldo. Swami Saradananda, while he was in America&#xA;(1896), copied them out from her notebook — &lt;em&gt;Ed&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All men, so-called, are not yet really human beings. Every one has to&#xA;judge of this world through his own mind. The higher understanding is&#xA;extremely difficult. The concrete is more to most people than the&#xA;abstract. As an illustration of this, a story is told of two men in&#xA;Bombay — one a Hindu and the other a Jain — who were playing chess in&#xA;the house of a rich merchant of Bombay. The house was near the sea, the&#xA;game long; the ebb and flow of the tide under the balcony where they sat&#xA;attracted the attention of the players. One explained it by a legend&#xA;that the gods in their play threw the water into a great pit and then&#xA;threw it out again. The other said: No, the gods draw it up to the top&#xA;of a high mountain to use it, and then when they have done with it, they&#xA;throw it down again. A young student present began to laugh at them and&#xA;said, &amp;ldquo;Do you not know that the attraction of the moon causes the&#xA;tides?&amp;rdquo; At this, both men turned on him in a fury and inquired if he&#xA;thought they were fools. Did he suppose that they believed the moon had&#xA;any ropes to pull up the tides, or that it could reach so far? They&#xA;utterly refused to accept any such foolish explanation. At this juncture&#xA;the host entered the room and was appealed to by both parties. He was an&#xA;educated man and of course knew the truth, but seeing plainly the&#xA;impossibility of making the chess-players understand it, he made a sign&#xA;to the student and then proceeded to give an explanation of the tides&#xA;that proved eminently satisfactory to his ignorant hearers. &amp;ldquo;You must&#xA;know&amp;rdquo;, he told them, &amp;ldquo;that afar off in the middle of the ocean, there is&#xA;a huge mountain of sponge — you have both seen sponge, and know what I&#xA;mean. This mountain of sponge absorbs a great deal of the water and then&#xA;the sea falls; by and by the gods come down and dance on the mountain&#xA;and their weight squeezes all the water out and the sea rises again.&#xA;This, gentlemen, is the cause of the tides, and you can easily see for&#xA;yourselves how reasonable and simple is this explanation.&amp;rdquo; The two men&#xA;who ridiculed the power of the moon to cause the tides, found nothing&#xA;incredible in a mountain of sponge, danced upon by the gods! The gods&#xA;were real to them, and they had actually seen sponge; what was more&#xA;likely than their joint effect upon the sea!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>799 JNANA YOGA - V</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/799_jnana-yoga_v/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/799_jnana-yoga_v/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jnana-yoga---v&#34;&gt;JNANA YOGA - V&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(These were originally recorded by a prominent American disciple of the&#xA;Swami, Miss S. E. Waldo. Swami Saradananda, while he was in America&#xA;(1896), copied them out from her notebook — &lt;em&gt;Ed&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The question why there cannot be eternal bodies is in itself illogical,&#xA;as &amp;ldquo;body&amp;rdquo; is a term applied to a certain combination of elements,&#xA;changeable and in its very nature impermanent. When we are not passing&#xA;through changes, we will not have bodies (so-called). &amp;ldquo;Matter&amp;rdquo; beyond&#xA;the limit of time, space, and causality will not be matter at all. Time&#xA;and space exist only in us, we are the one Permanent Being. All forms&#xA;are transitory, that is why all religions say, &amp;ldquo;God has no form&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Menander was a Greco-Bactrian king. He was converted to Buddhism about&#xA;150 B.C. by one of the Buddhist missionary monks and was called by them&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Milinda&amp;rdquo;. He asked a young monk, his teacher, &amp;ldquo;Can a perfect man (such&#xA;as Buddha) be in error or make mistakes?&amp;rdquo; The young monk&amp;rsquo;s answer was :&#xA;The perfect man can remain in ignorance of minor matters not in his&#xA;experience, but he can &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; be in error as to what his insight has&#xA;actually realised. He is perfect here and now. He knows the whole&#xA;mystery, the Essence of the universe, but he may not know the mere&#xA;external variation through which that Essence is manifested in time and&#xA;space. He knows the &lt;em&gt;clay&lt;/em&gt; itself, but has not had experience of every&#xA;shape it may be wrought into. The perfect man knows the Soul itself, but&#xA;not every form and combination of its manifestation. He would have to&#xA;attain more relative knowledge just as we do, though on account of his&#xA;immense power, he would learn it far more quickly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>800 JNANA YOGA - VI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/800_jnana-yoga_vi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/800_jnana-yoga_vi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jnana-yoga---vi&#34;&gt;JNANA YOGA - VI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(These were originally recorded by a prominent American disciple of the&#xA;Swami, Miss S. E. Waldo. Swami Saradananda, while he was in America&#xA;(1896), copied them out from her notebook — &lt;em&gt;Ed&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thought is all important, for &amp;ldquo;what we think we become&amp;rdquo;. There was once&#xA;a Sannyāsin, a holy man, who sat under a tree and taught the people. He&#xA;drank milk, and ate only fruit, and made endless &amp;ldquo;Prānāyāmas&amp;rdquo;, and felt&#xA;himself to be very holy. In the same village lived an evil woman. Every&#xA;day the Sannyasin went and warned her that her wickedness would lead her&#xA;to hell. The poor woman, unable to change her method of life which was&#xA;her only means of livelihood, was still much moved by the terrible&#xA;future depicted by the Sannyasin. She wept and prayed to the Lord,&#xA;begging Him to forgive her because she could not help herself. By and by&#xA;both the holy man and the evil woman died. The angels came and bore her&#xA;to heaven, while the demons claimed the soul of the Sannyasin. &amp;ldquo;Why is&#xA;this!&amp;rdquo; he exclaimed, &amp;ldquo;have I not lived a most holy life, and preached&#xA;holiness to everybody? Why should I be taken to hell while this wicked&#xA;woman is taken to heaven?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Because,&amp;rdquo; answered the demons, &amp;ldquo;while she&#xA;was forced to commit unholy acts, her mind was always fixed on the Lord&#xA;and she sought deliverance, which has now come to her. But you, on the&#xA;contrary, while you performed only holy acts, had your mind always fixed&#xA;on the wickedness of others. You saw only sin, and thought only of sin,&#xA;so now you have to go to that place where only sin is.&amp;rdquo; The moral of the&#xA;story is obvious: The outer life avails little. The heart must be pure&#xA;and the pure heart sees only good, never evil. We should never try to be&#xA;guardians of mankind, or to stand on a pedestal as saints reforming&#xA;sinners. Let us rather purify ourselves, and the result must be that in&#xA;so doing we shall help others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>801 JNANA YOGA - VII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/801_jnana-yoga_vii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/801_jnana-yoga_vii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jnana-yoga---vii&#34;&gt;JNANA YOGA - VII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(These were originally recorded by a prominent American disciple of the&#xA;Swami, Miss S. E. Waldo. Swami Saradananda, while he was in America&#xA;(1896), copied them out from her notebook — &lt;em&gt;Ed&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Self is the condition of all in the universe, but It can never be&#xA;conditioned. As soon as we know that we are It, we are free. As mortals&#xA;we are not and never can be free. Free mortality is a contradiction in&#xA;terms, for mortality implies change, and only the changeless can be&#xA;free. The Atman alone is free, and that is our real essence. We feel&#xA;this inner freedom; in spite of all theories, all beliefs, we know it,&#xA;and every action proves that we know it. The will is not free, its&#xA;apparent freedom is but a reflection from the Real. If the world were&#xA;only an endless chain of cause and effect, where could one stand to help&#xA;it? There must needs be a piece of dry land for the rescuer to stand on,&#xA;else how can he drag anyone out of the rushing stream and save him from&#xA;drowning? Even the fanatic who cries &amp;ldquo;I am a worm&amp;rdquo;, thinks that he is on&#xA;the way to become a saint. He sees the saint even in the worm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>802 JNANA YOGA - VIII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/802_jnana-yoga_viii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/802_jnana-yoga_viii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jnana-yoga---viii&#34;&gt;JNANA YOGA - VIII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(These were originally recorded by a prominent American disciple of the&#xA;Swami, Miss S. E. Waldo. Swami Saradananda, while he was in America&#xA;(1896), copied them out from her notebook — &lt;em&gt;Ed&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Both happiness and misery are chains, the one golden, the other iron;&#xA;but both are equally strong to bind us and hold us back from realising&#xA;our true nature. The Atman knows neither happiness nor misery. These are&#xA;mere &amp;ldquo;states&amp;rdquo;, and states must ever change. The nature of the soul is&#xA;bliss and peace unchanging. We have not to &lt;em&gt;get&lt;/em&gt; it; we &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; it; let&#xA;us wash away the dross from our eyes and see it. We must stand ever on&#xA;the Self and look with perfect calmness upon all the panorama of the&#xA;world. It is but baby&amp;rsquo;s play and ought never to disturb us. If the mind&#xA;is pleased by praise, it will be pained by blame. All pleasures of the&#xA;senses or even of the mind are evanescent, but within ourselves is the&#xA;one true unrelated pleasure, dependent on nothing outside. &amp;ldquo;The pleasure&#xA;of the Self is what the world calls religion.&amp;rdquo; The more our bliss is&#xA;within, the more spiritual we are. Let us not depend upon the world for&#xA;pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>803 JNANA YOGA - IX</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/803_jnana-yoga_ix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/lectures_and_discourses/discourses_on_jnana-yoga/803_jnana-yoga_ix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jnana-yoga---ix&#34;&gt;JNANA YOGA - IX&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(These were originally recorded by a prominent American disciple of the&#xA;Swami, Miss S. E. Waldo. Swami Saradananda, while he was in America&#xA;(1896), copied them out from her notebook — &lt;em&gt;Ed&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Expression is necessarily degeneration, because spirit can only be&#xA;expressed by the &amp;ldquo;letter&amp;rdquo;, and as St. Paul said, &amp;ldquo;the letter killeth&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Life cannot be in the &amp;ldquo;letter&amp;rdquo; which is only a reflection. Yet,&#xA;principle must be clothed in matter to be &amp;ldquo;known&amp;rdquo;. We lose sight of the&#xA;Real in the covering and come to consider that as the Real, instead of&#xA;as the symbol. This is an almost universal mistake. Every great Teacher&#xA;knows this and tries to guard against it; but humanity, in general, is&#xA;prone to worship the &lt;em&gt;seen&lt;/em&gt; rather than the unseen. This is why a&#xA;succession of prophets have come to the world to point again and again&#xA;to the principle behind the personality and to give it a new covering&#xA;suited to the times. Truth remains ever unchanged, but it can only be&#xA;presented in a &amp;ldquo;form&amp;rdquo;; so from time to time a new &amp;ldquo;form&amp;rdquo; or expression&#xA;is given to Truth, as the progress of mankind makes them ready to&#xA;receive it. When we free ourselves from name and form, especially when&#xA;we no longer need a body of any kind, good or bad, coarse or fine, then&#xA;only do we escape from bondage. &amp;ldquo;Eternal progression&amp;rdquo; would be eternal&#xA;bondage. We must get beyond all differentiation and reach eternal&#xA;&amp;ldquo;sameness&amp;rdquo; or homogeneity or Brahman. The Atman is the unity of all&#xA;personalities and is unchangeable, the &amp;ldquo;One without a second&amp;rdquo;. It is not&#xA;life, but it is coined into life. It is beyond life and death and good&#xA;and bad. It is the Absolute Unity. Dare to seek Truth even through hell.&#xA;Freedom can never be true of name and form, of the related. No form can&#xA;say, &amp;ldquo;I am free as a form.&amp;rdquo; Not until all idea of form is lost, does&#xA;freedom come. If our freedom hurts others, we are not free there. We&#xA;must not hurt others. While real perception is only one, relative&#xA;perceptions must be many. The fountain of all knowledge is in every one&#xA;of us — in the ant as in the highest angel. Real religion is one; all&#xA;quarrel is with the forms, the symbols, the &amp;ldquo;illustrations&amp;rdquo;. The&#xA;millennium exists already for those who find it. The truth is, we have&#xA;lost ourselves and think the world to be lost. &amp;ldquo;Fool! Hearest not thou?&#xA;In thine own heart, day and night, is singing that Eternal Music —&#xA;Sachchidānanda, Soham, Soham, (Existence, Knowledge, and Bliss, I am He,&#xA;I am He)!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
