<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bakery iyengars</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/bakery-iyengars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/bakery-iyengars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/as-caste-lines-blur-iyengar-bakery-owners-fight-for-survival-and-brand/articleshow/51876815.cms&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As caste lines blur, Iyengar bakery owners fight for survival and brand&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sandeep Moudgal / TNN / Apr 18, 2016, 14:53 IST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In pre-independence India, struck by poverty, illiteracy and a lack of livelihood, the family of Narayan Iyengar decided to move away from their village on the banks of the Hemavathi in Hassan, like many others of his community. As an apprentice at his relative&amp;rsquo;s bakery, he worked his way up to launch his own Iyengar Bakery in Bangalore.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>bhUmihar v1 claim</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/bhUmihar_v1_claim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/bhUmihar_v1_claim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bhumihars of Bihar and U.P. did not participate in the common front of Brahmins and Rajputs in 1857. Maharajas of Benaras, Hathua and Bettiah rendered signal service to the British during 1857. On the other hand the Britishers believed that 1857 was the mechinations of Brahmins and Rajputs in Bihar and U.P. Maharani Victoria&amp;rsquo;s declaration on Ist November, 1858, obliquely accepted the Caste hierarchy of Hindu Society. The result was the acceptance of Brahmin superiority and Kunwar Singh&amp;rsquo;s Rajput caste as second in caste category. A furore was created in the minds of Bhumihars, as they were placed third in the ad-hoc census of 1865 in U.P. and Bihar. The Regular Census began in 1881. The Bhumihars were greatly shocked and felt humiliated, finding themselves in the third position in the Regular Census.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>chattar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/chattar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/chattar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1688263681514012674.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;🧵on the Cattar or Cathiar. The Cathiar were Brahmin war bands found throughout Kerala and Tamil Nadu as well as the rest of Southern India, where they were referred to as ghatam/kalam.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Cathiar would take up arms for their respective kings. However upon defeat of their liege lord, they could be incorporated into the new kingdom. At times, they entered into political disputes, choosing the kings of the Cheras and Pallavas, or even founded kingdoms in the case of the Kadambas. To join the Cathiar, one had to be proficient in the Vedas and had to be certified by 5 current members that the candidate was proficient in Vaiyakarna, Mimamsa and Purohita.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fragmentation vs muslims</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/fragmentation_vs_muslims/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/fragmentation_vs_muslims/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/2016542745465418012.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reason I don’t comment on caste issues is for two reasons&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It makes Hs falsely think they are very divided people while Ms are united. (i.e- look up number of Alawite Shiites killed in Syria last year)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I blame UC elites for our problems, not OBCs SCs STs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;division-exaggerated&#34;&gt;Division exaggerated&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at 1) first. The idea that Hindus are divided on caste and hate each other is a misleading myth. Hindus are fragmented but do not hate each other. Muslims have a veneer of unity but hate each other to the point of murder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HT thai br Ahma Nas india 24</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/HT_thai-brAhmaNas_india_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/HT_thai-brAhmaNas_india_24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hinduismtoday.com/magazine/october-november-december-2024/siamese-brahmins-assist-the-king/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Siamese Brahmins Assist the King&lt;br&gt;&#xA;By Hinduism Today / October 1, 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For 800 years Hindu priests have guided Thailand’s royal court rituals&lt;br&gt;&#xA;By Hurditya Deva, Thailand&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Among the indian diaspora scattered across the globe, their settlement in Thailand, formerly known as Siam, often goes unnoticed. This likely stems from the seamless integration of Indian religions, culture and society into Thai life since ancient times. The propagation of Buddhism and Hinduism was primarily led by monks and priests who built monasteries and temples to promote their faiths. In early modern times, Hindu priests became known as Siamese Brahmins, an esteemed group headed by the Rajaguru, appointed by the monarch. They have played a pivotal role in shaping the country’s spiritual and cultural landscape since the Sukhothai period (13th–14th centuries ce) or earlier. Descendants of ancient lineages, these brahmins conduct royal ceremonies, preserve traditional rituals and provide spiritual guidance to the Thai monarchy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kAnyakubja-migration</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/kAnyakubja-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/kAnyakubja-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coming from Kanyakubja is a frequent claim among Brahmins living in distant areas from the Ganges heartland. Short thread on some instances of migration of Kanyakubja Brahmins. 🧵&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 4th century Nandisutra written in Nagari script found in Gujarat tells about Grants of Ancient Copper-plates to Brahmins who came to Gujarat from Kanyakubja. Interestingly there are Anavil Brahmins of Gujarat who claim to be descended from Kanyakubjas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most famous Instance of Kanyakubjas Migrating comes from Bengal when King Adisura who was troubled by the lack of Vedic prowess among Brahmins already residing there, invited 5 Brahmins from Kannauj for restoring the Brahminical order in Bengal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KAshMIra paNDita ids</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/kAshMIra-paNDita-ids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/kAshMIra-paNDita-ids/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scoopnews.in/det.aspx?q=33929&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The identities of Kashmiri Pandits&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By A.K. Trisal&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kashmir is an ancient principality. In the Puranas, it is mentioned by the name of Greek which means a hill. The Mahabharta and the Budhdist literature referred it as Kasmira. While Mulasarvastivada Vinaya calls it Kashmira Mandala. For Greek Astronomers it was Kaspeiria. To-yeng and Sun-Yan in 6th A. D. termed the Kashmir as Shiemi and Hieun-Tsang in 7th century A. D. called it Kia-shih-mi-lo. Kachal and Kashrat were the names given by Tibetans and the Dards respectively in the past while the ancient Kashmiris themselves called their country as Kasmira which was later shortened to Kashir, and is now known as Kashmir. Kashmir is surrounded by heaven high mountains. The twin peak of Nun and Kun to East and in the North West Nanga Parbat towers above the Indus. The mountains consist of three ranges namely:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NambUtiri faq</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/nambUtiri-faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/nambUtiri-faq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.namboothiri.com/articles/faq/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.namboothiri.com/articles/faq/faq3.htm&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Q-2. What is the origin of the name Embranthiri? Does it exclusively apply to Brahmins from South Kanara settled in Kerala? (Nikhil Rao, Software Engineer, USA)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ans: In the 8th century AD, as per the request from King Udayavarma Raja of Kolathunaad (a small ancient kingdom in north Kerala), King Mayooravarman of Gokarnam sent 237 Tulu Brahmanan families to Kolathunaad. These family members performed &amp;ldquo;Hiranyagarbha&amp;rdquo; and converted themselves to Malayalam Brahmanans. They had settled in Arathil, Cheruthaazham, Pilathara and Chirakkal. All these places are in and around one of the strongest Namboothiri Graamams (villages) of those days, Perinchelloor (near today&amp;rsquo;s Taliparamba in Kannur district in north Kerala).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sanADhya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/sanADhya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/jAtiH/articles/sanADhya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Sanadhya Brahman use Pandit as their title. The community has its origin from four villages of the district, viz., Anni, Dahni, Reunai and Parasrar of Badaun. They are principally found in Budaun, Bareilly, Agra, Etah, Aligarh, Etawah and Shahjahanpur districts. They live in the plains where climate is moderate and good for cultivation. The area is devoid of forest or has thin forest. There is generally medium rainfall.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The community members speak Hindi and use Devanagari script with kin group and also others in their day-to-day activity. They also have adequate knowledge of Sanskrit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
