<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;4 Going forward on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/4_going_forward/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;4 Going forward on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/4_going_forward/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>18 Human Factors</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/4_going_forward/18_Human_Factors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/4_going_forward/18_Human_Factors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Energy has occupied center-stage in this book because it is the physical currency of activity. Fossil fuel availability permitted the Industrial Revolution and all that came with it. Human civilization has never before faced the prospect of such a crucial global resource either disappearing or being abandoned due to other ills (e.g., climate change).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite the mixed suitabilities of alternative energy sources presented in Chapter 17, some physically viable avenues are open to us. In other words, physics itself does not preclude development of an energy landscape consisting primarily of solar, wind, and hydroelectric power, plus a few small contributions from a variety of other sources. Life may be different; less air travel or transportation in general, as one possibility. The enormous solar potential combined with decent storage technologies could conceivably maintain our 18 TW appetite without fossil fuels.+++(4)+++ Or we could scale back and not expect to live in such a profligate manner, viewing our current ways and expectations in the broader human experience as anomalous, temporary, and not important to preserve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 A Plan Might Be Welcome</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/4_going_forward/19_A_Plan_Might_Be_Welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/4_going_forward/19_A_Plan_Might_Be_Welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having discussed some of the human factors related to accepting and mitigating challenges, we now turn to the question of what humanity&amp;rsquo;s goal might be if we could collectively start rowing in the same direction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, we will have to assess the form that our actions have taken in the absence of a coherent plan. Next, we address challenges inherent in devising and adopting a roadmap for our future. Finally, a possible target is presented that bears consideration as we grapple with possible modes of human society going forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Adaptation Strategies</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/4_going_forward/20_Adaptation_Strategies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/4_going_forward/20_Adaptation_Strategies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We made it to the final chapter. How are we doing? Anxious? Excited? Alarmed? Inspired? This book has compressed a perspective that took the author many years to absorb. Exposure in one short sprint would likely be overwhelming, and might even generate an impulse to reject the message as both unfamiliar and grim-thus hopefully wrong?&#xA;Up to this point, the theme of the book might be characterized as one of closing lots of exits. Growth can&amp;rsquo;t continue indefinitely requiring a whole different economic model. Space is not a realistic escape hatch. Fossil fuels are what made this life possible, but will not last and are causing disruptive climate change. The alternative options all have their own practical limitations, and offer no drop-in replacements for fossil fuels. At least sunshine offers a ray of light as a super-abundant energy flow. But when it comes to making collectively smart decisions about a future path, more obstacles surface on the human side. Success requires long-term planning and not the more common crisis response.&#xA;This chapter changes gears a bit to touch on individual actions and values that could amount to big things in aggregate. At the very least, it may provide individual-scale escape hatches allowing some peace of mind about personal contributions to the problem.&#xA;20.1 Awareness&#xA;20.2 Communication&#xA;Predicament, not Problems 20.3 Guidelines for Adaptation Overall Framing &amp;hellip; Energy Assessment Rules . Quantitative Footprint &amp;hellip; Dietary Energy . Flexitarianism&#xA;328&#xA;330&#xA;332&#xA;332&#xA;333&#xA;334&#xA;337&#xA;339&#xA;.341&#xA;Discretionary Summary 20.4 Values Shifts&#xA;342&#xA;343&#xA;344&#xA;346&#xA;20.5 Flexibility in Uncertainty 20.6 Upshot on Strategies 20.7 Problems (Predicaments?). 347&#xA;20.1 Awareness&#xA;How many people do you know who are concerned about a legitimate threat of collapse of our civilization? It is an extreme outcome, and one without modern precedent. It seems like a fringe, alarmist position that is uncomfortable to even talk about in respectable company. Yet the evidence on the ground points to many real concerns:&#xA;Growing your own food is a great way to lower your impact and be closer to nature. Photo credit: Irina Fischer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epilogue</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/4_going_forward/Epilogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/4_going_forward/Epilogue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;350&#xA;This book may be distressing for some: a body-slam to hope. The message can be more than some are ready to take in, or of an unacceptable flavor. I myself first approached this subject-when assigned to teach a general-education course on energy and the environment-with great enthusiasm, intending to sort out to my own satisfaction how I thought our gleaming future would migrate to renewable energy.&#xA;As I &amp;ldquo;ran the numbers&amp;rdquo; on various sources, I came to appreciate the tremendous quantitative advantage that solar power has over the alternatives. Being a hands-on person, I started cobbling together various off-grid photovoltaic systems, learning the practical ins and outs of stand-alone solar power1 coupled with storage as a crucial means to mitigate intermittency of the solar resource. My wife and I also bought a plug-in hybrid vehicle in 2013 to learn the pros and cons2 of electric cars, while preserving the ability to do occasional longer trips on gasoline. My commute to work is via an electric-assist bicycle charged by my off-grid solar system for a fossil-free transportation option.3 I have found adventure and delight in challenging myself to live a lower-energy lifestyle, and know from personal experience that dialing down demand does not have to be a crushing defeat for the human race. Our ambitions1 might suffer, but our spirits need not.&#xA;This book takes an approach that deliberately asks the wrong question, chapter after chapter: how can we keep going in a manner resembling the present form in the face of declining fossil fuel resources and/or a commitment to wean ourselves from fossil fuels as a mitigation strategy for climate change? This approach manifested itself as: can we get 18 TW of power5 from this or that alternative resource? In most cases, the answer was no. Solar is the glaring exception. Also, nuclear breedersbringing a tangle of tough problems-and the perpetually intractable nuclear fusion could offer long term provision of electricity. But none of the abundant resources easily replace liquid fuels for transportation, and effective utilization of the abundant yet intermittent solar resource depends critically on storage capabilities.&#xA;Thus, pretending that the goal is to keep 18 TW and carry on business as usual after a tidy substitution of energy turns out to be misguided. The real question becomes one of adapting to a new landscape: one in which our ambitions are checked by planetary limits. Indeed, if energy became essentially unlimited by some technology, I shudder to think what it would mean for the rest of the planet.&amp;quot; An age-old saying goes: With great power comes great responsibility. Humans have achieved great power, but have not yet demonstrated a respectable degree of responsibility in prioritizing the protection of plants, animals, and ecosystems.&#xA;1:&#xA;&amp;hellip; as a miniature model of what society at large may one day hope to do in a solardominated energy landscape&#xA;2: We have watched battery capacity drift down to about 65% presently.&#xA;3: Charging the car from the off-grid system would require a substantial upgrade in system size and battery capacity, costing approximately $10,000.&#xA;4: So far, human ambitions have been for the most part unconstrained by physical limitations. Just as a child must eventually shed fantastical dreams and beliefs, so too might the human race need to reign in unrealistic hopes for our future.&#xA;5:&#xA;or some sizable fraction thereof&#xA;6: A children&amp;rsquo;s story called Don&amp;rsquo;t Let the Pigeon Drive the Bus echoes the sense that great power in the hands of incompetence can be bad news. We would not put a toddler in command of an arsenal.&#xA;Should attention to planetary limits turn out to be a crucial element in the assessment of our situation, then we owe it to ourselves to get it straight. Imagine that you are running across a rooftop and have to make a quick decision about whether to jump a large gap between buildings. Would you appreciate a lightning-quick analysis of physics concluding that a successful jump is impossible? Certainly, such insight would be valuable, permitting the formation of an alternate plan, and saving yourself from the unfortunate fate of misplaced faith in your jumping abilities or in some fanciful notion of gravity&amp;rsquo;s weak grip over the chasm.8&#xA;Humanity is staring at a leap unlike anything history has prepared us to face, having accelerated ourselves to previously unimaginable speeds by the grace of fossil fuels, but now confronting their inevitable removal from the menu. The past offers little guidance on how to navigate such a situation, so we need to do our level best to soberly assess the challenges and recognize what is and what is not within the realm of practical expectations. I would love to be wrong about the numerous concerns raised in the book, but the asymmetric risk of trying the leap and failing could lead to a devastation that frightens me. Please, let us not risk it all on unfounded hopes or magical thinking.&amp;quot;&#xA;9&#xA;The situation reminds me of the housing bubble in the U.S. in the early 2000s. My wife and I bought a house when we moved to San Diego in 2003, and soon became worried about a potential crash10 leaving us &amp;ldquo;underwater&amp;rdquo;-owing more than the reduced worth of the house. I pored over articles on the matter, and found two camps. One camp provided rafts of alarming quantitative analysis of the peril: sub-prime lending, soaring price-to-income ratios, unprecedented unaffordability by average families, vulnerability to any weakness in other sectors. The other camp said that the housing market was manifesting a new normal, that San Diego&amp;rsquo;s universal appeal would prevent a price drop, that scary lending practices were easily skirted by re-financing before interest payments ballooned. I chose to go with the quantitative analysis over the hand-wavy platitude-based set of beliefs, and am glad that I did.&#xA;Now consider the quality and nature of common counter-arguments to the core message in this book. Humans are smart, innovative, and will figure out something. People 200 years ago could not have possibly predicted our capabilities today, so we are likewise ill-equipped to predict how amazing the future will be. I get the appeal. I really do. But does that mean we get to dismiss the difficulties exposed by careful analysis? Can we ignore the fact that we are pushing planetary boundaries for the first time ever? I would argue that this time really is different. The facts are inescapable:&#xA;11&#xA;The world has never before been strained with 8 billion people.12&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
