<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;PART-1 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;PART-1 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CH I</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_I/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_I/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-gaol-at-dongri-bombay&#34;&gt;The Gaol At Dongri, Bombay&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You are sentenced to fifty years&amp;rsquo; transportation. The International Tribunal at Hague has given judgement that England cannot be constrained to hand you over to France&amp;rdquo;, said Mr. X to me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well then, I had never depended on any hopes from that quarter. But can I have a copy of the judgement to look at?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That does not rest with me, though I will try my very best for you. Yet the fortitude you have shown in hearing the news that has wrung the heart of a stranger like me, does not make me think that you will wait for any help from an outsider like me,&amp;rdquo; said my interlQoutor almost overwhelmed with feeling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH II In The Gaol At Byculla</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_II_In_The_Gaol_At_Byculla/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_II_In_The_Gaol_At_Byculla/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While climbing up to my cell in the Byculla prison I felt that I had to go one step higher in solitariness and dejection. For the cell here was more gloomy and far lonelier than the one I had occupied at Dongri. At Dongri I had no other person near about me, but the noise of the outer world fell upon my ears. I had, besides, a book or two to read, and some sundry articles about me. Here everything of that kind was gone. No noise was heard here of the humming world without. Not a soul moved here, and articles of daily use were not here, so that I had no companionship here of any kind whatsoever. For want of these, I felt here completely isolated in mind and body and hence more lonely and deserted than ever. I surveyed my room. There was nothing in it to see and inspect. I paced up and down. What must be the condition of my fellow-conspirators and of the revolutionary society we had formed? What plan must we work out for its future? - These thoughts occupied my mind at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH III</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_III/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_III/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;at-thana&#34;&gt;At Thana&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It seemed to be all bustle and noise in the prison at Thana. Every one was, as it were, on the tiptoe of expectation. A prisoner sentenced to fifty years&amp;rsquo; transportation to the Andamans, a bar-at- law was arriving! The Officers in charge had issued the strictest orders that none was to look at me even with an eye askance. A part of the prison was purged clean of its prisoners and warders. It was kept apart for my occupation. But nothing could repress the curiosity of its inmates to have a look at me. My cell was guarded by the worst known warders of the place. They were, one and all, Mussalmans. and the wickedest of them, into the bargain. There was preternatural calm and solitude about me. My meal was served in due time, but I could hardly touch a morsel thereof. It consisted of hard-baked jwari bread and some vegetables ill-cooked and too sour to taste. I broke the bread, put the piece of it in my mouth, could hardly bite it and had to wash it down with water. Only a little of it I could eat. Then came evening, the door was closed, and I lay on my bed for sleep. It was now completely dark, for night had followed, when I heard gentle tapping on the door. I heard the voice of some one calling. It came from somewhere, I felt, as if in fear and trembling. I turned round and saw and discovered that the wickedest of my warders was beckoning on to me. I went to the door when, all eyes and ears&amp;quot; he whispered to me, &amp;ldquo;Sire, we have heard about your daring and valour, I am a slave to one so brave as you; I will do all that I can for you, no fear about it. Today I have brought you some news which I may pray you will keep strictly to yourself, for woe to me if it were to leak out. You are a hero, and I feel sure that you will never let me down. But I must warn you all the same.&amp;rdquo; So he carried on in a suppressed tone, and then coming up very close to me, whispered, &amp;ldquo;your brother is here.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;What brother&amp;rdquo;? I asked him. He replied that it was my younger brother. And he left precipitately as if he was anxious not to be caught in the act by any casual, observer. For my part, Iwithdrew inside.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH IV</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_IV/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_IV/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-the-way&#34;&gt;On The Way&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The portion of the prison-house reserved for the chalan&amp;rsquo;s confinement in the gaol at Thana, was to me like crossing the threshold and entering the precincts ofthe Andamans. The room in which I was locked up in that outlying part of the gaol, though a solitary cell, was within hearing of the rooms occupied by the prisoners in die Chalan. I could hear from my room the noise they created, the sighs they heaved, their wails, their talks and their good cheer, clearly enough to divert me from the long loneliness of my own cell. My mind, oppressed as it was with dejection and grief, felt: relieved by this company of prisoners near me. They were really hilarious, for, as I know, man laughs even in the dungeon-hole of utter calamity, overbearing grief, and unbearable tortures of body and mind. Such is his resilience. Perhaps, that horrid laughter is the acme of all laughters as it unburdens the soul of aft the horrors of under-ground imprisonment. Man laughs when he is reduced&amp;rsquo; to extremes, and his grief laughs with him when he grows callous to it, as if he has thrown rt offhimself to pass it on to the shoufders of callousness itself. Excessive joy or the ecstasy of joy, if you will, makes a man burst into tears. Similarly an excess of grief tests out into broad laughter. It is said, that in the days of the French Revolution, when inhuman bloodshed, slaughter, girilfofinm&amp;rsquo;g and murder had been the order of the day; when no man&amp;rsquo;s head Was safe ori his shoulders; when the premier and leader of today found himself to be the arch-traitor of tomorrow, with the guillotine waiting to chop off his head; when things had passed into the reign of terror, theatres in Paris were full to over-crowding, as they were never before, and wine flowed freely in the taverns of the city. Hilarity, mirth, merriment and brutal murder kept each other company, and danced and laughed and roared in sheer recklessness. &amp;ldquo;Let us eat, drink ahd be merry for tomorrow we dje &amp;quot; That seemed to be the obsession of them all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH IX EARLY HISTORY OF THE POLITICAL PRISONERS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_IX_EARLY_HISTORY_OF_THE_POLITICAL_PRISONERS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_IX_EARLY_HISTORY_OF_THE_POLITICAL_PRISONERS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-cult-of-the-bomb&#34;&gt;The Cult of the Bomb&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first batch of political prisoners sent to the Andamans consisted of Bengalis involved in the Manik Tola Bomb Case, and two gentlemen from Maharashtra, namely Mr. Ganesh Savarkar and Mr. Wamanrao Joshi. Soon after them came another batch of six persons from Bengal implicated in the trial for political dacoity. Of all these, three from Bengal and two from Maharashtra happened to be sentenced to transportation for life. Others, who were all of them Bengalis, had been sentenced for three to ten years&amp;rsquo; imprisonment. When I reached the Andamans there were the Bengali persons, I have menioned, and four editors of Swarajya from Allahabad with seven to ten years&amp;rsquo; imprisonment against them. The latter were sentenced for sedition and treason against the Government and, not like us, for revolutionary crime against the State. Some of these editors were deadly against all revolution and had not even understood its theory or known its practice. Their association with us had this advantage, that they had begun to know both the theory and practice of revolutionary movement and had begun to sympathize with it. I must be satisfied with this general statement today for I do not recollect now the trials in which these men were involved, their names, and their opinions on the issues in question. I remember another being there in addition to those, I have already named. As the majority of the first batch were Bengalis, we were all, in prison- parlence, known as Bengalis, later on, the number was swelled by an influx from the Punjab in their hundreds, and several from other provinces as well. So we came to be designated now by the hybrid name- the Bomb-makers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH V</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_V/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_V/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-black-sea&#34;&gt;The Black Sea&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They took me on the ladder and put me in the ground-floor of that steamer. A portion with strong iron bars was set apart in that place, no better than a long and narrow cage to accommodate twenty or thirty of us, in which were to be huddled prisoners on transportation at least fifty in number. We were no better there than cattle huddled up on board the steamer. I saw in that iron cage all the prisoners-the chalan-the whole of it, from Thana- arrayed and standing cheek by jowl in the file. They were cribbed and cabined into a space too small to hold them. As I saw them I wondered whether I was to be put in the same place with them, when the door of that partitioned room opened to welcome me. Yes, I found my place in that crowd and in rank and file. In England, I had suffered from bronchitis, and it had left its traces which always made my breathing hard in a narrow and congested room. I also had some pain in the chest due to such hard breathing. So I pointed out to a European Officer who accompanied us, that it would be dangerous to lock me up in such a place. He conveyed the information to the doctor in charge of the steamer. The doctor asked me to stay there for a while, and then, he would let me know about it. If anything went wrong, he assured me, he would certainly arrange for me elsewhere. In the meanwhile, he selected for me a spot in a far off corner of the same apartment, and ordered me to spread my bedding on that spot. How this special favour to me worked out in the end I shall narrate as I go on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH VI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_VI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_VI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-andamans&#34;&gt;The Andamans&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The group of islands, including the Andamans and the Nicobars, constitute a link not only with the past history of India but also with her development in the world of tomorrow. As such no Indian can afford to be ignorant about this group of islands. India of today is bound to have cultural contacts with other parts of the world; and the Andamans are a part of it that she is bound to influence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH VII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_VII/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_VII/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-reach-andamans&#34;&gt;We reach Andamans&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our steamer had entered the port of the Andamans and her anchor was cast with ringing chain into its waters. She had stopped, and boats and officers&amp;rsquo; launches were seen gathering around her to remove the prisoners. We had to wait for a long time before we were let down into the boats. I cast a glance around me to survey the place where I was to pass the rest of my life. My fellow- prisoners, who had been there before me, and, occasionally, some sepoys explained to me the topography of the island. There was the Ras Island, the head-quarters of the Chief Commissioner of the Andamans. The island ornamented the sea like a palace built in the land of the fairies. It was, indeed, small in size compared with other islands. But it was so picturesque and compact that it could not fail to ravish the mind of even a prisoner in chains like me. On the other side of the island, the foreshore of the sea was fringed by a long line of coconut trees waving their crests in the gentle breeze overhead. Beyond, one observed clusters of mango trees, betel-nut trees, and pipal trees. On the wharf were crowds of people filling the whole atmosphere with their humming voices. Higher up and just on one end of the climb, we saw a stately building in perfect seclusion and enclosed within circular walls and shaded by a thick grove of coconut trees. All round it were gardens of coconut, betel- nut and plantain trees. They stood there like royal menials waving their fans and holding their umbrella over the head of this &amp;ldquo;grand monarque.&amp;rdquo; The building, with its perfect calm, struck us as the mansion of a happy, solitude-loving rich man or the manse of a retired clergyman. We inquired of our neighbours, and a sepoy told us that it was the very &amp;ldquo;Silver Jail&amp;rdquo; of Barrie Baba. The guards on board the steamer had referred to that name more than once to rebuke the unruly prisoners in their charge. And the sepoys were not mistaken in their belief that its mere mention was enough to strike terror into their hearts. The man, who told us the name, kindly added that, as we were presently going to that place, he need say no more about Barrie Baba and his residence. We were let down the boat one after another in a line, and each one carried his bedding on his head and the pot and pan in his hand. Landing on the pier, other prisoners were at once marched in a line up the steep climb, under the strict escort of regulars and warders from the prison beyond. I, alone, was kept waiting on the wharf, and in charge of European Officers. Thus segregated from the rest, I sat there, and it suddenly struck me that the islands were so located in the Bay of Bengal that they constituted the bastion in the naval fortification of India from the East. As such they had an abiding importance in the future defence of our country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH VIII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_VIII/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_VIII/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-week-in-my-cell&#34;&gt;The First Week in my cell&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Jamadar led me to Chawl No. 7. On the way lay a big reservoir of water. The Jamadar asked me to take my bath there. I had not taken my bath for four or five days. My body was full of sweat and dirt. The sea-voyage had done it. I was delighted with the permission to bathe. But I had no garment to change. The Jamadar gave me a piece of cloth no better than a suspender. I had never entered my bath in that naked condition. What then? Was I not to wear it for bath and for my labour all my life here? The mind revolted, but then said, &amp;ldquo;Fool! did not a saint like Ramdas use the same apparel? The world knows what you carry within it. From whom are you hiding it now? Has not Milton described it as &amp;lsquo;honour dishonourable&amp;rsquo;?&amp;rdquo; There was a sect in Europe which considered it a sin to wear clothes. For Adam and Eve never wore any. Their followers adopted the same mode of life. And they called themselves Adamites. Even today, if not for religion, then for hygiene, colonies of men and women in certain regions of the world go about as nudists except in the cold season. They expose their bodies to sunlight as a matter of health. For, certain doctors in the West condemn the practice of excessive clothing as harmful to a man&amp;rsquo;s health. In Europe they wear too many clothes for fashion&amp;rsquo;s sake. They seldom expose their bodies to sunlight. From birth to death they wrap themselves up in clothes; and the health of these people had suffered. So doctors had opined, and the people had followed them. I was thinking all this over while I was donning the strip of cloth that was given to me by the Jamadar. The Jamadar had watched, with delight, the trepidation and shame of many a person here when he was called upon to take a bath in this dress or absence of dress. But he was disappointed in me and, perhaps, he set me down as the most shameless of them all! I went to the tank and was about to dip my pot into it, when the Jamadar cried out, &amp;ldquo;Not so here, you are&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH X</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_X/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_X/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-see-my-elder-brother&#34;&gt;I see my elder brother&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Myself and my elder brother were in the same jail, and we had not seen each other yet. His heart received a shock to know that I was here. And the news ofhis sufferings had wrung my heart. But a day came to prove unto me that these happenings in the past were almost nothing in our experience of life. Joy is scarcely fraught with such pain as that day brought to us both.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH XI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_XI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_XI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-am-put-on-the-oil-mill&#34;&gt;I am put on the Oil-Mill&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For nearly a month after my entry into the Silver Jail, I did the work of picking oakum. Everyone was wondering how I was not put on the oil-mill. The optimist said, &amp;ldquo;Now, how can they put &amp;lsquo;a barrister-babu&amp;rsquo; like me on the oil-mill?&amp;rdquo; I said to him, &amp;ldquo;They will put me on it with the same mouth that they pronounced the sentence of transportation for life on me!&amp;rdquo; At last, one day, the Superintendent came to me and said, &amp;ldquo;From tomorrow you shall have to work on the oil-mill. Oakum must have hardened your hands by now, and you can very well take up that work forthwith.&amp;rdquo; At this Mr. Barrie laughed and said in a banter, &amp;ldquo;Now you are promoted to a higher form.&amp;rdquo; That evening Mr. Barrie sent for me in his office. In his conversations with me, he had already learnt that I was in full sympathy with the strike that political prisoners in this gaol had organised; and that I had denounced those who reviled the strikers and their fearless stand as work of a fraternity of insolent, indecent and foolish folk. Their mouths had by now been shut by my attitude towards the strike and the strikers. The secret reports that were being conveyed to Mr. Barrie, from day to day, had almost convinced him that, before long, I was going to join their ranks and to be one of these indecent fools-nay, the very &amp;lsquo;prince of fools.&amp;rsquo; Mr. Barrie had called me to know if I was going to passively resist the new task that had been assigned to me by him and his like. He was anxious to dissuade me from that course. After talking on other sundry matters, he, at last came to the point, and said, &amp;ldquo;You will please realise that I am helpless here, and I must follow the orders of my superiors. They have written to say that you shall be put on the oil-mill, and I had no hand in that business. However, I have persuaded the Superintendent, realising your worth, to relax the order in your favour. You shall have to do the work only for a fortnight. I will not put you on it repeatedly as I have to do in other cases. I know you well, I know your worth, I would have you go on with it and not resist it. Go, do it, I will help you as far as I can. Only do not compel me to punish you.&amp;rdquo; To which I answered, &amp;ldquo;I will do the best I can. I will work as far as I can help it. My life is already a heap of ashes, and I have no desire to bring more trouble cm my head.&amp;rdquo; Mr. Barrie pretended to be overcome, and said, &amp;ldquo;Look here, I am telling you all this in your best interest. You have fifty years to pass in this jail. It gives a shock to me to realise it. So I pray that you will keep aloof from all further entanglements. Let others do what they like. You should have nothing to do with them.&amp;rdquo; His constant allusion to my sentence had ceased to shock me or to unnerve me. The more he repeated it, the more callous I became towards it. It was like the artillery man whom the constant sound ofthe whizzing cannon-ball had ceased to frighten and unnerve. The next morning&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH XII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_XII/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_XII/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;consolidation-and-propaganda-in-the-andamans&#34;&gt;Consolidation and Propaganda in the Andamans&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I worked on the &amp;lsquo;Kolu’ I had an opportunity of knowing much, not only of the condition of the political prisoners inside the jail, but also of the situation in the Andamans as a whole. In spite of a thousand obstacles in their way, those who had learnt to love and admire me put themselves into contact with me and gave me news about the islands. I, therefore, felt that even from this prison I could do some work of consolidating our forces in the Andamans. Of course, it demanded strenuous efforts and I was prepared for it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH XIII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_XIII/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_XIII/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;correspondence-with-india-and-means-of-information&#34;&gt;Correspondence with India and means of information&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A prisoner in the Andamans was permitted to write only one letter home during the year. The letter had, perforce, to be as brief as possible. Again, it was to be an open letter, to be censored first by the jailor, next by the Colonial Officer, and to be despatched if approved by them. Every prisoner was warned that the letter shall not be forwarded if it breathed a single word against the jail authorities. Thus only a slip of a letter could be sent by him home once every year. Even this small facility was taken away from him for the year if he was guilty of the slightest offence like talking to a fellow-prisoner, committing nuisance outside the stated hours, not sitting in a line, so on and so forth. One can imagine how difficult it was to be free from any trivial offence of the kind we have mentioned, during the course of three hundred and sixty-five days. It was impossible, therefore for any prisoner in the Andamans to convey any news about him to the outside world. It need not be said that it was also impossible for the outside world to send any news to him. The prisoner, in these circumstances, could not write even two lines, every year without fail, to inform his people at home that he was alive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH XIV</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_XIV/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_XIV/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-coronation-ceremony-of-1911-and-its-shadow-on-the-prison-in-the-andamans&#34;&gt;The Coronation Ceremony of 1911 and its shadow on the prison in the Andamans&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As narrated in the previous chapter, the publication of Mr. Hotilal&amp;rsquo;s letter by The Bengali created a flutter in the official dovecotes. In the wake of that stir and excitement was created an atmosphere of sudden hope in the prison at Andamans. A thick rumour was abroad that all political prisoners, including myself, would be released in a month or two after the Coronation Durbar at Delhi to follow the King-Emperor&amp;rsquo;s Coronation in London. The date given was December 1911.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH XV</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_XV/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_XV/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-prisoners-food-in-the-andamans&#34;&gt;The prisoner&amp;rsquo;s food in the Andamans&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While these changes were going on in India between the end of 1911 and the beginning of 1912, I had nearly finished my one year of imprisonment in the island of the Andamans. In spite of bad food and inhuman treatment in that prison, I had managed to keep normal health, on the whole, during the period. I may, therefore, give here a general idea of the kind of food we were served in this prison.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH XVI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_XVI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-1/CH_XVI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;suicide-mental-derangement-arrests-the-second-and-the-third-strike&#34;&gt;Suicide, Mental derangement, arrests, the second and the third strike&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the first six months of my sentence in the Andamans, I was treated as a prisoner in solitary confinement. As a matter of fact almost all other prisoners were sent outside the prison for their work after they had finished their term of six months of simple or hard labour in the prison itself But at the time that they were taken out. I was released from my lonely cell. Even then I was not allowed to mix with other men, but only made to sit in the gallery and opposite the door of my own room all by myself. Other political prisoners were free to talk and move w ith neighbours in their own block and those in common work With them. I alone was kept apart and all alone by myself. A special watch was kept on me to prevent me from any intercourse with other people of my class. For the whole day I sat in the gallery and in front of my room busy in making coils of rope-my daily labour at the time. With the evening I was sent back to my own room and locked for the night. Years went on in this round of dull routine. The only exception of it being my hours of dinner, morning and evening. For two hours in the day. I could see human feces and exchange words with them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
