<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Geo on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/geo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Geo on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/geo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/geo/europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/geo/europe/</guid>
      <description>Europe Economic union Many countries in Europe are part of a union which allows easy travel and relatively free trade with low taxation. Many are also use a common currency, Euro, issued by a central bank.
A big part of the motivation for doing this was to quell fears that the strong German economy might again give rise to an expansionist war-machine.
Euro [Incomplete]
Strength of economies Economic viability of sovereigns is discussed elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>China</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/geo/china/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/geo/china/</guid>
      <description>Chinese economy is growing at a fast pace. Politically, China seems to be stable in the short to medium term.
Manufacturing China has a trade surplus relative to the USA. It is a manufacturing hub.
Media China, due to tight censorship, does not seem to be a hot-spot for internet businesses. It blocks Facebook, twitter - anything which can be used to organize subversion of the government.
Middle class 1.4% of urban households make more than $15,000 a year, and only 11% make $5,000-15,000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USA</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/geo/usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/geo/usa/</guid>
      <description>General economy USA has high trade deficit: especially with oil producing countries and manufacturers like China.
GDP Growth is much lower than in emerging economies: 0-3%.
Industry USA’s industry is highly innovative - one of the best in the world. Industries are highly mechanized.
Manufacturing America is the biggest manufacturer of goods in the world. But, much of the manufacturing is done in highly automated factories which are run by a handful of skilled employees overseeing the automation; manufacturing involving low skilled labour has moved to countries (in the developing world) with cheaper labor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>