<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;translation prose on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/translation_prose/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;translation prose on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/translation_prose/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>220 THE PROBLEM OF MODERN INDIA AND ITS SOLUTION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/translation_prose/220_the_problem_of_modern_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/translation_prose/220_the_problem_of_modern_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-problem-of-modern-india-and-its-solution&#34;&gt;THE PROBLEM OF MODERN INDIA AND ITS SOLUTION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(The above is a translation of the first&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;b6024_problem_of_modern_india.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt; article written by Swami&#xA;Vivekananda as an introduction to the &lt;em&gt;Udbodhana&lt;/em&gt;, when it was started&#xA;on the 14th of January, 1899, as the Bengali fortnightly (afterwards&#xA;monthly) journal of the Ramakrishna Order.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ancient history of India is full of descriptions of the gigantic&#xA;energies and their multifarious workings, the boundless spirit, the&#xA;combination of indomitable action and reaction of the various forces,&#xA;and, above all, the profound thoughtfulness of a godly race. If the word&#xA;history is understood to mean merely narratives of kings and emperors,&#xA;and pictures of society — tyrannised over from time to time by the evil&#xA;passions, haughtiness, avarice, etc., of the rulers of the time,&#xA;portraying the acts resulting from their good or evil propensities, and&#xA;how these reacted upon the society of that time — such a history India&#xA;perhaps does not possess. But every line of that mass of the religious&#xA;literature of India, her ocean of poetry, her philosophies and various&#xA;scientific works reveal to us — a thousand times more clearly than the&#xA;narratives of the life-incidents and genealogies of particular kings and&#xA;emperors can ever do — the exact position and every step made in advance&#xA;by that vast body of men who, even before the dawn of civilisation,&#xA;impelled by hunger and thirst, lust and greed, etc., attracted by the&#xA;charm of beauty, endowed with a great and indomitable mental power, and&#xA;moved by various sentiments, arrived through various ways and means at&#xA;that stage of eminence. Although the heaps of those triumphal flags&#xA;which they gathered in their innumerable victories over nature with&#xA;which they had been waging war for ages, have, of late, been torn and&#xA;tattered by the violent winds of adverse circumstances and become worn&#xA;out through age, yet they still proclaim the glory of Ancient India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>221 RAMAKRISHNA: HIS LIFE AND SAYINGS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/translation_prose/221_ramakrishna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/translation_prose/221_ramakrishna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ramakrishna-his-life-and-sayings&#34;&gt;RAMAKRISHNA: HIS LIFE AND SAYINGS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;b6007_ramakrishna.pdf&#34;&gt;Translation&lt;/a&gt; of a review of &lt;em&gt;Ramakrishna: His&#xA;Life and Sayings&lt;/em&gt; by Prof. Max Müller, contributed to the &lt;em&gt;Udbodhana&lt;/em&gt;,&#xA;14th March, 1899.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Among the Sanskrit scholars of the West, Professor Max Müller takes the&#xA;lead. The Rig-Veda Samhitā, the whole of which no one could even get at&#xA;before, is now very neatly printed and made accessible to the public,&#xA;thanks to the munificent generosity of the East India Company and to the&#xA;Professor&amp;rsquo;s prodigious labours extending over years. The alphabetical&#xA;characters of most of the manuscripts, collected from different parts of&#xA;India, are of various forms, and many words in them are inaccurate. We&#xA;cannot easily comprehend how difficult it is for a foreigner, however&#xA;learned he may be, to find out the accuracy or inaccuracy of these&#xA;Sanskrit characters, and more especially to make out clearly the meaning&#xA;of an extremely condensed and complicated commentary. In the life of&#xA;Professor Max Müller, the publication of the Rig-Veda is a great event.&#xA;Besides this, he has been dwelling, as it were, and spending his whole&#xA;lifetime amidst ancient Sanskrit literature; but notwithstanding this,&#xA;it does not imply that in the Professor&amp;rsquo;s imagination India is still&#xA;echoing as of old with Vedic hymns, with her sky clouded with&#xA;sacrificial smoke, with many a Vasishtha, Vishvāmitra, Janaka, and&#xA;Yājnavalkya, with her every home blooming with a Gārgi or a Maitreyi and&#xA;herself guided by the Vedic rules or canons of Grihya-Sutra.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>222 THE PARIS CONGRESS OF THE HISTORY OF RELIGIONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/translation_prose/222_the_paris_congress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/translation_prose/222_the_paris_congress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-paris-congress-of-the-history-of-religions&#34;&gt;THE PARIS CONGRESS OF THE HISTORY OF RELIGIONS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Translated from &lt;a href=&#34;6038_paris.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt; from a Paris letter written&#xA;to the &lt;em&gt;Udbodhana&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the Paris Exhibition, the Congress of the History of Religions&#xA;recently sat for several days together. At the Congress, there was no&#xA;room allowed for the discussions on the doctrines and spiritual views of&#xA;any religion; its purpose was only to inquire into the historic&#xA;evolution of the different forms of established faiths, and along with&#xA;it other accompanying facts that are incidental to it. Accordingly, the&#xA;representation of the various missionary sects of different religions&#xA;and their beliefs was entirely left out of account in this Congress. The&#xA;Chicago Parliament of Religions was a grand affair, and the&#xA;representatives of many religious sects from all parts of the world were&#xA;present at it. This Congress, on the other hand, was attended only by&#xA;such scholars as devote themselves to the study of the origin and the&#xA;history of different religions. At the Chicago Parliament the influence&#xA;of the Roman Catholics was great, and they organised it with great hopes&#xA;for their sect. The Roman Catholics expected to establish their&#xA;superiority over the Protestants without much opposition; by proclaiming&#xA;their glory and strength and laying the bright side of their faith&#xA;before the assembled Christians, Hindus, Buddhists, Mussulmans, and&#xA;other representatives of the world-religions and publicly exposing their&#xA;weakness, they hoped to make firm their own position. But the result&#xA;proving otherwise, the Christian world has been deplorably hopeless of&#xA;the reconciliation of the different religious systems; so the Roman&#xA;Catholics are now particularly opposed to the repetition of any such&#xA;gathering. France is a Roman Catholic country; hence in spite of the&#xA;earnest wish of the authorities, no religious congress was convened on&#xA;account of the vehement opposition on the part of the Roman Catholic&#xA;world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>223 KNOWLEDGE: ITS SOURCE AND ACQUIREMENT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/translation_prose/223_knowledge_its_source_and_acquirement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/translation_prose/223_knowledge_its_source_and_acquirement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;knowledge-its-source-and-acquirement&#34;&gt;KNOWLEDGE: ITS SOURCE AND ACQUIREMENT&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Translated from a &lt;a href=&#34;b6031_gyanarjan.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt; contribution by Swami&#xA;Vivekananda to the &lt;em&gt;Udbodhana&lt;/em&gt;, 12th February, 1899.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Various have been the theories propounded as regards the primitive&#xA;source of knowledge. We read in the Upanishads that Brahmā, who was the&#xA;first and the foremost among the Devas, held the key to all knowledge,&#xA;which he revealed to his disciples and which, being handed down in&#xA;succession, has been bequeathed as a legacy to the subsequent age.&#xA;According to the Jains, during an indefinite period of cycle of Time,&#xA;which comprises between one thousand and two thousand billions of&#xA;&amp;ldquo;oceans&amp;rdquo; of years, are born some extraordinary, great, perfected beings&#xA;whom they call Jinas, and through them the door to knowledge is now and&#xA;shell opened to human society. Likewise Buddhism believes in, and&#xA;expects at regular intervals, the appearance of the Buddhas, that is,&#xA;persons possessed of infinite universal wisdom. The same is the reason&#xA;also of the introduction of Incarnations of God by the Paurānika Hindus,&#xA;who ascribe to them, along with other missions, the special function of&#xA;restoring the lost spiritual knowledge by its proper adjustment to the&#xA;needs of the time. Outside India, we find the great-souled Zoroaster&#xA;bringing down the light of knowledge from above to the mortal world. So&#xA;also did Moses, Jesus, and Mohammed, who, possessed of heavenly&#xA;authority, proclaim to fallen humanity the tidings of divine wisdom in&#xA;their own unique ways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>224 MODERN INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/translation_prose/224_modern_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/translation_prose/224_modern_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;modern-india&#34;&gt;MODERN INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Translated from a &lt;a href=&#34;b6171_modern_india.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt; contribution to&#xA;the Udbodhana, March 1899&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Vedic priests base their superior strength on the knowledge of the&#xA;sacrificial Mantras. (Vedic hymns uttered by the priests to invoke the&#xA;Devas at the time of sacrifice.) By the power of these Mantras, the&#xA;Devas are made to come down from their heavenly abodes, accept the drink&#xA;and food offerings, and grant the prayers of the Yajamānas. (The men who&#xA;perform sacrifices.) The kings as well as their subjects are, therefore,&#xA;looking up to these priests for their welfare during their earthly life.&#xA;Raja Soma (The name of the Soma plant as commonly found in the Vedas.&#xA;The priests offered to the Devas the juice of this plant at the time of&#xA;sacrifice.) is worshipped by the priest and is made to thrive by the&#xA;power of his Mantras. As such, the Devas, whose favourite food is the&#xA;juice of the Soma plant offered in oblation by the priest, are always&#xA;kind to him and bestow his desired boons. Thus strengthened by divine&#xA;grace, he defies all human opposition; for what can the power of mortals&#xA;do against that of the gods? Even the king, the centre of all earthly&#xA;power, is a supplicant at his door. A kind look from him is the greatest&#xA;help; his mere blessing a tribute to the State, pre-eminent above&#xA;everything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>225 THE EDUCATION THAT INDIA NEEDS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/translation_prose/225_the_education_that_india_needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/translation_prose/225_the_education_that_india_needs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-education-that-india-needs&#34;&gt;THE EDUCATION THAT INDIA NEEDS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Written to Shrimati Saralā Ghosal, B.A., Editor, &lt;em&gt;Bhārati&lt;/em&gt;, from&#xA;Darjeeling, 24th April, 1897. (Translated from&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;b7332e4trans_prose_edu.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt; .)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In reply to your questions about the methods of work, the most important&#xA;thing I have to say is that the work should be started on a scale which&#xA;would be commensurate with the results desired. I have heard much of&#xA;your liberal mind, patriotism, and steady perseverance from my friend&#xA;Miss Müller; and the proof of your erudition is evident. I look upon it&#xA;as a great good fortune that you are desirous to know what little this&#xA;insignificant life has been able to attempt; I shall state it to you&#xA;here, as far as I can. But first I shall lay before you my mature&#xA;convictions for your deliberation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>226 OUR PRESENT SOCIAL PROBLEMS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/translation_prose/226_our_present_social_problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/translation_prose/226_our_present_social_problems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Addressee &lt;a href=&#34;../../volume_5/epistles_first_series/089_mother.htm&#34;&gt;»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-present-social-problems&#34;&gt;OUR PRESENT SOCIAL PROBLEMS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Translated from a &lt;a href=&#34;b8518e4trans_prose_social.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali letter&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;written to Shrimati Mrinalini Bose from Deoghar (Vaidyanāth), on 23rd&#xA;December, 1898.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;स ईशोऽनिर्वचनीयप्रेमस्वरूपः — &amp;ldquo;The Lord whose nature is unspeakable&#xA;love.&amp;rdquo; That this characteristic of God mentioned by Nārada is manifest&#xA;and admitted on all hands is the firm conviction of my life. The&#xA;aggregate of many individuals is called Samashti (the whole), and each&#xA;individual is called Vyashti (a part). You and I — each is Vyashti,&#xA;society is Samashti. You, I, an animal, a bird, a worm, an insect, a&#xA;tree, a creeper, the earth, a planet, a star — each is Vyashti, while&#xA;this universe is Samashti, which is called Virāt, Hiranyagarbha, or&#xA;Ishvara in Vedānta, and Brahmā, Vishnu, Devi, etc., in the Purānas.&#xA;Whether or not Vyashti has individual freedom, and if it has, what&#xA;should be its measure, whether or not Vyashti should completely&#xA;sacrifice its own will, its own happiness for Samashti — are the&#xA;perennial problems before every society. Society everywhere is busy&#xA;finding the solution of these problems. These, like big waves, are&#xA;agitating modern Western society. The doctrine which demands the&#xA;sacrifice of individual freedom to social supremacy is called socialism,&#xA;while that which advocates the cause of the individual is called&#xA;individualism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
