<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;reports in american newspapers on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;reports in american newspapers on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>085 volume 2/reports in american newspapersnote</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/085_note/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/085_note/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NOTE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These reports from American newspapers have been given exactly as they&#xA;were in the original. The wrong spellings of proper names, faulty&#xA;punctuation and grammar have been left uncorrected. — &lt;em&gt;Publisher&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>086 DIVINITY OF MAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/086_divinity_of_man/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/086_divinity_of_man/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;divinity-of-man&#34;&gt;DIVINITY OF MAN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Ada Record&lt;/em&gt;, February 28, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The lecture on the Divinity of Man by Swami Vive Kananda, (In the&#xA;earlier days Swami Vivekananda&amp;rsquo;s name was thus mis-spelt by the American&#xA;Press. — &lt;em&gt;Publisher.&lt;/em&gt;) the Hindu monk, drew a packed house at the Opera&#xA;last Friday evening [February 22].&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He stated that the fundamental basis of all religions was belief in the&#xA;soul which is the real man, and something beyond both mind and matter,&#xA;and proceeded to demonstrate the proposition. The existence of things&#xA;material are dependent on something else. The mind is mortal because&#xA;changeable. Death is simply a change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>087 SWAMI VIVEKANANDA ON INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/087_swami_vivekananda_on_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/087_swami_vivekananda_on_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;swami-vivekananda-on-india&#34;&gt;SWAMI VIVEKANANDA ON INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Bay City &lt;em&gt;Daily Tribune&lt;/em&gt;, March 21, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bay City had a distinguished visitor yesterday in the person of Swami&#xA;Vive Kananda, the much talked of Hindoo monk. He arrived at noon from&#xA;Detroit where he has been the guest of Senator Palmer and proceeded&#xA;immediately to the Fraser house. There he was seen by a reporter for&#xA;&lt;em&gt;The Tribune&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kananda spoke entertainingly of his country and his impressions of this&#xA;country. He came to America via the Pacific and will return via the&#xA;Atlantic. &amp;ldquo;This is a great land,&amp;rdquo; he said, &amp;ldquo;but I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t like to live&#xA;here. Americans think too much of money. They give it preference over&#xA;everything else. Your people have much to learn. When your nation is as&#xA;old as ours you will be wiser. I like Chicago very much and Detroit is a&#xA;nice place.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>088 RELIGIOUS HARMONY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/088_religious_harmony/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/088_religious_harmony/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;religious-harmony&#34;&gt;RELIGIOUS HARMONY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Saginaw Evening News&lt;/em&gt;, March 22, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Swami Vive Kananda, the much talked of Hindoo monk, spoke to a small but&#xA;deeply interested audience last evening at the academy of music on &amp;ldquo;The&#xA;Harmony of Religions&amp;rdquo;. He was dressed in oriental costume and received&#xA;an extremely cordial reception. Hon. Rowland Connor gracefully&#xA;introduced the speaker, who devoted the first portion of his lecture to&#xA;an explanation of the different religions of India and of the theory of&#xA;transmigration of souls. The first invaders of India, the Aryans, did&#xA;not try to exterminate the population of India as the Christians have&#xA;done when they went into a new land, but the endeavour was made to&#xA;elevate persons of brutish habits. The Hindoo is disgusted with those&#xA;people of his own country who do not bathe and who eat dead animals. The&#xA;Northern people of India have not tried to force their customs on the&#xA;southerns, but the latter gradually adopted many ways of the former&#xA;class. In southernmost portions of India there are a few persons who are&#xA;Christians and who have been so for thousands [?] of years. The&#xA;Spaniards came to Ceylon with Christianity. The Spaniards thought that&#xA;their God commanded them to kill and murder and to tear down heathen&#xA;temples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>089 FROM FAR OFF INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/089_from_far_off_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/089_from_far_off_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-far-off-india&#34;&gt;FROM FAR OFF INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Saginaw Courier-Herald&lt;/em&gt;, March 22, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Seated in the lobby of the Hotel Vincent yesterday evening was a strong&#xA;and regular featured man of fine presence, whose swarthy skin made more&#xA;pronounced the pearly whiteness of his even teeth. Under a broad and&#xA;high forehead his eyes betoken intelligence. This gentleman was Swami&#xA;Vive Kananda, the Hindoo preacher. Mr. Kananda&amp;rsquo;s conversation is in pure&#xA;and grammatically constructed English sentences, to which his slightly&#xA;foreign accent lends piquancy. Readers of the Detroit papers are aware&#xA;that Mr. Kananda has lectured in that city a number of times and aroused&#xA;the animosity of some on account of his strictures upon Christians. *The&#xA;Courier-Herald * representative had a few moments&amp;rsquo; conversation with the&#xA;learned Buddhist [?] just before he left for the Academy, where he was&#xA;to lecture. Mr. Kananda said in conversation that he was surprised at&#xA;the lapses from the paths of rectitude which were so common among&#xA;Christians, but that there was good and bad to be found among members of&#xA;all religious bodies. One statement he made was decidedly un-American.&#xA;Upon being asked if he had been investigating our institutions, he&#xA;replied: &amp;ldquo;No, I am a preacher only.&amp;rdquo; This displayed both a want of&#xA;curiosity and narrowness, which seemed foreign to one who appeared to be&#xA;so well versed upon religious topics as did the Buddhist [?] preacher.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>090 AN EVENING WITH OUR HINDU COUSINS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/090_an_evening_with_our_hindu_cousins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/090_an_evening_with_our_hindu_cousins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-evening-with-our-hindu-cousins&#34;&gt;AN EVENING WITH OUR HINDU COUSINS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Northampton Daily Herald&lt;/em&gt;, April 16, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For Swami Vive Kananda proved conclusively that all our neighbors across&#xA;the water, even the remotest, are our close cousins differing only a&#xA;trifle in color, language, customs and religion, the silver-tongued&#xA;Hindu monk prefacing his address in city hall Saturday evening [April&#xA;14] by an historic sketch of the origin of his own and all other&#xA;leading nations of the earth which demonstrated the truth that&#xA;race-kinship is more of a simple fact than many know or always care to&#xA;admit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>091 THE MANNERS AND CUSTOMS OF INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/091_the_manners_and_customs_of_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/091_the_manners_and_customs_of_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-manners-and-customs-of-india&#34;&gt;THE MANNERS AND CUSTOMS OF INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Boston Herald&lt;/em&gt;, May 15, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Association Hall was crowded with ladies yesterday, to hear Swami&#xA;Vivekananda, the Brahmin (Meaning Hindu. — &lt;em&gt;Publisher&lt;/em&gt;.) Monk talk about&#xA;&amp;ldquo;The Religion of India&amp;rdquo; [actually &amp;ldquo;The Manners and Customs of India&amp;rdquo;],&#xA;for the benefit of the ward 16 day nursery [actually, Tyler-street Day&#xA;Nursery]. The Brahmin monk has become a fad in Boston, as he was in&#xA;Chicago last year, and his earnest, honest, cultured manner has won many&#xA;friends for him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>092 THE RELIGIONS OF INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/092_the_religions_of_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/092_the_religions_of_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-religions-of-india&#34;&gt;THE RELIGIONS OF INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Boston Herald&lt;/em&gt;, May 17, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Brahmin monk, Swami Vivekananda, lectured yesterday afternoon in&#xA;Association Hall on &amp;ldquo;The Religions of India&amp;rdquo;, in aid of the Ward 16 Day&#xA;Nursery. There was a large attendance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The speaker first gave an account of the Mahommedans, who formed, he&#xA;said, one-fifth of the population. They believed in both Old and New&#xA;Testaments, but Jesus Christ they regarded only as a prophet. They had&#xA;no church organization, though there was reading of the Koran.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>093 SECTS AND DOCTRINES IN INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/093_sects_and_doctrines_in_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/093_sects_and_doctrines_in_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;sects-and-doctrines-in-india&#34;&gt;SECTS AND DOCTRINES IN INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Harvard Crimson&lt;/em&gt;, May 17, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Swami Vivekananda, the Hindoo monk, gave an address last evening in&#xA;Sever Hall under the auspices of the Harvard Religious Union. The&#xA;address was very interesting, the clear and eloquent voice of the&#xA;speaker, and his low, earnest delivery making his words singularly&#xA;impressive.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are various sects and doctrines in India, said Vivekananda, some&#xA;of which accept the theory of a personal God, and others which believe&#xA;that God and the universe are one; but whatever sect the Hindoo belongs&#xA;to he does not say that his is the only right belief, and that all&#xA;others must be wrong. He believes that there are many ways of coming to&#xA;God; that a man who is truly religious rises above the petty quarrels of&#xA;sects or creed. In India if a man believes that he is a spirit, a soul,&#xA;and not a body, then he is said to have religion and not till then.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>094 LESS DOCTRINE AND MORE BREAD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/094_less_doctrine_and_more_bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/094_less_doctrine_and_more_bread/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;less-doctrine-and-more-bread&#34;&gt;LESS DOCTRINE AND MORE BREAD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Baltimore American&lt;/em&gt;, October 15, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Lyceum Theater was crowded last night at the first of a series of&#xA;meetings by the Vrooman Brothers. The subject discussed was &amp;ldquo;Dynamic&#xA;Religion&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Swami Vivekananda, the high priest [?] from India, was the last&#xA;speaker. He spoke briefly, and was listened to with marked attention.&#xA;His English and his mode of delivery were excellent. There is a foreign&#xA;accent to his syllables, but not enough to prevent him from being&#xA;plainly understood. He was dressed in the costume of his native country,&#xA;which was decidedly picturesque. He said he could speak but briefly&#xA;after the oratory that had preceded him, but he could add his&#xA;endorsement to all that had been said. He had traveled a great deal, and&#xA;preached to all kinds of people. He had found that the particular kind&#xA;of doctrine preached made little difference. What is wanted is practical&#xA;sort of work. If such ideas could not be carried out, he would lose his&#xA;faith in humanity. The cry all over the world is &amp;ldquo;less doctrine and more&#xA;bread&amp;rdquo;. He thought the sending of missionaries to India all right; he&#xA;had no objections to offer, but he thought it would be better to send&#xA;fewer men and more money. So far as India was concerned, she had&#xA;religious doctrine to spare. Living up to the doctrines was needed more&#xA;than more doctrines. The people of India, as well as the people all over&#xA;the world, had been taught to pray, but prayer with the lips was not&#xA;enough; people should pray with their hearts. &amp;ldquo;A few people in the&#xA;world,&amp;rdquo; he said, &amp;ldquo;really try to do good. Others look on and applaud, and&#xA;think that they themselves have done great good. Life is love, and when&#xA;a man ceases to do good to others, he is dead spiritually.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>095 THE RELIGION OF BUDDHA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/095_the_religion_of_buddha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/095_the_religion_of_buddha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-religion-of-buddha&#34;&gt;THE RELIGION OF BUDDHA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Morning Herald&lt;/em&gt;, October 22, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An audience which filled the Lyceum Theatre [Baltimore] from pit to&#xA;dome assembled last night at the second of the series of meetings held&#xA;by the Vrooman Brothers in the interest of &amp;ldquo;Dynamic Religion&amp;rdquo;. Fully&#xA;3,000 persons were present. Addresses were made by the Rev. Hiram&#xA;Vrooman, Rev. Walter Vrooman and Rev. Swarri Vivekananda, the Brahmin&#xA;High Priest now visiting this city. The speakers of the evening were&#xA;seated on the stage, the Rev. Vivekananda being an object of particular&#xA;interest to all. He wore a yellow turban and a red robe tied in at the&#xA;waste [sic] with a sash of the same color, which added to the Oriental&#xA;cast of his features and invested him with a peculiar interest. His&#xA;personality seemed to be the feature of the evening. His address was&#xA;delivered in an easy, unembarrassed manner, his diction being perfect&#xA;and his accent similar to that of a cultured member of the Latin race&#xA;familiar with the English language. He said in part:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>096 ALL RELIGIONS ARE GOOD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/096_all_religions_are_good/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/096_all_religions_are_good/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-religions-are-good&#34;&gt;ALL RELIGIONS ARE GOOD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;, October 29, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Kananda spoke yesterday at the People&amp;rsquo;s Church on the invitation of&#xA;Dr. Kent, pastor of the church. His talk in the morning was a regular&#xA;sermon, dealing entirely with the spiritual side of religion, and&#xA;presenting the, to orthodox sects, rather original proposition that&#xA;there is good in the foundation of every religion, that all religions,&#xA;like languages, are descended from a common stock, and that each is good&#xA;in its corporal and spiritual aspects so long as it is kept free from&#xA;dogma and fossilism. The address in the afternoon was more in the form&#xA;of a lecture on the Aryan race, and traced the descent of the various&#xA;allied nationalities by their language, religion and customs from the&#xA;common Sanskrit stock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>097 THE HINDU VIEW OF LIFE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/097_the_hindu_way_of_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/097_the_hindu_way_of_life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-hindu-view-of-life&#34;&gt;THE HINDU VIEW OF LIFE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Brooklyn Times&lt;/em&gt;, December 31, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Brooklyn Ethical Association, at the Pouch Gallery last night,&#xA;tendered a reception to Swami Vivekananda. . . . Previous to the&#xA;reception the distinguished visitor delivered a remarkably interesting&#xA;lecture on &amp;ldquo;The Religions of India&amp;rdquo;. Among other things he said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Hindoo&amp;rsquo;s view of life is that we are here to learn; the whole&#xA;happiness of life is to learn; the human soul is here to love learning&#xA;and get experience. I am able to read my Bible better by your Bible, and&#xA;you will learn to read your Bible the better by my Bible. If there is&#xA;but one religion to be true, all the rest must be true. The same truth&#xA;has manifested itself in different forms, and the forms are according to&#xA;the different circumstances of the physical or mental nature of the&#xA;different nations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>098 IDEALS OF WOMANHOOD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/098_ideals_of_womanhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/098_ideals_of_womanhood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ideals-of-womanhood&#34;&gt;IDEALS OF WOMANHOOD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Brooklyn Standard Union&lt;/em&gt;, January 21, 1895)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Swami Vivekananda, after being presented to the audience by Dr. Janes,&#xA;president of the Ethical Association, said in part:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The product of the slums of any nation cannot be the criterion of our&#xA;judgment of that nation. One may collect the rotten, worm-eaten apples&#xA;under every apple tree in the world, and write a book about each of&#xA;them, and still know nothing of the beauty and possibilities of the&#xA;apple tree. Only in the highest and best can we judge a nation — the&#xA;fallen are a race by themselves. Thus it is not only proper, but just&#xA;and right, to judge a custom by its best, by its ideal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>099 TRUE BUDDHISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/099_true_buddhism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/099_true_buddhism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;true-buddhism&#34;&gt;TRUE BUDDHISM&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Brooklyn Standard Union&lt;/em&gt;, February 4, 1895)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Swami Vivekananda, being presented by Dr. Janes, the president of the&#xA;Ethical Association, under whose auspices these lectures are given, said&#xA;in part: &amp;ldquo;The Hindoo occupies a unique position towards Buddhism. Like&#xA;Christ, who antagonized the Jews, Buddha antagonized the prevailing&#xA;religion of India; but while Christ was rejected by his countrymen,&#xA;Buddha was accepted as God Incarnate. He denounced the priestcraft at&#xA;the very doors of their temples, yet to-day he is worshipped by them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>100 INDIA&#39;S GIFT TO THE WORLD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/100_indias_gift_to_the_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/100_indias_gift_to_the_world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;indias-gift-to-the-world&#34;&gt;INDIA&amp;rsquo;S GIFT TO THE WORLD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Brooklyn Standard Union&lt;/em&gt;, February 27, 1895)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Swami Vivekananda, the Hindoo monk, delivered a lecture Monday night&#xA;under the auspices of the Brooklyn Ethical Association before a fairly&#xA;large audience at the hall of the Long Island Historical Society, corner&#xA;Pierrepont and Clinton streets. His subject was &amp;ldquo;India&amp;rsquo;s Gift to the&#xA;World&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He spoke of the wondrous beauties of his native land, &amp;ldquo;where stood the&#xA;earliest cradle of ethics, arts, sciences, and literature, and the&#xA;integrity of whose sons and the virtue of whose daughters have been sung&#xA;by all travelers.&amp;rdquo; Then the lecturer showed in rapid details, what India&#xA;has given to the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>101 CHILD WIDOWS OF INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/101_child_widows_of_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/101_child_widows_of_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;child-widows-of-india&#34;&gt;CHILD WIDOWS OF INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Daily Eagle&lt;/em&gt;, February 27, 1895)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Swami Vivekananda, the Hindu monk, lectured in Historical hall Monday&#xA;night under the auspices of the Brooklyn Ethical association, on&#xA;&amp;ldquo;India&amp;rsquo;s Gift to the World&amp;rdquo;. There were about two hundred and fifty&#xA;people in the hall when the Swami stepped on the platform. Much interest&#xA;was manifested on account of the denial by Mrs. James McKeen, president&#xA;of the Brooklyn Ramabai circle, which is interested in Christian work in&#xA;India, of the statement attributed to the lecture that the child widows&#xA;of India were not protected [ill-treated]. In no part of his lecture&#xA;was reference made to this denial, but after he had concluded, one of&#xA;the audience asked the lecturer what explanation he had to make to the&#xA;statement. Swami Vivekananda said that it was untrue that child widows&#xA;were abused or ill treated in any way. He added:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>102 SOME CUSTOMS OF THE HINDUS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/102_some_customs_of_the_hindus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_2/reports_in_american_newspapers/102_some_customs_of_the_hindus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-customs-of-the-hindus&#34;&gt;SOME CUSTOMS OF THE HINDUS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Brooklyn Standard Union&lt;/em&gt;, April 8, 1895)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A special meeting of the Brooklyn Ethical Association with an address by&#xA;Swami Vivekananda, the Hindu monk as the main feature, was held at the&#xA;Pouch Gallery, of Clinton avenue, last night. &amp;ldquo;Some customs of the&#xA;Hindus what they mean, and how they are misinterpreted,&amp;rdquo; was the subject&#xA;treated. A large throng of people filled the spacious gallery.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dressed in his Oriental costume, his eyes bright, and a flush mantling&#xA;his face, Swami Vivekananda started to tell of his people, of his&#xA;country, and its customs. He desired only that justice be shown to him&#xA;and to his. In the beginning of his discourse he said he would give a&#xA;general idea of India. He said it was not a country but a continent;&#xA;that erroneous ideas had been promulgated by travellers who had never&#xA;seen the country. He said that there were nine separate languages spoken&#xA;and over 100 different dialects. He spoke severely of those who wrote&#xA;about his country, and said their brains were addled by superstition,&#xA;and that they had an idea that everyone outside of the pale of their own&#xA;religion was a horrible blackguard. One of the customs that had often&#xA;been misinterpreted was the brushing of the teeth by the Hindus. They&#xA;never put hair or skin in their mouths, but use a plant. &amp;ldquo;Hence a man&#xA;wrote,&amp;rdquo; said the speaker, &amp;ldquo;that the Hindus get up early in the morning&#xA;and swallow a plant.&amp;rdquo; He said the [custom of widows throwing themselves&#xA;under the] car of juggernaut did not exist, never had, and that no one&#xA;knew how such a story started.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
