<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v2/north/uttarapatha/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v2/north/uttarapatha/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The defense of oDDiyAna</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v2/north/uttarapatha/MT_lekhAH/2006-06-05_the-defense-of-oddiyana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v2/north/uttarapatha/MT_lekhAH/2006-06-05_the-defense-of-oddiyana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/06/05/the-defense-of-oddiyana/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The famed pITha of oDDiyAna on the earthly plane, was the in kingdom of&#xA;oDDiyAna, which was ruled by the clansmen of shubhakara-siMha. The last&#xA;days of this glorious pITha under the constant assault of the&#xA;Mohammedans poorly known, but we can piece together some details from&#xA;the Chinese chronicles and the rAjatara~NgiNi of kalhaNa. The heroic&#xA;Hindu resistance in this region is largely forgotten but we provide an&#xA;outline, which we hope to fill in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A brief history of shubhakara siMha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v2/north/uttarapatha/MT_lekhAH/2006-05-01_a-brief-history-of-shubhakara-simha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v2/north/uttarapatha/MT_lekhAH/2006-05-01_a-brief-history-of-shubhakara-simha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/05/01/a-brief-history-of-shubhakara-simha/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The mahA-chInAchArya, shubhakara siMha, a nAstIka of the second varNa,&#xA;was a remarkable, even if forgotten, figure in history largely forgotten&#xA;in his homeland India. He was a descendent of the ikShvAku chieftain&#xA;amR^itodana whose clan held a small kingdom in what is the border&#xA;between modern Madhya Pradesh and Orissa. They were overthrown by the&#xA;rAShTrakUTa army and as a consequence fled to oDDiyAna pITha in central&#xA;Asia. Here they established themselves as rulers of oDDiyAna. It was&#xA;here that shubhakara siMha was born. His father believed he saw the&#xA;signs of divine favor in him. Just then the brutal onslaught of the&#xA;terror called Islam was spreading into central Asia under the directives&#xA;of the Umayyad Kalifs. shubhakara siMha was put in command of his army&#xA;at the tender age of 10 years and led his troops to a great victory&#xA;against the marauding Moslems. The chIna records mention how the kingdom&#xA;of oDDiyAna repulsed the attack of the Moslems. At the age of 13 his&#xA;father died and he was declared rAjan of oDDiyAna. He was a popular&#xA;ruler, but this sparked an intercine conflict with his brothers in&#xA;course of which he was wounded on his head by the blow of a chakra and&#xA;an arrow. He however crushed his brothers and regained total control of&#xA;the kingdom. After this intercine war he is said to have lost interest&#xA;in the kingdom, and released his defeated brothers and handed the&#xA;kingdom to the eldest of them. He decided to take sannyAsa prematurely.&#xA;But his mother gave him an ancestral pearl, which the symbol of&#xA;inheritence of the oDDiyAna throne, before he left the palace. He&#xA;travelled south to saindhava, where he wandered on the shore studying&#xA;the nAstIka tantras of the bauddhamata. After rigorous japa and yoga he&#xA;became a great tantric. He found a ship of vaishyas setting forth on a&#xA;trading expedition around the coast of India to the far East. They&#xA;agreed to take him along on the journey, and on the ship he kept&#xA;performing various japa-s to 7 crore devatA-s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Destruction of the 4 central Asian Indic garrisons</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v2/north/uttarapatha/MT_lekhAH/2005-11-24_destruction-of-the-4-central-asian-indic-garrisons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v2/north/uttarapatha/MT_lekhAH/2005-11-24_destruction-of-the-4-central-asian-indic-garrisons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/11/24/destruction-of-the-4-central-asian-indic-garrisons/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 615 AD, the 3 Central Asian kingdoms of Kucha, Agni (later Qara Shahar) and Khotan were islands of the Indic civilization in the Tarim Basin. They were at the pinnacle of their power and prosperity and were great centers of Sanksritic learning, producing a variety of texts on buddhist and classical hindu philosophies. These regions were like mini-India’s with Buddhism, Zoroastrianism and Hinduism being practiced by its citizens and were actively maintained by the flourishing trade along the Silk Road. Kucha’s rulers belonged to the suvarNa dynasty and its ruler suvarNa puShpa had signed a treaty of non-aggression with the Chinese emperor Yang-ti. In 630, the famous Chinese traveler, Hsuen Tsang had passed through Kucha and Agni and was warmly welcomed by the rulers. The new king of Kucha, suvarNadeva renewed the non-aggression pact with Tai-tsung, the expansionist Chinese emperor. In all likelihood Hsuen Tsang was also acting as a spy to the emperor and providing him intelligence regarding these Indic Kingdoms. Shortly after Hsuen Tsang passed through this region, Tai-tsung decided to swallow these kingdoms, without much of a warning. In 632 he asked to Tarim kingdoms to humbly accept his suzerainty- fearing an attack they sent token embassies to please the Emperor. However, realizing that the Chinese were advancing a vast army into the region in 640 AD, the king of Agni, formed an alliance with the Turko-Mongol Khanate of the Tuchueh and prepared to face the Chinese troops. Tai-tsung sent his general Kuo Hiao-ko to invade Agni and destroy it. Seeing the Turks and the Agnians massing to face the Chinese troops, Kuo cleverly marched towards Yulduz, causing the defenders to lower their guard. Then at night, he made a lightning march back to Agni and attacked the city from an undefended direction at dawn. The king was killed in the battle and Agni was captured and placed under the Chinese agent Lipo-chuen. However, in 644 the surviving prince of Agni, with the help of the Tuchueh Khan and SuvarNadeva of Kucha slew Lipo-chuen and re-conquered his kingdom from the Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A brief history of the Vijayan rule of Khotan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v2/north/uttarapatha/MT_lekhAH/2004-09-17_a-brief-history-of-the-vijayan-rule-of-khotan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v2/north/uttarapatha/MT_lekhAH/2004-09-17_a-brief-history-of-the-vijayan-rule-of-khotan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/09/17/a-brief-history-of-the-vijayan-rule-of-khotan/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nilakantha Shastri brings attention to the Indian rulers of Khotan and&#xA;has attempted to reconstruct their chronology from various sources.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://idp.nlc.gov.cn/chapters/topics/buddhism/khotanese/images/khotan_map.jpg&#34;&gt;Map of&#xA;Khotan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the period that followed the death of the great emperor lalitAditya,&#xA;and the confusion during the reign of saMgrAmapIDa, the Chinese generals&#xA;Yao Yao and Wei-ch’ih-Sheng devised a daring plan to take Khotan. With&#xA;the help of the internal Sinitic population they engineered a revolt and&#xA;suddenly appeared at the head of a massive Chinese army of 80,000 to&#xA;beseige and conqueror the kingdom. First Sheng and there after Yao&#xA;declared themselves rulers of Khotan. Alarmed at this advance the&#xA;descendent of lalitAditya, jayAditya, son of saMgrAmapIDa, who ascended&#xA;the throne in 751 CE, assigned general vijaya vikrama a descendent of&#xA;the original Hindu royal family of Khotan to wrest it back from the&#xA;chInas, hUnas and “mlecchas”. With a mobile calvary force he cut off the&#xA;supply line of the chInas and then luring them into an ambush in narrow&#xA;escape route he destroyed the chIna army completely.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;In late 756 vijaya vikrama was crowned rAja of Khotan. His dynasty as&#xA;currently reconstructed:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
