<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;mAdhava rAv on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/mAdhava-rAv/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;mAdhava rAv on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/mAdhava-rAv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>mAdhav rAv on squabbling</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/mAdhava-rAv/mAdhava-rAv_on_squabbling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/mAdhava-rAv/mAdhava-rAv_on_squabbling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is now over twenty months since you were asked to proceed to the north with a force numbering some fifty thousand led by picked captains. Never since the celebrated expedition of Bhau Saheb to Panipat had such a large force advanced to that region. You were invested with full powers and asked to reduce the Jat and other rulers who had thrown off their allegiance to our government and to impress upon the Rajputs, the Sikhs and the Abdali king that the Maratha rule had again been as vigorously restored in north India as before. Full confidence was reposed in your capacity and valour to achieve these objects, and thereby to bring in a plentiful supply of money contributions. The two experienced chiefs of the houses of Sindia and Holkar, the main props of our State, were purposely associated with you in your present undertaking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mAdhava rAv on English</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/mAdhava-rAv/mAdhava-rAv_on_english/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/mAdhava-rAv/mAdhava-rAv_on_english/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[mAdhava rAv&amp;rsquo;s letter to mahadji at Delhi in Jan-Feb 1772. He died late that year.]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I quite appreciate the value of a performance which the English desisted from undertaking. I should, however, like to know what amount of money and territory the Emperor has given you. You have now been out there for three seasons. The Emperor has attained his cherished object, but I don&amp;rsquo;t see what you have gained. Our men have shed their blood, in return for which you must acquire money and territory proportionate to the sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mAdhava rAv&#39;s will</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/mAdhava-rAv/mAdhava-rAv-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/mAdhava-rAv/mAdhava-rAv-will/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 1772 Sep 30, shortly before his untimely death, one of the finest peshva-s, mAdhava rAv issued his final will with the following points.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;All my debts should be paid even by using, if necessary, my private purse  in the possession of Guruji (Mahadaji Ballal) :&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The system of farming the revenues is found oppressive to the ryots: it should be modified after a careful enquiry.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The two holy places Prayag and Benares should be released from Muslim control. This was the ardent desire of my sires and now is the time to carry it out.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;My mother&amp;rsquo;s desire to perform the pilgrimage of Benares should be fulfilled as soon as convenient.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The obsequies of Bhau Saheb should be performed next February, whether aunt Parwatibai becomes sati or not.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The annuities assigned to the worthy Brahmans of Benares should be regularly paid and continued in heredity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dinners in connection with my funeral rites should be served to two lacs of Brahmans each with half an anna for dakshana.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dadasaheb should have five lacs of jagir assigned for his maintenance in order to keep him contented.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;9&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The charities of the Shravan month should be continued as long as the administration brings in at least 5 lacs of revenue yearly.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The responsible officers swore in the presence of Ganapati that they would execute all these wishes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
