<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Sea on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/sea/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Sea on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/sea/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chennai beach erosion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/sea/articles/chennai-beach-erosion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/sea/articles/chennai-beach-erosion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1824422402433974343.html?utm_campaign=topunroll&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;#Marina beach is one of the most iconic destinations in Chennai and one of the most visited beaches in the world. However the beach as we see today didn&amp;rsquo;t exist a century ago.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This thread explains the formation of #Chennai&amp;rsquo;s Marina beach&#xA;This map below shows the approximate original coastline of Chennai during British era. It was much closer to the Kamarajar road. A promenade was developed during the british era and that is when it got the name, &amp;ldquo;Marina&amp;rdquo;. However the big sandy expanse itself didnt exist&#xA;2/n&#xA;Image&#xA;Seas are very dynamic in nature. Whenever the waves hit the beach which is called as &amp;ldquo;swash&amp;rdquo;, they bring in sand and when the water goes back (&amp;ldquo;backwash&amp;rdquo;), it removes the sand. This balance is critical for beach existence.&#xA;The sand which the beaches need are brought by the sea from other places and one of the biggest suppliers of sand are our rivers. The rivers bring a lot of sand particularly during rainy seaons and these help in providing sand for the beaches&#xA;But these waves when they hit the land, they dont actually move straight. Becaue of the winds prevailing in that season, they have a slight angle to them. This means that it takes sand from one place and moves to another place.&#xA;For Chennai, during the winter months of November, December, January, the drift is from north to south. Because of this and moves from north to south in that time period&#xA;This can be clearly observed in this satellite image where the plume of Cooum river can be seen going towards the south. The plume (black in colour) is clearly identifiable because of the difference in the nature of water brought by Cooum river&#xA;But in the rest of the months of the year, the drift moves from south to north&#xA;This can be observed in this satellite image from April where the plume from Cooum river is moving to the north direction&#xA;Though both the direction exist in different months, the south to north one is dominant in Chennai. It is more like &amp;ldquo;2 steps forward and 1 step back&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
