<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ant parasitism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/MT/ant-parasitism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/MT/ant-parasitism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1964422711012135018&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09425-w&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;A remarkable case of sexual parasitism in an ant to clonally maintain a male from a different species to produce hybrid workers. Here, the male ant from a different species is produced by the queen by having its nuclear genome replace the queen&amp;rsquo;s haploid genome in the egg. This male is thus maintained in the population independently of its original species. When this cloned male from the different species mates with the queen, it produces workers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breeding</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/MT/breeding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/MT/breeding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems optimal breeding would be within your own ethnicity with someone who is genetically separated around 8-12 generations. Of course, this might vary if the population itself is very inbred.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deviance</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/MT/deviance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/MT/deviance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1017617003618689024.html&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The primary function of sex in eukaryotes is recombinogenic generation of diversity that evolved as response to the life-and-death pressures of biological conflicts. Hence, any sexual activity that does not satisfy this function is clearly either of secondary value+++(5)+++ or maladaptive or accidental(not significant).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several instances of atypical sexual activity like svali~Ngamaithuna in various animals is simply accidental or the main function misfiring. In several primates, in particular the Homo-Pan clade sex has a secondary signaling value. In one member of this clade Pan paniscus it does seem that homosexual coitus might have some signaling role. The evidence that it has a similar role in extant Homo is very limited or even unlikely. For most part but not entirely atypical sexuality has a biological basis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pathogens Genetics</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/MT/pathogens_genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/MT/pathogens_genetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1054058066029789184.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a good piece of writing for a layman&amp;rsquo;s on the pathogen hypothesis. Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AgentSaffron/status/1053723371752644609&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt; On related matter, this genre of hypothesis in their broader scope also encompass Cochran&amp;rsquo;s hypothesis for homosexuality stemming from perinatal infections.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, it should be stated that the pathogen hypothesis has been given here like the primary explanation for something which was otherwise without a proper etiology.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The points made by Cochran in defense of his pathogen hypothesis are quite applicable even to this case.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perfume</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/MT/perfume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/MT/perfume/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1962729337414668504&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The remarkable jumping spider Evarcha culicivora, which has as its highest dietary preference mosquitoes that have fed on the blood of humans or other vertebrates. It locates the blood-fed female mosquitoes by specifically localizing to human dwellings or to specific plants that attract such mosquitoes. Having fed on the vertebrate blood from the gut of the mosquito, it metabolizes compounds from the blood into a &amp;ldquo;vampyric&amp;rdquo; perfume that attracts the opposite sex. It cannot generate this perfume if it feeds on ordinary non-biting lake flies or male mosquitoes that do not drink blood.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
