<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;on hinduism on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;on hinduism on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00  Foreword</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/00_fore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/00_fore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Foreword&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Reawakening of Dharmic and Native Traditions&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two major groups of religions in the world today. First are&#xA;the conversion-based religions of Christianity and Islam. Each holds&#xA;that it is the only true faith for humanity and solely represents God&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;plan and God&amp;rsquo;s will. Both reflect an exclusivist ethos of One God, a&#xA;single holy book, a final prophet or single savior, an historical&#xA;revelation, salvation from sin, and heaven or hell as the ultimate&#xA;resting-place for the soul. Christianity and Islam became the dominant&#xA;religions of the Western world over the centuries through a long process&#xA;of struggle and warfare, as they displaced, often cruelly, all other&#xA;religions that came in their path. Both conversion-based religions are&#xA;based on an older Jewish monotheistic tradition that was critical of the&#xA;diverse Pagan cults around it. They turned this rejection, which for the&#xA;Jews was meant to preserve their own culture, into an article of faith&#xA;and a need to eradicate all other beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01  Chapter 1         Sanatana Dharma: Anusmriti and Anudhyâyana</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/01_ch01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/01_ch01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 1&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sanatana Dharma: Anusmriti and Anudhyâyana&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repeated and Cherished Recollection&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and Meditation on Sanatana Dharma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. I take refuge in the great Sanatana dharma, the mother of many&#xA;religions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spiritual Teachings: Âtma and &lt;em&gt;Anâtma&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2. The ancient sages studied man and for that they started with&#xA;themselves; they turned their gaze inward and found there a vast&#xA;internal life. Going still deeper, they discovered, beyond their more&#xA;external being, another life or principle which takes another language&#xA;to describe it; they found it self-existent, bodiless, pure, luminous&#xA;and conscious; they found that it is in some way unborn and undying;&#xA;that it does not come along with the body nor does it die with it; that&#xA;it is beyond sorrow and decay; that it shines from within and it knows&#xA;itself as self-evident. They found that it is their very essence, their&#xA;true Self; they called it &lt;em&gt;âtman&lt;/em&gt;, which is pure, immortal, and&#xA;untouched by evil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02  Chapter          2         Cultural Self-Alienation Among the Hindus1</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/02_ch02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/02_ch02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 2&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Cultural Self-Alienation Among the Hindus&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When two cultures meet on unequal military terms - as the Hindu culture&#xA;met the West and earlier met Islam - it gives rise to grave problems of&#xA;self-identity for the defeated party. When India finally realized that&#xA;she had lost in the military and diplomatic contest and that the British&#xA;were supreme, she was overwhelmed and filled with a deep sense of&#xA;inferiority. Under such circumstances, as it usually happens, other&#xA;non-military forces came into play. Different people sought&#xA;psychological rehabilitation in different ways. Some retired into their&#xA;shell and became apathetic; a majority met the situation by&#xA;self-repudiation and wholesale imitation. They disowned their nationhood&#xA;and their culture and adopted the ways and attitudes of the victors whom&#xA;they regarded as their superiors. They saved their self-respect through&#xA;self-alienation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03  Chapter          3         Buddhism vis-a-vis Hinduism1</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/03_ch03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/03_ch03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 3&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Buddhism vis-a-vis Hinduism&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Buddhism is returning home to India after a long exile of a thousand&#xA;years and, like the proverbial prodigal son, is being received with open&#xA;arms. Religious tolerance of the average Hindu partly explains the warm&#xA;reception. But a very important reason is the fact that Buddha and&#xA;Buddhism form an intimate part of Hindu consciousness. Buddha was a&#xA;Hindu. Buddhism is Hindu in its origin and development, in its art and&#xA;architecture, iconography, language, beliefs, psychology, names,&#xA;nomenclature, religious vows and spiritual discipline. Though living in&#xA;distant lands for so long, it remains essentially Hindu, at least, in&#xA;the expression of its religious ideals and spiritual experience at the&#xA;highest level. Hinduism is not all Buddhism, but Buddhism forms part of&#xA;the ethos which is essentially Hindu.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04  Chapter          4         Indo-European Encounter: An Indian Perspective</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/04_ch04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/04_ch04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 4&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Indo-European Encounter: An Indian Perspective&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;India and Europe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; originally came out in German in 1981. The&#xA;English translation which was originally published by the State&#xA;University of New York in 1988 has now been brought out in an Indian&#xA;edition and made available to readers in India. The English translation&#xA;is a much enlarged version of the original German edition and the Indian&#xA;edition carries a special Preface by the author. The book contains 604&#xA;pages divided into three sections sub-divided into twenty-four chapters.&#xA;The first section divided into ten chapters deals with &amp;ldquo;India in the&#xA;History of European Self-Understanding&amp;rdquo;. It is probably the best portion&#xA;of the book and very useful to an Indian reader. It presents valuable&#xA;historical material well digested and analysed. It deals with important&#xA;sub-topics like India as seen by the Greeks of the Classical period,&#xA;India as approached by the missionaries as Europe entered its modern&#xA;period, India as seen by the Europe of Deism and the Enlightenment, and&#xA;shows how its own internal controversies were given an edge or even&#xA;shaped by Indian presence. It gives us the history of Indology, it tells&#xA;us what some of the greatest European thinkers like Voltaire, Herder,&#xA;Hegel, Schelling and Schopenhauer thought of India. In this sense, the&#xA;book is also Europe&amp;rsquo;s own self-portraiture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05  Chapter 5         Development in Huxley&#39;s Thought: Hindu-Buddhist Influences</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/05_ch05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/05_ch05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 5&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Development in Huxley&amp;rsquo;s Thought: Hindu-Buddhist Influences&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hinduism-Buddhism has been making a great impact on the West&amp;rsquo;s religious&#xA;thinking. C.E.M. Joad even called it a &amp;ldquo;counter-attack from the East&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;This is a kind of impact however which cannot be measured in terms of&#xA;&amp;ldquo;converts&amp;rdquo;. The influence remains even unacknowledged. But it works&#xA;nonetheless unconsciously and at a deeper level. &amp;ldquo;Karma&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Yoga&amp;rdquo;,&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Experience&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Consciousness&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Meditation&amp;rdquo; and other such intimately&#xA;Indian concepts are very much current. Fully 23% American young adults&#xA;believe in Reincarnation. Under this influence, there is less belief in&#xA;dogmas and official Saviours, but there is more emphasis on an&#xA;experimental approach, on personal experience and on finding for&#xA;oneself. The Church is no longer regarded as the sole vehicle of grace&#xA;except in die-hard circles; on the other hand, there is a new awareness&#xA;of the spiritual wealth of non-European and non-Christian nations and&#xA;cultures, a thought quite new to the West&amp;rsquo;s traditional religion. This&#xA;new universality and wider appreciation are the best gifts of&#xA;Hinduism-Buddhism to the West since it discovered the East.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06  Chapter 6         The Hindu View of Education</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/06_ch06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/06_ch06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 6&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The Hindu View of Education&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A nation&amp;rsquo;s theories about education depend upon its theories about man.&#xA;Its definition and understanding of education depend upon its definition&#xA;and understanding of man.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If we regard man as a physical entity, our approach to education would&#xA;be of one kind; if we regard man as a mental being, our approach would&#xA;be of a different kind. But if we regard man as a spiritual being, our&#xA;educational formulations are bound to be different.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07  Chapter 7         Educational System During Pre-British Days</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/07_ch07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/07_ch07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 7&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Educational System During Pre-British Days&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ancient India was celebrated for its learning all over civilized Asia&#xA;and Europe. Megasthenese (ca. 302 BC) was struck by the depth of this&#xA;learning during his mission to the court of Chandragupta. Fa-hien, the&#xA;famous Chinese traveller (399413 AD) spent some years at the Pataliputra&#xA;and Tamralipti monasteries. He also spent two years in Ceylon which too&#xA;had its monasteries after the India fashion. These monasteries were a&#xA;big affair, housing and teaching several hundred monks each. Two&#xA;centuries after came Hiuen Tsang undertaking a hazardous journey across&#xA;Central Asia and northern parts of India. During the seventeen years he&#xA;spent in India (629-645 AD) he visited many monasteries belonging to the&#xA;Mahayana and the Hinayana schools. He visited Hiranyaparvata, the Golden&#xA;Hill (Munghir), a city on the bank of the Ganges, which had 10&#xA;Sangharamas with 4,000 priests, and 12 Deva temples. At Tamralipti (at&#xA;the mouth of Hoogly), there were 10 monasteries with a thousand monks.&#xA;The same story is told of many other towns he visited.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08  Chapter 8         India and Greece</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/08_ch08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/on_hinduism/08_ch08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 8&lt;br&gt;&#xA;India and Greece&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movement of men and ideas from the West to the East is a recent&#xA;phenomenon. There was a time when the movement was in the opposite&#xA;direction and the East had gone to the West in a big way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At that time, India&amp;rsquo;s cultural frontiers too were wider than her&#xA;political frontiers and her ideas influenced lands and people far away&#xA;from her physically. Vedic India shared many of her Gods with Iran and&#xA;one of them, Mithra (&lt;em&gt;Mitra&lt;/em&gt;), went on a long journey to the West.&#xA;Mithraea, temples dedicated to Mithra, have been found all over Syria,&#xA;Asia Minor, Spain and even in many Western ports. One Mithraeum was&#xA;found in London in 1954. Many relics have been found in Germany too, as&#xA;at Hedernheim, near Frankfurt-on-Main.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
