<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;ayodhya case against temple on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;ayodhya case against temple on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Foreword</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/01_for/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/01_for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foreword&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The present book is my last contribution to the literature on what is&#xA;known in India as “communalism”, meaning the conflict between the&#xA;different religions, principally Hinduism and Islam.  Some of the&#xA;authors whose works were published by Voice of India, notably Prof.&#xA;Harsh Narain and Sri Suhas Majumdar, had only started speaking out on&#xA;the communal question in the very last years of their lives.  We must be&#xA;grateful to them that they were willing to sacrifice their years of&#xA;well-earned rest to a diagnosis of this unpleasant problem. I am very&#xA;fortunate in having discovered the problem at an earlier stage of life&#xA;and being offered a forum where I could contribute to the research into&#xA;and reflection on its causes.  In terms of my own potential, I feel I&#xA;have exhausted the topic and I now intend to move on (or return) to more&#xA;fundamental subjects of philosophy and religion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 1. The Ayodhya debate: focus on the “no temple” evidence</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/02_ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/02_ch1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The Ayodhya debate: focus on the “no temple” evidence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In May 1998, the World Archaeological Congress held a conference on the&#xA;island of Brac, Croatia, where a session was devoted to the Ayodhya&#xA;dispute. I had registered to read a paper, and though I couldn’t make it&#xA;to the conference due to unforeseen family matters, I had prepared the&#xA;following text.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.1.Two sides to the story&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In references to the question whether there really was a Hindu temple at&#xA;the Ayodhya site later covered by the Babri Masjid, the focus is&#xA;invariably on the case made by the Hindu side, viz. that there was a&#xA;temple, and that different types of evidence confirm this.  The standard&#xA;question is: is this evidence for the temple demolition scenario valid?&#xA;Have they succeeded in proving the existence of the temple?  By&#xA;contrast, the &lt;em&gt;opponents&lt;/em&gt; of the temple hypothesis are but very rarely&#xA;asked to put their evidence on the table.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 2. Ashoka and Pushyamitra, iconoclasts?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/03_ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/03_ch2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Ashoka and Pushyamitra, iconoclasts?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the diversionary tactics employed by the “eminent historians” in&#xA;order to shield Islamic iconoclasm from the public eye is to allege that&#xA;Hinduism itself is the guilty religion, viz. of persecuting minority&#xA;religions such as Buddhism.  So much is this accusation now taken for&#xA;granted, that any attempt to stick to the historical record fills the&#xA;secularists with exasperation at such Hindu fanatical blindness.  Thus,&#xA;Tavleen Singh challenges us: “Try, for instance, to get a BJP leader to&#xA;admit that Hindus did to Buddhist shrines pretty much what Muslims were&#xA;later to do with Hindu temples and you will find that it is nearly&#xA;impossible.”^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 3. The Bodh Gaya temple controversy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/04_ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/04_ch3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The Bodh Gaya temple controversy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When anti-Hindu lobbies unite, they often manage to get the contemporary&#xA;form of Indian Buddhism on their side, viz.  Ambedkarite neo-Buddhism.&#xA;Because of its political background, the conversion of Scheduled Caste&#xA;leader Dr. Bhimrao Ramji Ambedkar and many of his Mahar castemen to&#xA;Buddhism (1956), in effect contributed to the genesis of what one might&#xA;call Buddhist communalism.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) The anti-Hindu bias of Ambedkarite&#xA;Buddhism was strengthened by the parallel Buddhist animus against Tamil&#xA;Hindus in Sri Lanka and Burma/Myanmar, as well as by the tendency among&#xA;Nehruvian intellectuals to construe Buddhism historically as an&#xA;anti-Hindu revolt.  As a materialization of this anti-Hindu animus, the&#xA;neo-Buddhist movement has tried to create controversies over certain&#xA;temples in imitation of the Ayodhya temple/mosque controversy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 4. Harsha of Kashmir, a Hindu iconoclast?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/05_ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/05_ch4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Harsha of Kashmir, a Hindu iconoclast?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.1. Claims of Hindu iconoclasm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whenever the history of the many thousands of temple destructions by&#xA;Muslims is discussed, the secularists invariably come up with the claim&#xA;that Hindus have done much the same thing to Buddhists, Jains and&#xA;Animists.  In particular, the disappearance of Buddhism from India is&#xA;frequently explained as the result of “Brahminical onslaught”.  Though&#xA;extremely widespread by now, this allegation is entirely untrue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 5. Vandalism sanctified by scripture</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/06_ch5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/06_ch5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Vandalism sanctified by scripture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(After Hindu activists demolished a mosque in a small town in&#xA;Rajasthan, the on-line magazine “OutlookIndia” published a comment with&#xA;an entirely predictable message by the well-known secularist Yoginder&#xA;Sikand.  At the editor’s invitation, I wrote the following rebuttal,&#xA;published on 31 August 2001.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In his article “Sanctified Vandalism As A Political Tool”&#xA;(&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.OutLooklndia.com&#34;&gt;www.OutLooklndia.com&lt;/a&gt;, Aug. 23, 2001), Yoginder Sikand tries to explain&#xA;away Muslim iconoclasm as marginal and uncharacteristic, all while&#xA;accusing “the Hindus and others” of just such iconoclasm.  In both&#xA;endeavours, he predictably relies on Richard Eaton’s book &lt;em&gt;Essays on&#xA;Islam and Indian History&lt;/em&gt; (OUP Delhi 2000).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 6. The details about Hindu iconoclasm</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/07_ch6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/07_ch6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. The details about “Hindu iconoclasm”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A remarkable aspect of the Ayodhya debate is the complete lack of active&#xA;involvement by Western scholars.  Their role has been limited to that of&#xA;loudspeakers for the secularist-cum-Islamist party-line denying that any&#xA;temple demolition had preceded the construction of the Babri Masjid.&#xA;Even those who (like Hans Bakker and Peter Van der Veer) had earlier&#xA;given their innocent support to the historical account, putting the&#xA;Ayodhya case in the context of systematic Islamic iconoclasm, hurried to&#xA;fall in line once the secularist campaign of history-rewriting started.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 7. Why did Aurangzeb demolish the Kashi Vishvanath temple?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/08_ch7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/08_ch7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Why did Aurangzeb demolish the Kashi Vishvanath temple?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moghul emperor Aurangzeb Alamgir (r.1658-1707) is an icon of Islamic&#xA;iconoclasm in India.  His name counts as synonymous with destruction of&#xA;Hindu temples, though he also levelled many Hindu human beings.  Yet,&#xA;the dominant school of historians would like to salvage Aurangzeb’s&#xA;reputation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Percival Spear, co-author (with Romila Thapar) of the prestigious&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Penguin History of India&lt;/em&gt;, writes: “Aurangzeb’s supposed intolerance is&#xA;little more than a hostile legend based on isolated acts such as the&#xA;erection of a mosque on a temple site in Benares.”^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) This claim,&#xA;warhorse of the “secularist” school of history-rewriting, provides us&#xA;with an excellent case study in the ongoing historians’ conflict in&#xA;India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 8. From Ayodhya to Nazareth</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/09_ch8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/09_ch8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. From Ayodhya to Nazareth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Indian Cbilstians and their allies in the international media have&#xA;mostly taken the Muslim side in the Ayodhya dispute.  This was the&#xA;reason for the following open letter to the Church dignitaries, written&#xA;in the last days of the year 1999, the occasion being the emergence of a&#xA;vaguely similar problem in Nazareth.  Muslims bad illegally started&#xA;building a mosque next to a church, and the Israeli authorities bad not&#xA;dared to interfere.  It may be added now (February 2002) that in the&#xA;context of the “second intifada” and the ongoing Israeli crackdown on&#xA;Islamic terrorism, Israeli Minister and former Soviet dissident Nathan&#xA;Sharansky bas ordered the construction work to be stopped.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 9. Ayodhya and the Supreme Court</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/10_ch9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/10_ch9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Ayodhya and the Supreme Court&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What follows is a reworked version of my paper “The Ayodhya demolition:&#xA;an evaluation”, contributed to the collective volume: &lt;em&gt;The Ayodhya&#xA;Reference.  Supreme -Court Judgment and Commentaries&lt;/em&gt; (Voice of India,&#xA;Delhi 1995), which also included papers by Swapan Dasgupta, M. Rama&#xA;Jois, Arun Jaitley and S.P. Gupta.  The book was occasioned by the&#xA;Supreme Court’s decision not to help Narasimha Rao’s Government out of&#xA;the Ayodhya dilemma by offering an opinion on the historical evidence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 10. Mohammed Habib&#39;s history-rewriting</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/11_ch10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/11_ch10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Mohammed Habib’s history-rewriting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is but rarely that a secularist or a Muslim actually takes issue with&#xA;what I have written.  Mostly they resort to swearwords and the use of&#xA;institutional power to deny me access to important forums.  So, when&#xA;someone does take the trouble of reading a book of mine and even writing&#xA;a rebuttal, I will gladly oblige and take my turn to comment on the&#xA;comment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 11. The Ayodhya evidence debate</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/12_ch11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/12_ch11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11. The Ayodhya evidence debate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This paper was written as an adaptation from an earlier paper, “The&#xA;Ayodhya debate”, published in the conference proceedings of the 1991&#xA;International Ramayana Conference, which had taken place in my hometown,&#xA;Leuven.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) The present version represents my own text prepared&#xA;for the October 1995 Annual South Asia Conference in Madison, Wisconsin,&#xA;U. S.A. A few notes have been added.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The atmosphere at the conference was frankly hostile.  After the&#xA;academic authorities, who may have been ignorant of my controversial&#xA;reputation, had allowed my paper to be read, the practical organization&#xA;of the panel session was entrusted to graduate students belonging to the&#xA;Indian Communist organization, &lt;em&gt;Forum of Indian Leftists&lt;/em&gt; (FOIL).  They&#xA;scheduled me as the last speaker in a panel of four, chaired by an&#xA;Indian female graduate student, a nice girl but obviously unable to&#xA;perform the most difficult duty of a panel chairperson, viz. keeping the&#xA;speakers to their allotted time.  Moreover, they arranged for our&#xA;session to be held in a room where another panel was scheduled at noon,&#xA;making it impossible for the last speaker to read his paper in excess of&#xA;the panel session’s allotted time.  Two panel speakers played along by&#xA;comfortably expounding and repeating the points they could easily have&#xA;made in half the time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 12. About the Hindu critique of monotheism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/13_ch12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/13_ch12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12. About the Hindu critique of monotheism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This final text was written just recently, after I was given a copy of&#xA;probably the first book containing a paper devoted specifically to a&#xA;position taken by Voice of India, viz. its critique of m Monotheism.&#xA;This was a central theme in the work of the late Ram Swarup and has&#xA;remained so for those who have learned from him, including Sita Ram Goel&#xA;and Arun Shourie, the authors specifically studied in the paper under&#xA;consideration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 13. Postscript: a lasting solution</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/14_ch13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/14_ch13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13. Postscript: a lasting solution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13.1. Say it with poetry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It happened a whole decade ago, but the method could still be tried out&#xA;today.  In the dying days of Khalistani terrorism, secularist Prime&#xA;Minister V.P. Singh visited Panjab and proposed as his solution for&#xA;terror and separatism this colourful formula: “We must open the treasury&#xA;of our hearts.” He was indulging in mere poetic sentimentalism to avoid&#xA;facing the real problem of Khalistani terrorism.  But it is true that&#xA;the Sikh masses had kept the treasury of their hearts open and felt hurt&#xA;when the Hindus were victimized.  And a few years later, Khalistan was&#xA;only a bad memory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Bibliography</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/15_bib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/ayodhya_case_against_temple/15_bib/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bibliography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ADVANI, L.K.: &lt;em&gt;Ram Janmabhoomi: Honour People’s Sentiments&lt;/em&gt;.  BJP, Delhi&#xA;1989.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-: &lt;em&gt;Why Rathyatra?&lt;/em&gt; Jagarana Prakashana, Bangalore 1990.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-: &lt;em&gt;Ayodhya Before and After&lt;/em&gt;.  Janadhikar Samiti, Delhi 1992.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AGGARWAL, J.C., and CHOWDHRY, N.K.: &lt;em&gt;Ram Janmabhoomi through the Ages&lt;/em&gt;.&#xA;S. Chand &amp;amp; Co., Delhi 1991.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AHIR, D.C.: &lt;em&gt;Bamiyan Buddhas. Senseless Destruction by Taliban&lt;/em&gt;.&#xA;Blumoon Books, Delhi 2001.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AKHTAR, Mohammed Jamil: &lt;em&gt;Babri Masjid: a Tale Untold&lt;/em&gt;. Genuine Publ.,&#xA;Delhi 1997.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ANSARI, Abdul Quddoos: &lt;em&gt;Archaeological Remains of Bodhgaya&lt;/em&gt;.  Ramanand&#xA;Vidya Bhavan, Delhi 1990.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
