<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/tibeto-burman/burma/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/tibeto-burman/burma/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pregnancy malnutrition</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/tibeto-burman/burma/articles/pregnancy-malnutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/tibeto-burman/burma/articles/pregnancy-malnutrition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1460844066187399179&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1460844066187399179&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A thread on mortality in colonial Burma.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In agrarian economies, births &amp;amp; deaths must equalize in the long-run. Late marriage, periods of voluntary abstinence, labor migration, &amp;amp; longer breastfeeding are possibilities for affecting the fertility side of the equation. Infanticide, which may be subjectively classified as either fertility restraint or mortality is another method. Conscious infanticide was common in Europe, East &amp;amp; South Asia and the Middle East (IDK about SS Africa or indigenous pre or post-1500 Latin America, happy to learn). In Europe the church would not tolerate open infanticide. East Asian states expressed disapproval as well, but tacitly tolerated it to some extent. European infanticide could take the form of abandonment in the woods (e.g. Hansel &amp;amp; Gretel), abandoning a child to a foundling home with an 80% chance of death before reaching adulthood, exposure, or unequal allocation of nutrition among children. But there is no evidence of infanticide in colonial or pre-colonial Burma. So what fertility or mortality factors drove the Malthusian equilibrium?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
