<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>KolhApur v2 vs aundh v1</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/kolhApur-v2_vs_aundh_v1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/kolhApur-v2_vs_aundh_v1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source - ravilochana&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;aundh&#34;&gt;Aundh&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This dvivarna controversy was actually rooted in the fight between kolhapur darbar and pant pratinidhi of aundh darbar. Former even killed one of the latters rulers in the past. They claimed that Aundh were not even proper broms. Aundh retaliated by claiming that kolhapur rulers were not kshatriya. Personal feud led to this rift between Brahmins and kshatriyas of MH.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;shivaji-coronation&#34;&gt;shivAjI Coronation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nothing in early maratha bakhars show any such opposition to shivAjI&amp;rsquo;s coronation by brahmins. In fact some of the marathas who were with sultanates opposed his claim. Brahmins were ok with sacchudra kings. Nayakas were very much supported by Brahmins and vice versa. Same with reddy kings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tilak-jail-books</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/tilak-jail-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/tilak-jail-books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tilak’s Study in Jail&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: Reminisces and Anecdotes of Lokamanya Tilak,  Edited by S V Bapat, 1928&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;=================&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Lokamanya Tilak returned to his mother-country after his six years incarceration at Mandalay he carried with him nearly four hundred books, mostly on Gita and Hindu religious philosophy. These books were packed in two crates and a list of them was made by Lokamanya Tilak himself and signed by the jailor with the remark “Packed in my presence”.  We print the list below for the information of the readers. It shows Lokamanya’s vast reading and the amount of trouble he took in preparing his Magnum Opus! the Gita-Rahasya. The list will be useful to the students of Gita and the Gita-Rahasya. It will alao be helpful to those who wish to furnish public or private libraries with literature about the Gita and Hindu Philosophy and Ethics – Editor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
