<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;translation of writings on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/translation_of_writings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;translation of writings on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/translation_of_writings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>721 volume 7/translation of writingsnote</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/translation_of_writings/721_note/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/translation_of_writings/721_note/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NOTE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Swami Vivekananda left Calcutta for the West, for the second time, on&#xA;the 20th June, 1899, by the BISN steamship Golconda. In reading these&#xA;pages the reader should remember that Swamiji wrote them in a light,&#xA;humorous tone in Bengali, which it is impossible to render in English.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;memoirs_of_european_travel_ii.htm&#34;&gt;second section&lt;/a&gt; of these&#xA;memoirs, relates to his return journey from the West at the end of 1900.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These were originally published in the Udbodhan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>722 MEMOIRS OF EUROPEAN TRAVEL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/translation_of_writings/722_memoirs_of_european_travel_i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/translation_of_writings/722_memoirs_of_european_travel_i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;memoirs-of-european-travel&#34;&gt;MEMOIRS OF EUROPEAN TRAVEL&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Translated from &lt;a href=&#34;6043_memoirs_of_european_travel.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Om Namo Nārāyanāya&lt;/em&gt;, (&amp;ldquo;Salutations to the Lord&amp;rdquo;; the usual form of&#xA;addressing a Sannyasin. These memoirs of his second journey to the West&#xA;were addressed to Swami Trigunatitananda, Editor, &lt;em&gt;Udbodhan&lt;/em&gt; and hence&#xA;this form of address.) Swāmi. — Pronounce the last syllable of the&#xA;second word in a high pitch, brother, in the Hrishikesh fashion. For&#xA;seven days we have been on board the ship and every day I think of&#xA;writing to you something about our mode of life, and of writing&#xA;materials also you have given me enough, but the characteristic lethargy&#xA;of a Bengali stands in the way and foils everything. In the first place,&#xA;there is idleness; every day I think of writing — what do you call it —&#xA;a diary, but then, on account of various preoccupations, it is postponed&#xA;to the endless &amp;ldquo;tomorrow&amp;rdquo;, and does not progress an inch. In the second&#xA;place, I do not remember the dates etc., at all; you must do me the&#xA;favour to fill these up yourselves. And, besides, if you be very&#xA;generous, you may think that like the great devotee, Hanuman, it is&#xA;impossible for me to remember dates and such other trivialities — owing&#xA;to the presence of the Lord in the heart. But the real truth is that it&#xA;is due to my foolishness and idleness. What nonsense! What comparison&#xA;can there be between &amp;ldquo;the Solar Dynasty&amp;rdquo; (Swamiji here refers to&#xA;Kālidāsa&amp;rsquo;s famous line of the &lt;em&gt;Raghuvamsham&lt;/em&gt;: &amp;ldquo;O the difference between&#xA;the majestic Solar Dynasty and my poor intellect!&amp;rdquo;) — I beg your pardon&#xA;— between Hanuman with his whole heart given to Shri Rāma, the crown of&#xA;the Solar Dynasty, and me, the lowest of the low! But then he crossed at&#xA;one bound the ocean extending a hundred Yojanas, while we are crossing&#xA;it confined within a wooden house, so to say, being pitched this side&#xA;and that and somehow keeping ourselves on our feet with the help of&#xA;posts and pillars. But there is one point of superiority on our side in&#xA;that he had the blessed sight of Rākshasas and Rākshasis after reaching&#xA;Lankā, whereas we are going in company with them. At dinner time that&#xA;glittering of a hundred knives and the clattering of a hundred forks&#xA;frightened brother T__ (Turiyananda) out of his wits. He now and then&#xA;started lest his neighbour with auburn hair and grey, cat-like eyes,&#xA;through inadvertence might plunge her knife into his flesh, and the more&#xA;so, as he is rather sleek and fat. I say, did Hanuman have sea-sickness&#xA;while crossing the sea? Do the ancient books say anything on that? You&#xA;are all well-read men, proficient in the Ramayana and other scriptures,&#xA;so you may settle that question. But our modern authorities are silent&#xA;on that point. Perhaps he had not; but then the fact of his having&#xA;entered into the jaws of somebody raises a doubt. Brother T__ is also&#xA;of opinion that when the prow of the ship suddenly heaves up towards&#xA;heaven as if to consult with the king of gods, and immediately after&#xA;plunges to the bottom of the ocean as if to pierce king Vali, residing&#xA;in the nether worlds — he at that time feels that he is being swallowed&#xA;by the terrible and wide-gaping jaws of somebody.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>723 MEMOIRS OF EUROPEAN TRAVEL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/translation_of_writings/723_memoirs_of_european_travel_ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/translation_of_writings/723_memoirs_of_european_travel_ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;memoirs-of-european-travel&#34;&gt;MEMOIRS OF EUROPEAN TRAVEL&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Translated from &lt;a href=&#34;6092_memoirs_of_european_travel_ii.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have an adage among us that one that has a disc-like pattern on the&#xA;soles of his feet becomes a vagabond. I fear, I have my soles inscribed&#xA;all over with them. And there is not much room for probability, either.&#xA;I have tried my best to discover them by scrutinising the soles, but all&#xA;to no purpose — the feet have been dreadfully cracked through the&#xA;severity of cold, and no discs or anything of the kind could be traced.&#xA;However, when there is the tradition, I take it for granted that my&#xA;soles are full of those signs. But the results are quite patent — it was&#xA;my cherished desire to remain in Paris for some time and study the&#xA;French language and civilisation; I left my old friends and&#xA;acquaintances and put up with a new friend, a Frenchman of ordinary&#xA;means, who knew no English, and my French — well, it was something quite&#xA;extraordinary! I had this in mind that the inability to live like a dumb&#xA;man would naturally force me to talk French, and I would attain fluency&#xA;in that language in no time — but on the contrary I am now on a tour&#xA;through Vienna, Turkey, Greece, Egypt, and Jerusalem! Well, who can stem&#xA;the course of the inevitable! — And this letter I am writing to you from&#xA;the last remaining capital of Mohammedan supremacy — from&#xA;Constantinople!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>724 MEMOIRS OF EUROPEAN TRAVEL
ADDENDA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/translation_of_writings/724_addenda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/translation_of_writings/724_addenda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;memoirs-of-european-travel-addenda&#34;&gt;MEMOIRS OF EUROPEAN TRAVEL ADDENDA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(These interesting jottings were found among Swamiji&amp;rsquo;s papers — Ed.)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(&lt;em&gt;Translated from &lt;a href=&#34;6108_addenda.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first view of Constantinople we had from the train. It is an ancient&#xA;city, with big drains running across the walls, narrow and crooked lanes&#xA;full of dirt, and wooden houses, etc., but in them there is a certain&#xA;beauty owing to their novelty. At the station we had great trouble over&#xA;our books. Mademoiselle Calvé and Jules Bois tried much, in French, to&#xA;reason with the octroi officers, which gradually led to a quarrel&#xA;between the parties. The head of the officers was a Turk, and his dinner&#xA;was ready; so the quarrel ended without further complications. They&#xA;returned all the books with the exception of two which they held back.&#xA;They promised to send them to the hotel immediately, which they never&#xA;did. We went round the town and bazar of Stamboul or Constantinople.&#xA;Beyond the Pont or creek is the Pera or foreigners&amp;rsquo; quarters, hotels,&#xA;etc., whence we got into a carriage, saw the town, and then took some&#xA;rest. In the evening we went to visit Woods Pasha, and the next day&#xA;started on an excursion along the Bosphorus in a boat. It was extremely&#xA;cold and there was a strong wind. So I and Miss MacLeod got down at the&#xA;first station. It was decided that we would cross over to Scutari and&#xA;see Pére Hyacinthe. Not knowing the language we engaged a boat by signs&#xA;merely, crossed over, and hired a carriage. On the way we saw the seat&#xA;of a Sufi Fakir. These Fakirs cure people&amp;rsquo;s diseases, which they do in&#xA;the following manner. First they read a portion of their scriptures,&#xA;moving their body backward and forward; then they begin to dance and&#xA;gradually get a sort of inspiration, after which they heal the disease&#xA;by treading on the patient&amp;rsquo;s body.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
