<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Savarkar and his times on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Savarkar and his times on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 PREFACE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/01_PREFACE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/01_PREFACE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Swatantryaveer Savarkar needs no introduction to the&#xA;Indian public, neither does his biography. Long ago, Mr. Asaf&#xA;Ali described Savarkar as the spirit of Shivaji and the late&#xA;Sri Srinivas Sastri said of him that “ he was a great and fear-&#xA;less patriot and volumes could be written about his yeoman&#xA;services in the cause of Indian Freedom.” This is, however,&#xA;too small a volume to describe that spirit and those services&#xA;adequately.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 CONTENTS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/02_CONTENTS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/02_CONTENTS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Preface v&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Childhood and Youth 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II. The Rising Leader 15&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;III. Revolutionary Activities in Europe 27&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IV. The Storm Breaks &amp;hellip;.. 49&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;V. Epic Escape and World-Famous Trials . 70&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VI. The Indian Bastille &amp;hellip;.. 93&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VII. Genius Thrives in Jail &amp;hellip;. 119&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VIII. Out op His Grave &amp;hellip;.. 141&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IX. Social Revolution &amp;hellip;.. 153&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;X. Rationalist and Author &amp;hellip;. 181&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;XI. Back to Freedom &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip; 193&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;XII. Whirlwind Propaganda &amp;hellip;.. 198&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 ILLUSTRATIONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/03_ILLUSTRATIONS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/03_ILLUSTRATIONS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SWATANTRYAVEER SaVARKAR - Frontispiece&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Savarkar and his Comrades - facing page&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;80&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;India House in 1909 99&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;81&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Savarkar Brothers . . . •&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;99&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;152&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Batch of Ratnagiri Hindu Sanghatanists .&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;99&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;153&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Madura Procession&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;99&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;99&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;208&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Trio and the Generalissimo&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;99&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;99&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;209&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Savarkar with Subhas and Working Committee „&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;99&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;260&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the Occasion of the Cripps Mission&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;99&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;99&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;261&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Orator&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;99&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;99&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;296&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Mammoth Meeting &amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Childhood and Youth</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/04_Childhood_and_Youth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/04_Childhood_and_Youth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In politically fallen, socially degraded and financially ruined&#xA;Hindusthan, the eighteen-eighties and nineties witnessed the&#xA;darkest period in the history of our country. The first peep&#xA;of the dawn in the form of the refonns of 1909 was still to&#xA;come. The dawn of 1919 was beyond the horizon. The&#xA;spiritual planets like Maharshi Ranade, Swami Dayananda&#xA;Saraswati and Swami Vivekananda were kindling light of&#xA;social regeneration and spiritual heritage. Dayananda,&#xA;Dadabhai, Ranade and Vivekananda were rousing the people&#xA;from their slumber ; Ram Singh Kuka and Wasudeo Balwant&#xA;had disturbed their thoughts for a good while. Tilak was&#xA;carrying discontent and unrest from towns to villages and&#xA;cottages. Babu Anand Mohan Bose and Babu Surendranath&#xA;Banerjee were infusing a spirit of new life in Bengal. Dreading&#xA;the resurgent revolts for the overthrow of its power, the&#xA;British mind was deeply engrossed in finding out a safety&#xA;valve for the wrath of the Indian revolution. And not long&#xA;before, the British top-ranking officers and politicians founded&#xA;the Indian National Congress on December 28, 1885, despite&#xA;the fears and opposition of Sir Syed Ahmed, who warned the&#xA;Muslims to keep aloof from the Congress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 The Rising Leader</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/05_The_Rising_Leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/05_The_Rising_Leader/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Savarkar passed his Mati’iculation Examinatiou in Decem-&#xA;ber 1901, and left Nasik for Poona in January 1902. What&#xA;was the state of Poona ? Exactly a year before Poona had&#xA;lost Mahadeo Govind Ranade, India’s foremost torchbearer&#xA;of learning and light. Ranade was a great social reformer,&#xA;a towering scholar, an ardent patriot, a renowned thinker,&#xA;an eminent economist and an exemplary judge. He was the&#xA;foremost torchbearer of a new age, and wished to build a&#xA;social structure conforming to the demands of fresh ideas.&#xA;Though not strictly a Congressman his word was law in every&#xA;annual session of the Indian National Congress of his day.&#xA;His political ideal for India was, in his own words : “ A&#xA;federated India distributed according to nationahties and&#xA;subjected to a common bond of connection with the Imperial&#xA;Power of the Queen-Empress of India.” * Sri R. P. Paranjpe&#xA;had just returned from England with a dazzling success in his&#xA;academic career. Gokhale was about to leave the Fergusson&#xA;College and enter upon a political career. Tilak was becom-&#xA;ing a formidable leader. Shivrampant Paranjpe was a domi-&#xA;nating figure with his magic pen and marvellous oratory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 Revolutionary Activities in Europe</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/06_Revolutionary_Activities_in_Europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/06_Revolutionary_Activities_in_Europe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The year 1906 was a landmark in Indian politics. During&#xA;this year Savarkar, the leader of the Abhinava Bharat, went&#xA;to London. That year saw the birth of the Muslim League at&#xA;Dacca. The formation of Barindranath’s revolutionai&amp;rsquo;y party&#xA;at Maniktola, a suburb of Calcutta, and the foundation of the&#xA;revolutionary institution, the Anushilan Samiti, took place&#xA;during the same year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With a band of a few hundred youths at his command in&#xA;Maharashtra, Savarkar left India. Maharashtra was too small&#xA;a field for the young lion and the lion went in search of lions.&#xA;During those days revolutionaries from Russia, Ireland, Egypt&#xA;and China occasionally took shelter in London. Under the&#xA;garb of a law student, Savarkar also was going to enter the&#xA;gates of the Empire capital. His main object was to have a&#xA;look at the den of the British lion, to learn how to organize&#xA;a revolution and carry on the struggle for the liberation of&#xA;Hindusthan by inculcating tenets of revolution into the&#xA;brilliant brains of the cream of the Indian students, who went&#xA;abroad either for academic careers or for qualifying them-&#xA;selves for the civil service. The young orator of Maharashtra&#xA;was now to be in London, the largest debating society under&#xA;the sun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 The Storm Breaks</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/07_The_Storm_Breaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/07_The_Storm_Breaks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Abhinava Bharat was pondering over the sentences&#xA;passed upon the Maniktola revolutionaries. Babarao Savar-&#xA;kar’s heroic sacrifice blazed vigorously under the sacrificial&#xA;firmament. The boiling point of British reaction was reached.&#xA;The zero hour had struck. And Sir Curzon Wyllie, the brain&#xA;and eye of Indian affairs at the India House, fell a victim to&#xA;the bullets of Madanlal Dhingra on the first night of July 1909.&#xA;Along with him also fell Dr. Cawas Lalcaca, an Anglecised&#xA;Parsee zealot, who tried to save the life of Sir Curzon WyUie.&#xA;The fateful incident took place in the Hall of the Imperial&#xA;Institute, London, at the conclusion of a meeting held to cele-&#xA;brate the annual function of the National Indian Association.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 Epic Escape and World-Famous Trials</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/08_Epic_Escape_and_World-Famous_Trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/08_Epic_Escape_and_World-Famous_Trials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the first day of July 1910, the steamer s.s, morea convey-&#xA;ing Savarkar to India started on her historic voyage from&#xA;London ! Proud like a kite, she held her prey in the clutches.&#xA;She tossed on. But woe followed the waves. The book of&#xA;fate was signed and sealed by destiny ! There was some&#xA;engine trouble and the morea required repairs in the neigh-&#xA;bourhood of the port of Marseilles. So she anchored at&#xA;Marseilles on Thursday evening, July 7, 1910. On June 29&#xA;the British Government had informed the French Govern-&#xA;ment that the morea was bound for India with a political&#xA;prisoner, and requested the French Government to watch the&#xA;steamer, if she anchored at Marseilles, and to guard against&#xA;any possible attempt of Savarkar’s rescue by the Indian&#xA;revolutionaries on the Continent. Mr. Parkar, the C.I.D.&#xA;officer from London and Mr. Power, Assistant Superintendent&#xA;of Police from Bombay, were in charge of the illustrious&#xA;prisoner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 The Indian Bastille</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/09_The_Indian_Bastille/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/09_The_Indian_Bastille/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With a blanket on his head and a platter in one hand,&#xA;Savarkar stood in chains before the ferocious lofty gates deco-&#xA;rated with all kinds of chains, hand-cuffs, fetters, guns and&#xA;bayonets. The gate creaked ! Someone whispered that&#xA;Mr. Barrie was coming on. Savarkar was preoccupied and&#xA;was not conscious of Barrie’s arrival. A voice roared, “ Leave&#xA;him. He is not a tiger ! ” The harsh voice waked Savarkar&#xA;up. Turning to Savarkar the jailer opened conversation with&#xA;him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Genius Thrives in Jail</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/10_Genius_Thrives_in_Jail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/10_Genius_Thrives_in_Jail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i&#34;&gt;I&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In his utter helplessness and colossal frustration of life&#xA;Savarkar was striving superhumanly to wring some good&#xA;out of it. A true ascetic and man of action as he was, he&#xA;resolved to make the most of life and to make the best of it.&#xA;Such men of supreme courage and indomitable mil make&#xA;appearance from age to age. Stone walls do not imprison&#xA;them, nor do iron bars encage them. Their angelic souls rise&#xA;above and soar. Their life is real. Earnestness is its breath.&#xA;The grave is not its goal. Their souls are indestructible. A&#xA;cruel thread of destiny was weaving and tightening round the&#xA;neck of Savarkar. Despite the horrible and indescribable&#xA;agonies, his genius throve in jail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Out of his Grave</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/11_Out_of_his_Grave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/11_Out_of_his_Grave/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The World War I terminated in 1918 and soon after a&#xA;systematic and persistent propaganda was carried on through-&#xA;out the country for the release of all political prisoners.&#xA;People, popular leaders and the Press voiced their demand&#xA;for the release of political prisoners through petitions, meet-&#xA;ings, Conferences, Congress Sessions and in Coimcils. The&#xA;National Union of Bombay, Sri Anantrao Gadre, Senapati&#xA;Bapat and Sri Shivrampant Paranjpe took a leading part in&#xA;collecting signatures of the people on the petition and the&#xA;great petition was forwarded to Mr. Montagu, the Secretary&#xA;of State for India. The Secretary of State for India rejected&#xA;it. The Amritsar Congress demanded the release of all&#xA;political prisoners by a special resolution. The District Home&#xA;Rule Leagues from Maharashtra, too, wired to the Viceroy&#xA;demanding the release of the Savarkar brothers. The royal&#xA;proclamation in connection with the royal clemency to&#xA;political prisoners issued on December 24, 1919, stated in clear&#xA;terms ; “ I therefore direct my Viceroy to exercise in My&#xA;name and on My behalf My Royal clemency to political&#xA;prisoners in the fullest measure which, in his judgment, is&#xA;compatible with public safety. I desire to extend it on this&#xA;condition to persons who, for offences against the State or&#xA;imder any special or emergency legislation are suffering&#xA;imprisonment or restriction upon their liberty.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Social Revolution</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/12_Social_Revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/12_Social_Revolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thus Savarkar was interned in Ratnagiri where the&#xA;defeated and dethroned King Theba of Burma had perished.&#xA;Two weeks after this memorable event of January 6, 1924,&#xA;the Ratnagiri Hindu Sabha was established ostensibly&#xA;through the influence and attempts of Babarao Savarkar, but,&#xA;in fact, inspired by Savarkar himself. The main object of the&#xA;Sabha was to organize, consolidate and unite the Hindus into&#xA;one organic whole and enable them to oppose effectively any&#xA;unjust aggression ; thus while protecting their own cultural,&#xA;religious and economic rights, the Hindus were to strive for&#xA;the general welfare of mankind, universal compassion being&#xA;the basic urge of Hinduism !&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Rationalist and Author</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/13_Rationalist_and_Author/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/13_Rationalist_and_Author/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern civilization is th» atcome of scientific research and&#xA;progress. Science and Der io^racy are two great potential&#xA;forces in the modern wo) d Democracy defines the shape&#xA;and aims of social and political endeavour. It strives for a&#xA;good, just, equitable and progressive life. Good and&#xA;progressive life demands an equal and proportionately just&#xA;enjoyment of all the material and cultural resources and&#xA;possession. Those possessions and resources are brought&#xA;within the reach of men by science which controls the laws&#xA;and forces of Nature and bends (hem to the services of men.&#xA;While bringing about this change, science emancipates the&#xA;mind of man from the bondage of superstition and ignorance.&#xA;Thus science plays a dominant part in the reconstruction of&#xA;every country’s life and economy, and solves its crucial&#xA;problems of food, clothing, shelter, security, and peace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Back to Freedom</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/14_Back_to_Freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/14_Back_to_Freedom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In spite of his heroic work in the direction of social and&#xA;mental revolution thi^oughout the period of internment at&#xA;Ratnagiri, Savarkar was trying his utmost to break his&#xA;shackles. Gnveriimeni wt c trying their way to prolong the&#xA;period of his internment oi some plea or other. It is said that&#xA;climate influences characteis Inhabitants as they were of a&#xA;region where fire is a luxury, the Britishers took great care&#xA;of fire wherever it burnt in their Indian Empire. They&#xA;watched the fire-places in India with special care. Whenever&#xA;any fire broke out in any part of India, Savarkar &amp;rsquo;s&#xA;residence was shadowed. Surprise * raids were a common&#xA;feature for Savarkar’s residence. Once the Superintendent&#xA;of Police surrounded Savarkar’s residence at dawn, and&#xA;showed Savarkar the order under which he was directed to&#xA;search Savarkar’s residence for copies of the proscribed book,&#xA;The Indian War of Independence of 1857. Savarkar came out&#xA;of the house with his family and said to the officer with a&#xA;smile : “ Yes, we have come out. You can go in and search the&#xA;house. But remember that I have struggled with Scotland&#xA;Yard for four years and outwitted them.” Yet the police had&#xA;not come to Savarkar’s residence without reason. Sardar&#xA;Bhagat Singh had printed two thousand copies of that famous&#xA;book of Savarkar to raise funds for his revolutionary society&#xA;and had respectfully sent the first two copies of the book to&#xA;Savarkar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Whirlwind Propaganda</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/15_Whirlwind_Propaganda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/15_Whirlwind_Propaganda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Savarkar’s dramatic release was a pleasant surprise to&#xA;Hindudom. Leaders like Sri Kelkar, Bhai Parmananda,&#xA;Dr. Moonje and Sri Aney were happy over the exhilarating&#xA;event that brought to them the release of a national force. The&#xA;reaction of the Congress High Command to his release was&#xA;notable. Pandit Nehru welcomed Savaikar back to freedom.&#xA;Rajaji felt great joy at the release of a national hero, who was&#xA;to him a symbol of courage, bravery and patriotism. Desha-&#xA;gaurav Subhas Bose welcomed him, and urged him to join&#xA;the Congress and strengthen the national movement. He&#xA;added that bright future awaited Savarkar. Sri M. N. Roy&#xA;welcomed the hero and hoped that Savarkar would devote&#xA;his life again to the emancipation of India on his own line of&#xA;thinking.^ Gandhiji had nothing to say about it. He was&#xA;proverbially silent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Hindu Manifesto or Savarkarism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/16_Hindu_Manifesto_or_Savarkarism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/16_Hindu_Manifesto_or_Savarkarism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ideal and ideology which Savarkar laid down and&#xA;propagated is called the Hindu Sanghatan ideology or Hindu&#xA;Nationalism or Savarkarism. Although a natural development,&#xA;an outgrowth and a manilestation of the various views and&#xA;tenets upheld by several Hindu nationalists jointly, severally&#xA;or individually, the ideology is put into a form and finally&#xA;formulated and codified into an integrated doctrine of social&#xA;and political outlook on life by Savarkar. Savarkar is there-&#xA;fore to this Hindu ideology what Newton is to the Law of&#xA;Gravitation or Marx to Socialism. Each of them applied&#xA;his own logic to the diverse views and brought unity in&#xA;diversity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Differences with the Congress</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/17_Differences_with_the_Congress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/17_Differences_with_the_Congress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Owing to their stupendous ignorance of and a wrong&#xA;approach to the Moslem problem, the Congress leaders&#xA;betrayed a woeful lack of self-confidence in the conduct of&#xA;the national struggle. This ultimately discredited the prestige&#xA;and patriotism of the Hindus, undermined the pov/er of the&#xA;national majority, and mortgaged the destiny of the country&#xA;to the anti-national forces.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Savarkar’s insight perceived this growing danger from the&#xA;designs of the awakened Muslim mind. He knew that Muslim&#xA;opposition to the national aspirations was not confined to a&#xA;song here or a piece of music there. According to him there&#xA;was a fundamental difference in their outlook on life and&#xA;literature and in their aspirations for the governance of&#xA;Hindusthan as a nation. Therefore the first thing Savarkar&#xA;did was to strive to bring into operation the Federal part of&#xA;the 1935 Act, and frustrate the Muslim designs. Though the&#xA;Federal part of this Act, he said, handed over no real power&#xA;especially in the matter of Military and Foreign policy to the&#xA;representatives of the people, it offered an opportunity for the&#xA;realization of national unification of the States and other&#xA;parts under the British occupation into an organized and&#xA;corporate whole. But partly being not sure of the party&#xA;domination at the Centre, and partly being afraid of the&#xA;opposition led in the field by the youthful left-wing forged by&#xA;President Subhas Bose, the Congress High Command&#xA;bypassed the issue of Federation, Not because there was no&#xA;promise for immediate independence that the Congress did&#xA;not accept the Federation. The Congress could have fought&#xA;here, too, to undo the unsatisfactory portion of the Federation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Roosevelt, Churchill and Cripps</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/18_Roosevelt_Churchill_and_Cripps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/18_Roosevelt_Churchill_and_Cripps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meantime, there was a move in tlie Liberal Circles to solve&#xA;the deadlock in their way. They held a Non-Party&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conference in March 1941 at the Taj Malial Hotel, Bombay.&#xA;The Convener of the Conference was the late Sir Tej Bahadur&#xA;Sapru. It may be noted here that a few days before this&#xA;Gandhiji had called on the ailing knight at his residence in&#xA;Allahabad. Sir Tej was also in coi&amp;rsquo;respondence with Gandhiji,&#xA;and Dr. Jayakar had seen Savarkar in the preceding month.&#xA;Intellectual and legal luminaries of India attended the&#xA;Conference. Prominent among those who attended the&#xA;Conference weie Sir Jagdish Prasad, Sir Nripendranath&#xA;Sirkar, Sir Chimanlal Setalvad, Loknayak Aney, Dr. Moonje,&#xA;Pandit Kunzru, Dr. Jayakar, Savarkar and Dr. Mookerjee.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Mahasabha Marches On</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/19_Mahasabha_Marches_On/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/19_Mahasabha_Marches_On/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Akhand Hindusllian movement was gradually gaining&#xA;ground. Savarkar’s voi. was capturing the imagination of&#xA;the people. Congress iri&amp;rsquo;u- nce with the ma.sses was at a&#xA;low ebb. Even in Englan-i and in America the people and&#xA;the Press evinced interest and eagerness to learn more&#xA;about the Hindu Mahasabha and its movement, its organiza-&#xA;tion and its leaders. The Hindu Mahasabha was defeating&#xA;Congress candidates in Municipal, Local and District Local&#xA;Board elections and bye-elections to the Legislatures. In 1941&#xA;the Congress suffered a significant defeat in Maharashtra when&#xA;Sri Jamnadas Mehta, supported by the Hindu Mahasabha,&#xA;defeated the Congress candidate in the election to the Central&#xA;Assembly. In Bengal where the opposition to the Mahasabha&#xA;came from the Forward Block, the Congress being then a&#xA;dwindling force there, Sri Ashutosh Lahiri, the General&#xA;Secretary of the Hindu Mahasabha, defeated the Forward&#xA;Block candidate in the election to the Provincial Assembly.&#xA;Sri K. C. Neogy, supported by the Hindu Mahasabha, defeated&#xA;the Forward Block candidate, Sri Mujumdar, in Bengal in&#xA;the bye-election to the Central Assembly when a seat fell&#xA;vacant due to the disappearance of Subhas Bose in January&#xA;1942.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 The Writing on the Wall</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/20_The_Writing_on_the_Wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/20_The_Writing_on_the_Wall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the meanwhile, attempts were made by leading pro-&#xA;Pakistani Hindus, who were outside the jails, to capture the&#xA;Hindu Mahasabha by r. /p d^ciat and make it accept the&#xA;Pakistan scheme at least ]vrinciple so that the Hindu Maha-&#xA;sabha could be a handmaid Lo the Congress in supporting the&#xA;latter’s anti-national surrender to the Pakistani forces. Sri K.&#xA;M. Munshi had even attended a meeting of the Working&#xA;Committee of the Hindu Mahasabha and Rajaji had almost&#xA;captivated Dr. Mookerjee and Raja Maheshwar Dayal. In&#xA;order to ward off that danger, expose and frustrate the&#xA;conspiracy, Savarkar resolved not only not to resign as already&#xA;announced by him, but also to contest the election to the&#xA;Presidentship of the Hindu Mahasabha at the annual Session&#xA;of the Mahasabha in 1942. This was the only time when&#xA;Savarkar actually contested the election to the Presidentship&#xA;of the Hindu Mahasabha ; and backed by the wisdom and&#xA;overwhelming confidence of its electorates, Savarkar was&#xA;almost unanimously elected to the Presidentship. The annual&#xA;Session was held at Cawnpore in the last week of December&#xA;1942.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Fight for Akhand Hindusthan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/21_Fight_for_Akhand_Hindusthan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/21_Fight_for_Akhand_Hindusthan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now we come to a very important chapter in the life of&#xA;Savarkar. By now Rajaji, the whilom member of the All-&#xA;India Congress Committee, released to the press his corres-&#xA;pondence with Mr. Jinnah concerning his offer to the League&#xA;leader which was fathered by Gandhiji during his fast at the&#xA;Aga Kh^n Palace. Rajaji had now advanced to the far end&#xA;of the proposed Pakistan scheme. Speaking on the birthday&#xA;anniversary of the Prophet at Bangalore on April 12, 1943,&#xA;Rajaji had said : “ I stand for Pakistan because I do not want&#xA;that State where we Hindus and Muslims are both not&#xA;honoured. Let Muslims have Pakistan. If we agree then our&#xA;country will be saved.’’ ^ Mr. Jinnah in his press interview&#xA;on July 30, 1944, referred to the correspondence with Rajaji&#xA;and the proposal put forward by him and said : “ As regards&#xA;the merits of the proposal, Mr. Gandhi is offering a shadow,&#xA;a husk, a maimed, mutilated and moth-eaten Pakistan and&#xA;thus trying to pass off as having met our Pakistan scheme and&#xA;Muslim demand.” In one of his telegrams sent to Mr. Jinnah&#xA;and now released to the press, Rajaji said : “ Mr. Gandhi,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 From Parity to Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/22_From_Parity_to_Pakistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/22_From_Parity_to_Pakistan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The year 1946 opened with general elections to the&#xA;Provincial Legislatures all over India. Congressmen used the&#xA;same old tactics and reiterated the pledge of a United India.&#xA;On January 14, 1946, Sardar Patel thundered at Ahmedabad :&#xA;‘‘ Granting of Pakistan is not in the hands of the British Gov-&#xA;ernment. If Pakistan is to be achieved, Hindus and Muslims&#xA;will have to fight. There will be a civil war. The Congress&#xA;is no longer going to knock at the doors of the League. The&#xA;Congress has tried to settle with the League many times. But&#xA;it has been kicked every time.’’ Such masterpieces of the&#xA;Sardar, the steam-roller of the power and prestige of the party&#xA;that had ruled, and the press, purse and propaganda let loose&#xA;by the greatest political organization in India, overran the&#xA;Hindu Mahasabha candidates in elections. And the Hindu&#xA;Mahasabha was entirely thrown into the shade. The League&#xA;emerged as the authoritative mouthpiece of the Muslims and&#xA;the Congress of the Hindus alone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 The Red Fort Ordeal and After</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/23_The_Red_Fort_Ordeal_and_After/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/23_The_Red_Fort_Ordeal_and_After/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the shots fired by Nathuram Vinayak Godse&#xA;disappeared one of the greatest political figures from the stage&#xA;of world politics. The act was committed in broad daylight,&#xA;in a public place, in the sight of a multitude by a man dressed&#xA;in khaki bush jacket and blue trousers. The newspapers&#xA;described him as a batchelor of thirty-seven with medium&#xA;height, fair skin, square jaws, a resolute and sober face, serious&#xA;flickering eyes, a high forehead, close-cropped hair, all giving&#xA;the appearance of a man of serious purpose.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 The Man</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/24_The_Man/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/24_The_Man/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The story of Savarkar is the history of resistance, strife,&#xA;struggle, sufferings and sacrifices for the cause of political,&#xA;social and economic emai^cipation of this Bharat Varsha. His&#xA;is a political career extended over fifty long years. How&#xA;many of his great contemporaries could see pioneers from&#xA;Ranade to philosophers like M. N. Roy, could strive for inde-&#xA;pendence of India and yet have the good fortune to see the&#xA;sun of freedom rise over India ? An active political leader&#xA;who either saw, talked or discussed politics with thinkers&#xA;from Ranade to Roy, leaders from Surendranath to Subhas,&#xA;from liberator Tilak to fighter Achyutrao Patwardhan ! No&#xA;other life on the political stage of India is marked by so many&#xA;vicissitudes, punctuated with raging storms and lightning and&#xA;tantalized with gaping gallows ! This is a political life&#xA;chequered with romantic threads of sufferings and is fringed&#xA;with sacrifices. Woven with recollections of the sea and&#xA;the steamer, it is interspersed with hell-like prison life and is&#xA;lined with historic arrests, trials and releases. Even one single&#xA;incident from the matchless drama of Savarkar’s life is long,&#xA;charming and thrilling enough to provide the span for a play&#xA;of immortal fame.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 INDEX</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/25_INDEX/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/sAvarkar_and_his_times/25_INDEX/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AVihinava Bharat, 9, 24, 27, 29, 30,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;31, 33, 35, 36, 37, 38, 39, 44, 48,&#xA;49, 57, 58, 60, 78, 107, 109, 125,&#xA;133, 134, 197, 201, 3.58, 411, 413.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acharya, M. P. T., 33.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Khan, H.H., the, 41, 50, 254.&#xA;Avarkar, 166, 167, 182, 185, 187,&#xA;188, 396.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aiyar, Sir C. P. Ramasv/ami, 278,&#xA;288&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aivor, V. V. S., 32, 40, 41, 44,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;21, 72. 178.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aklred, Gu/ A., G5, 67, 81, 83, 84,&#xA;1VV;&amp;gt;. 235, 4.V0.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
