<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/articles/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/articles/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>shrI rAmAnuja deshika, one of the last great kaumAra tantrics</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/articles/MT_lekhAH/2007-01-14_shri-ramanuja-deshika-one-of-the-last-great-kaumara-tantrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/articles/MT_lekhAH/2007-01-14_shri-ramanuja-deshika-one-of-the-last-great-kaumara-tantrics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2007/01/14/shri-ramanuja-deshika-one-of-the-last-great-kaumara-tantrics/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The below note is neither meant as a sectarian effusion nor a historical&#xA;account. It is a hagiography and just that.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;sarva-bhUtAmakaM manmanobodhakaM sat-kR^ipAsAgaraM devasenApate pAhi mAM&#xA;pAhi mAM pAhi mAM deva tubhyaM namo deva tubhyaM namo deva tubhyaM namaH&#xA;||&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The shrI-vaiShNava AchArya, sudarshana sUrI, was proceeding to&#xA;shrIperaMputtur after visiting the old temple of viShNu at venkaTagiri&#xA;(not Tirupati) and consecrating a shalagraman there. On his way back on&#xA;his horse cart he had to pass by the shrine housing the great vAyu&#xA;li~Nga of the terrible rudra, kAlahasti. rudra’s presence was felt here&#xA;in the form in which he had destroyed gajAsura. The zealous vaiShNava&#xA;who did not recognize the greatness of The god, asked his henchmen to&#xA;draw the curtains in his cart and he closed his eyes so that even by&#xA;error he might not cast his eyes on the shrine of rudra. When he was a&#xA;safe from kAlahasti distance he opened his eyes but to his horror he had&#xA;turned blind. Shocked he uttered the verse:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;sarvAtmatA te shrutiShu prasiddhA satyaiva sA kAlakarIsha nUnaM |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;apashyatastvA madhunA samastaM yato na me dR^iShTipathaM prayAti ||&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tilak</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-09-03_tilak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-09-03_tilak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/09/03/tilak/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The brahmins of the coastal strip of the maharaTTa country shot to&#xA;prominence under their first hero Balaji Vishvanath who turned the tide&#xA;on the Islamic deluge in India. His son&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://manollasa.blogspot.com/2006/02/on-bajirao-i.html&#34;&gt;Bajirao&lt;/a&gt;, and&#xA;successor was the greatest luminary of this community who in his brief&#xA;lifespan achieved success that nearly unmatched by any other Hindu&#xA;general before him. The one other man of his jAti, who came close to his&#xA;level of glory was Balgangadhar Tilak- the man who led India’s struggle&#xA;against the Chrisitian tyrants from England. The British who were a&#xA;fitting adversary if ever there was one (after all Vakimchandra&#xA;correctly realized that they were vastly superior enemies of India to&#xA;the Mahommedans), realized the threat from Tilak and tried their best&#xA;after that to cap Hindu nationalism once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some works of nArAyaNa bhaTTathiri</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-08-21_some-works-of-narayana-bhattathiri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-08-21_some-works-of-narayana-bhattathiri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/08/21/some-works-of-narayana-bhattathiri/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MelpattUr nArAyaNa bhaTTathiri, was a great nambuthiri sanskrit writer&#xA;who apparently lived for a 106 years (born 1560) after escaping death&#xA;due to syphilis earlier in his life. He wrote a remarkable vaishNava&#xA;tract, the nArAyaNIyaM, which is a glorious work of sanskrit poetry&#xA;despite its extremist stance. prakriyA sarvasva was his famous treatise&#xA;on saMskR^it grammar that took the place of the siddhAnta kaumudI of&#xA;bhaTToji dIkShita in the midst of the nambuthiris. He also revolted&#xA;against the pANinian grammatic tradition by composing the ApANinIya&#xA;prAmANya sAdhAna where he built upon his teacher achyuta pishAraDi’s&#xA;work of non-pANinian approach to grammar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
