<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/magic/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/magic/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>maratha-rAjput</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/magic/articles/maratha-rAjput/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/magic/articles/maratha-rAjput/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to Sabhasad Bakhar, Mirza Rajah Jai Singh before embarking on his Deccan campaign—against CSM and Bijapur sultanate—sponsored a grand three-month-long sacrifice, employing 400 brahmins, in order to propitiate the Goddess Bagalamukhi-Kalaratri. The Bakhar further claims the Goddess Tuljabhavani possessed Chhatrapati and advised him to broker peace with Mirza Rajah, warning him of his inability to defeat the latter, as he had turned invincible for the time being as a result of his tantric penances.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mogol-safavid</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/magic/articles/mogol-safavid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/magic/articles/mogol-safavid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Use of tantric rituals, war magic was quite common in medieval warfare.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the siege of Kandahar, the Mughals and Safavids engaged in a black magic contest; employing sorcerers and performing magical rites.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the course of jotting down his diary, Rashid Khan mentions that various sorcerers frequented the Mughal army camp. As with astrology, the occult arts were cultivated as an accepted body of practice and knowledge throughout the period, both in Hindustan and among the neighboring Muslim dynasties. The author of the Lataif does not make too much of these episodes―he casually weaves them into a larger mass of detail on the day&amp;rsquo;s happenings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tangut-mongol</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/magic/articles/tangut-mongol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/magic/articles/tangut-mongol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Tangut kingdom of Xixia employed Tibetan Buddhists skilled in war magic in their court. When the kingdom was laid to siege by Chinggis Khan, one such cleric summoned Mahakala on the battlefield, forcing the Mongols to retreat.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Mongols themselves would later invoke Mahakala to their aid during the conquest of China under Qubilai Khan, defeating not just the Chinese armies, but the Chinese God of War Zhenwu himself. Mahakala would become the state deity of the Yuan Mongols.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
