<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>amara-siMha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/amara-siMha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/amara-siMha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rattibha.com/thread/1503589082621902850?lang=en&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Typically when we speak of Mewar, it usually ends with Rana Pratap and the Battle of Haldighati. Not much is really known about his son Amar Singh,who like his father, fought 17 battles with the Mughals, winning a good many of them. Thread on a forgotten hero.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While Rana Pratap’s rivalry with Akbar is well known and chronicled, not known is the fact that his son Amar Singh fought an equally long war with Jahangir, before he was forced to surrender. Sadly many historians evaluated him on the basis of the treaty with Jahangir, not understanding the fact that it was a rather painful decision, and even that treaty was not complete surrender.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kumbha - HH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/kumbha_hh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/kumbha_hh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rattibha.com/thread/1544008946863820801?lang=en&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;~1421: Maharana Kumbha was born to Maharana Mokal Singh &amp;amp; Sobhagya Devi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1433: Kumbhakarna became Maharana at age of 13, after Mahipal Panwar assassinated young Maharana Mokal. Mahipal fled Mewar &amp;amp; took refuge with Malwa’s Sultan Mahmud Khalji aka Alauddin Mahmud Shah-I. Rao Ranmal Rathore was the regent of Mewar during the initial phase of Kumbha’s rule. He destroyed the internal rebels.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1439: Maharana Kumbha told Sultan Mahmud Khalji to deport Mahipal Panwar to Mewar for exacting the revenge of the murder of Maharana’s father. The Malwa Sultan refused to do so, &amp;amp; challenged the Maharana for a battle. Maharana set off with 1 lakh army &amp;amp; 1400 elephants to fight Mahmud. ⚔️Battle of Sarangpur took place, in which Maharana defeated the Sultan after a brutal battle. The Sultan fled to Mandu fort. The Mewar army pursued him to Mandu &amp;amp; besieged the fort. The desperate Mahmud sortied out of the fort to give battle to Kumbha, only to face defeat! Mahmud was held captive for 6 months, &amp;amp; only left free after exacting a monetary tribute.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
