<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;hindu temples 1 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;hindu temples 1 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Preface</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/01_pre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/01_pre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preface&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movement for the restoration of the Ramajanmabhumi Temple at Ayodhya has brought to the fore a suppressed chapter of India’s history, namely, the large-scale destruction of Hindu temples&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; by the Islamised invaders.  This chapter is by no means closed.  The Appendix to this book provides details of many temples destroyed by Muslims all over Bangladesh as recently as October-November 1989.  Currently, temples, or whatever had remained of them, are meeting a similar fate in the Kashmir valley.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Chapter One Hideaway Communalism Arun Shourie</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/02_ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/02_ch1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter One&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Hideaway Communalism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Arun Shourie&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A case in which the English version of a major book by a renowned&#xA;Muslim scholar, the fourth Rector of one of the greatest centres of Islamic learning in India, listing some of the mosques, including the Babri Masjid, which were built on the sites and foundations of temples, using their stones and structures, is found to have the tell-tale passages censored out;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The book is said to have become difficult to get;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Chapter Two The Tip of An Iceberg Sita Ram Goel</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/03_ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/03_ch2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter Two&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;The Tip of An Iceberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sita Ram Goel&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The mention made by Maulana Abdul Hai (&lt;em&gt;Indian Express&lt;/em&gt;, February 5) of Hindu temples turned into mosques, is only the tip of an iceberg, The iceberg itself lies submerged in the writings of medieval Muslim historians, accounts of foreign travellers and the reports of the Archaeological Survey of India. A hue and cry has been raised in the name of secularism and national integration whenever the iceberg has chanced to surface, inspite of hectic efforts to keep it suppressed.&#xA;Marxist politicians masquerading as historians have been the major contributors to this conspiracy of silence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Chapter Three Some Historical Questions Sita Ram Goel</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/04_ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/04_ch3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter Three&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Some Historical Questions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sita Ram Goel&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why did Islamic invaders continue to destroy Hindu temples and desecrate the idols of Hindu Gods and Goddesses throughout the period of their domination? Why did they raise mosques on sites occupied earlier by Hindu places of worship?  These questions were asked by Hindu scholars in modern times after the terror of Islam had ceased and could no more seal their lips.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 Chapter Four In the Name of Religion Sita Ram Goel</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/05_ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/05_ch4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter Four&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;In the Name of Religion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sita Ram Goel&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We shall now take up the explanation provided by the theology of Islam derived from the Quran and the Hadis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ibn Ishaq, the first biographer of the Prophet, devotes many pages to a description of Arab polytheism at the time when Islam started taking shape.  Every Arab household, he tells us, had an idol of some God or Goddess.  He also gives the names of many idols which were housed in sanctuaries maintained by different tribes across the Arab peninsula.&#xA;The Ka‘ba at Mecca which housed 360 idols was only one of these sanctuaries, though it was the most prestigious.  One of the idols in the Ka’ba was named Allah.  Though it had some primacy over other idols, it was far from being an exclusive deity.  Besides, there were many sacred groves and places of pilgrimage visited by Arabs on special occasions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 Chapter Five A Need to Face the Truth Ram Swarup</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/06_ch5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/06_ch5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter Five&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;A Need to Face the Truth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Ram Swarup&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The article “Hideaway Communalism” (&lt;em&gt;Indian Express&lt;/em&gt;, February 5, 1989), is unusual.  It discusses a question which has been a taboo and speaks on it with a frankness rare among Indian intellectuals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Similarly, in his articles “The Tip of An Iceberg” and “In the Name of Religion” (February 9, May 21) Sita Ram Goel brings to the subject unequalled research and discusses it in a larger historical perspective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 Chapter Six Historians Versus History Ram Swarup</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/07_ch6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/07_ch6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter Six&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Historians Versus History&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Ram Swarup&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wole Soyinka, African Nobel Laureate, delivering the 20th Nehru Memorial Lecture on November 13, 1988, made an important though by no means a new observation - that the colonial histories have been written from the European viewpoint.  Speaking about Indian histories, he said that “there is a big question mark on everything that the British historians have written”.  He added that serious efforts are being made by historians back home “to rewrite African history.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 Chapter Seven November 9 Will Change History Jay Dubashi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/08_ch7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/08_ch7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter Seven&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;November 9 Will Change History&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Jay Dubashi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is the need of the hour, someone asked me the other day.  Is it stability, is it unity, is it communal peace?  It is none of these things, I told him.  The need of the hour is COURAGE.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We Hindus have become a timid race, almost a cowardly race.  We lack the courage of our convictions.  Some of us don’t even have any convictions, and have been trying to hide our shame under high-sounding but empty phrases like secularism.  For the last so many centuries, the history of the Hindus has been created by non-Hindus, first the Moghuls, then the British.  Even today, the Hindus are being denied their right to write their own history, which, to me, is almost like genocide.  Until we write our own history, this land cannot be ours.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 Chapter Eight From Shilanyas to Berlin Wall Jay Dubashi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/09_ch8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/09_ch8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter Eight&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;From Shilanyas to Berlin Wall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Jay Dubashi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;History has its quirks but there is a method behind the madness.  I said in my last column that November 9, 1989, would go down in Indian history as one of those dates that actually make history.  I was not aware at the time that on the very same day the first brick of the Ramshila foundation was being laid at Ayodhya, the Berliners were removing bricks from the Berlin Wall. While a temple was going up in Ayodhya, a communist temple was being demolished five thousand miles away in Europe. If this is not history, I do not know what is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Chapter Nine Rama-Janmabhumi Temple Muslim Testimony Harsh Narain</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/10_ch9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/10_ch9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter Nine&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Rama-Janmabhumi Temple Muslim Testimony&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Harsh Narain&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All relevant British government records followed by the District Gazetteer Faizabad compiled and published by the Congress government in 1960 declare with one voice that the so-called Babari mosque at Ayodhya is standing on the debris of a Ramjanmasthan temple demolished by the order of Babar in 1528.  Syed Shahabuddin, JNU historians, and. self-styled ‘secular’ scholars and leaders are hotly contesting that the existence and demolition of such a temple is a myth floated by the British in pursuance of their policy of ‘divide and rule’.  Syed Shahabuddin and many Muslim divines go a step further and assert that neither Babar nor any other Muslim for that matter would take into his head to erect a mosque by displacing a temple, for, they argue, such a mosque would not be a mosque in the eye of the Shari’ah and would be liable to demolition by the Muslims themselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Chapter Ten Let the Mute Witnesses Speak Sita Ram Goel</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/11_ch10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/11_ch10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter Ten&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Let the Mute Witnesses Speak&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sita Ram Goel&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The cradle of Hindu culture[^1] on the eve of its Islamic invasion included what are at present the Sinkiang province of China, the Transoxiana region of Russia, the Seistan province of Iran and the sovereign states of Afghanistan, Pakistan, India, Nepal and Bangladesh. The Islamic invasion commenced around 650 A.D., when a Muslim army secured a foothold in Seistan, and continued till the end of the eighteenth century, when the last Islamic crusader, Tipu Sultan, was overthrown by the British. Hordes of Arabs, Persians, Turks, and Afghans who had been successively inspired by the Theology of Islam poured in, in wave after wave, carrying fire and sword to every nook and corner of this vast area. In the process, Sinkiang, Transoxiana region, Seistan and Afghanistan became transformed into &lt;em&gt;daru’l-IslĀm&lt;/em&gt; where all vestiges of the earlier culture were wiped out.  The same spell has engulfed the areas which were parts of India till 1947 and have since become Pakistan and Bangladesh.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Appendix</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/12_app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_1/12_app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appendix&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using the Babari Masjid-Ramajanmabhumi controversy as a pretext, Muslim mobs went on a rampage all over Bangladesh. They attacked and burnt down Hindu houses and business establishments in many places, murdered some Hindus and inflicted injuries on many others. Hindu temples and monasteries invited their special attention everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Starting on October 29, 1989, the mob fury reached its climax on November 9 and 10 after the Shilanyas ceremony at Ayodhya. Many temples were demolished or burnt down or damaged in various ways. Images of deities were broken and thrown out. Temple priests were beaten up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
