<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Indian givers on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Indian givers on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 SILVER AND MONEY CAPITALISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/1_SILVER_AND_MONEY_CAPITALISM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/1_SILVER_AND_MONEY_CAPITALISM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Each morning at five-thirty, Rodrigo Cespedes eats two rolls and drinks a cup of tea heavily laced with sugar before he slings his ratty Adidas gym bag over his shoulder and leaves for work Rodrigo lives in Potosi, the world&amp;rsquo;s highest city, perched in the Bolivian Andes at an elevation of 13,680 feet above sea level. At this altitude Rodrigo stays warm only when he holds himself directly in the sunlight, but this early in the morning, the streets are still dark. He walks with other men going in the same direction, but like most Quechua and Aymara Indians they walk along silently. The loudest sounds come from the scraping noise of the old women who laboriously sweep the streets each morning. Bent over their short straw brooms, these women look like medieval witches dressed in the traditional black garments woven in Potosi and the tall black hats native to the area.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 The Indian Healer</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/10_The_Indian_Healer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/10_The_Indian_Healer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The midday sun scorched everything it touched one January afternoon at the height of the dry season in Teli, a village of the Dogon tribe in Mali. I was en route to Kani Kombole and passed the heat of the day napping on a wooden platform bed covered with reed mats beneath a thatched roof. I had eaten my fill of chicken and rice with peanuts and chilies, I had consumed endless calabashes of cool, clear water, and I had only sipped politely from the calabash of kojo, the bubbling millet beer proffered by the headman. While I slept the children and women kept a watchful distance, but the men had long before retreated to their toguna, an open-sided shelter with a thick roof of millet straw insulating it from the strong rays of the sun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 The Drug Connection</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/11_The_Drug_Connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/11_The_Drug_Connection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sitting across from me on the back of the open truck crossing the Andes, an old Indian man reached into his pocket and pulled out a small plastic bag of leaves. He carefully extracted several crumpled leaves and a pinch of dark-brown paste and held them out to me. In the proper Quechua way I cupped my two hands together to receive them and bowed my head in a silent gesture of thanks. The Quechua Indians lack an equivalent of the European phrase &amp;ldquo;thank you,&amp;rdquo; since their culture teaches that sharing is a requirement of life and that gratitude can only be shown in deeds and not in words. The old man then took a portion for himself, and the two of us began to chew the dusty-smelling leaves. The coca made my mouth feel as fresh as though I were chewing mint or had just left the dentist&amp;rsquo;s office after having my teeth cleaned. After I had chewed a little longer my tongue and cheeks felt slightly numb.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Architecture And Urban Planning</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/12_Architecture_And_Urban_Planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/12_Architecture_And_Urban_Planning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The oldest signs of human habitation in Nicaragua appear in the hardened mud along the edge of Lake Managua, which the Indians called Xolotan. Along this shore in the northwestern part of Managua, seventeen men, women, and children left footprints indelibly marked into once soft mud.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jaguar paw prints and deer hoof-prints crisscross the human tracks, adding a sense of dramatic urgency to the mute artifacts as though the people and animals had all been fleeing something quite frightening. The depth of the adult prints suggests that the men and women struggled under the weight of heavy burdens, which may have been young children, loads of food, or prized possessions, as they ran toward the possible safety of the water. Whatever danger threatened them must have been quite awesome to scare not only these seventeen people but the animals as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 The Pathfinders</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/13_The_Pathfinders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/13_The_Pathfinders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Late one January afternoon I arrived with five other people at a cluster of houses beside Mango Creek on the Caribbean shore of Belize. We were en route to the offshore village of Placentia. The road ended at the water&amp;rsquo;s edge, and the few local fishermen had already hauled in their equipment and settled down for the evening. One young man about sixteen years old volunteered, for a price, to take us over to Placentia in his dugout. While waiting for him to borrow an outboard motor and some gasoline, our group divided. Three people made camp and stayed with the Land Rover, while three of us prepared for the trip over to where we were to meet an archaeologist who was excavating coastal Mayan sites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 When Will America Be Discovered?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/14_When_Will_America_Be_Discovered/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/14_When_Will_America_Be_Discovered/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The old Yuqui woman jerked her head up toward me and stared blindly into my face. As flies crawled across her eyes and drank from the only moist place left on her body, her left hand scratched habitually at the lice and filth encrusted into her hair. No one knew her age, but she was the oldest survivor of a band of Yuquis living in the rain forest of the southern Amazon region. Most of her life she had wandered through the forest with her fellow Yuquis following the same culture as unknown generations had done before them. She had lived most of her life without knowledge of whites or other outsiders except that they lurked on the edges of her forest world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 PIRACY, SLAVERY, AND THE BIRTH OF CORPORATIONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/2_PIRACY_SLAVERY_AND_THE_BIRTH_OF_CORP/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/2_PIRACY_SLAVERY_AND_THE_BIRTH_OF_CORP/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The gray-haired clerk and her teenage assistant sat silently behind the sales counter gazing out the window at the abandoned building on the far side of Victoria Street.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was a quiet May afternoon in Thunder Bay, Ontario, in the pause between the thawing of the ice and the first appearance of buds and birds. On one side of the store stood assorted stacks of serious winter equipment, including fur parkas, heavy mittens, and gargantuan scarves. On the other side hunW the pelts of rabbits, muskrats, raccoons, and squirrels interspersed with miniature tomahawks crowned with bright blue and red feathers, little buckskin dolls dressed as Ojibwa or Cree children, and small drums stamped &amp;ldquo;Souvenir of Canada.&amp;rdquo; A black velvet painting depicted a naked Eskimo woman reclining seductively on a bed of white fox fur.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 THE AMERICAN INDIAN PATH TO INDUSTRIALIZATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/3_THE_AMERICAN_INDIAN_PATH_TO_INDUSTRIAL/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/3_THE_AMERICAN_INDIAN_PATH_TO_INDUSTRIAL/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The German village of Kahl lies where the small Kahl River flows into the Main River at the northern border of Bavaria with Hesse. If you stroll along the smaller river, you pass through a bucolic setting reminiscent of the era of the Grimm brothers, who collected their fairy tales in this area nearly two hundred years ago. The little river meanders across a meadow, past the garden plots of the villagers, around the old mill, and past a few half-timbered farmhouses and barns from which cows and goats amble down to the water&amp;rsquo;s edge for an occasional drink.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 THE FOOD REVOLUTION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/4_THE_FOOD_REVOLUTION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/4_THE_FOOD_REVOLUTION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is only one Machu Picchu, but it guards many mysteries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ruins of this ancient Peruvian city sit perched eight thousand feet above sea level on a mountain overlooking the Urubamba River. Even though in size Machu Picchu barely surpasses a village, the ruins show a complexity indicative of a much more important place. The stone houses with trapezoidal doorways and simple lintel construction do not resemble the houses of the puric, the common peasants, and the public buildings surpass any administrative or religious building one might expect to see in a town of comparable size. The ruins show precision-crafted buildings with the neat regular lines, beveled edges, and mortarless seams that characterize the best of Inca architecture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 INDIAN AGRICULTURAL TECHNOLOGY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/5_INDIAN_AGRICULTURAL_TECHNOLOGY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/5_INDIAN_AGRICULTURAL_TECHNOLOGY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The seaplane dropped out of the clouds to pass over a small cluster of houses on a high bank of the Ucayali River an hour&amp;rsquo;s flight upstream from where the Ucayali joins the Amazon. All the way to the horizon on every side we could see nothing but the endless stretch of high jungle. We circled the village once as the pilot tried to make sure that this actually was the community of Genaro Herrera. His government map indicated that the closest village should be San Filipe and that Genaro Herrera lay farther upstream, and even though this air force captain had fifteen years of experience flying the Amazon and tributaries, he had never been to this particular community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 THE CULINARY REVOLUTION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/6_THE_CULINARY_REVOLUTION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/6_THE_CULINARY_REVOLUTION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The small port of Dire on the Niger River lies at the southern edge of the Sahara. In this part of the desert, temperatures easily reach 130 degrees Fahrenheit in the summer and at night barely dip below 100 degrees. Very little rain falls in the best of years, and some years see no rain. Severe dust storms harass the area at the end of the long, dry winter and turn day into virtual night. In April, even in years with good harvests, the young children, the elderly, and the weak start dying from malnutrition; in the years of drought, otherwise healthy people also die from starvation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 LIBERTY, ANARCHISM, AND THE NOBLE SAVAGE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/7_LIBERTY_ANARCHISM_AND_THE_NOBLE_SAVA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/7_LIBERTY_ANARCHISM_AND_THE_NOBLE_SAVA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a hot Friday afternoon in the last week of August, cars, pickup trucks, camping vans, and school buses slowly pull into a park on the edge of Fargo, North Dakota. Young people greet their friends excitedly, and old Ojibwa women solemnly shake hands with one another with greetings of &amp;ldquo;Bozhoo, bozhoo&amp;rdquo; and look over one another&amp;rsquo;s grandchildren.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dakota men greet one another with the friendly &amp;ldquo;Huu, kota&amp;rdquo; before exchanging stories and jokes. Lakota families carve out small pieces of territory around their vehicles, making the park into a series of encampments, each with its own blanket on the ground, aluminum folding chairs, and grill.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 THE FOUNDING INDIAN FATHERS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/8_THE_FOUNDING_INDIAN_FATHERS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/8_THE_FOUNDING_INDIAN_FATHERS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every day of the school year, troops of children march across the lawn of the United States Capitol perched atop the District of Columbia&amp;rsquo;s highest elevation. The building dominates the Washington skyline, a model of classical symmetry and precision. Two giant wings of precisely equal proportion reach out from a Roman dome that surveys the city of Washington. If reduced to a ruin, the forest of Greek columns decorating the building would appear to be as much at home in Rome or Naples as in Athens or Corinth. The building revels in its Old World heritage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Red Sticks and Revolution</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/9_Red_Sticks_and_Revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/indian-givers/9_Red_Sticks_and_Revolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One warm January afternoon, I was driving a Land Rover with some of my students over a virtually impassable road in Guatemala&amp;rsquo;s northeastern province of Peten. We had just entered Guatemala that day from Carmen Viejo del Benque in Belize, where we had spent the previous night in very commodious huts along the Mopan River just below the fortified Mayan ruins of Xunantunich. We were exploring the ruins but also visiting various contemporary villages of Kekchi and Mopan Maya. Now we were on the way to the unique city called Flores.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
