<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;who is a hindu on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;who is a hindu on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Foreword</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/01_for/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/01_for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foreword&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book contains a part of my Ph.D. thesis, updated and adapted for general publication.  It can best be read in conjunction with the main part of the thesis, now in print under the title *Decolonizing the Hindu Mind*.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My thanks are due to Mrs. Yamini Liu, Mr. Gopi Maliwal, Mr. Krishan Bhatnagar, Mr. Pradeep Goel, Mr. Satinder Trehan, Dr. Tushar Ravuri and Mr. Vishal Agarwal, as well as to the late Prof. Kedar Nath Mishra.  But any mistakes are of course due only to my own oversight.  Corrections and other feedback are welcomed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 1. Credal definitions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/02_ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/02_ch1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Credal definitions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“The question is”, said Alice, “whether you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; make words mean so many different things.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“The question is”, said Humpty Dumpty, “which is to be master-that’s all.”^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lot of ink has flowed over the question how to &lt;em&gt;define&lt;/em&gt; Hinduism. There is no other religion for which the question of definition is so difficult.  A Roman Catholic could be defined as a person who is baptized by a priest ordained within an apostolic succession going back to Jesus, and who accepts the Nicean Creed and the authority of the Bishop of Rome.  A Muslim is defined by the Muslims themselves as one who has affirmed the Islamic creed: that there is no god beside Allah and that Mohammed is Allah’s prophet.  A Buddhist is one who has taken the triple refuge into the Buddha, his teachings and his community.  But there seems to be no accepted definition of a Hindu, neither one sanctioned by Hindu tradition nor one on which the scholarly community agrees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 2. Hindus as “Indian Pagans”</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/03_ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/03_ch2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Hindus as “Indian Pagans”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1. Historical definition of “Hindu”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Hindu scriptures, the word “Hindu” is not to be found.  Yet, long before Western scholars sat down to invent definitions of “Hindu”, the term already carried a definite meaning.  The normal procedure ought to be, to listen to this original version first.  It was brought into India by the Islamic invaders, and meant: “Indian Pagan”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The term “Hindu” is the Persian equivalent of the Indo-Aryan term “Sindhu”, “river”, “the Indus”.  The equivalence is a simple application of the regular phonetic relation between the indo-Aryan and Iranian branches of the Indo-European language family: initial [&lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt;] is retained in Indo-Aryan but changed into [&lt;em&gt;h&lt;/em&gt;] in Iranian, while aspirated voiced stops like [&lt;em&gt;dh&lt;/em&gt;] are retained in Indo-Aryan but lose their aspiration in Iranian.  The Iranians used the word &lt;em&gt;Hindu&lt;/em&gt; to designate the river Sindhu and the countries and populations situated around and beyond the Sindhu.  From Persian, the Greeks borrowed the river name as Indos and the people’s name as &lt;em&gt;Indoi&lt;/em&gt;, hence English&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Indus, India, Indian&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 3. Legal definition of “Hindu”</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/04_ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/04_ch3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Legal definition of “Hindu”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.1. Hindu law&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;India’s Constitution does not give a definition of the term &lt;em&gt;Hindu&lt;/em&gt;, but it does define to whom the “Hindu Law” applies.  It has to do this because in spite of its pretence to secularism, the Indian Constitution allows Muslims, Christians and Parsis a separate Personal Law.  In a way, this separate treatment of different communities merely continues the communal autonomy of castes and sects accepted in pre-modern Hindu states, but it exposes the credibility deficit of Indian secularism.  At any rate, the situation is that Personal Law is divided on the basis of religion, and that one of the legal subsystems is called &lt;em&gt;Hindu Law&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 4. Hindutva</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/05_ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/05_ch4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Hindutva&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.1. Savarkar’s definition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ideological contours of the Hindu Mahasabha and the RSS-BJP are usually summed up in the term &lt;em&gt;Hindutva&lt;/em&gt;, literally “Hindu-ness”, meaning Hindu identity as a unifying identity transcending castewise, regional and sectarian differences within Hindu society.  The term was coined by the Freedom Fighter and later HMS president V. D. Savarkar as the title of his book &lt;em&gt;Hindutva&lt;/em&gt;, written in prison and clandestinely published in 1924.  Inspired by the doctrines of the Italian liberal nationalist Giuseppe Mazzini, he tried to give a nationalist content to the concept of Hinduness. Incidentally, non-Hindutva nationalists including Jawaharlal Nehru equally recognized the influence which Mazzini had had on their ideological orientation during their student days.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 5. “Semitization”, of Hinduism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/06_ch5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/06_ch5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. “Semitization”, of Hinduism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.1. The “Semitic religions”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the height of the Ayodhya controversy, many secularists suddenly set themselves up as teachers of Hinduism, of “real Hinduism” as opposed to the “distorted” Hinduism of the Hindu Nationalists.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) This was a crucial step forward for the Hindu cause, for it meant that Hinduism was replacing secularism as the norm.  The secularists told the Hindu activists that Hinduism is alright, only, it is something altogether different from what you think it is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 6. Are Hindu reformists Hindus?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/07_ch6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/07_ch6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Are Hindu reformists Hindus?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The historical and legal definition of “Hindus” as “Indian Pagans” is clear-cut, easy to use, and it has the law and historical primogeniture on its side.  This inclusive definition of Hinduism is eagerly used by Hindu nationalist organizations (usually in its Savarkarite “Hindutva” adaptation), but there is still a serious problem with it: a number of the people included object to the label “Hindu”. Indeed, this label is often in conflict with the self-descriptions of certain communities, particularly among the Buddhists, Jains, Sikhs and some of, the Scheduled Tribes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 7. Are Jains Hindus?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/08_ch7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/08_ch7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Are Jains Hindus?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7.1. Joins in the Minorities’ Commission&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the least vocal communities in India is the Jain community.  When the Minorities’ Commission was formed in 1978, the Jains were somehow overlooked, though Sikhs and Buddhists were invited to join.  No Jain protest was heard.  It seemed that as a prosperous business community, the Jains were not too interested in the politics of grievances, and therefore they didn’t care too much whether they were entitled to minority status.  In 1996, however, a delegation of prominent Jains submitted a memorandum to Prime Minister Deve Gowda requesting recognition of the Jain community as a religious minority.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) In 1997, the Minorities’ Commission did invite the Jains.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 8. Are Sikhs Hindus?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/09_ch8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/09_ch8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Are Sikhs Hindus?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8.1. The problem of Sikh identity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In most of the contemporary literature, Sikhism is treated as a separate religion.  The questioning of this separateness by Hindus is usually only mentioned in scornful tones, as a sign of “Hindu fundamentalist” sympathies.  Most non-specialist Western sources implicitly support Sikh separatism, at least the religious, non-territorial variety.  Thus, the cover story on India in the non-political American monthly &lt;em&gt;National Geographic&lt;/em&gt; carries a picture of a typical-looking Sikh before the Hari Mandir in Amritsar, with the caption: “The Golden Temple in Amritsar serves as the spiritual centre for the world’s 20 million Sikhs.  ‘From Hindus and Muslims have I broken free’, said Arjan Dev Ji, the fifth Sikh guru, in the 1590s.  The faith holds all people equal in the eyes of God.”^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) Of these three sentences, two are statements of support to Sikh separatism, and both are open to criticism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 9. Are Indian tribals Hindus?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/10_ch9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/10_ch9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Are Indian tribals Hindus?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9.1. “Animism”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hindu Revivalists, unlike Hindu traditionalists, agree that the so-called tribals of India are Hindus.  V.D. Savarkar wrote: “Every person is a Hindu who regards and owns this Bharat Bhumi, this land from the Indus to the seas, as his Fatherland as well as Holyland, i.e. the land of the origin of his religion (…) Consequently the so-called aboriginal or hill tribes also are Hindus: because India is their Fatherland as well as their Holyland of whatever form of religion or worship they follow.”^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 10. Are Buddhists Hindus?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/11_ch10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/11_ch10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Are Buddhists Hindus?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10.1. A polemic and a high-brow debate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now that Christians have started talking about “Jesus the Jew”, it is to be expected that Hindus and Buddhists should explore the notion “Buddha the Hindu”, or at least to highlight the Hindu foundations on which the Buddha built.  It is now fairly widely accepted that Jesus was a millennarist cult leader inside the Jewish fold who did not conceive of his own message and mission as a new religion; the question may be asked whether the Buddha was not likewise an innovator within the Hindu tradition.  But so far, that question has only been raised by the Hindu Revivalists and a lone Western scholar, certainly not by Buddhists, and to secularists the question is mere proof of evil Hindu imperialist (“boa constrictor”) designs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 11. Are neo-Buddhists- Hindus?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/12_ch11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/12_ch11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11. Are neo-Buddhists- Hindus?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11.1. The challenge of Ambedkarite neo-Buddhism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On 2 October 1956, two months before his death, the former Law Minister Dr. Bhimrao Ramji Ambedkar led several hundreds of thousands of followers, mostly belonging to his own ex-untouchable Mahar caste, into conversion to Buddhism.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) He extracted twenty-two promises from his followers.  We will list them here with their original numbers but regrouped in two categories.  The first category consists of positive expressions of commitment to the Buddhist way:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 12. General conclusion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/13_ch12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/13_ch12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12. General conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12.1. A concession to convention&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As part of their entrenched power position, the British colonisers and later their Nehruvian successors have always tried to control the discourse on religion.  Among other concerns, they have seen to it that the term “Hindu” got divorced from its historical meaning, which quite inclusively encompassed all Indian Pagans, in order to fragment Hindu society.  In parallel with their effort to pit caste against caste, they have tried to pit sect against sect, offering nurture to the egos of sect leaders by telling them that in fact they were popes in their own right of full-fledged religions, equal in status but morally superior to Hinduism.  Hindu Revivalists have countered this effort by reaffirming the basic Hindu character of tribal Animism, Jainism, Buddhism, Sikhism and more recent reformist sects.  In some cases, the separation of sects from the Hindu commonwealth was entirely contrived and artificial, in others it had a partial doctrinal justification, though even there the proper distinction was never between them and “Hinduism” as historically conceived, but between them and the Vedic-Puranic “Great Tradition” of Hinduism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Bibliography</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/14_bib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/who_is_a_hindu/14_bib/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bibliography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buddhism, Jainism, Karma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AGARWAL, C.V.: &lt;em&gt;The Buddhist and Theosophical Movements&lt;/em&gt;.  Mahabodhi Society of India, Sarnath 1993.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AHIR, D.C.: &lt;em&gt;The Pioneers of Buddhist Revival in India&lt;/em&gt;, Indian Books Centre, Delhi 1989.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-: &lt;em&gt;Heritage of Buddhism&lt;/em&gt;, B.R. Publ., Delhi 1989.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-: &lt;em&gt;How and Why Buddhism Declined in India&lt;/em&gt;. Blumoon, Delhi 1996&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-: India&amp;rsquo;s Debt to Buddhism. Blumoon, Delhi 1996.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AMBEDKAR, Bhimrao Ramji: &lt;em&gt;The Buddha and His Dhamma&lt;/em&gt;.  Siddharth Publ., Bombay 1984 (1957).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
