<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cut appalachia</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/MT/cut-appalachia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/MT/cut-appalachia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A mahAmlechCha outdoorsman mentioned wanting to spend a part of his life walking the &amp;ldquo;International Appalachian Trail&amp;rdquo;: It is staggering when we contemplate that the Appalachians, the North African Atlas mountains, the Irish and Scottish Highlands, the Highlands of Greenland and the mountains of Norway are all the same mountain range rent asunder as if by the vajra of vR^itrahan&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kant - disks</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/MT/kant_disks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/MT/kant_disks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1839498960559370622&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several proto-planetary discs imaged by the ALMA interferometer. It is remarkable that the German philosopher Immanuel Kant had come up with a theory of the origin of solar systems that broadly laid out the foundations of the modern theory of planetary origins in 1755 CE.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kant had none of the modern knowledge of our own and other solar systems. Yet he connected to something deep (inspired by the ancient Roman philosopher Lucretius Rarus) when he correctly posited the formation of structures like the protoplanetary discs directly imaged here by ALMA and the formation of planets within them. This and his thoughts on natural laws lead us to regard Kant highly among the neo-Occidental philosophers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
