<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Meta articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Meta articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cajal on flaws</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/cajal_on_flaws/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/cajal_on_flaws/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Diseases of the Will:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Neuroscience Founding Father Santiago Ramón y Cajal on the Six Psychological Flaws That Keep the Talented from Achieving Greatness&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Our neurons must be used … not only to know but also to transform knowledge;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;not only to experience but also to construct.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By Maria Popova&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Diseases of the Will: Neuroscience Founding Father Santiago Ramón y Cajal on the Six Psychological Flaws That Keep the Talented from Achieving Greatness&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math : Post rigorous</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/terry_tao_math_rigor_proofs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/terry_tao_math_rigor_proofs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: There’s more to mathematics than rigour and proofs&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Author: Terrance Tao&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;_The history of every major galactic civilization tends to pass through three distinct and recognizable phases, those of Survival, Inquiry and Sophistication, otherwise known as the How, Why, and Where phases. For instance, the first phase is characterized by the question ‘How can we eat?’, the second by the question ‘Why do we eat?’ and the third by the question, ‘Where shall we have lunch?’ ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Douglas_Adams&#34;&gt;Douglas Adams&lt;/a&gt;, “&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Hitchhiker%27s_Guide_to_the_Galaxy&#34;&gt;The Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy&lt;/a&gt;“ )&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nature on Sci Hub India case</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/nature_on_sci-hub-india-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/nature_on_sci-hub-india-case/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sci-Hub, the popular website that offers access to millions of pirated research papers and books, is no stranger to legal action. But, for the first time, the site is defending its operations in court, in a copyright case filed in India by a group of major publishers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a lawsuit presented in Delhi’s high court, the American Chemical Society, Elsevier and Wiley say that the site infringes their copyright, and ask the court to instruct Internet service providers in India to block access to it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parapsychology - Control Group</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/parapsychology_control-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/parapsychology_control-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://slatestarcodex.com/2014/04/28/the-control-group-is-out-of-control/?comments=false&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Allan Crossman calls parapsychology &lt;a href=&#34;http://lesswrong.com/lw/1ib/parapsychology_the_control_group_for_science/&#34;&gt;the control group for science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That is, in let’s say a drug testing experiment, you give some people the drug and they recover. That doesn’t tell you much until you give some other people a placebo drug you know doesn’t work – but which they themselves believe in – and see how many of them recover. That number tells you how many people will recover whether the drug works or not. Unless people on your real drug do significantly better than people on the placebo drug, you haven’t found anything.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practicing western science</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/practicing_western_science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/practicing_western_science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Practising Western Science outside the West: Personal Observations on the Indian Scene&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Arnab Rai Choudhuri&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Social Studies of Science, Vol. 15, No. 3. (Aug., 1985)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;DISCUSSION PAPER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;reader-notes&#34;&gt;Reader notes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So much of this paper rang true even regarding my own experience as a grad student in USA 2007-10. Suhas mentions: &amp;ldquo;(This) has had a great influence on me, and several others (like Vishvas) that I have shared it with. Thank you for giving me the right perspective towards science at an early stage in my scientific training.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Science - strong-link-problem</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/science_strong-link-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/science_strong-link-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.experimental-history.com/p/science-is-a-strong-link-problem&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two kinds of problems in the world: strong-link problems and weak-link problems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I originally heard these terms on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pushkin.fm/podcasts/revisionist-history/my-little-hundred-million&#34;&gt;this podcast&lt;/a&gt; discussing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Numbers-Game-Everything-About-Soccer/dp/0143124560&#34;&gt;this book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Weak-link problems are problems where the overall quality depends on how good the &lt;em&gt;worst&lt;/em&gt; stuff is. You fix weak-link problems by making the weakest links stronger, or by eliminating them entirely.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Food safety, for example, is a weak-link problem. You don’t want to eat anything that will kill you. That’s why it makes sense for the Food and Drug Administration to inspect processing plants, to set standards, and to ban dangerous foods. The upside is that, for example, any frozen asparagus you buy can only have “&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fda.gov/food/ingredients-additives-gras-packaging-guidance-documents-regulatory-information/food-defect-levels-handbook#commodities&#34;&gt;10% by count of spears or pieces infested with 6 or more attached asparagus beetle eggs and/or sacs&lt;/a&gt;.” The downside is that you don’t get to eat the supposedly delicious &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Casu_martzu&#34;&gt;casu marzu&lt;/a&gt;, a Sardinian cheese with live maggots inside it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selectivity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/selectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/selectivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;S.K. Belvalkar&amp;rsquo;s advice to the great Prakrit scholar A.N. Upadhye (August 21, 1939):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just one word of caution from an elder colleague in the line: anantapāram kila sabda-śāstram, and at your age and with your energy there is the temptation to attempt everything. It often leads to a crop of unfinished projects, which weigh heavily upon you as you approach the end of your journey. Please therefore do choose the very best and the highest that you want to achieve and just concentrate upon that. Let the lesser works be left severely alone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
