<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;PART-III The Conflagration on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;PART-III The Conflagration on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 THE FIGHT IN DELHI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/01_THE_FIGHT_IN_DELHI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/01_THE_FIGHT_IN_DELHI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AFTER declaring her Independence on the 11th of May, the city of Delhi had been busy in organising the wild storm, that such a bold step has raised into a systematised revolution. By restoring the Emperor of Delhi to the ancient throne of the Moguls, the citizens of Delhi had already created a nucleus mighty enough, by the very prestige of its name, to sustain the struggle of a people&amp;rsquo;s liberation. But this restoration of the old Mogul was a restoration, neither to the old power nor to the old prestige, nor to the old traditions. Though the raising of the old Bahadur Shah to the Emperirship of Hindusthan was, in a narrower sense, a restoration to him of his ancient throne, still in a wider and truer sense, it was no restoration at all. For, the Mogul dynasty of old was not chosen by the people of the land. It was thrust upon India by sheer force, difnified by the name of conquest, and upheld by a powerful pack of alien adventures and native selfseekers. It was not this throne that was restored to Bahadur Shah today. No, that would have been impossible; for, such thrones are conquered and not received. That would have been suicidal; for, then, it would have been in vain that the blood of hundreds of Hindu martyrs had been shed in the three or four centuries preceding. Ever since the rising power of Islam left its native wilds of Arabisthan and went conquering East and West, irresistible and unchallenged, country after country and people after people had been made to prostrate in submission of Islam. But the unopposed wave was opposed, for the first time in the land of Bharat, with such strenuous, uncompromising, and undaunted tenacity as could be found only very rarely&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 HAVELOCK</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/02_HAVELOCK/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/02_HAVELOCK/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WHEN the Sikh Sepoys delivered the Allahabad fort into the hands of the English, instead of into the hands of the Revolutionaries, the English made it a base of operations on their side. There was now no longer the danger of having to carry on all civil and military operations in the North India from a distant centre like Calcutta. Lond Canning decided to shift the capital itself to Allahabad until the Revolution was suppressed and, accordingly, he came in a few days to reside at Allahabad. But, in the meanwhile, came the news of the miserable plight of the English at Cawnpore and their piteous cries for help. General Neill, therefore, kept a small army for protection at Allahabad and sent the rest under Major Renaud to raise the siege of Cawnpore. This deatchment marched on burning villages indiscriminately, on their way. Just then, Havelock was appointed to the command of the Cawnpore army in place of Neill. He arrived at Allahabad towards the end of June. He was a trained and an experienced officer. Fortunately for the English, the war with Persia came to an end about the time when the revolution actually broke out, and the whole English army, under good commanders like Havelock, arrived in India just at the time when they were very badly wanted. Though Neill was extremely chagrined to find that Havelock superseded him as the chief officer at Allahabad and that he had to be under him, he did not allow his private feelings to come in the way of the welfare of his country&amp;rsquo;s rule in India. He made vigorous efforts towards the equipment of the army. He gave every help to the army which was to be commanded by Havelock, made all arrangements as to the commissiariat, and quietly handed over the charge of the troops to Havelock when the latter officer arrived. This army was now fully prepared to go to the assistance of the English at Cawnpore. Havelock was eager to start, when suddenly news came that Sir Hugh Wheeler was defeated and had surrendered and that all the Englishmen, including him, had been massacred on the banks of the Ganges!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 BEHAR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/03_BEHAR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/03_BEHAR/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE province of Behar and its capital, Patna, did not remain aloof from the wave of Revolution which was sweeping over the North- Western Provinces, Allahabad, Agra, and Bengal. Of the different districts in the province, the chief towns were Gaya, Arrah, Chapra, Motihari, and Muzzafferpore. The army to control the province was stationed near Patna, in the town of Danapur. There was the 7th, 8th, and 40th native infantry and, to keep these in check, there were the European artillery and a European regiment, all under the command of Major-General Lloyd; besides, there was the 12th native cavalry regiment under Major Holmes stationed near by, at Sigwali.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 DELHI FALLS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/04_DELHI_FALLS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/04_DELHI_FALLS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WHEN the third chief commander of the English army before Delhi became hopeless of taking the town and resigned, Brigadier-General Wilson replaced him. At that time, in the camp of the English army maddened by the attacks of the Revolutionaries, it was seriously discussed, in despair, whether the siege should be raised. It is difficult to say what would have been the course of the Revolution of 1857 if this plan had been resolved upon. Still, it is clear that this one movement on the part of the English would have harmed their cause more than many defeats at the hands of the Revolutionaries. The English had a strategic advantage in thus besieging the town of Delhi, because the Revolutionary army was shut up there in one place. If that vast host had spread over the province instead of being thus bottled up and had harassed the English after forming small detachments everywhere, this guerilla warfare would have soon reduced the small English force to impotence. But Delhi being besieged, the battlefield was restricted, the English force had not to put up with an unbearable strain, and the Revolutionaries were inconveniently huddled up together in one city and thus were more liable to attack. In these circumstances, to raise the siege of Delhi was to break the dam and let the Revolutionary forces inundate the whole country. Even if Delhi were captured, the Sepoys would no doubt have spread all around. But there was a vast difference between driving them out of Delhi, defeated and dejected, and making them elated by raising the siege and allowing them to fall upon the English. Though the English commander thoroughly understood this difference, despair, discouragement, and the fierce onslaughts of the Revolutionaries made him think of raising the siege. At that moment, the English power in India hung in the balance. It was, indeed, fortunate for the English that there was, at this time, a bold and desperately courageous officer like Baird-Smith in the&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 LUCKNOW</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/05_LUCKNOW/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/05_LUCKNOW/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ON the day on which the Revolutionaries were successful in the battle of Chinhat, the English power in Oudh came to an end and the revolt had openly assumed the form of a national Revolution. The Sepoys, princes, and people began by establishing a ruler liked by them on the vacant throne of Lucknow. The anarchy which raged everywhere for the space of a week after the battle of Chinhat had to be first suppressed before preparations for war could be made. Therefore, the Revolutionaries set themselves to the task of administration at Lucknow, though the week&amp;rsquo;s interval gave an opportunity to the English of fortifying their defences. The late Nabob of Lucknow, Wajid Ali Shah, being a prisoner of the English at Calcutta, they unanimously elected and placed on the throne his son, Prince Birjis Kadir. This Birjis Kadar being a minor, the regency of the kingdom of Oudh was given in the hands of his mother, Queen Hazrat Mahal. As in the palace of Delhi, on account of the extreme old age of Emperor Bahadur Shah, the affairs of state were looked after by Begum Zinat Mahal in the Emperor&amp;rsquo;s name, so in the palace at Lucknow, the Nabob being a minor, the Government depended on his mother, Begum Hazrat Mahal. This Begum of Oudh, thought not quite another Lakshmi Bai, was undoubtedly a great organiser, full of love of liberty and the spirit of daring. She had perfect confidence in an Omrah (nobleman) of the court, called Mahbub Khan. She appointed various officers to the judicial, revenue, police, and military departments. These officers selected were such as were loved and honoured by the representatives of the Sepoys, by Mahbub Khan and other leaving Sirdars, and also by the large numbers of the people who hurried from all parts of Oudh to Lucknow to join in the great War of Independence. Every day, a Durbar was held to discuss political affairs, and there, the Begum Sahiba exercised authority in the name of the Nabob. The news that Oudh&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 TATIA TOPE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/06_TATIA_TOPE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/06_TATIA_TOPE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WHEN the army of the &amp;ldquo;mutineers&amp;rdquo; had been defeated at Cawnpore on the 16th of July, Srimant Nana left Cawnpore and proceeded to Brahmavarta. That night - the 16th of July - was spent by Nana in his palace there, in deliberation as to his future plans; and the very next morning saw Nana Sahib approaching the boats waiting on the river Ganges with his youngest brother Bala Sahib, his nephew Rao Sahib, his aide-de-camp Tatia Tope, with all the ladies belonging to the royal household, and with his treasure and a few supplies. Nana was going to Fatehpur in the Lucknow province. Choudhuri Bhopal Singh, an intimate friend of Nana Sahib, received them there very cordially and entertained them in his house. While Havelock with all his army was besieging Cawnpore and was thinking of pressing on to Lucknow, Nana also was deliberating in full Durbar as to the best means of opposing Havelock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 THE FALL OF LUCKNOW</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/07_THE_FALL_OF_LUCKNOW/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/07_THE_FALL_OF_LUCKNOW/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AFTER thus stemming the fierce tide of Tatia&amp;rsquo;s progress at Cawnpore, Sir Colin started reconquering the other portions of the country that had risen. Seaton had been marching slowly, &amp;lsquo;paficying&amp;rsquo; provionces on the way, and had now come down to Aligarh. So now Walpole was sent by Kalpi road to accomplish the same task for all the territory from Aligarh to Cawnpore. Walpole was to march upwards from Cawnpore and Seaton was to go downwards from Aligarh; they were to meet at Minpuri; and, thus, all the tract of the Doab along the Jumna was to be reconquered. While this was being done, Sir Colin was to march towards Fatehgarh from Cawnpore. Such was the plan of operations. It was thought that the Doab Revolutionaries would be pressed back by the English army and would eventually enter Fatehgrah. And hence it was decided that the closing finale of the operations should be conducted and a great battle should be fought near Fatehgarh, where the three armies of Walpole, Seaton, and Campbell were to meet after the close of their individual operations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 KUMAR SINGH AND AMAR SINGH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/08_KUMAR_SINGH_AND_AMAR_SINGH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/08_KUMAR_SINGH_AND_AMAR_SINGH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HUNTED out of the valleys of Jagadishpur by General Eyre, Kumar Singh, the old but energetic lion of the territory of Shahabad was roaming restlessly but always on the alert for every chance to spring at the neck of those who had deprived him of his liberty. Under his banner had united his brother Amar Singh and two other chiefs, Nisswar Singh and Jawan Singh. They were now lying in wait in the forests. With them were their beloved wives, heroic women, but ready to join in the fight, combing their hair not with the delicate combs of the Zenana but with sharp arrows, flourishing in their delicately fashioned hands, &amp;ldquo;tenderer than the very flower,&amp;rdquo; the flashing Damascus blade, &amp;ldquo;harder than adamant.&amp;rdquo; They were, also, waiting to drink the blood of the enemy! To drink the blood of the enemy, we say again; for, old as Kumar Singh was and proudly insolent as his opponent was, the ambition of Kumar Singh was nothing short of drinking the enemy&amp;rsquo;s blood! For, though &amp;ldquo;reduced to extremities with hunger, besieged by age, - a picture of hard misery, with no position, and courting death,&amp;rdquo; as the lion of the famous poem, our Kumar was still the king of the forest! And, therefore, whatever the reverses, how would he eat the dead grass of slavery? His ambition was - one ambition alone could be the ambition of the lion of the poem referred to - to break open, with his steel-claws, the skull of the elephant!&#xA;With the land belonging to his family for generations as far as your memory could go now usurped by the stranger with his very palace of Jagadishpur in the hands of the foreigner, and his temples and images pulled down by the desecrating hands of the enemy, Kumar Singh did not show any excitement. He did not make a dash for Jagadishpur, nor did he persist in holding Shahabad. His capital was strictly guarded by the English and his army was small - only a thousand and two hundred Sepoys and five hundred untrained volunteers. He did not show, therefore, the least anxiety to recover his capital immediately. But his great desire was to hold aloft the bright golden banner of the War of Independence! The very day that he gave up Jagadishpur without serious resistance - that very day he had made up his mind to take to a different mode of warfare altogether. That mode of warfare is the one mode that goes farthest to secure success in any War of Independence. It is guerilla warfare.&#xA;Therefore, enraged as he was at the loss of his capital, Kumar Singh sent not his army against the enemy, for then his soldiers would have perished like moths before the rushing enemy; but he moved quietly into the forests of West Behar and along the river Shon, carefully nothing the weak points of the enemy. In the meanwhile, news reached him that troops, Nepalese and English, were being sent from Azimgarh into Oudh to destroy Lucknow. As soon as with his keen scent he scented the prey, the lion of Jagadishpur took one leap out of the forest. Unlike those who would still, in fallen days, hover round their capital without the least chance, and unlike those weak persons who give way completely to passion and emotion to console themselves, our Kumar Singh was the very genius of guerilla warfare. Though the British army was marching on to Lucknow, they still had an eye on Jagadishpur, where his activities might be expected to be centred. Kumar Singh, therefore, postponed indefinitely his operations there and started for eastern Oudh, to make one spring for that part where the British army was weakest, hoping to surprise Azimgarh by uniting together all the revolutionaries that were scattered in eastern Oudh, and then to make a dash, if victorious, on Benares or even Allahabad and, thus, to avenge the Jagadishpur insult. On the 18th of March 1858, even the Revolutionaries of Beeva joined him; and the united armies encamped near the fort in Atrolia.&#xA;Azimgarh is twenty - five miles&amp;rsquo; run from Atrolia. Learning that Kumar Singh was so near, Milman marched on Atrolia with three hundred infantry and horse and two guns. Before the morning rays of the sun of the 22nd of March had lighted the field of Atrolia, the vanguards of Milman and of the Revolutionaries were within sight of each other. Milman gave them not even a moment&amp;rsquo;s time to recover themselves, taken aback as they seemed to be by the sudden appearance of the British troops. He began the fight at once. But, of course, how long could the Revolutionaries fight against the British? They were soon totally defeated. What an ending to the vainglorious boast of Kumar Singh! All glory to the British army which showed such fine front even after the all-night march of the previous day. Ye have earned your breakfast, British soldiers, by the sweat of your brow, nay, by the free flow of blood from your bodies; so, enjoy your breakfast, with your commanders, in the cool share of the mango groved! The rays of the morning sun are welcoming you, gay because of the great victory earned so lately. Arms were arranged all around, breakfast was ready, the hungry mouths were chewing the first morsel; the cups of drink were filled ready, - and then!&#xA;Boom, boom! What is up? The cups are dashed down from the lips, the morsels of food have slipped off the mouths, the breakfast dishes are shattered and, instead the army has to take up the arms only this hour laid down with a sense of relief! Has Kumar Singh come after all? Yes, yes! Kumar Singh has descended like a thunderbolt upon the English, who had been contemplating with delight their supposed victory. As soon as Milman was completely enticed into the security of a false victory, the hero - old in age but youthful in spirit – came out of the fort of Atrolia and smiled with contempt at the prey, now completely his. Malleson says: &amp;ldquo;What more could a general long for? Everything was in his favour. Kumar Singh, then, marched to a victory which he deemed assured. The imagination can almost picture him making to the confidant by his side an exclamation near akin to that which burst from the lips of Wellington when he noticed the false&#xA;movement of Marmont which brought on the battle of Salamanca! Mon cher Alva, Marmont est perdu!&amp;ldquo;42 Still Milman struggled to escape and marched on with bondness, hoping to frighten Kumar Singh by keeping up a good and steady attack. But a regular shower of bullets was kept on from the avenues of sugarcane, from the trees of the mango grove, and from the mud—banks everywhere. The army of Kumar Singh numbered five on six times that the Milman and, seeing that his enemy threatened to surround him completely, Milman was obliged to stop weakly in the midst of his hold attack. This weakness increased the determination of Kumar Singh to surround him. Now the British army, frightened and almost suffocated, began to fall back. Now began the wolf-like warfare of Kumar Singh&amp;rsquo;s troops, moving forward to shoot at stray soldiers and the flanks of the enemy. The temporary triumph did not turn Kumar Singh&amp;rsquo;s head. He did not attack unitedly the retreating troops of the enemy; for, he knew well the nature of the troops under him. He could not be sure how long they would have held on in a hand to hand fight. Hence, shrewd as he was, he determined only to continue the guerilla tactics. He drove the army of the enemy, hunting them from Atrolia straight to their camp at Kosilla.&#xA;But the British army was destined not to get a safe refuge even in the Kosilla camp. Already the news of the defeat of the army had reached there and the Indian servants had left with their oxen and everything else that was in their keeping. No servants ahead, no provisions near, with Kumar Singh&amp;rsquo;s army preying on the stray unfortunates like wolves, Milman began his retreat leaving the camp behind him. Kumar Singh pursued - pursued even after he had taken complete possession of everything the enemy had, and hunted the British army and the miserable Milman from Kosilla right up to Azimgarh. At Azimgarh, Milman’s hopes revived again! For, there he had aid of three hundred and fifty fresh forces from Benares and Ghazipur, who had come in response to his express message. Colonel&#xA;42 Malleson&amp;rsquo;s Indian Mutiny, Vol. IV, p. 319&#xA;Dames was the commander of the united forces. With a strong base like Azimgarh, with the British army reinforced to double the former number, with Colonel Dames to lead them – they determined to take revenge for the temporary defeat, come what might!&#xA;So Colonel Dames set out from Azimgarh resolving to revenge himself on Kumar Singh on the 28th of March. He thought he had his revenge, for he was victorious over Kumar Singh; but it was only to find the old game repeated again, perhaps better than before. The fresh soldiers with their fresh commander got such a sound bearing that Colonel Dames ran from the field right to Azimgarh and took refuge within the fortifications of the city. No one now&#xA;even spoke of attacking Kumar afresh. Kumar now entered Azimgarh and leaving the work of annihilating the few Englishmen in the fortifications to a few of his followers - and to famine - he pushed on triumphant to Benares!&#xA;The governor-general who, as we have said before, was now at Allahabad, was filled with terror, now that the lion had opened wide his jaws. &amp;ldquo;Knowing what sort of a man Kumar Singh was, that he possessed audacity and courage, and that he knew the value of time in military operations, Lord Canning realised at once the danger of the situation.&amp;ldquo;43 He who had just imprisoned the English forces at Azimgarh and, having marched with wonderful rapidity the eighty-one miles of the way, had threatened to cut off Allahabad from Calcutta by attacking the city of Benares, he - the Rana Kumar Singh, reinforced as he now was by the Sepoys flying away after the defeat at Lucknow and knowing full well the art of keeping together and in discipline even such demoralised forces as he had, was not to be lightly treated by Lord Canning. It was owing to the firm grip on the cities of Allahabad and Benares which the English could maintain through the loyalty of the Sikhs in the first part of the mutiny, that&#xA;43 Malleson&amp;rsquo;s Indian Mutiny, Vol. IV, page 321. .&#xA;the rebellion was nipped in the bug in the provinces round Calcutta; and when it seemed the design of Kumar Singh to catch again the lost opportunity by dashing on Benares and Allahabad, Lord Canning ordered Lord Mark Kerr himself to march on this &amp;lsquo;rebel&amp;rsquo; chief in all haste.&#xA;Lord Mark Kerr, well known in the Crimean campaigns and well experienced in Indian military matters, marched off at once with five hundred men and eight guns and arrived within eight miles of Azimgarh. After a little rest, he started onwards on the morning of the 6th of April. At about six o’clock in the morning, he learnt that Kumar Singh’s men had been watching his progress. But pretending ignorance of this fact, he ordered his army to advance in readiness and at once commenced the attack on Kumar’s left flank. No sooner did the English commence the attack than Kumar’s left began a veritable shower of bullets on the enemy. On that day, the old Kumar was seen fighting lightning-like in the thick of the battle, seated on his favourite white horse. Knowing full well that the strength of his army was not so much in their number which was simply swelled as a threat to the enemy by allowing all sorts of camp-followers to enter the fighting ranks, Kumar Singh solely relied upon his own skill and courage and intrepidity.&#xA;He spread out his force to attack Lord Mark Kerr on his flanks. The guns of the enemy were vomiting fire upon him and he had no guns to silence them, still did he succeed in bringing his army right to the rear of Lord Mark! This movement upset the plan of the enemy so totally that their guns had to fall back; and this was the signal for the Revolutionaries to rush forward with a triumphant war-cry. Kumar Singh had, by this time, tightened his grip on the English rear so firmly that the English elephants began to run amock, the conductors on them lost all hope of life and clung round their necks with both hands, and the servants and all began to run wheresoever they found a way. Yet Mark Kerr said &amp;ldquo;Let us hold on for a while - victory might still be ours!&amp;rdquo; He had captured some houses on the Revolutionaries&amp;rsquo; front, while they had totally routed his rear.Thus was this&#xA;strange battle fought. In the beginning, the front of Kumar was opposed to the front of the English army and now the rear of the British army is opposed to the front of Kumar; now he has even set the rear of the enemy on fire! When Mark Kerr saw the rear surrounded in flames of fire, he dedtermined to leave the battlefield and began to press on to Azimgarh. For, if not victory, at least the secondary purpose of carrying succour to Azimgarh should be accomplished if possible. His guns did him a splendid service, specially as Kumar Singh had none with him. At midnight, Lord Mark brought his army to Azimgarh. About this battle and the strategic movements and errors of Kumar Singh and the difficulties under which he laboured, Malleson says :- &amp;ldquo;That leader had showed himself greater as a strategist than a tactician. His plan of campaign was admirable but, in carrying it into execution, he committed many serious errors. Milman gave him a great, an unexpected opportunity. He had that officer at his mercy. When Milman&amp;rsquo;s men were waiting for their breakfast in the mango grove near Atrolia, it was in the power of Kumar Singh to cut them off from Azimgarh. He preferred to attack them in front. Then, when he had forced him to fall back, he did not press the pursuit with sufficient vigour. A capable commander would still have cut them off. Once having seen them housed in Azimgarh, he should have left a portion of his force to blockade them, pressed on with the remainder towards Benares, and occupied a position in which he could have engaged Lord Mark Kerr with advantage. He had at his disposal, it subsequently transpired, about twelve thousand men. To oppose these the few men led by Lord Mark were alone available. Everything was within his grasp had he dared to stretch out his hand. The chances are that, capable man as he was, he saw all this. But he was not supreme master of the situation. Every petty leader who had brought his contingent to serve under him wished to dictate a programme. The counsels of the rebels tended, then, almost always to a compromise.&amp;ldquo;44&#xA;44 Malleson&amp;rsquo;s Indian Mutiny, Vol. IV, pages 326-327.&#xA;But Lord Mark Kerr was baulked not only of his victory but even of this secondary purpose of relieving Azimgarh. For still the whole city was in the hands of the Revolutionaries who had also a perfect hold of the whole surrounding province. A born commander is he who knows exactly the nature and capacities of his forces. Few men could have excelled Kumar Singh in this necessary quality of a commander. As he had correctly gauged the power and strength of his enemy, even so he measured the merits and demerits of his own followers. Therefore is it that he did not try at all to attack and carry the fortress in which the English had taken refuge. He had closely observed the fact that the Sepoys, for whatever reasons or panic it might be, were ready to undergo any other ordeal but that of facing the English bayonets - a fact which had been clearly demonstrated in both the sieges of Arrah and Lucknow. Therefore, having rendered it difficult for the English forces to come out of the besieged fortress, he began to plan in his daring heart quite another scheme of worsting his enemy. In the forces of the Revolutionaries that had entered the field in 1857, it was clearly seen that there were men of two different temperaments - the one class, who would throw themselves right in the jaws of death with unflinching and firm and disciplined resistance on the battle-field, whether opposed to the cannon or the bayonet of the foe; the other who, possessing the will to die for the nation but lacking in the courage to carry it into effect, would flinch back and get routed at the very moment when they ought to have stood unmoved. Out of these two sorts of men, Kumar Singh collected those who belonged to the&#xA;first sort and had proved immovable in the field, and organised them into a separate band of chosen veterans. Having made this selection and created a body on whom he could depend for any adventure however difficult, Kumar Singh became ready to put into execution the daring scheme which he had set his heart upon, and ordered his newly selected veteran band to stand on the bridge of the Tanu river.&#xA;For, it was by this little bridge that a British general, named Lugard, was marching ahead to relieve the English forces at Azimgarh. Lugard first, and most naturally, thought that the object of this Revolutionary band in contesting the passage of the bridge was simply to preserve the grip of the Revolutionaries on the city of Azimgarh. “But”, says Malleson, “the wily chieftain had matured plans far deeper than even those about him could fathom.” This unfathomable plan of the wily chieftain was to deceive the enemy by a false show of holding&#xA;Azimgarh at any cost, to fix their whole attention there on that spot and, while they were thus completely beguiled there, to march off straight on to Jagadishpur. This scheme was matchless in its military widsom. To march off from Azimgarh to Ghazipur, thence to jump into the Ganges, to cross it, to press on, and to reconquer Jagadishpur - all this in spite of the pursuing force of Lugard at the rear and in the face of the deluded English force of Arrah in front! It was for the execution of this very bold plan that he ordered his veteran band to guard the bridge of the river Tanu. His orders to those veterans were to hold the bridge against the attacks of Lugard till the other division of his forces had time to leave Azimgarh and escaping the vigilance of the English, to take the road leading to Ghazipur. If once he reached Ghazipur and crossed the Ganges, the lion would be back again into his native forests of Jagadishpur, and the English must re-enact the whole drama right anew, as all that they had done during the previous twelve months would be as if not done at all.&#xA;But to succeed in all these plans depends upon your bravery, O soldiers on the bridge of the Tanu! You must not allow the British forces under Lugard to step upon this bridge till the whole army of Kumar Singhhas gone out of the range of the enemy&amp;rsquo;s sight! You have been selected by your chief in the brief that you alone would rise equal to the occasion. May your bravery not belie his confidence! Let one thought, one determination, one vow alone be yours, namely, not to let the enemy capture this bridge till Kumar Singh had led off in safety his whole force out of the&#xA;sight of the duped enemy! As Baji Deshpande, the Mahratta soldier, held out in the famous gorge of Pavankhind till Shri Shivaji could reach the fort of Rangana in safety, even so fight on hard and hot till Kumar&amp;rsquo;s order is carried out to the letter, his forces saves and his confidence vindicated! Lugard, too led assaults after assaults on his handful of the Revolutionary band as often as Fazul did against the Mahratta, but he could not gain a foot-hold on the bridge even for a second. Every charge of the English was firmly and vigorously repulsed by the Revolutionary forces who were defending it. Till Kumar Singh signalled to them his safe departure from Azimgarh and his successful march on the way to Ghazipur, the veteran band held this bridge, contesting it inch by inch! Col. Malleson says, &amp;ldquo;They held the bridge of boats with a resolution and perseverence worthy of veterans, and it was not until they had by their long residence ensured the safety of their comrades, that they fell back.&amp;ldquo;45 Thus, the brave band accomplished its mission, fell back with perfect order, and, as settled, succeeded in rejoining their chief, Raja Kumar Singh.&#xA;Seeing the suggen evacuation of the bridge, Lugard rushed on, but found, to his utter dismay, the magic-like disappearance of the whole army of Kumar Singh, as if it never was there! So to pursue and find out this invisible force, he despatched a detachment of European cavalry and a horse battery. Twelve miles did they gallop on; yet, Kumar singh could not be found - and when found at last, he was found in such a strong position as to make it impossible to distinguish who was the pursuer and who the pursued! It was not the Revolutionaries who were frightened at the sight of the foe but it was the English forces who seemed to have lost their balance at the sight of the Revolutionaries. Kumar Singh&amp;rsquo;s army was drawn up in battle array, with their swords unsheathed and with their guns pointed at the enemy. One of the English officers engaged in this fight says, &amp;ldquo;It was all we could do to hold our own against such odds. Immediately our cavalry&#xA;45 Malleson&amp;rsquo;s Indian Mutiny, Vol. IV, page 330.&#xA;charged, they stood and formed square and used to abuse and tell us to come on.&amp;rdquo; And, when the English did go on, they received them with such a hot welcome that many soldiers and even officers on the side of the English fell dead. The squares of Kumar&amp;rsquo;s forces remained impenetrable, and the English were completely thrown on the defensive. After this engagement, Kumar Singh pursued his march and was approaching nearer and nearer to the banks of the Ganges!&#xA;News of the ill-success of the English pursuing force reached Azimgarh. The British general, Douglas, started with five or six more guns and came to their aid. Douglas had already tasted the sharpness of Kumar&amp;rsquo;s sword, and so he came on with circumspect steps as far as the&#xA;village Naghai, in pursuit of the Raja. There also the Raja was quite ready. When the forces were within striking distance, Kumar Singh led on his veteran band to face the foe and again ordered them to fight on till the signal should come, and, dividing the remaining forces into two parts, he despatched them onwards by two different routes to the banks of the Ganges. While these movements were secretly being carried out, the veteram band kept up a vigorous fight with the enemy, in spite of the lack of gund to reply to the hot fire of the enemy’s artillery which was mowing them down like grass. They wavered not, nor did their ranks break up, nor did their charge flag in the least! For our miles this living battle pressed on! At last, when the army of the enemy showed signs of exhaustion, the two divisions of Kumar Sing’s army, until now going by different routes, united together and the whole force marched unhampered, and Raja Kumar Singh was again marching nearer and nearer towards the banks of the Ganges! This exhausted British force passed the night of the 17th of April near the village of Athusi. Early in the morning, Douglas, thinking he had given no start to the Revolutionary forces, ordered a march again - only to find that Kumar Singh was already thirteen miles ahead to him. The whole of the British horse and the British artillery had been pursuing Kumar Singh; but, as the British infantry, through total exhaustion, were unable to proceed further, they were given rest for another night. The scouts of Kumar Singh were matchless in bringing him all detailed information about the enemy&amp;rsquo;s plans and whereabouts. They did not fail to inform him of their exhausted condition. At this, the old general stood up, determined to take full advantage of this chance and, with his force, the octogenarian chief recommenced the march in the midnight and came straightway to Sikandarpur, reached the river Ghogra, crossed it, and entered the province of Ghazipur. He presseed on right up to the village of Manohar, and there ordered a temporary rest to the now tired, worn-out, and hungry forces which had so bravely responded to the intrepid will of their patriotic chief. It was humanly impossible to avoid stopping here, though Kumar Singh knew full well that the poosition was rather a weak one. When Doughlas heard that Kumar had gained a start over him, he started in hot pursuit and eventually reached Manohar soon after Kumar Singh. He began the attack immediately and, as the Revolutionaries were tired on account of their long and continuous marching, their stand was feeble and they lost the battle, losing also many elephants and ammunition and food supplies. But Kumar Singh&amp;rsquo;s heart and will remained as much unconquered and unconquerable as ever. For, no sooner he was the signs of a crushing defeat than he put into execution the same tactics that he had hitherto been pursuing. He divided his troops into small bands and, as each division effected its retreat from the losing battle-field by a different route, the pursuit of the enemy was frustrated. Kumar had given the captains of the different bands definite instructions to meet at a pre-arranged place at a fixed hour, and lo, when the hour struck, Kumar Singh&amp;rsquo;s forced had come together and were ready for their march. This place where they met was so completely hidden from the enemy that the victory of the English was altogether barren of any result, and so the English commander had to stop at the village of Manohar itself to ascertain the whereabouts of Kumar Singh&amp;rsquo;s army, while Kumar Singh and his forces were all the while marching nearer and nearer to the banks of the Ganges!&#xA;Nearer and nearer to the banks of the Ganges! Nay, now, he has won the terrible race and actually reached the banks of the Ganges. The English forces were also close upon his rear. But, as his forces were now greatly reduced, he decided that it was not wise to fight the enemy and so he now pursued quite diffeent tactics. He spread a rumour all over the province that, owing to the scarcity of boats, his forces were going to cross the Ganges on the baks of&#xA;elephants somewhere near a place called Balita. The English scouts brought the news to the general who must have felt triumphant of the efficiency of his intelligence department! How can now this rebel chief succeed in crossing the Ganges when my scouts have enabled me to know the exact place where he intends to cross the river? - He is doomed to be drowned along with his elephants! So, the British general, with his white forces, went to Balila and kept himself in concealment, elephants of Kumar Singh as soon as they would appear. Brave soldiers! Enjoying all the while the sweet prospects of success, conceal yourself near Balila till the looked for enemy comes! There, seven miles below this very spot, is Kumar Singhh actually crossing the river Ganges! Having duped the English by the story of the elephants and Balila, the Raja got together as many boats as he wanted and, from the Ghat of Shivapur, he began to the scaret Bhagirathi at night.The duped foe, awaked to this fact, got extremely irritated and, hurriedly marching from Balila, reached Shivapur and even succeeded in capturing a boat belonging to Raja - but that was the last boat! The whole army had already been sent on the other side and in a minute or two the chieftain too, having supervised the crossing of the army, would have crossed the river himself. But, alas! What a calamity this one moment has brought with it! While this hero of the nation, the pride of chivalry, the sword of Liberty - Rana Kumar Singh was in the middle of the stream, a bullet shot from the enemy&amp;rsquo;s gun entered his wrist! But old as he was, the octogenarian leader did not mind it at all! And when amputation was deemed necessary, with his own hand - the hand that was not wounded - Kumar Singh unsheathed his&#xA;sword, lopped off the wounded arm at the elbow, and threw it into the sacred Ganges saying, &amp;ldquo;Accept thou, Mother, this last sacrifice of a loving son!&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Though innumerable are the people who have addressed the Ganges as Mother, it is Kumar - this brave son of Ganga, and such as he, that make the motherhood of the sacred Ganges fruitful and glorious. As the poet says, innumerable are the stars that are in the sky; but, it is the moon alone that adorns it and makes it lovely!&#xA;After offering this sacrifice to the Mother Ganges, this distinguished son succeeded in crossing the river without further trouble from the English army. The enemy, on the other hand, like a hunter whose prey is escaped out of his reach, unable to cross the river, stopped there with their pride wounded and mission unaccomplished. The lion, now triumphant by freeing itself from the hunter&amp;rsquo;s nets and lances, again rushed into his native forests of Shahabad, came to Jagadishpur and, on the 22nd of April, re-entered this his old capital. It was from this capital that he was hunted out eight months back. Once more now, in the palace of&#xA;Jagadishpur is ruling the prince of Jagadishpur. His brother, Amar Singh, who had collected together a force of patriotic peasants and villagers even before Kumar Singh had crossed the Ganges, now joined him. The brave Kumar ordered out in divisions these united forces to guard the capital on all sides, while he too, as intrepid and unexhausted as ever, took again to warfare.&#xA;The entrance into Jagadishpur was so sudden and dashing that the British forces at Arrah which had been kept there for the express purpose of watching Jagadishpur had no notice of Kumar Singh&amp;rsquo;s descent on Arrah. Thus outwitted, Le Grand, the British general at Arrah, became wild at the discovery of this his enemy&amp;rsquo;s triumph. What audacity that this rebel chief should give the slip to all the British forces in East Oudh, should enter&#xA;Jagadishpur, and even begin to rule with all the pomp of an independent prince here, under the very nose of the British general? It is not even eight months since Sir Eyre had chased this rebel out of these forests; - well, even like that will this Le Grand rush in the Jagadishpur wilds to hunt down this marauding chief. With this hope, the brave general, with four hundred British troops and two guns, marched on the doomed city of Jagadishpur on the 23rd of April. How, now, is it possible that this field should be contested by Kumar Singh? During all these months, the old warrior had been fighting incessantly and without a moment&amp;rsquo;s rest; his forces had never been able to snatch a hearty meal or an undisturbed sleep; but yesterday had he come to Jagadishpur after the death-dealing struggle in East Oudh, and he and his forces had not even taken one day&amp;rsquo;s rest. According to the English official report itself his forces were &amp;ldquo;disjointed, badly armed, and without guns,&amp;rdquo; numbering at the most to a thousand, with very few trained soldiers amongst them, and the octogenarian chief himself was founded mortally in his hand! Against this army was marching the fresh, the vigorous, the disciplined forces of the British, well armed with guns and led by General Le Grand. The issue of the battle was, then, a foregone conclusion! And with this full confidence, the English army entered the forest which was about one mile and a half from the town. The English guns began to thunder forth unchallenged, for Kumar Singh had no guns to oppose them. But, still, it seems that he means to smother us in this thickly grown jungle by stretching out his forces round us; - well then, let the all unfailing stroke be given. Let that straight and bold front attack of the Europeans, which had always been the terror of the Asiatics, be ordered! It was ordered; the Europeans rushed forth irresistible; the army of Kumar Singh, too, began to contest; and none knows how, but in a moment, the brave Briton got confused and struck with terror and sounded the retreat. But, though the bands sounded the retreat, as Kumar Singh held the British force in his grip, it was more dangerous to attempt a treat than even to try to make a stand. But, if retreat is as ruinous as a stand, then, O brave Briton, why not make a stand to prove that unflinching courage of your people which so many times you have boasted&#xA;that you possess? Matters not whether it is proved or disproved, he along lived who ran! And they did; all the British forces, like hunted deer, left the jungle and began to fly wherever the way led, while Kumar Singh&amp;rsquo;s army pursued them hot and the rout was complete! One of the men who himself was present in this rout, writes to this effect of his experience, in a letter written at the time: - &amp;ldquo;Indeed, it makes me extremely ashamed to write what followed. We began flying out of the jungles, leaving the battle-field and being constantly beaten by the enemy. Our people, dying of thirst, rushed forth at the sight of a wretched, dirty pool of water, in the most confused manner possible. Just then, the horses of Kumar Singh closed upon our rear. Henceforth, there was no limit to our disgrace, and the disaster was complete. No sense of shame was left in any one of us. Everyman ran wherever he thought his safety lay. Orders were thrown to the winds. Discipline and drill were dead. In all directions, nothing could be heard but sighs, curses and wailings. Bands of Europeans dropped dead in the flight by sunstroke. Nor was it possible to ask for medicine; for, the dispensary was already captured by Kumar Singh. Some died there and then; the rest cut down by the enemy; the carriers dropped the dolis and fled; all was confusion - all terror! Sixteen elephants were all full- laden with the burden of the wounder. General Le Grand himself was shot dead by a bullet in his breast! Soldiers running for their lives for five miles and more had now no strength, even for lifting up their guns. The Sikhs, accustomed to the heat of the sun, took off the elephants and fled away ahead of all. None would be with the white. Out of a hundred and ninety-nine whites, about eighty alone could survive this terrible massacre! We were led into this jungle like cattle into the slaughter-house, simply to be killed!&amp;ldquo;46&#xA;The forces of Kumar Singh were thus completely successful. They had in spite of the fact that they had no artillery to speak of on their side, routed the British forces with a terrible loss and slaughter, and had&#xA;46 Charles Ball&amp;rsquo;s Indian Mutiny, Vol. II, page 288.&#xA;captured even the two guns which the British had so proudly brought.47But, one fact is most significant in this pursuit; the number of Sikhs that fell on that day was only nine. It substantiates most thoroughly the tradition that Kumar Singh was in the habit of issuing strict injunctions to spare as many lives as could be spared of the Indian people even though they were on the enemy&amp;rsquo;s side, while there should be no mistaken mercy shown to the foreigh foe. In the first outbreak of the Revolution many of the Babus of Bengal were made prisoners, for joining the English side, by Kumar&amp;rsquo;s men; but he not only released them but sent them without harm on elephants to the city of Patna where they wished to go. When the&#xA;Sepoys determined to burn down all government papers written in English, it was Kumar who stopped them from doing so, as &amp;ldquo;otherwise, after the English were driven out of the country, there would be no proof of the rights of the people, and no evidence to determine the amount due from one party to the other.&#xA;Having vanquished his foe thus completely and thoroughly, the old chief, Rana Kumar Singh, entered again his palace of Jagadishpur on the 23rd of April, crowned with fresh laurels and a fresh fame!&#xA;This was his last entrance, for no more will Kumar Sing re-enter on the stage of the world. The wound caused by the amputation of his hand proved mortal and, on the 26th day of April, the third day after his latest victory, the great Rana died in his own palace. He died on an independent throne and under the flag of freedom. The day he died, it was not the Union Jack of the British Isles but the Golden Banner of a free and liberated nation, the triumphant symbol of his Desh and Dharma, that was waving radiant over the palace of Jagadishpur. It was under the cool shade of this banner that he died. What nobler death can a Rajpur long for?&#xA;47 &amp;ldquo;The English sustained on this occasion a complete defect of the worst kind.&amp;rdquo; White&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;History of the Mutiny.&#xA;He had avenged his wrongs; he had, with poor means, worsted a mighty foe more than once in a fair battle-field; he had not proved a traitor to the nation nor a renegade to his Dharma but had broken the chains that bound his land and made her free so far as one man could do it, and to-day, in a noble field, he had been crowned by Victory’s own hands with a wreath of laurels. Then, this is the auspicious day : this is the supreme moment for you, O great Rajput, to close your eyes for ever, to lay down your body – not through disease, but even as a worthy sacrifice to the cause of your mother’s freedom, by the wounds received on the battle-field! Let your death be as noble and as matchless as was your life!&#xA;He died on that day and under the banner of a free people. What nobler death can a Rajput wish for?48&#xA;The personality of Shrimant Kumar Singh is striking in more than one respect. His personal dash and high character had naturally infused in his army the two indispensable virtues of discipline and bravery. It is rarely the case that persons who are called upon to lead a nation&amp;rsquo;s regeneration are in their private morals as unimpeachable as they are unchallengeable in their public ability. This rare consistency of character was conspicuous in great degree in the life of this great Indian. Such was the influence of his pure conduct on his people that none would dare even to smoke openly in their verandahs for fear of being seen by him. Amongst all the leaders of the Revolutionaries in 1857, there was none who could surpass Kumar Singh in military ability. It was he who at once grasped trhe utility of guerilla warfare in the War of Independence and it was he alone who could imitate the masterful tactics of a veteran guerilla leader like Shivaji. If we compare the two great generals that 1857 brought to the front, Tatia Tope and Kumar Singh, in their military achievements as guerilla leaders, we shall be struck with one distinguishing point. To Tatia Tope may&#xA;48 The English historian, Holmes, says : “The old Rajput who had fought so honourably and so bravely against the British power died on April 26, 1858.” – History of the Sepoy War.&#xA;be at once assigned a very high place in the negative side of guerilla warfare, while Kumar Singh holds the position with equal eminence in the positive as well as in the negative side of it. Tatia Tope did not allow the enemy to completely crush his forces or his power to raise them, but Kumar Singh, while succeeding in&#xA;doing this, could even succeed in crushing the enemy’s forces by severe defeats. To ensure ultimate success, it is imperatively necessary in guerilla warfare to prevent the demonstration of one’s followers which the constant flights from the field or avoidance of battles against a mightier foe do inevitably tend to beget. The defeats which are suffered intentionally by the leader, and the flights which he finds it necessary to effect, ought not to be allowed to create demoralisation or diffidence in the minds of his followers. The constant avoidance of battles ought not to be allowed to create in the followers a fear for battle itself. The skilful avoidance of a battle and a panic-stricken flight in the course of the battle are two very different things. So it is most important in guerilla tactics never to leave the field through cowardice; but whenever a battle is decided to be given, it sould be given so sternly and dashingly as to strike a sudden terror into the heart of the enemy and to infuse an overwhelming confidence into the heart of one’s own followers. The main skill lies in taking care never to be forced to give battle where the chances are of an unequal contest. But once the die is cast, such must be the tenacity and desperation in contesting the field as was shown by Baji in the Pawankhind or by Kumar Singh on the Tanu Nadi. In short, if the strength is unequal, the leader should not get entangled into a battle; if the chances are equal, he should cast the die; but, in either case of a forced or voluntary contest, never should a battle once begun be left, through fear or want of discipline, but, on the contrary, it should be fought on so desperately and so bravely, in spite of an assured defeat or of an immediate death, as never to lose fame, though success be lost in the field. Thus attacked, the enemy is struck with error, the followers do not get demoralised, discipline is not slackened, and inspiration increases by stories&#xA;of martyrdom; bravery begets bravery, and victory becomes insured. The guerilla general and his forces should never give the least chance to create an impression that their foe conquered them through superiority in bravery. This is the key to guerilla warfare.&#xA;But Tatia Tope could not follow this positive side of this warfare. Tatia&amp;rsquo;s campaigns when trying to cross the Narbada and Kumar&amp;rsquo;s campaigns when trying to cross the Ganges demonstrate this difference. Tatia suffered many a defeat. Though this was due entirely to the panicky and sometimes even cowardly conduct of the Sepoys, he had to lead and could not be attributed to any inferiority in his capacity. Kumar Singh, while marching off, had all the while kept up such a bold front and, whenever opportunity offered, had hit his pursuing foe so hard, that all the while his forces were full of self-confidence and high inspiration in spite of the fact that they were retreating before pursuing enemy. Now, it ought not to be forgotten that Tatia had to take up to guerilla tactics when his forces were already completely demoralised by previous defects and when all the veterans had been either killed or disabled in the earlier stages of the war, and so it was quite natural that, in spite of his skill and insight into the guerilla&amp;rsquo;s art, he should not be able to put them in practice owing to the lack of materials. Whatever the reason, one thing is clear that, more than once, Tatiahad during his wonderful career as a general to leave the field through panic and fear striking his ranks; while Kumar Singh, like his prototype, the great Mahratta Shivaji, never allowed his army to become diffident, but created in them absolute confidence in themselves as well as in himself, their leader, by his personal valor and intrepidity and discipline; and he, also, exhibited matchless skill both in giving battle and in avoiding it - in both the positive and the negative sides of guerilla warfare; into dust, in the midst of a proud victory, on an independent throne, and under the banner of freedom - the old, the brave, the great Indian could die an honourable death!&#xA;On the 26th of April,1858, Kumar Singh died. No sooner did this actor pass off from the stage than another - equally brave, equally noble,&#xA;and equally patriotic - appeared on the scene. This new general was no other than the younder brother of Kumar Singh. Raja Amar Singh, without allowing a moment&amp;rsquo;s slackening in the vigour of the war, without taking a rest of even four days, marched straight on the knock at the gates of Arrah itself! Having heard of the defeat of Le Grand of Arrah, the British forces which had stopped on the other side of the Ganges had by this time crossed it; and the two generals, Brigadier Douglas and general Lugard, marched on Raja Amar Singh on the 3rd of May. At Bihiya, Hatampur, Dalilpur, and several other places, each alternate day, the English forces attacked the Revolutionaries. Therefore, now Amar Singh resorted to different tactics. If he saw that the enemy was gaining the upper hand, he would order his forces to divide themselves into small bands, to retire in divers but well- mapped-our directions and, thus rendering pursuit by the enemy hopelessly impossible, to get united again at the appointment signal. How, now, to fight with this invisible army - was the chief question before the British. Every battle seemed to them quite decisive, but the very next moment the army of Amar Singh was as strong and as active at some other place as ever! No sooner he was driven from one end of the jungle then he appeared again in the second, and as soon as he was driven from that, he would wheel round and reign supreme in the first. At last, worn out, disgraced, and disappointed - the British general, Lugard, resigned on the 15th of June and returned to England to rest. His army, too left the field and entered the camp.&#xA;And this was the signal for Amar Singh to reunite his bands and to appear on the battle-field with the pomp of a victorious general. Now the police of Gaya were won over to fight for the freedom of the nation. Then, sending the English forces on a wrong scent, Amar Singh attacked Arrah itself and entered it. Nay, now he is actually entering back into that capital of Jagadishpur. July passed; August and September also passed; - yet the banner of a free people was flashing forth from the towers of Jagadishpur and the Rana Amar Singh was reigning the beloved monarch of a liberated people! Brigadier Douglas and his seven thousand English forces were sworn to finish him. Nay, they had even offered prizes to anyone who would bring the head of Amar Singh by hook or crook. They had, by this time, cleared the jungles and made roads; from post to post, the British bands were constantly advancing; but nothing availed against the worthy successor of Kumar Singh. It was not possible for want of space to enumerate his different activities. Suffice it to say that the Rana Amar Singh fought in such a manner as to make his whole people think that Kumar Singh died not at all!&#xA;At last, the English decided to end the whole campaign by a supreme effort and seven different armies advanced from seven different directions on Jagadishpur. All the roads leading to Jagadishpur were thus closed up and the Rana was caught as if in a trap. The cordon slowly began to close round Amar Singh and, at last, on the 17th of October, it tightened its grip on the capital itself. Alas! It is in this net that the liberty-loving lion is to be captured and killed! At the appointed time, all these forces rushed simultaneously from all directions into Jagadishpur and the helpless lion was hit - but, well done, Amar Singh, well done! It was the cage that was hit, and the lion had already escaped all unscatched!&#xA;For, though six divisions had advanced and fallen on the town as ordered, yet the seventh one was late by five hours and the shrewd Amar Singh, with all his forces, vanished by his very side, taking full advantage of the delay of that division of the foe.&#xA;Therefore, abandoning the plan which had proved so ineffectual as regards the crushing of the Behar Revolutionaries, the English government sent a division of mounted infantry to pursue them. This ever- increasing and ever-pursuing force of the enemy left not one moment of rest to Amar Singh. The new rifles that were introduced into the enemy&amp;rsquo;s camp at this time had made the matchlocks of the Revolutionary forces almost useless, and the infantry found it impossible to outrun the horsemen&amp;rsquo;s pursuit. Still, Amar Singh talked not of surrender! On the 19th of October&#xA;the English forces shut up the Revolutionaries, first in the village of Nonadi and, out of four hundred of them, they cut off three hundred! The remaining one hundred dashed out desperately into the field outside, like infuriated tigers, and fought a bloody battle with the new division of British forces that had just arrived. It was found in the end that out of these only three escaped - and one out of the three was the Rana Amar Singh who had been fightting all the while incognito. Many were the bloody encounters and many the pools of blood through which the Panday army had to swim across. But, still, the flag of liberty was unbent! So narrow were theior escapes that, once, the very elephant of the Rana was captured; but the Rana jumped off from it and vanished. In this way, the Revolutionaries contested every inch of their ground, while being pressed onwards and onwards out of their province; and now they had reached the hills of Kaimur, for &amp;ldquo;the whole population of the district constantly and systematically misled the British pursuers by false information.&amp;ldquo;49&#xA;With this sympathy of the populace, the patriotic chief entered the Kaimur hills but was soon followed by the relentless foe pursuing in his track. Still there was no talk of surrender. Every hill and every dale, every hillock and every rock, fought on with the alien till the whole of the&#xA;Panday army died fighting for the liberty of the land, for the honour of their Dharma! Died fighting, yes, for not only the men but even the women of that patriotic band did not return back to their homes as captives and slaves! The hundred and fifty ladies of the Royal palace of Raja Shrimant Kumar Singh, seeing that no hope or chance of success remained to them in this world, stood before the guns, set fire to the fuse with their own hands, and got themselves blown up into the - Immortality of Martyrdom! Thus fought Behar for its birthrights against the foreign foe!&#xA;49 Malleson’s Indian Mutiny, Vol. IV, page 344.&#xA;But Rana Amar Singh did not fall into the hands of the enemy. Fortune left him, but his unconquerable soul could never! But what became of him? - Where did he end his days? Bewildered History echoes back, &amp;lsquo;where?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 MOULVIE AHMAD SHAH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/09_MOULVIE_AHMAD_SHAH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/09_MOULVIE_AHMAD_SHAH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AFTER the fall of Lucknow, there remained no powerful nucleus to concentrate the forces of the Revolutionaries in the provinces of Rohilkhand and Oudh. The tide of British conquest that has been sweeping over the Doab and Behar had driven all the Revolutionaries from these provinces into the ever-narrowing circle of Oudh and Rohilkhand. By this irresistible pressure on all sides and by want of powerful stronghold, the Revolutionaries had to give up the old system of open warfare and pitched battles and to take to guerilla tactics. Had they done so at the very start, the chances of success had been over whelmingly innumerable. But, better late than never! For, though success was rendered extremely difficult, yet there was not the least suggestion in the Revolutionary camp of surrender or desertion. So, the leaders of Oudh and Rohilkhand decided to continue the War of Independence by pursuing guerilla tactics, and issued the following Proclamation and military order all over the provinces: &amp;ldquo;Do not attempt to meet the regular columns of the infidels in open battle, because they are superior to you in discipline and they have big guns. But watch their movements, guard all the Ghats on the rivers, intercept their communications, stop their supplies, cut up their daks and posts, and keep constantly hanging about their camp. Give the Feringhi no rest!&amp;ldquo;50 Moulvie Ahmad Shah at once began to put into execution these orders. He began to hand about the camp of the British forces which were at Lucknow and camped at Bari, a place twenty-nine miles away from the English camp. The&#xA;50 Russel says: &amp;ldquo;This general order bears marks of sagacity and points out the most formidable&#xA;war we would encounter.&amp;rdquo; - Diary, page 276.&#xA;Begum Hazrat Mahal was encamped at Bitaoli with six thousand men. In order to break both these forces, Hope Grant started from Lucknow with a strong force of three thousand soldiers and a powerful artillery, first in the direction of Bari. The next day brought with it an incident which showed the wonderful courage and cleverness of the Revolutionary scouts. The Moulvie had sent out some of his scouts to get correct information about the British force. On the same night they entered the camp of the English with perfect nonchalance. The English watchmen stopped them and asked, &amp;ldquo;Who goes there?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;We are the men of the 12th regiment!&amp;rdquo; was the answer. This&#xA;answer was literally true, for all of them had indeed belonged to the 12th regiment. But how were the poor watchmen to know that this 12th regiment was one of those which rose in rebellion as far back as the July of the previous year and had killed their English officer? The steady and firm step of these men, that resolute answer, and that fearless simplicity of behaviour drove away all suspicion about them, and the watchmen replied “Alright!” The daring band entered unopposed into the English camp, obtained all the information that they wanted, and came out all unscathed to report it to their master!&#xA;Having thus informed himself of the exact situation and the plan of the British camp, the Moulvie quickly formed his plans, marches ahead, and took possession of a village four miles from Bari. The plan of the Moulvie was that, while his infantry should hold this village against the enemy, his cavalry should march ahead by a secret route and should wheel round and attack the rear of the British forces. He knew it for certain that the next morning the British general was coming to that very place, suspecting no harm and in a perfect sense of security. As soon as this unwary prey came into the trap, the Moulvie&amp;rsquo;s infantry was to attack him from the front, while his cavalry was to fall on the enemy&amp;rsquo;s flanks or rear. Malleson says: &amp;ldquo;It was realy a brilliant idea and did credit to his tactical skill.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;There were two things most necessary for the success of this brilliant design. The one thing was to keep perfect secrecy about the fources of the Moulview in the village; and the other was that the cavalry that was to make a flank attach should not sally forth and put the enemy on his guard before the front attack should be begun. The Moulvie did whatever he had to do. He sent his cavalry from Bari that same night by the route agreed on; he quietly took possession of the village and succeeded in concealing himself there, and so cleverly that the next morning actually saw the unsuspecting British general approaching the banks of the river. Half an hour more and the British forces would be done for!&#xA;But in that half an hour, the splendid plan of the Moulvie was shattered to pieces by the impetuosity of the cavalry men. They had already occupied a very convenient place on the flank of the British forces and had been holding themselves ready to pounce upon the foe. But their leader, while lying in ambush, saw some guns unprotected in front of them and, forgetting the strict orders of the Moulvie, made for them with the intention of capturing them, and even captured and obtained possession of them for a while; but soon, the English woke to their danger, the guns were recaptured, and the whole plan of the Moulvie was shattered. For, this fighting at the rear opened the languid eyes of the English commander and he saw the danger in his rear as well as his front. Seeing his plan thus nullified by the rashness of his cavalry, the Moulvie who was holding the village left it after a skirmish and marched off - to find another opportunity and to mature another design.&#xA;While Hope Grant was pressing the Revolutionaries upwards and upwards, from Bari to Bitaoli, with a view to drive them out of Oudh, there on the other side, on the 15th April, was being fought a hotly contested battle, near the fort of Ruiya. We have seen how, sometime before this, in the province of the Doab, the English army, being divided into separate divisions and marching by separate routes, pressed on the Revolutionaries simultaneously and systematically, sweeping off the whole province, till&#xA;they drove them all into the town of Fatehgarh. In the same manner, a campaign had been organised and put into execution to sweep the Revolutionaries off the whole province of Oudh, by different British forces, from all possible quarters, pressing them onwards and upwards towards the northern frontier of Oudh. About the 1st of April, 1858, the total number of the white forces in India had risen to ninety-six thousand soldiers, besides which there were the loyal armies of the Sikhs. The brigades consisting of the Pathans, Pariahs, and other raw recruits, though originally raised in haste, had by this time become quite like veterans through constant experience on the field. Again, the &amp;lsquo;contingent&amp;rsquo; forces of the native princes which had been sent forth to the assistance of the English, were also busy in the field. The pick of these innumerable brown and white troops were now engaged in the supreme effort of reconquering Oudh. As described in the last chapter, Lugard and Douglas were sent into Behar, Sir Hope Grant was sent towards Bari and Bitaoli, and Walpole was ordered to march up from the banks of the Ganges. Thus, these different forces, including those of the commander-in-chief and others, marching in the line to drive out the Revolutionaries to a man further and further to the north till they were pushed into Rohilkhand; and then, the idea was to annihilate them by one supreme effort. With this intention, Walpole too had started to do his own part on the 9th of April, 1858; and now, on the 15th of April, he was busy in attacking the fort of Ruiya which is fifty-one miles from Lucknow.&#xA;It was not that either the fort of Ruiya was very strong or that its owner Narapat Singh was a very big and mighty chieftain. But small Zemindar though he was, ever since this great sacrificial fire was lighted up on the field of liberty, this Narapat Singh had offered himself with his all- in-all, as a willing victim for the regeneration of his nation. The 15th of April saw a mighty English army, armed with the most modern artillery, attacking this little chief in his tiny fort. As he had not even two hundred and fifty men with him in the forst, the English naturally expected that the chief must have already evacuated the place. But, on that very morning, one&#xA;of the white prisoners whom Narapat Singh had released came to the English camp and informed the general that he had heard Narapat Singh say that he would evacuate the fort but not until he had had his vengeance. - Not until a gory fight is fought, not until one bloody defeat is inflicted will Narapat leave his fort!&#xA;What! This little chief is to inflict a bloody defeat? And then alone is he to evacuate the fort? Walpole was furious and ordered his men to attack the fort. The English forces, as usual, circulated a rumour that the forces of Narapat Singh numbered about two thousand! When we are sure of crushing this Narapat Singn, what other way of magnifying our sure victory than of exaggerating the strength of the adversary? So even Walpole agreed that the forces with Narapat must be at least a thousand and five hundred. This released English captive who attests to the fact of only two hundred and fifty men defending the fort, though an eyewitness, might be a mad man! The English forces advanced - and that too, not on the weak side of the fort though its weakness was well-known to them, but the brave general would insist on marching against the strongest face of the fort! The defenders of the fort began to pour a shower of bullets as soon as they saw the British attacking the fort from among the trees in front of it. The shower grew hottest when the enemy approacdhed the ditch. Out of a hundred and fifty who marched, forty-six English soldiers were killed on the spot. Grove could not move one step forward on account of the fire of the Pandays. Now then, the skilful Walpole, seeing this crisis at the strong face of the fort, took his guns and rushed against the weak side of it; and with such accuracy he aimed his guns, that the English cannon balls sent from this side crossed over the fort and fell right amidst the English forces on the other side! Many are the generals who fight with their enemies, but matchless and the first without a second is General Walpole, who would fight with both friend and foe with equal skill and bravery! At the sight of this matchless skill of the veteran general, another general, Hope, came forth to save the day - but alas! he is killed by the unbearable fire of the Revolutionaries. Even grove&#xA;is retiring - confusion worse confounded! The confused British army left the field and fell back, disgracefully repulsed!&#xA;The death of this brave general, Hope, came as a shock over all Englishmen resident in India. Lord Canning and Sir Colin, why, all English was overwhelmed with grief. Not even the death of hundreds of soldiers would have inflicted such a sorrow and mourning on the English nation as did the death of this Hope - one of the bravest and most energetic of the English officers of that period. The tiny chieftain, Narapat Singh, had done what he said, &amp;ldquo;he had his vengeance&amp;rdquo;, and then left the fort with his handful of men, and went on fighting with the unsullied banner of liberty in his hand!&#xA;After these different divisions had swept off the Revolutionaries from the province of Oudh towards the north and then to Rohilkhand, the commander-in-chief got all the forces united and marched on to Rohilkhand in person. All the leaders of the Revolutionaries had now assembledin Shahjahanpur. There was Nana Sahib of Cawnpore and Moulvie Ahmad Shah. These two men had baffled all the innumerable attempts of the British generals to get hold of them and were still as energetic and unconquered as ever. So, when the news was brought to Sir Colin that these two leaders of the Revolutionaries were within his reach in the same place and perhaps ignorant of his movements, Sir Colin formed the shrewd plan of closing the town from all sides. He marched and closed on Shahjahanpur - but only to find that the birds had flown away! It was but natural that Sir Colin should be extremely piqued at this, as he had ordered four different forces to guard all the four sides, and the Revolutionary leaders escaped by the side guarded by the commander-in-shief himself!&#xA;Now that the plan of Shahjahanpur was frustrated, Sir Colin was desirous of reducing at least the city of Bareilly. So, leaving a division of his forces with four guns in Shahjahanpur, he started and arrived on the 14th of May within a day&amp;rsquo;s distance of Bareilly. The Rohilla, Khan Bahadur Khan&#xA;was still holding out in this city. After the fall of Delhi and Lucknow, the Revolutionaries had been pouring into this still independent town of their party. Mirza Feroz Shah, the brave prince of the Delhi dynasty, Shrimant Nana Sahib, Moulvie Ahmad Shah, Shrimant Bala Sahib, Begum Hazrat Mahal, Raja Teja Singh, and many of the lesser leaders, had retreated into Rohilkhand and Bareilly, its capital, where still was waving the flat of a free people. And it was for this very reason that Sir Colin had vowed vengeance against this city. But in the Indian Camp there was no talk of making any stand at the city itself, as the leaders of the Revolution had determined, even according to the general order they had just issued, to resist the enemy by guerilla tactics. Their plan was to evacuate the city and get scattered all over the fields of Rohilkhand. All preparations had been made for leaving the city and only the last order of evacuation remained to be given. But when the brave Rohillas actually saw the hated Feringhi just near the town, the majority of them refused to evacuate the city without first tasting the steel of the foe - until, once at least, they had given proof of their readiness to die for the cause of their nation and their faith.&#xA;The English forces that had surrounded that city were exceedingly strong. Their artillery was well-equipped and they had numerous guns; their cavalry and their infantry were well-armed and well- disciplined; and the command was in the hands of no less a general than the commander-in-chief Sir Colin Campbell himself. Against these, the guns of Khan Bahadur Khan could make no impression, and so, on that 5th of May, the Revolutionary guns had to be silent and the Revolutionary sword flashed forth. The sword belonged to the martyr-spirits who, in spite of the hopelessness of success, nay, in virtue of the hopelessness of success, instead of leaving the battle-field, preferred to embrace death with a smile on their lips and the unconquered and unconquerable faith in the holiness of their cause in their heart. To die while fighting in a good cause is the key to the gates of Heaven, that was their belief; and they knew that the cause of the freedom of a prople was one of the best causes for the sake of which one could lay down one&amp;rsquo;s life. So they unsheathered their swords and dashed like thunderbolt on the English forces. With green turbans on their head, with a Kummerbund girded round their loins, and a silver ring inscribed with chosen sentences of the Koran in their finger, these terrible-looking Ghazis rushed up from the right, holding their head behind their shields, with their swords shining aloft in the sun, and shouting wildly their war-cry of &amp;ldquo;Din,Din!&amp;rdquo; They closed with the British troops with a tremendous shock, and, at this desperate attack, though they were very few, the British soldiers were startled and confused and swept away; the 42nd Highlanders tried to check their onrush - but the death-dealiong Ghazis still advanced, while some of them even succeeded in reaching to the rear of the British forces! Not one of them returned back - all of them fell while fighting and mowed down the English soldiery like sheaves before the scythe! They fell; they like lions, despising even the thought of retreat or surrender; one only fell without being byoneted by the enemy. Why? Wait a minute and the answer comes; for, there is coming up to this spot the Commander-in-Chief of the British forces; nay, he has come here! And just then this martyr, who had been pretending death, jumps up from among the corpses and falls on the commander, but alas! a loyal Sikh standing by the commander scents this danger and cuts the Ghazi off!51&#xA;Of the few instances of the immortal bravery of martyrdom in the history of the worls, none can be greater than this!&#xA;Next day, having baffled the attack of the British to capture them, the Revolutionaries, with Khan Bahadue Khan at their head, marched out of Bareilly on the 7th of May, 1858, and the English forces took possession of the evacuated capital of Rohilkhand.&#xA;51 Russel&amp;rsquo;s Diary.&#xA;Disappointed on account of the safe escape of Khan Bahadur Khan out of his clutches, but still feeling triumphant for the capture of Bareilly, Sir Colin was standing in his mighty camp. Just then, there rose one deafening cry all over the camp – the cry of “The Moulvie! The Moulvie!! The Moulvie, again!!!”&#xA;It was an extremely surprising design that the Moulvie was hatching there at the town of Shahjahanpur. Having baffled Sir Colin, it was not simply to avoid a fight that Nana Sahib and the Moulvie had left Shahjahanpur. All the government buildings in the town had been demolished by the order of Nana Sahib even before they left the town. The keen-sighted leaders had rightly gussed that the English commander would leave only a few troops in Shahjahanpur, and would proceed to Bareilly; and they had decided that, when he was thus away, the Moulvie should wheel round and fall on the city, crush the English forces there, and thus avenge the loss of Bareilly by the sack of Shahjahanpur. This was their plan and all things turned up as they guessed. For the British commander did go to Bareilly, leaving only a small detachment, though with a strong complement of artillery composed of four field- pieces. And the English detachment had to encamp on a plain, unprotected and open, as Nana Sahib had already caused all fortified places to be pulled down. On the 22nd of May, Moulvie Ahmad Shah started for Shahjahanpur by rapid marches, while his prey was indulging in false security. But, after midnight, the forces of the Moulvie - none can say by whose foolish obstinacy - stopped for a while within four miles of the town. This stay made the excellent plan barren of fruits, as &amp;ldquo;native spies employed by the British were on the alert, and one of them flew with the intelligence of his dangerous vicinity to Colonel Hale at Shahjahanpur.&amp;rdquo; As soon as this traitorous spy brought the news, the British commander moved into the newly-built fortified position with his soldiers. The Moulvie pressed on, though now his prey was awake and occupying a strong position. He attacked and occupied the town, captured the fort, and levied a tax on the rich inhabitants of the place for the supplies of his&#xA;forces. Even Malleson admits that, &amp;ldquo;in acting thus, he simply conformed to the custom of war in Europe.&amp;rdquo; Not only this; but in a war of independence, when a handful of noble spirits offer their fresh blood to wipe off the shame and slavery of a whole nation, it is the duty of the people to support them voluntarily. After taking possession of the town the Moulvie brought eight guns, and began a cannonade on the fortified place where his foe was under shelter. When this news reacher Sir Colin at Bareilly on the 7th of May though he was surprised, his joy knew no bounds. The lost opportunity, which had worried the Commander-in-Chief so much ever since the escape of the Moulvie some days before, seemed now about to be restored by the action of the Moulvie himself. And therefore, taking the utmost precaution possible, Sir Colin started by forced marches to pounce upon his prey. Now, it was clear that there was no loop-hole whatsoever left through which the Moulvie Ahmad Shah could escape. From the 11th of May, for three days there was a continuous fight. It was, indeed, impossible for the Moulvie to escape. So, from all sides the different Revolutionary leaders brought all their forces together, in order to save this most popular and most energetic of patriots. The Begum of Ayodhya, Mayyan Sahib, the King of Mahmadi, the Prince Feroze Shah of Delhi, Nana Sahib of Cawnpore - all these leaders poured in with their forces, before the 15th of May, to help the flag of liberty, now in such immediate danger in Shahjahanpur. Thus reinforced, the Moulvie marched out of Shahjahanpur, warring night and day with his&#xA;now discomfited foe, and again escaped the coils that the commander-in- chief had prepared for him. So sure was Sir Colin of capturing the Moulvie that, in view of the certainty of the ruin of the Revolutionary party at Shahjahanpur, he had already issued orders for dividing his forces again and sending them to different directions. And, having dashed to pieces these orders and hopes of the enemy, where did the Moulvie go? He entered Oudh - the very province which the English had, after a year&amp;rsquo;s trouble and bloodshed and with the greatest difficulty, succeeded in sweeping clear of the Revolutionaries. Sir Colin conquered Ayodhya - the Moulvie occupied&#xA;Rohilkhand; now, Sir Colin comes and conquers Rohilkhand - the Moulvie wheels back and again occupies Oudh!&#xA;In such a dogged manner and with such bravery did the Moulvie fight with the foreign foe.&#xA;The British power is now bent on crushing him and putting an end to his dangerous activities. Is there anyone who would assist them in this plight? Whose sword is mighty enough to kill this powerful headof the Revolution, whom the sword of Sir Colin has proved too blunt to cut? What is the best way to accomplish this end?&#xA;What is the best way? There need not be any such anxiety in the English camp. Is it not true that the British sword had, many a time before the present, proved equally helpless and unsuccessful in eradicating the enemies of British power in India? Well then, those who could and did save England in all those periods of danger and despair would come forward to save her once more. If the English sword is too blunt to cut to pieces this Indian patriot, let the dagger of treachery accomplish the task!&#xA;After the re-entry into Oudh, while trying to offer as much and as dogged a resistance to the foreigner as he could, the Moulvie thought it would be a great help to the new storm that he was preparing to raise in Oudh if the Raja of Powen would lend the little might he possessed to drive out the alien from the land. With this purpose, he sent a request sealed with the Royal seal of the Begum to this Raja at Powen. This tiny Raja was quite shocked at the mere mention of war and battlefield. Yet, as treacherous as he was cowardly, he wrote back that he would like to see the Moulvie personally. In answer to this invitation, the Moulvie started to see this Raja. But, to the Moulvie&amp;rsquo;s great surprise, he foud the gates of the town closed and the walls of it guarded by armed men; and in the midst of them, he found standing the Raja Jagannath Singh himself, with his brother by his&#xA;side. Though the Moulvie knew the meaning of this sight, still undaunted, he began to hold a parley with the Raja. The wretch on the walls&#xA;of the town was naturally the last man to appreciate his eloquence. When it became clear that the crowd was not going to open the gates willingly, the Moulvie ordered his Mahut to goad on the elephant on which he was sitting to break upon the gates of the fort. One stroke more of the mighty animal&amp;rsquo;s head - and the gates would have been forced. But, the brother of the Raja took aim and Moulvie Ahmad Shah was shot deat by the hand of that wretched coward! The fat Raja and his brother at once came out of the gate, severed the head of the Moulvie from his body and, covering it up in a cloth, ran forth to the nearest British Thana, thirteen miles from the place, - to the city of Shahjahanpur. Here the British officers were at their table in the dining-room. The Raja came in, unpacked the burden which he had held forth as a trophy, and let roll on the ground, by the feet of the officers, the head of the Moulvie still gushing with blood! Next day, the civilised Britishers hung on the kotawali the head of an enemy who had fought against them so bravely and so honouraly, and the fact brute of Powen was rewarded with fifty thousand Rupees for this, his nefarious act of treachery!&#xA;As soon as the news of his death reached England, the relieved Englishmen felt that &amp;quot; the most formidable enemy of the British in Noprthern India was no more!&amp;ldquo;52 In person, the&#xA;Moulvie was tall, lean and muscular, with large deep-set eyes, bettle brows, a high aquiline nose, and lantern jaws. The life of this brave Mahomedan shows that a rational faith in the doctrines of Islam is in no way inconsistent with, or antagonistic to, a deep and all - powerful love of the Indian soil; and that the true believer in Islam will feel it a pride to belong to, and privilege to die for, his mother-country! Even the English historian Malleson, in no way inclined to assess rightly – far less to exaggerate – the&#xA;52 Hlome&amp;rsquo;s History of the Indian Mutiny, page 539.&#xA;virtues of the Revolutionist leaders, is carried off by his inner feelings and, forgetting for the moment that he is an Englishman, remarks: “The Moulvie was a very remarkable man&amp;hellip;. Of his capacity as a military leader many proofs were given during the revolt, but none more decisive than those recorded in this chapter. No other man could boast that he had twice foiled Sir Colin Campbell in the field! &amp;hellip;. Thus dies the Moulvie Ahmand’allah (sic) of Fyzabad. If a patriot is a man who plots and fights for the independence, wrongfully destroyed, of his native country, then most certainly the Moulvie was a true patriot. He had not stained his sword by assassination; he had connived at no murders; he had fought manfully, honourably, and stubbornly in the field&#xA;against the strangers who had seized his country; and his memory is entitled to the respect of the brave and true-hearted of all nations.&amp;ldquo;53&#xA;53 Malleson&amp;rsquo;s Indian Mutiny, Vol. IV, page 381.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 RANI LAKSHMI BAI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/10_RANI_LAKSHMI_BAI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/indian_war_of_independence/p3/10_RANI_LAKSHMI_BAI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GIVE up my Jhansi? I will not. Let him try to take who dares!&amp;quot; With this challenge the heroic Ranee of Jhansi rose against the British and as it is recorded in previous parts of this History she assumed the leadership of the Revolution, drove the English and began to rule at Jhansi as the Queen of the province. The forces of the Revolution had wreaked a bloody vengeance on the English people and army and left not a trace of their rule at Sagar. Naogaon, Banda, Banapur, Shahgarh and Karki. The people everywhere hailed the Queen as their own. She then busied herself - in restoring order and peace in her liberated province.&#xA;The Ranee&amp;rsquo;s daily life at this period has been described as follows :- &amp;ldquo;The Bai got up at five in the morning and took a bath with fragrant attar. After dressing - and she generally wore a Chanderi Saree of faultless white - she would sit for her daily prayers. First, she dropped the necessary water as a prayaschitta for keeping hair on her head after her husband&amp;rsquo;s death; then, she used to worship the Tulsi in the Tulsi grove. Then began the Parthiva Puja at which the Durbar musicians would sing in choir. Puraniks would then start reading the Puran. Then, Sirdars and dependants came and she returned their usual salutes. Being very keen of memory, even if a single man among the seven hundred and fifty who paid their respects to her in the morning was not present, the very next day, the Bai would not fail to inquire why he did not come the previous day. After the worship of God began the dinner. After dinner, she would take an hour&amp;rsquo;s siesta unless there was urgent work to do. Then she would order the presents of the morning to be brought before her, which was done on silver trays covered over with silk cloths. Those things that she liked, she accepted; the others were given over to the Kothiwalla (minister of the presents department) for distribution&#xA;amongst her servants. At three she went to the Durbar, when she usually put on male attire. She wore a pyjama, a coat of dark blue, a cap on the heat, and a beautiful turban on the top of it, a dupeta of embroidered cloth round the slender waist, and the sword decked with gems by her side. Attired in this wise, this fair woman looked like Gauri herself. Sometimes, she wore the female dress. After her husband&amp;rsquo;s death, she never wore nath or similar ornaments. Her hands had round them bangles of diamond; she wore a small necklace of pearls round her neck and a diamond ring on her little finger. These were the only jewels worn by the Bai Sahib. Her hair was gathered up together behind. She wore a white saree and a plain white bodice. Thus, sometimes in male attire and sometimes in female, the Bai Sahib used to honour the Durbar by her presence. Those assembled in Durbar never used to see her person. For the room in which she sat was separate from, and only opened into, the Durbar hall. Gold carving adorned the doors, and over these fell gracefully the chintz curtain, embroidered with gold cloths. In this room sat the Bai Sahib on a gadi of soft down, leaning on a soft pillow. Outside the door, two pages with maces of silver and sold always attended. Opposite the room, Lakshman Rao Dewanji stood with a bundle of important documents in his hand, and beyond him sat the Registrars of the Durbar. Being very keen and intelligent, the Bai quickly grasped every matter brought before her, and her orders were clear and definite and to the point. Sometimes she wrote her orders out herself. She was very careful in affairs of justice, and decided civil and criminal cases alike with great ability. Ranee Sahib worshipped Mahalakshmi devoutly. The temple of that Goddess was situated on the banks of a lake filled with lotus flowers, and every Friday and Tuesday the Bai visited the temple. One day, it so happened that after the&#xA;Bai had returned from the temple and was passing through the south gate, she was thousands of beggars blocking the passage and creating a disturbance. So, she inquired of the Minister, Lakshman Rao Pande, the reason of this. He inquired and informed her that the people were very poor,&#xA;and that they suffered immensely on account of excessive cold, and that, therefore, they requested that the Bai would kindly consider their condition. The Bai left very grieved for these poor people, and she at once issued orders - kind-hearted that she was - that, on the fourth day from thence, a gathering of beggars should take place, where every one should be provided with a thick coat and a cap and a blanket either white or black. The very next day, all the tailors of the town were given orders to make caps and coats. On the day appointed it was proclaimed that all the beggars were to gather in front of the palace. Poor people, too, had been included in his gathering. All were given clothes by the Bai and they went away satisfied In the fight with Nathe Khan when the wounded men were brought into the city, the Bai herself would insist on being present when their wounds were being dressed. Her very presence soothed their pain, and they felt themselves sufficiently rewarded by the kind and sympathetic interest she took in their well-being. The Ranee grieved at their grief, gave them ornaments and medals, patted them, and showed such sympathy that others, instead of being disheartened at the sight of these wounded soldiers, felt that they could even give up their lives for the sake of the Ranee. The grandeur of the Bai&amp;rsquo;s processions passes description. On the occassions of the visits to the temple of Mahalakshmi, she started sometimes in a palanquin, and sometimes on horseback. When in the palanquin, the palanquin would be covered with curtains of gold and embroidered cloths tied with golden ribbon. When she was on horseback, in male attire, the end of a thin and beautiful batti floated on her back and it fitted her admirably. The national flag of freedom was carried before her, with the band playing military music. Two hundred Europeans followed the flag and a hundred horsemen rode before and behind her. With the palanquin came the karbharis, ministers, feudatories, and other officers like Bhayya Sahib Upasane; and others either rode or followed on foot. Sometimes troops accompanied the procession. When the Bai started from the palace, the choughada on the fort&#xA;made sweet music. The choughada of the nagarkhana of Mahalakshmi started at the same time.&amp;ldquo;54&#xA;And thus, from the Vindhyas to the Jumna, there was not a vestige of British authority left, Brahmins, Moulvies, Sirdars, Dorkdars, Sepoys, the police, Rajas, Raos, bankers, villagers - all were desirous fighting for only one thing, and that was Independence! And to unite together these thousand voices in one harmonious whole, the Lakshmi of Jhansi declared with her sweet but firm voice &amp;ldquo;None can have my Jhansi; he who dares may try!&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Very rarely had the world heard such a firm &amp;ldquo;No!&amp;rdquo; Generous and liberal to a fault India has always been pronouncing and swearing by &amp;ldquo;I shall give!&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;I shall give!&amp;rdquo;, so far. But here was a strange phenomenon to-day - a set face and a stern voice which said, &amp;ldquo;I will not give! I will not give up my Jhansi!&amp;rdquo; Would to heaven, O Mother, that every one of thy sons and daughters had said the same! The Feringhi was taken aback at this unexpected assertion; and Sir Hugh Rose was sent, with five thousand armed men and a considerable number of guns, to gauge the extent of the disturbance and to quell it.&#xA;In the beginning of 1858, the English had drawn up a complete military plan for the reconquest of all the territory, from the Himalayas to the Vindhyas, which was under the Revolutionaries. The whole territory was divided into two portions, and to each of them a huge army was sent to subdue it. We have in an earlier chapter described how commander-in- chief Sir Colin Campbell marched upwards from Allahabad to the north of the Ganges and the Jumna and, with his big army, conquered the Doab, and crossed the Ganges and marches on Lucknow; how, after destroying Lucknow, he extinguished the flames of insurrection ranging in Behar, in Benares and round if, and in Oudh; how he forced all the Revolutionaries&#xA;54 D.B.Parasnis&amp;rsquo;s Life of Lakshmi Bai, paged 147-151. into Rohilkhand, where the final engagement took place, and how, thus, the northern portion of the territory which was in the hands of the Revolutionaries was reconquered by the English. While Sir Colin was advancing from the north of the Jumna towards the Himalayas, Sir Hugh Rose advanced to conquer the southern portion lying between the Jumna and the Vindhyas. In the north, the Sikhs, the Gurkhas, and other Indian troops and feudatories had joined Sir Colin; so also in the south, Sir Hugh Rose had on his side the help of the princes of Hyderabad, Bhopal, and other states. He had, in addition, got the valuable assistance of the troops of Madras and Bombay and the Hyderabad contingent. To mention specially that the Indian troops had joined Sir Hugh Rose is unnecessary. For, to mention that Sir Hugh Rose was successful would imply the first proposition. For the English to obtain a victory, of themselves, is as impossible as the most impossible thing in the world. The traitorous Indian troops thus collected together for conquering the southern parts were divided into two divisions. One was under the command of Brigadier Whitlock who was to start from Jubbulpore and, subduing the provinces on the way, was eventually to join Sir Hugh Rose. The other was under Sir Huge Rose himself. As soon as Whitlock started from Jubbulpore, Sir Hugh was also to start from Mhow; he was to advance through Jhansi on Kalpi. According to the plan of campaign, Sir Huge started from Mhow on the 6th of January 1858 and, after a fight, he captured the fort of Rajgarh. From thence, he advanced to Sagar, released the prisoners kept there by the Revolutionaries, advanced further south, reducing various positions of the enemy on the way, captured Banapur on the 10th of March, and reconquered the famous fort of Chanderi. On the 20th of March, the triumphant English army encamped about fourteen miles from Jhansi. By these many struggles, bands of Revolutionaries distributed all over the country from the banks of the Narbada upwards, now crowded into Jhansi; and that is why Sir Hugh advanced with great dispatch on Jhansi to reduce this stronghold of the Revolutionaries. But Lord Canning and Sir Colin both issued orders to Sir Hugh first to relieve the Raja of Charkhari who was being besieged by&#xA;Tatia. This order, if he obeyed it, would have spoiled Sir Hugh&amp;rsquo;s plan of reducing Jhansi. What was he to do? He could neither disobey nor find his way to obey the orders. As, in these trying circumstances, the best interests of the British government lay in advancing on Jhansi, Sir Robert Hamilton took upon himself the whole responsibility of disobeying the orders of the two highest authorities in Hindusthan; and the British army, emboldened by a high national feeling, advanced towards Jhansi, hopeful of victory. But the English army suffered enormously as soon as they set foot on the soil of Jhansi. For they found, to their great surprise, that all the tract of land surrounding Jhansi had been laid waste by order of the Queen in orderthat the enemy should have no supplies of any sort. Not a blade of corn in the fields, not a vestige of grass on the meadows, not a tree which could afford shelter; So had William of Orange, when there appeared to be a possibility of the Netherlands falling into the hands of the Spanish tyrant and invader, ordered that the dykes be opened and the sea let in, rather than that the country should fall in the hands of the enemy. And this day Jhansi had adopted a similar course.&#xA;The same terrible thunder is in her voice; her eyes are spouting forth the red flames of anger! Mardan Singh, Raja of Banapur, the enraged chief of Shahagarh, the brave Thakurs, with their lives in their hands, Sirdars of Bundelkhand, resolute as ever, with their many followers - all these hot incendiary elements in the interior of Jhansi are burning and flame-red. The flames leap up even as the Jaripatka; and look, the central figure of the whole fight is there, shining above all! Aye, she is the central idea, the flashing impersonation of Swaraj! She is the inspiration, she is the incarnation of Liberty!&#xA;In spite of the barrenness of the country around, the English approached Jhansi. For, thanks to the loyalty of the Scindia and the Raja of Tehri, the force was throughout the operations abundantly supplied with&#xA;grass, firewood, and vegetables.55 As the Scindia and the Raja of Tehri are helping the Feringhis, surrounded as you are by treachery and disloyalty, betrayed by relations as by strangers, you have not the slightest hope of success. Why not then avoid extinction by surrendering to the English? But, surrender? And for the Ranee of Jhansi? Dewan Lakshman Rao, Moro Punt Tambe, brave Thakurs and Sirdars, all heroes of Liberty, if you surrender, you will be saved; if you fight, you will die. Which will you choose?&#xA;Jhansi answered from her thousand mouths, sternly, in the words of the Scripture, &amp;ldquo;As everyone who is born must die, why sully fair fame uselessly?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;So, it was determined to give battle to the English for the honour of the country. And Jhansi was busy by night and by day preparing for the fight. Brave men, there were many in her army; but trained men, there were very few. Want of discipline was very apparent. The queen herself, however, let the whole army. On every rampart and every gate, she was moving about actively; she was standing where guns were being planted and moved into position; she was budy selecting clever gunners; and she was to be found everywhere inspiring heroism even in the coldest hearts. The learned Brahmins of Jhansi were praying for the success of the country. Its temples blessed the soldier who went to the field, and tended the wounded who returned from battle; its workmen were busy preparing ammunition and other necessary for war. The men of Jhansi manned their guns, loaded the muskets; its women carried ammunition, built Top Khanas, supplied provisions.56 When the night of the 23rd fell, sounds of battle- drums were heard throughout the town and lighted torches shone forth at frequent intervals from the fort. The guards fired a few shots too. The&#xA;55 Malleson&amp;rsquo;s Indian Mutiny, Vol. V, page 110.&#xA;56 “The women were seen working in the batteries and carrying ammunition, etc.”- Sir Hugh Rose.&#xA;morning of the 24th approached. No more delay now! The Ghanagarj (thunder-clap) gun began its work. The noise made by that gun was terrific.&#xA;We shall quote an eye witness’s account of the early stages of the siege.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;From the 25th, the engagement began in right earnest. The enemy poured in a heavy fire all day and night. In the night came cannon- balls on the forst and the city. The sight was terrible to see. A cannon-ball of fifty or sixty pounds weight would look as small as a tennis ball but red like live charcoal. During the day one would not see these balls clearly for daylight, but in the night, they were clearly visible and gave a weird appearance to the night. On the 26th, at midday, the English silenced the guns on the southern gate, and not a man could make a stand there. All men in the field were nearly disheartened at this. Then, the gunner on the western gate moved the gun round and fired at the enemy; the third shot killed the best gunner in the English army, and the English gun was silenced, in its turn. At this, the Bai Sahib was very pleased and presented the gunner with a silver anklet. The name of the brave gunner was Gulam Ghose Khan. He had displayed similar skill in the engagement with Nathe Khan also.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;On the fifty or the sixth day, the same sort of engagement took place. For four or five hours, the Bai&amp;rsquo;s guns were working wonders and the English lost heavily. Many of their guns, too, were silenced for some time. Then again, the English guns would be more vigorous, and the Jhansi troops would be disheartened and their guns silenced. On the seventh day, at sunset,&#xA;the gun to the left was disabled. None could stand there. The battlement was destroyed owing to the enemy’s fire. But in the night, eleven masons were brought under cover of blankets to the walls of the fort, and the work was completed before the day dawned. Thus, the battlement was repaired, and the English, to their great surprise, found the Jhansi gun in working order.&#xA;At this time, the English were careless. They suffered considerably and their guns were disabled for quite a long time.&#xA;“On the morning of the eighth day, the English army went for Shankar Killa. The English had very expensive and modern telescopes and, with their aid, they began to pour a heavy fire on the reservoir of water within the fort. Of the six or seven who approached near for taking water, four were killed: the others ran leaving their vessels there. As they could not get water for nearly four hours, even baths and other ordinary functions could not be carried on. Now, the gunners on the western and southern gates stopped the guns of the English attacking the Shankar Killa, by a continued fire on them. Then it became possible to get water from the reservoir for bath and dinner. There was a powder factory in the tamarind grove. As soon as two maunds of powder was prepared, it was taken to the sellers to be stocked. A cannon- ball fell on the factory, and thirty men and eight women were killed. On the same day, there was a great turmoil. There was a terrible fight. The fighters were shouting loudly. There was a terrific noise from muskets, and guns firing heavily. Trumpets and bugles were sounding everywhere. Dust and smoke filled the air. Many gunners on the ramparts and a number of Sepoys were killed. Others were appointed in their place. The Bai Sahib was working very hard. She looked to everything, issued the necessary orders, and repaired every point of weakness. By this, the men in the army were very much encouraged and fought continually. On account of this determined resistance, the English, in spite of all their powder and ammunition, could not enter the fort till the 31st of March.&amp;ldquo;57&#xA;But pressed as she is by this constant succession of disasters, why is Queen Lakshmi looking so earnestly in that particular direction? And see, she is smiling too! Be ready now and fire your salutes; let triumphal drums beat loudly; let war-cries rend the air! For there is Tatia Tope advancing with his army to aid Jhansi!&#xA;57 D.B.Parasnis&amp;rsquo;s Life of Lakshmi Bai, pages 187-193.&#xA;with his twenty-two thousand troops. While playing as children, people hardly noticed them; to-day, the whole world is looking on their game!&#xA;Tatia Tope has come with his army to dishearten the English army and to give courage to Jhansi. After the defeat of Wyndham at Cawnpore and Sir Colin’s victory, Tatia crossed the Ganges and joined Shrimant Nana. Then, leaving Nana, he crossed the Jumna near Kalpi. As the Raja of Charkhari refused to help in the war for the country started by the Peshwa, Tatia, as representative of the Peshwa, attacked his capital, punished the traitor well, captured twenty-four of his guns, and took from him a contribution of three lacs of Rupees. And then Tatia turned towards Kalpi. There, he received a letter from Ranee Lakshmi Bai requesting him to come to Jhansi and relieve the siege. He sent the note to the Rao Sahib Peshwa, the chief in authority; and, as soon as he got the orders, he charged the rear of the English army. It is on seeing him that a smile of hope has come to the lips of Lakshmi. These two had played together as children in the palace at Brahmavarta, without anyone noticing them particularly. To- day they are playing on the battle-field; the one, on the fortifications of Jhansi, is standing amidst rings of flaming fire, the other is approaching close to the Betwa, with his twenty-two thousand troops. While playing as children, people hardly noticed them; to-day, the whole world is looking on their game!&#xA;Tatia had under him, now, the largest number of troops he ever had, and hence the English were not a little disconcerted. They would have been completely so in the battle too, handful as they were. For, in front of them was the Ranee Lakshmi Bai; behind them was this Mahratta tiger, with his twenty-two thousand claws. Why should he not, then, tear Sir Hugh to pieces and eat him up? He advanced to do this, but his twenty-two thousand claws seemed all of a sudden disabled, they could hardly be lifted. And what could even a tiger do without his claws? Alas! A most shameful poltroonish cowardice was exhibited by the Revolutionary troops on the river Betwa.&#xA;The army of Jhansi was to attack the rear, and Tatia was to attack the front; the plan was admirable. But the English, with the dash of despair, advanced on Tatia and opened fire on Jhansi. This nullified the two attacks of the aggressive party. One determined attack, like that of the Mawalas of Shivaji or the select band of Kumar, and vultures had fed upon the Union Jack and its followers. But, the English charged straight on the enemy. The cowards did not even offer fight, and - was it treachery or terror - not a cannon-shot from Jhansi was heard. So, the army and its commander were routed and ran away. Plentiful military supplies were captured by the English, Tatia&amp;rsquo;s guns fell into their hands, and one thousand and five hundred of the Revolutionaries were killed in the pursuit. Fifteen hundred people killed in the flight! Mad men and fools! Instead of dying the death of cowards while fleeing, if you had only attacked Sir Huge Rose, you would have died the death of the Ghazis of Bareillyk, you would have destroyed the whole army with Sir Hugh Rose, and your name would have lived for ever! Yet God forgive you! If not our respect, you deserve at least our sympathy. For, howsoever you died, you died for the liberty of your country! May my country learn from your death at least the lesson that soldiers who fly to live, die, and that those who fight to die, live!&#xA;And for death was Ranee Lakshmi Bai fighting! Why, then, this hopelessness on the part of Sirdars, Thakurs, and Sepoys? For nine days and nine nights, you stood the deadly charge of gun-fire in the hope that Tatia Tope would soon come to your aid. When he came, you shouted for delight; by the defeat of Tatia on the 1st of April, not only that joy but the very hope of victory is dashed to pieces; and those supplies, to deprive the enemy of which thousands of lives had been sacrificed, have fallen with ease into the enemy&amp;rsquo;s hands. Tatia&amp;rsquo;s ammunition and guns also have fallen into their hands. All this is certainly true. But, why this despair? The enemy may render it impossible for you to live victorious, but he cannot deprive you of a death of glory. There is nothing to despair for, then! And stop, hear the steady, firm, courageous voice of Ranee Lakshmi.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;It was not relying on the Peshwa that Jhansi fought so long nor does she require his help to continue her fight in the future. So far, your bravery have been exhibited by you most admirably. I urge to do the same now and to fight with courage and desperation.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Aye, fight with desperation, be ready, let the battle-drums beat, and the trumpets sound! Let was-cries rend the air and let big guns thunder forth! The 3rd of April has dawned and the last assault of the English on Jhansi has begun. They are coming from all sides and pressing hard. Start, then, in right, good, deadly earnest! See how the goddess of war has taken the sword and see how she is making her way through the troops. She is moving about with lightning rapidity, presenting some with golden bracelets, some with dresses; some she is touching with her sacred touch to pat, to some she is offering her sweet smile; others she is encouraging with her heroic words. So now! Gulam Ghose Khan and Kuar Khuda Bhaksh, let the fire be most deadly! The enemy is storming the main gate and the fortifications, ladders have been planted at eight different places. &amp;ldquo;Har, Har, Mahadev!&amp;rdquo; From the fort, from ramparts, and from houses came a perfect shower of bullets, a constant succession of shots. The deep-mouthed cannon are vomiting forth burning red-hot balls. &amp;ldquo;Maro Feringhiko!&amp;rdquo; Lieutenant Dick and Lieutenant Meiklejohn have mounted the ladders and are calling upon their men to follow them. Boom, boom! Instantly, the daring Englishmen fell in the jaws of death! Anyone coming behind? Lieutenant Bonus and heroic Lieutenant Fox, you seem anxious for death - your desire shall be accomplished; - die, then! Seeing these four heroes who had scaled with the greatest difficulty shot down, the ladders trembled. They swayed and broke under the weight of the English troops. The English sounded the bugle to retire; the army began to go back - it went back, the soldiers concealing themselves behind every stray stone!58&#xA;58 “No sooner did we turn into the road leading towards the gate, than the enemy’s bugle sounded, and a fire of indescribabl e fierceness opened upon us from the whole line of the walls and from the tower of the fort overlooking this site. For a time it appeared like a sheet of fire,&#xA;A strong defence was thus offered at the principal gate. But who is giving forth that tragic wail near the southern ramparts? May it be that mean treachery had lost the Morcha gate? Yes, unfortunately yes; the English have captured the gate, with the air of treachery - so it is said - and they have mounted the ramparts, and are advancing rapidly on. There was no other thought that day but to kill or be killed! Once within the city, the English gave no quarter and streams of blood flowed freely. The English, taking one position after another, massacring, firing, destroying - came right up to the palace. As soon as the palace was forced, thousands of Rupees were looted, guards were massacred, and buildings were destroyed. At last, alas! Jhansi had fallen into the enemy&amp;rsquo;s hands!&#xA;Standing on the rampartrs, the Ranee looked back for one moment at Jhansi. Before her rose the hideous picture of the terrible disaster that had happened near the south gate. The enemy had, after all, defiled her Jhansi! Her eyes were ablaze with anger; she was almost mad with rage. She took up her sword and, with her small force of a thousand or fifteen hundred men, she marched down the fort. The tigress to avenge her cubs runs not so fleetingly. As soon as she saw the white troops near the southern gate, she rushed for them, and then, “swords crossed, the two armies were mixed up before you could count even fifty; swords flourished and dealt heard blows. Many Englishmen were killed. The rest ran towards the town and began to fire shots from under cover!” By this sight of Feringhi blood, the anger of this Kali was a little appeased, and now she saw that it was foolhardy to fight alone so far from the fort. But echoes of such daring heroism were now to be heard in every street in the city. Fifty stablemen in the palace, while the whole town and the palace itself was bathed in blood shed by English&#xA;out of which burst a store of bullets, round shots, and rockets destined for our annihilation&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip; But the fire of the enemy waxed stronger, and amidst the chaos of sounds, of volleys of musketry and roaring of cannon, hissing and bursting rockets, stink-pots, infernal machines, huge stones, blocks of wood, and trees, all hurled upon our heads, it seemed as though Pluto and the Furies&#xA;had been loosened upon us, carrying death amongst us fast. At this instant a bugle sounded on our right&#xA;for the Europeans to retire.” – Lowe’s Central India, page 254.&#xA;swords, refused to give up the stables! “Surrender” was a word not to be found in their dictionary. Everyone of these men cut down the enemy as hard as he could, and it was only when everyone of them was killed that the paga fell into the enemy’s hands! The English had, by now, rendered the whole town desolate. Everyone who fell into their hands, from children of five to old men of eighty, were massacred; the whole city was set fire to; wailings from the wounded and the dying, and the cries of those who killed, filled the air. A huge wail rose from the whole town!&#xA;When the Queen stood on the walls of the fortress (which the enemy had decided to storm only the next day on account of its strength), looking at this sad, sad picture, she was smitten with grief and tears started to her eyes! The Queen of Jhansi wept! Those beautiful eyes were red with weeping! Her Jhansi to be reduced to this! Then she looked up and saw the flag of the Feringhi flying over the walls of Jhansi, and a strange fire shone from those weeping eyes! All glory to her courage! But why is this messenger running hard towards her? He said, &amp;ldquo;Your Majesty, the pre- eminently brave Sirdar who guarded the chief gate of the fort, Sirdar Kuar Khuda Buksh, and Gulam Ghose Khan, the chief gunner of the artillery, have both been shot down by the English!&amp;rdquo; What a blow this to the already afflicted Queen! What a succession of disasters this! What is your next plan, then, Queen? Aye, one and one alone! She said to the messenger, who was no other than an old Sirdar, &amp;quot; I have determined to blow myself up with the fort, setting fire to the ammunition with my own hands.&amp;rdquo; With her Jaripatka she must be - if not on the throne, at least on the pyre!&#xA;Hearing this, the old Sirdar calmly replied, &amp;ldquo;Your Majesty, as it is not safe to be in this neighbourhood now, your Majesty should leave the fort to-night breaking through the enemy&amp;rsquo;s camp and should join the Peshwa&amp;rsquo;s forces. If death comes on the way, the conquest of heaven by a dip in the sacred waters of the battle-field is always at hand!&amp;rdquo; Lakshmi said, &amp;ldquo;I should choose to die on the battle-field, but, being a woman, I fear that the enemy might insult my person!&amp;rdquo; To this the whole Durbar answered with one voice: &amp;ldquo;Insult! So long as there is life in the body of the least among us, our sword shall cut to pieces the enemy who woulod dare so much as touch your sacred person!&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Well then, the night had fallen; Lakshmi greeted all her dear subjects and gave them her blessings for the last time! Her subjects were full of tears at the thought that she was leaving Jhansi, perhaps for ever. She took a selected number of horsemen with her. An elephant with jewels on him was placed in the middle and Ranee Lakshmi descended the fort amidst cries of &amp;ldquo;Har, Har, Mahadev!&amp;rdquo; She put on male apparel; a steel armour covered her person, a Jammia was in her girdle; a fine sword hung from her belt, a silver cup was in her Pudder, and her adopted child Damodar was on her back, tied in silk Dhoti. Thus accoutred, riding on a noble white steed, this queen, Lakshmi, looked like the goddess of war. When the north gate came, the sentry who belonged to the traitor army of the Tehri State asked, &amp;ldquo;Who goes there?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;The army of Tehri is going to the aid of Sir Huge Rose,&amp;rdquo; was the answer. The sentry was satisfied and Ranee advanced, evading the English sentry too in a similar manner. One maid, one bargeer, and ten or fifteen horsemen formed her body-guard, and marched through the camp of the enemy. But her other horsemen were stopped by the English on suspicion and had to fight hard. Moro Punt Tambe, wounded though he was, was able to run as far as Datia. But the traitor Dewan of that State captured him and gave him over to the English, who later on hanged him.&#xA;But, Lakshmi, put your horse now in a gallop. For Lieutenant Bowker is galloping behind, followed by select horsemen, in order to capture you. And you, O horse, fortunate on account of the sacred treasure you carry, gallop on! Let the men of Bharata be traitors, but, ye animals, ye at least be faithful! O Night, drop the curtain of darkness between Queen Lakshmi and her enemies ! O horse, fleeting as you are, quicker than the wind, balance Lakshmi lightly! Ye paths, do not obstruct the horse&amp;rsquo;s onward march! O ye stars, shine not for the enemy, but just shine so that this tender beauty, delicate as a flower, should be encouraged on the way by your rays,&#xA;cool as nectar! The dawn has now broken; so, heroic Queen, flying all night on the wings of the wind, rest thee near the village of Bhandeir. The Mahalkuree of the village will feed your darling Damodar.&#xA;As soon as breakfast was over, she again started on her journey on the Kalpi road. But what is this dust behind? Spur your horses on! Lakshmi, keep Damodar safe on the back and gallop on. Tak our your sword! There, Bowker is pressing close! Here is the reward for your wicked pursuit! Dare you hold back the lightning? A long sweep of her sword, and Bowker was violently thrown off his horse. A deadly fight took place between her fifteen or twenty horsemen and the English pursuers; those who were alive advanced forward to protect Lakshmi Bai. Wounded Bowker and his handful of men gave up the pursuit. The sword of the Mother advanced triumphant, shining. The sun in the heaven above, Ranee Lakshmi Bai on earth - both were marching forward. Morning was gone and mid-day came, but the Ranee did not stop. Afternoon came, the shades of evening began to fall, the sun went down the horizon - but the Ranee still would not stop. The stars rose. They saw her just as they had seen her the night before - marching, marching in hot haste. At last, at midnight, Ranee Lakshmi entered Kalpi. A ride of a hundred and two miles she accomplished, and that, fighting with Lieutenant Bowker and his soldiers and with the burden of a child on her back. That horse just lived, it so seemed, to carry her to Kalpi. For, as soon as he saw the rider safe in Kalpi, he fell down on the ground all in a heap. Six men were immediately ordered to attend to the horse. The Ranee loved the horse very much. A horse which carried safe such a person with such faithfulness deserves to be remembered, and his memory will be loved for all time.&#xA;The Ranee slept till dawn. In the morning, the touching meeting between the Ranee and Shri Rao Sahib Peshwa took place. Both remembered their ancestors - the thought that they were descended from those who had done such seemingly impossible deeds inspired them both. They realised that the flag of the Mahratta empire waved as far as Attock&#xA;because men like the Scindia and the Holkar, the Gaekwar and Bundela and Patwardhan were ready to give up their lives for Swaraj. And for that very flag, for that very Swaraj for which their fathers and grandfathers had bled, they resolved to continue uninterrupted, to the very last breath of their lives, the war already begun against those who attempted to enslave their motherland. So, they resolved to carry on the war as vigorously as ever. And again did Lakshmi Bai and the brave Tatia Tope begin to make preparations for the coming deadly fight.&#xA;While these arrangements are going on there, we shall take a rapid glance at the activities of Brigadier Whitlock whom we had left sometime back. To reconquer the tract between the Narbada and the Ganes and the Jumna, two armies had started and, of these, the one under Sir Hugh Rose, as we had already seen, had taken Jhansi. When Jhansi was taken, the British indulged in a wholesale looting such as Nadir Shah alone had accomplished before, defiling of temples and polluting of images, and massacring terribly all alike. That finished, the army continued the campaign. The last part of the campaign had been appointed for Brigadier Whitlock to accomplish. Accordingly, Brigadier Whitlock started on the 17th of February from Jubbulpore, with all his army - European regiments, Indian regiments from Madras, &amp;ldquo;black&amp;rdquo; and white cavalry, and splendid artillery. He entered Sagar in triumph, where the loyal Raja of Oorcha joined him. The, the English army began to advance on the Nabob of Banda, the chief leader of the Revolutionaries in that province. In the beginning of the Revolution at Jhansi, Sagar, and other places, cruel massacres had taken place and the Europeans from those places ran wherever they could to save their lives. The Nabob had brought them to his palace and was looking after them well. But, at the same time, he was as busy in trying to throw off the British yoke already tottering through the shocks of the Revolution as he was in saving the lives of these Enbglishmen. From the very beginning, the symbols of slavery in his kingdom had been smashed and he was runing as&#xA;an independent prince. Seeing the English army coming to deprive him of his liberty, the Nabob, urged and aided by the whole populace, was ready for battle. Several engagements took place between the two parties, but, being defeated in them, the Nabob started for Kalpi with his army, and Whitlock entered Banda in triumph on the 19th of April. The next march was to be on the Rao of Kirwi.&#xA;Rao Madhav Rao of Kirwi was a child of ten and his guardianship was in the hands of the English. The Rao of Kirwi was a near relation of Baji Rao Peshwa. In 1827, Anant Rao, the then ruler of Kirwi, deposited two lakhs of Rupees with the English Government for some charities in connection with the temples of Benares. As soon as he died, the English swallowed the whole amount. More than that, they took unlawful possession of a further sum of several lakhs of Rupees foolishly deposited with them by Anant Rao&amp;rsquo;s son, Vinayak Rao, in spite of the lesson he had already received. This was soon after Vinayak Rao&amp;rsquo;s death. Rao Madhav, the adopted son of Vinayak Rao, being a minor, as the supervision of the whole state was in the hands of the English, and Ramachandra Rao, the chief Karbhari, had been appointed by the English, there was every reason to suppose that there would not be much fear of revolt in the Kirwi State. But, in 1857, whatever the Raos and Maharaos did was not quietly acquiesced in by the people. Sometimes obsecurely and sometimes clearly, the power of the people, the strength of the real nation, was slowly struggling into prominence. The Zemindars, the priests, the merchants of Kirwi, nay, even the common people, inspired by the strong ideal of liberty, hailed with joy the news which one day proclaimed Delhi free and the next day Lucknow and the third that Jhansi had uprooted the flags of the Feringhi. Encouraged by these hopeful incidents, they proclaimed the independence of Kirwi and the destruction of the alien yoke, not waiting for the opinion of the Rao or the sanction of his ministers. Now, while this proclamation was being loudly celebrated by the populace, the Rao, a boy of nine or ten, had not done even a single thing against the English! Nay, when the English army returned to&#xA;Bundelkhand, he went forward to receive them and invited them into the city. According to his invitation, the English army entered the city silently, but they entered to imprison this little Rao, to destroy his capital and to pull down his palace! Dreadful looting,59 wholesale burning, and a vengeance of wickedness took place. And the State was annexed.&#xA;Whitlock now encamped at Mahoba, in order to &amp;lsquo;pacify&amp;rsquo; the conquered provinces. As a matter of fact, he had now completed his campaign. He had conquered all the eastern part of Bundelkhand and he had sent small expeditions to &amp;lsquo;pacify&amp;rsquo; one or two places. So now, leaving Whitlock, let us again follow the sacred steps of the gallant Queen of Jhansi.&#xA;The Ranee, now again full of hope, made an advance on Kunchgaon, forty-two miles from Kalpi, with the army of te Peshwa. But the Rao Sahib, if would appear, had not arranged the forces as she would have liked him to. It must be borne in mind, however, that it was not possible to make effective arrangements, either for Rao Sahib or Tatia Tope. Though in that place, the Nabob of Banda, the Raja of Shahgarh, and the Raja of Banapur had all gathered together under the same flat, they had not gathered together as the organised and disciplined parts of a grand military force, moved by oneness of heart, with a unity of plan and constitution, sustained by strict military discipline and subordination. No one could get his ideas carried out. But, in the opposing army, there was no such conflict amongst leaders. It seemed that the whole organisation was perfect and wellcontrolled. Before Sir Hugh Rose was appointed commander, there was heated discussion and difference of opinion; but, once he was the&#xA;59 “With regard to this injustice done to Rao, Malleson has to confess : “Not a shot had been fired against him (Whitlock), but he resolved nevertheless to treat the young Rao as though he had actually opposed the British forces. The reason for this perversion of honest dealing lay in the fact that in the palace of Kirwi was stored the wherewithal to compensate soldiers for many a hard fight and many a broiling sun. In its vaults and strong rooms were specie, jewels, and diamonds of priceless value&amp;hellip;.. The wealth was coveted.” – Kaye and Malleson’s Indian Mutiny, Vol. V, pages 140,141.&#xA;commander, his opinion was the opinion of all. Whatever orders he issued were&#xA;right; and, even if they were not right, they must be obeyed. And even mistaken orders of a weak general carried out by the obedient and unanimous bravery of the troops under him, become successful – are bound to become successful. On the other hand, even well-planned orders of a capable general lead to disaster and defeat, through the self-willed behaviour of the troops and the lack of oneness in command and proper subordination.&#xA;Otherwise the rout at Kunchgaon could never have been place. As soon as Sir Hugh Road came from Jhansi, the Revolutionaries met him at Kunchgaon. Knowing that the mid-day sun was unbearable to the English, the Revolutionaries had ordered in one of their commands, “None should engage in a fight with the Feringhis before ten in the morning. The fight should begin always after ten.” This very clever rule was put into practice this day. Much havoc was thereby created in the English army as happened on many other occasions where the fight took place after ten. But, in spite of this, the Revolutionaries were defeated at Kunchgaon and retired towards Kalpi. The admirable way in which they retired, the organised manner in which they fell back has been praised very much even by the enemy.60 But then this excellent organisation came after and not before the engagement.&#xA;60 &amp;ldquo;Then was witnessed action on the part of the rebels which impelled admiration from their&#xA;enemies. The manner in which they conducted their retreat could not be surpassed. They&#xA;remembered the lessons which the European officers had well taught them. There was no&#xA;hurry, no disorder, no rushing to the rear. All was orderly as on a field-day. Though their line&#xA;of skirmishers was two miles in length, it never wavered in a single point. The men fired, then&#xA;ran behind the relieving men, and loaded. The relieving men then fired, and ran back in their&#xA;turn. They even attempted, when they thought the pursuit was too rash, to take up a position,&#xA;so as to bring on it an enfilading fire.&amp;rdquo; - Malleson&amp;rsquo;s Indian Mutiny, Vol. V, page 124.&#xA;With this defeat, the Revolutionaries came on to Kalpi. There, they began to make up for the defeat by wrangling against and abusing one another, - the infantry laid the defeat at the door of the cavalry, the cavalry blamed the Jhansi troops, and all together blamed the general, Tatia.&#xA;But, Tatia Tope is not going to come any more to Kalpi to hear these wranglings. He has gone at present to the village of Charkhi, near Jalwan, to see his father. No one knows definitely where he is going after that, or whether he is going there at all. Let us remember that Gwalior lies in the direction of his road ! May the meeting between this extraordinary son and his fortunate father be full of love! And after that loving visit, may this great messenger of the Revolution go with despatch to carry out whatever designs he might have set his heart on!&#xA;While Tatia was going on this journey, Ranee Lakshmi went to the royal tent of the Peshwa. The heroic Lakshmi relieved him of his dejection after the defeat of Kunchgaon and said to him that, if the army was properly organised, the enemy should never again be victorious. The Nabob of Banda was inspired by her speech. Proclamations in spirited language were again published in the Revolutionary army. And to-day, on the banks of the Jumna, crowds are gathering. Swords and guns, angry Sepoys invoking the Jumna to bless the cause of the indedpendence of their soil - such a Revolutionary pilgrimage the banks of the Jumna had probably never before seen. These banks are simply echoing forth the triumphant cries for the Mother and for Dharma!&amp;rdquo; Jai Jumna! With this thy sacred water in our hands, we swear that the Feringhis shall be extinct, that Swadesh shall be independent, and that Swadharma shall be re-established! Jai Jumna! If all this is accomplished, then alone we will live. If not, we will die this day on the field of battle. We swear, by thee, O Kalindi, three times!&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Heroes, thrice bound by this oath, come on then to the field. Rao Sahib will lead the whole army. Drive away this 25th infantry under Sir&#xA;Hugh Rose. They are all Indians - drive these traitors before you! Major Orr advances - make him share the same defeat! In this maidan before Kalpi, our position - with this undulatory part to cover - is almost impregnable. But look, the vanguard is falling back! It went too far, and being not well covered, has had to retreat. Run then, Lakshmi, run to protect them. She rushed forward sword in her hand with lightning-like rapidity, and fell on the right wing of the English, with her red-uniformed cavalry. The triumphant right stopped dead, so sudden was the attack; stopped dead, and then retired back helpless. This rapid onslaught of the girl of twenty-one, her horse at full speed, her sword cutting men down to the right and to the left, - seeing this, who would not fight for her? Who would not be inspired by her? All the Revolutionaries were inspired by her strength; the battle raged bloody and hot. The Feringhi gunners of the light field artillery began to die one after another. The Ranee and her cavalry, then, advanced right on the guns which were spitting deadly fire, and attacked the artillery. English gunners left the guns; the horse artillery was routed; the heroes of the Revolution advanced on and on, from all sides, overjoyed at the prospect of crushing the Feringhis who had so long escaped them; and before them all fought Lakshmi!&#xA;This praise by the enemy does credit to the Panday party.&#xA;Sir Hugh Rose, taken aback by this terrible onslaught, then advanced with his reserve camels, and the English saved their own lives, simply because of the camels. An English writter says, “Fifteen minutes more, and the mutineers would have cut us down! Fresh camels, one hundred and fifty in number, changed the fortunes of the day. Ever since that day, I have looked on the camel with eyes of affection.” By the strength of the camelmen alone, on the 22nd of May, the Feringhis succeeded in forcing the Peshwa’s army to retire towards Kalpi. After another complete defeat of the Peshwa’s troops and after a few skirmishes, Sir Hugh entered Kalpi on the 24th May. In the fort of Kalpi, the English captured a very considerable amount of military supplies which Shri Rao Sahib Peshwa and&#xA;Tatia Tope had, with great trouble, gathered together in one year. Sixty thousand pounds of gunpowder were found buried under the ground; muskets beautifully made, brass balls of the latest type for the guns, factories for making and repairing cannon-balls, heaps of military uniforms, flags, drums, French trumpets, Howitzer guns manufactured in Europe, and arms of various kind - such was the very useful find that the English army came upon! What they did not capture was the brave and ever-memorable leaders of the Revolutionaries. For, when Kalpi fell after a week, Rao Sahib, the Nabob of Banda, Ranee Lakshmi Bai, and other leaders had left Kalpi and gone - nobody knew where. But now these unfortunate, helpless people, without an army and without arms, could do nothing beyond falling into the jaws of death, either by privations, or ny capture, or ny suicide!&#xA;Thus Sir Colin had begun the reconquest from the northern bank of the Jumna, and went on conquering as far as the Himalayas. Sir Hugh Rose and Whitlock be.gan from the Narbada, and conquered all the country as far as the South bank of the Jumna. The English had now every reason to congratulate themselves that they had destroyed the Revolution completely. Sir Hugh Rose congratulated his army in these eloquent words :- &amp;ldquo;Soldiers, you have marched one thousand miles, captured one hundred guns, swam rivers, crossed mountains, marched through jungles, defeated big armies, reconquered extensive tracts, and reestablished the glory of your country! Brave you are; and you have also observed the strictest discipline; for courage without discipline is nought. In the midst of difficulties, temptations, and trouble, you have obeyed strictly the orders of your general, and have never showed even a single sign of insubordination. From the waters of the Narbada to the waters of the Jumna, this, your success, has come to you through your splendid discipline!&amp;rdquo;&#xA;After publishing this glorifying proclamation, Sir Hugh resigned his charge for the sake of his health. And the triumphant English army,&#xA;having destroyed the enemy completely, sighed the sigh of relief and wished to rest.&#xA;But how dare you rest yet? While Tatia and Ranee Lakshmi Bai are alive, there is no rest possible for the British troops. Come, stand up! And if you would not stand of your own accord, here is the whole force of Gwalior, ready to goad you on! After escaping from Kalpi, the Revolutionary leaders went to Gopalpur to discuss their future plans. Practically, at this time, there was not a sign of hope. From the Narbada to the Jumna, and from Jumna to the Himalayas, the English had conquered back the whole territory. The Revolutionaries were without an army, without a fort, without any hope of getting fresh forces - defeated as they were again and again. But Tatia Tope was still alive, and that was enough! Tatia, too, had returned to Gopalpur. People say he had returned after visiting his father. Whatever people say, history does not say so. It was when Sir Hugh tried his deep-laid game at Kalpi that Tatia had a sudden fit of fondness for his father - a fondness, by -the-bye, which seemed to exceed even his fondness for fight; and, no longer able to control his filial feelings, he want to Charkhi to see his father. What was the secret of this sudden passion? The secret was that, as soon as Kalpi fell, it was absolutely necessary to get hold of some other strong position, some strong fortress, and some new army. And, therefore, this Messenger of the Revolution had escaped from Kalpi secretly to enter Gwalior, and see how the Revolutionary idea was progressing there! He accepted the promises of the chief officers of the army and created a new army for the Revolution, by secretly winning over the Durbar functionaries, Sirdars, and others. They promised to give him all the aid they could, and in one month he had the whole of Gwalior in the hollow of his hand. He then collected every information about the military position of Gwalior and, thus, after undermining the throne of the Scindia, Tatia returned to Rao Sahib at Gopalpur. He had &amp;lsquo;seen his father&amp;rsquo;! Learning the glad news, that Tatia had come back from Gwalior having successfully won over the people to the sided of the Revolution, Ranee Lakshmi urged the Peshwa to advance straight towards Gwalior. On the 28th of May, the Revolutionaries came to Amin Mahal. The Mahalkars tried to stop them. They were answered, &amp;ldquo;Who are you to obstruct us? We are the Peshwa and his forces and we are fighting for Swaraj and Swadharma.&amp;rdquo; These words of Rao Sahib silenced the cowards, and thousands of patriots in that part welcomes the Revolutionaries heartily, and thus the army of the Peshwa pressed right on the walls of the city of Gwalior. They had written to the Scindia, &amp;ldquo;We are coming to you in a friendly spirit. Remember our former relations. We expect help from you, so that we shall be enabled to proceed towards the south.&amp;rdquo; But this ungrateful man had forgotten the former relations. Well then, remember the former and the present relations too! &amp;ldquo;The ancestors of the Scindia were our servants, our Hujres - that was the former relation. And, the present relation? The whole army of the present Scindia has joined us. Tatia had gone to Gwalior, seen the leaders, and gained all necessary information!&amp;rdquo; But still, forgetting all this the Scindia, with all his army and all his guns, advanced on the Peshwa on the 1st of June, near Gwalior. The Shrimant who deserves the respect of the whole country thought for a moment that the Scindia had repented and was coming forward to salute the flag of Swadesh. But, Lakshmi said that he was coming, not to salute, but to smash that golden flag. She came forward with her three hundred horsemen and advanced right on the guns of the Scindia. Soon, she caught the view of Jayaji Rao Scindia and his personal guard the brave&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Bhaleghate&amp;rdquo; troops. The cobra shows not such rage when it is trodden upon as Lakshmi showed at the sight of this traitor! Like an arrow she dashed at his troops. Behold, you Bahadur - descendant of Mahadaji, this helpless girl of twenty-two, brought up in the Zenana, is inving you for a trial of strength of the sword! Let us all see now how much of the prowess of Mahadaji, the&#xA;devoted lover of his country, has descended upon this Jayaji the devoted slave of the Feringhi! As soon as this angry lightning struck him hard on the front, his personal guards wavered and the Scindia, with all his &amp;ldquo;Bhaleghate&amp;rdquo; troops,was routed. But, at least, there was hope that his huge army and terrible artillery would do their best - and they did do their best! As soon as they saw Tatia, these troops which had been bound over by secret oaths to Tatia refused, point-blank, to fight against the Peshwa. As previously arranged, they joined the Peshwa with all their officers; the guns were silent and everyone in Gwalior honoured the flag of the Peshwa. The throne of the Scindia thus crumbled to pieces at the touch of the Revolutionary magician.&#xA;And so, Jayaji Rao Scindia, coward as he was, and his minister, Dinkar Rao, fled, not only from the field, but from Gwalior itself, and ran to Agra!&#xA;Gwalior, was now mad with joy. The army fired salutes in honour of the Shrimant. The Finance Minister, Amar Chand Bhatia, surrendered the whole treasury of the Scindia, to the last pie, to Shrimant. Those few patriots who were in prison under the old regime for having shown sympathy with the Revolutionaries were released from their prisons amidstthe joyous cries of the populace. The traitors who had advised the Scindia to join the English had fled, but their mansions and their property were destroyed so that not a vestige of them remained. The black charge that the Asiatics do not understand the true relation between a ruler and his subjects, was washed away completely by Gwalior. For, how can he who goes against his own country and against his own Dharma be a ruler? Poona had been in 1818 guilty of being a traitor to the motherland is not having dragged Rao Baji from his Peshwai in right time. Gwalior was not guilty of that! And therefore, this Revolution of 1857 must be recorded in history as the first indication in modern India of the omnipotence of the vox populi, the power of the people. If Scindia joins not his country, the country shall not aid him either. Swords and guns, infantry and cavalry, Durbar and Sirdars, Mankarees and citizens, temples and images - all are for the&#xA;country, alone; and if the Scindia is not for the country, drag him down from his throne; and outside the palace, outside the capital, outside the borders of the kingdom let him be driven out! Hereafter, according to the Scriptures, &amp;ldquo;The King receives his power only by pleasing the people!&amp;rdquo;&#xA;And now, we must not let this auspicious day, the 3rd of June, slip by uselessly. And so &amp;ldquo;a big Durbar was held in Phul Bagh. All Sirdars, statesmen noblemen, Shiledars, and cavalry officers, who had joined the Shrimant, took their seats according to their rank. Tatia Tope and the Arabs, Rohillas, Pathans, Rajputs, Rangdes, Pardeshis, and others under him came to the Durbar in their military uniform and with swords by their side. The Shrimant himself was dressed in the Peshwa&amp;rsquo;s uniform Shirpana and Kalgitura on head, pearls in his ears, and pearl and diamond necklaces, round his neck. Thus, with all the paraphernalia of the Peshwai, Bhaldars and Chobdars making way for him, and Mourchas flying, the Shrimant came to the Durbar. Then, as usual, all stood up in reverence, salutes were received, and the Shrimant ascended the throne. With tears of joy in his eyes, he congratulated all the noblemen with great eloquence. Ram Rao Govind was appointed Chief Minister. Tatia Tope was made general and a sword studded with precious stones was presented to him. The eight ministers were elected. Twenty lakhs of Rupees were distributed to the army. The Durbar was a complete success. Joy was on every face and salutes of guns were fired.&amp;ldquo;61&#xA;Shrimant Rao Sahib, representative of Nana Sahib Peshwa, had thus established a new throne, infusing a new hope and a new life into the Revolutionary party, and had created a centre, a basis, round which might be attracted the scattered forces of the Revolution. Tatia Tope was not mad in busying himself with this coronation and giving salutes after salutes just&#xA;61 D.B.Parasnis&amp;rsquo;s Life of Lakshmi Bai, page 309.&#xA;in a midst of the war. The whole world had seen the dead body of the Revolution which by this means alone he now lifted from the grave of despair. The world – some with pleasure and others with despair – had cried : “That is a dead body, there is no life in it!” But what wonderful magic this! Tatia took the dead earth at Gopalpur, he breathed on it thus, and – wonderful! – the whole world saw with the dumbness of surprise, a throne rising from the thimbleful of earth, jingling with lakhs of Rupees! Wonder of wonders! See the thousands of swordsmen advancing; hear the salutes thundering forth from the guns! A new army is up, new guns are up, Tatia has captured a new kingdom! Tatia has done all this not meely to strike the world dumb with his splendid triumph. He knew that the Revolutionaries who had spread far and wide would, on hearing the salutes proclaiming the Shrimant as a Peshwa of the Mahratta empire, get a concentrated inspiration, vigour, and hope. He knew that the sight of the triumphant flag of the nation, thus unfurled at Gwalior, would infuse an uncontrollable enthusiasm and dash. He knew that the lawlessness which had set in owing to the want of a rallying point, would now make way for discipline, through respect for the new-established throne. All this Tatia saw. And what he foresaw soon came to pass. For the body of the Panday party was soon instinct with life. While thus, on the one hand, his countrymen were encouraged, the English army, which just gave a sigh of relief, was, on the other hand, again disheartened. It was for this that the coronation was proclaimed loudly by Tatia and other leaders of the Revolution. Their deep- laid game was successful. For, by this very thunder of Tatia&amp;rsquo;s cannon, Sir Hugh Rose&amp;rsquo;s idea of rest was rudely shattered to pieces!62&#xA;62 Malleson, writing about the cleverness and diplomacy which Tatia and Lakshmi Bai showed in taking Gwalior, says :- &amp;ldquo;How the &amp;ldquo;Impossible&amp;rdquo; happened has been told &amp;hellip;. He&#xA;(Sir Hugh Rose) realised, moreover, the great danger which would inevitably be caused by&#xA;delay. No one could foresee the extent of evil possible if Gwalior were not promptly wrested&#xA;from rebel hands. Grant them delay, and Tatia Tope, with the immense acquisition of political&#xA;and military strength secured by the possession of Gwalior, and with all its resources in men,&#xA;So far so good; but once having shocked Sir Hugh Rose and disheartened him, woe betide him who listened not to the words of Ranee Lakshmi Bai! All other functions but the one great function of war must be stopped. But it seemed that, as ill-luck would have it, the intoxication of the Revolutionaries would make them blind to the necessity of heeping the army in complete readiness. They were all immersed in luxury, good dinners, and fatal dilatoriness – they thought, perhaps, that this was the sole end of Swaraj!&#xA;They were onlo losing Swaraj. For, the surprised Sir Hugh Rose marched rapidly on Gwalior with his excellent army under him. He brought with him the renegade Scindia and proclaimed to all that the English were going to fight only for the Scindia’s sake! It was a trick to deceive the simple men of Gwalior, who had the slavish and discreditable merit of blind loyalty, and it was calculated to prevent these from fighting against the Scindia. But the old world had changed, giving place to the new. Tatia, so far successful in awakening the Revolutionaries,&#xA;rushed forward to meet the English. The English had already defeated the Morar contingents. Now, with the shadow of defeat on them, there began some excited movements among the Revolutionary leaders. Rao Sahib was hastening towards the house of the Nabob of Banda and the Nabob of Banda was rushing towards the house of Rao Sahib. But, in the midst of all this confusion, the Ranee alone was calm and was ready. Her sword was out. What need she fear now? Hope as well as despair she had trampled under&#xA;money and material at his disposal, would be able to form a new army on the fragments of that&#xA;beaten at Kalpi, and to provoke a Mahratta rising throughout India. It might be possible for&#xA;him, using the dexterity of which he was a master, to unfurl the Peshwa&amp;rsquo;s banner in the&#xA;southern Mahratta districts. Those districts were denudedof troops, and a striking success in&#xA;Central India would probably decide their inhabitants to pronounce in favour of the cause for&#xA;which their fathers had fought and bled.&amp;rdquo; - Malleson&amp;rsquo;s Indian Mutiny, Vol. V, pages 149-150.&#xA;foot; she treated with contempt the things on this earth; she had one aspiration alone, namely, that the flag of liberty should stand proudly erect until she gave up her last breath! Neither of them were to be in the dust; they were to lie in battle alone. So, she gave Rao Sahib a word of courage, rearranged the undisciplined troops as far as she could, and took upon herself the task of guarding the eastern gate. She only demanded, &amp;ldquo;I am ready with all my soul to do my duty; mind, you do yours!&amp;rdquo;&#xA;She donned her usual military uniform, rode a noble steed, took out her gem-bestudded sword from the sheath, and ordered the army under her to march on. She made ready all the posts near Kotaki Serai which had been given to her care and, when the English army was in sight, everywhere, trumpets and pipes, drums and nagaras rent the air. If only she had an army, equal in courage and daring to herself! Even the insubordinate and hesitating felt heroic under her influence and, with them and her select band of horsemen, she charged hard the English army! Her two female friends, Mandar and Kashi, also fought bravely by her side. May the sweet memory of those two patriotic girls - beautiful in appearance, with male attire put on, taking pleasure in fight - live in history along with that of their mistress as long as history lives! A general like Smith was charging the Ranee&amp;rsquo;s army, but to-day the Ranee&amp;rsquo;s bravery and daring were a sight to see. Like lightning, she moved about all day. The English attacked the solid phalanx a number of times. One very occasion she maintained her hold firm. Her army occasionally felt enthusiastic and attacked the British and cut down many of them. At last, Smith was forced to retire; he gave up the attempt of breaking the mass and began to turn to another side, leaving the nest of the cobra alone!&#xA;Thus closed the day and thus rose the 18th of the month! This day, the English had resolved to make desperate charges. From all directions, they advanced on the fort, and tried their utmost. General Smith, forced to retire the day before, was very determined to-day and, aided by re- inforcements, he charged the same Jhansi side he had gone for the day&#xA;before. Sir Hugh Rose thought that his presence was also absolutely necessary and so he was personally present with the force attacking the Jhansi side. The Ranee too was ready for him with all her forces. &amp;ldquo;She&#xA;was ready with all her soul to do her duty.&amp;rdquo; That day, she wore a Chanderi turban embroidered all over, a tamamee cloak, and pyjamas. A pearl necklace was round her neck. Her famous steed being tired that day, a new, fresh-looking horse was made ready for her, fully caparisoned. While her two beautiful maids were taking sherbet, news came that the English were advancing. Lakshmi immediately darted forwarded from her tent. The arrow flies not so rapidly, the lightning flashes not forth with such force from the clouds, a lioness leaves not her lair so quickly to fall upon the approaching elephant! She rode her horse, lifted her sword, and charged the enemy with her army. As English writer says, &amp;ldquo;Immediately the beautiful Ranee went over the field and made a firm stand against the array of Sir Hugh Rose. She led her troops to repeated and fierce attacks and, though her ranks were pierced through and were gradually becoming thinner and thinner, the Ranee was seen in the foremost rank, rallying her shattered troops and performing prodigies of valour. But all was of no avail. The camel corps, pushed up by Shri Huge Rose in person, broke her last line. Still the dauntless and heroic Ranee held her own.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;But while her side was fighting with such unexampled bravery, she saw the English army advancing on her rear - for they had broken through the ranks of Revolutionaries who were holding the posts behind her!&#xA;The artillery dumb, the main army routed, the victorious English army closing on her from all sides, with only fifteen or twenty horsemen with her, Ranee Lakshmi, accompanied by her maids, put her horse to a gallop, in order to break through the enemy, and to join her comrades on the other side. The Feringhi horsemen of the Hussars, who knew not so far where she was, fired shot after shot on her and pursued her like hounds. But the Queen, with unexampled courage, cleared her way with her sword and&#xA;marched on. Suddenly was heard a cry, &amp;ldquo;I am dead, Bai Sahib, I am dead!&amp;rdquo; Alas, whose is this cry? Lakshmi turned round and found that it was her maid Mandar whom a white soldier had shot and killed! Angered, she attacked the Feringhi, and her blow felled him on the spot. She had avenged the death of fair Mandar! She then marched on. She came to a small rill. Now, one jump and Jhansi would have been out of the Feringhi&amp;rsquo;s clutches. But her horse would not take that jump! If only she had had her old horse! As if the fiery line of a magician was round him the horse moved in circles, round and round, but would not cross. Before you could say &amp;ldquo;one&amp;rdquo;, the English horsemen closed on her! Still not a word of surrender or fear! One sword against their several swords, - yet she closed on them. She crossed sword with sword with them all, but one of them hit her on the head from behind. With that blow, the right part of her head, and even her&#xA;right eye came out - just then, another blow hit her on the chest. Oh Lakshmi, Lakshmi! The last drop of thy sacred blood is dripping and, therefore, now, Mother, take this last sacrifice for thee! Even at the point of death, she killed the British foe who had attacked her, and now the young Queen was breathing her last breath! A faithful servant, Ramchandra Rao Deshmukh, was near. He took her to a cottage near by. Ganga Das Bawa gave her cold water to drink to quench her thirst and a bed to lie down upon. Bathed in blood, this goddess of war reclined on the bed, and then her soul quietly fleeteed from her body to heaven! As soon as she was dead, Ramchandra Rao, in accordance with her dying instructions prepared a pile of grass unseen by the enemy; he put her on that pure and, before the touch of slavery could defile even her dead body, she was cremated.&#xA;On the pyre, if not on the throne! But Lakshmi is still with her sweetheart Liberty! She has forced open the gates of death by falling in battle and has now entered the other world. Pursuit can no longer harm her. Wicked Pursuit must pass through those roaring flames before it can do so.&#xA;Thus fought Lakshmi. She had achieved her purpose, fulfilled her ambition, carried out her resolve! One such life vindicates the whole existence of a nation! She was the concentrated essence of all virtues. A mere woman, hardly twenty-three yet, beautiful as rose, charming in her manners, pure of conduct, she had a power of organisation of her subjects, exhibited by very few, even among men. The flame of patriotism was always burning in her heart. And she proud of her country&amp;rsquo;s honour and pre- eminent in war! It is very rarely that a nation is so fortunate as to be able to claim such an angelic person, as a daughter and a queen. That honour has not yet fallen to the lot of England. In the Revolution of Italy, high ideals and heroism of the very highest type are to be found; yet, in all this period of glody, Italy could not give birth to Lakshmi!&#xA;But, even our land could hardly have given birth to such a Queen but for this glorious War of Independence! The precious pearls in the ocean are not to be found on its surface. The Suryakanta jewel does not give out flames in the quiet of the night; nor does the flint give up its spark on soft cushions. They want resistance. Injustice must make the mind restless; really, not apparently, every drop of blood most actually boil; intense national feeling is thus set aflane in such a furnace, the particles of virtue begin to flow, the test goes on, the dross is eliminated, then, the concentrated essence of virtues begins to appear. In 1857, the heart of this our Motherland took fire; then, a terrible explosion which would deafen the world took place; - A spark at Meerut, and the whole country, which, under the roller of Dalhousie, had been reduced to the monotony of a dead level and seemed to be a heap of dust, proved to be a powder-magazine filled with the most inflammable material. Just as when a mighty rocket in a fireplay, fired in the air, explodes, arrows and trees and various other picturesque objects rise and rush and burn and die away, such was the case of this gigantic Revolutionary Rocket! Its length is from Meerut to the Vindhyas; its width from Peshawar to Dumdum;- and it was fired! Fire and flames raged in all directions. Blood coming down like rain, - sieges of Delhi,&#xA;revenges of Plassey, massacres of Cawnpore, and the Sikandar Bagh of Lucknow! Thousands of heroes are fighting - and dying; cities are burning. Kumar Singh comes, struggles, falls; the Moulvie comes, struggles, and falls; the throne of Cawnpore, the throne of Lucknow, the throne of Delhi, the throne of Bareilly, the throne of Jagadishpur, the throne of Jhansi, the throne of Banda, the throne of Furrukabad, five thousand, ten thousand, fifty thousand, a lakh of swords, flags, banners, generals, horses, elephants - all are coming out out after another, move about in the turmoil of the raging fire! Some are ascending one flame, some another; they poise themselves a while, reel, fight, fall down unseen! Everywhere battle and thunder-storms! A veritable volcanic conflagration this! And the pyre, flaming near the cottage of Gangadas Bawa, is the last and the most lustrous flame of this raging volcanic conflagration of the War of Independence of 1857!&#xA;END OF THE THIRD PART&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
