<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Y-haplogroups on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/genetics/Y-haplogroups/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Y-haplogroups on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/genetics/Y-haplogroups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>African background</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/genetics/Y-haplogroups/African_background/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/genetics/Y-haplogroups/African_background/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The great father in Africa belonged to the the E1b-M180 clade. His descendants in thre1e great spurts from around 5300-4800 YBP expanded among the speakers of Niger-Congo languages and spread across the vast African continent. .. It is likely that the E1b-M180 lineage arose there and then penetrated deep into sub-Saharan Africa as the Niger-Congo languages diversified. Its initial expansions could have been triggered by the events of the emergence of civilization in the Egyptian cultural zone, with its bearers subsequently acquiring high status in the sub-Saharan milieu east and west.&#xA;[&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2016/05/08/the-giants-among-the-lilliputs/&#34;&gt;M16&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>H1</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/genetics/Y-haplogroups/H1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/genetics/Y-haplogroups/H1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;H1 in contrast is hardly present in Sino-Tibetan and Eastern populations. Its centre gravity in terms of frequency is the central part of the country from where it appears to have expanded outwards. We explain H1 expansion as an expansion of agricultural indigenous population associated with Central and South Indian archaeological cultures like Jorwe and Daimabad and these agricultural groups managed ascend the ladder of the Indo-Aryan hierarchy coming in from the North.&amp;rdquo;[&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/12/20/socio-genetic-stratification-of-india/&#34;&gt;MT5&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L1</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/genetics/Y-haplogroups/L1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/genetics/Y-haplogroups/L1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;L1 marker is predominant in Tamils and to some extant in Marathas, with the most prevalent presence in Tamil middle castes like Vellalars, Vanniyars, Ambalavasis and the like. It is low or absent in most of the Dravidian tribal groups outside Tamil Nad, though it is present in Brahmins in the Tamil region. It is also peculiarly found in Balochistan and Makran but low in the Brahui speakers. &amp;quot; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/12/20/socio-genetic-stratification-of-india/&#34;&gt;MT5&lt;/a&gt;]&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kallars, a middle level warrior Tamil caste, has up to 50% L1 markers. L1 haplogroup is also found in the Yadava caste, a group of cowherds from from the Andhra country (the clan of the famous cowherd hero kATaM rAju) show about 19%, Kammas of Andhra 17%, so also the Sinhalese show about 17% of it. &amp;quot; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/12/25/chenchus-lambadis-and-the-l1-haplogroup/&#34;&gt;M0512&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;L1 which is restricted to Tamil population but seen across caste boundaries albeit with the greatest presence in the middle-low castes is interpreted as not being spread by the Dravidians. As most Dravidian tribals have it lower levels and it is absent in Dravidians outside Tamilnad we specifically see at the haplogroup expanded by the proto-Tamil cultural rennaisance, probably archaeologically corresponding to the expansion of the Megalithic (neDukkal/vira-kal) culture. This appears to have expanded from the middle of the peninsular India somewhat Northwards to coastal Pakistan and Makran and of course its main center was the Tamil country. This expansion possibly also bore with it the H1 marker, further driving it up the caste hierarchy.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/12/20/socio-genetic-stratification-of-india/&#34;&gt;MT5&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;We suspect that the Tamil upper castes absorbed native priests as kurukals and the like that resulted in the influx of L1 into their ranks.&amp;rdquo;[&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/12/20/socio-genetic-stratification-of-india/&#34;&gt;MT5&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The later point is illustrated by the fact that in Brahmins of Tamil Nad, Andhra and Maharashtra (the Konkanastha Brahmins) the L1 haplogroup is seen in 10-13% frequency. Most interestingly, the Saurashtrans who are an immigrant group into Tamil Nad from the Gujarat-Maharastra zone show upto 25% frequency of the L1 marker. This is in fact in contrast to the overall level of L1 in Gujarat being around 10% (Albeit a relatively small sample of 29 males), and in general in Maharashtran upper and middle castes around 10-11%. Thus, despite retaining their unique language of the Indo-Aryan family, the Saurashtrans have acquired a considerable component from the Tamil gene pool (lower bound of 15%). This suggests that even the rather insulated Saurashtrian jAti was genetically porous to a certain degree. Probably the Saurashtran jAti’s tight connection with certain professional guilds strongly preserved its language while letting people in.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/12/25/chenchus-lambadis-and-the-l1-haplogroup/&#34;&gt;M0512&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>O2a</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/genetics/Y-haplogroups/O2a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/genetics/Y-haplogroups/O2a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot; The O2a marker is seen in all tribal groups but hardly in any caste groups, suggesting that it was indeed one of the markers of the earliest population. In contrast to O2a, H1 while highest in the tribal populations is also seen in caste population in a declining gradient. It was in this early population that probably Austro-Asiatic, Nahali, Kusunda and possibly Indo-Pacific languages arose. Of these the Austro-Asiatic and Dravidian languages showed an expansion. .. Both the frequency and variance plots of the O2a haplogroup show an increasing Eastern component. This would imply that its expansion was probably associated with an Eastern population expansion and emigration. The expansion probably corresponded with the Austro-Asiatic expansion.&amp;quot;[&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/12/20/socio-genetic-stratification-of-india/&#34;&gt;MT5&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R1 clade: Background information</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/genetics/Y-haplogroups/R1_clade_Background_information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/genetics/Y-haplogroups/R1_clade_Background_information/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;R1 clade: Background information&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;haplogroup-r&#34;&gt;Haplogroup R&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;23andme: &amp;ldquo;Haplogroup R is a widespread and diverse branch of the Y-chromosome tree that is extremely common in Europe, where it spread after the end of the Ice Age about 12,000 years ago. The haplogroup appears to have originated in southwestern Asia about 30,000 years ago. It then split into two main branches. R1 ultimately spread widely across Eurasia, from Iceland to Japan, whereas R2 mostly remained near its region of origin. Today it can be found in southwestern Asia and India.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;haplogroup-r1&#34;&gt;Haplogroup R1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;23andme: &amp;ldquo;R1 is the dominant haplogroup in Europe today, accounting for well over half of all men. After being confined to the continent&amp;rsquo;s southern fringes during the Ice Age, it expanded rapidly in the wake of the receding glaciers about 12,000 years ago. &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;haplogroup-r1a-and-r1b&#34;&gt;Haplogroup R1a and R1b&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;R1a and perhaps R2 expanded in the Central/Western Asian zone close to the boundary of the Eurasian steppes somewhere between 10-15,000 years BP. These two seem to have then seeped into India at a gradual rate seeding the indigenous tribal groups with R1a1 males at some low rate. The main bulk of the less diverse R1a1 appears to have come from Western/Central Eurasia along with the other above-mentioned Western Eurasian markers where it had already differentiated into eastern and western branches. The time of divergence with the central Asian R1a1 comes to around 6000-10000yrs bp.&amp;rdquo;[&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/12/20/socio-genetic-stratification-of-india/&#34;&gt;MT5&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
