<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Financial services on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Financial services on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hawala</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/hawala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/hawala/</guid>
      <description>Modus operandi   hawala    A customer (A, left-hand side) approaches a hawala broker (X) in one city and gives a sum of money (red arrow) that is to be transferred to a recipient (B, right-hand side) in another, usually foreign, city. Along with the money, he usually specifies something like a password that will lead to the money being paid out (blue arrows). The hawa calls another hawala broker M in the recipient&amp;rsquo;s city, and informs M about the agreed password, or gives other disposition of the funds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/trading_infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/trading_infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Securities Exchanges Stock markets provide a regulated/ facilitated environment for carrying out securities transactions/ trades. It operates in fixed trading hours - beyond those hours, brokers may trade on their amongst themselves in extended trading hours.
Brokerages Every trade is accomplished by agents/ brokers authorized to trade in the stock market - usually on behalf of their customers. A fraction of each trade is usually collected by the stock exchange as fees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insurance</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/insurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/insurance/</guid>
      <description>Insurance products, besides serving the main purpose of hedging to counter financial risk, often also function as investment in mutual funds.
Functioning As security This business takes advantage of the fact that risk of a particular kind (house burning down, theft, death), affects a small fraction of a population at any given time, with very high probability. So, it collects fees/ premiums from a large number of insured people, and compensates those on whom a bad event befalls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermediary trading</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/intermediary_trading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/financial_services/intermediary_trading/</guid>
      <description>Basic negotiable securities tradings actions are considered elsewhere.
Role in markets Intermediary traders buy and sell items, holding them for a short time while it changes hands between long-term investors. In doing so, they make a profit.
So, they focus strongly on the guessing and taking advantage of the motives of investors - aka front-running investors.
Liquidity, cost The benefit they provide is in bringing greater liquidity to assets, buy supplying a sea of ready purchasing and selling power.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>