<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Mon &amp; Khmer on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austro-asiatic/mon-khmer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Mon &amp; Khmer on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austro-asiatic/mon-khmer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Champa &amp; Kinh</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austro-asiatic/mon-khmer/champa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austro-asiatic/mon-khmer/champa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;thumbnail&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;../../images/vietnam_champa_1100.gif&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;../../images/vietnam_champa_1100.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;        Champa 1100&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chinese-influence&#34;&gt;Chinese influence&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Muong/ monglong and Kinh (ethnic Vietnamese) separation happened when the proto-Vietnamese became heavily Sinicised, beginning from the 111 BC invasion by Chinese Emperor Wu of Han, while the Muong, living in the mountains, developed independently. &amp;hellip; The Muong and the Tai have had a mutual influence on each other&amp;rsquo;s culture.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;An official successfully revolted against Chinese rule in central Vietnam, and Lâm Ấp was founded in AD 192. &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Kinh continued to be influenced culturally by Chinese, despite being geographically, linguistically and genetically Southeast Asian.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;genetics&#34;&gt;Genetics&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;While Northern Vietnam Kinh people assimilated Han Chinese immigrants into their population, have a sinicized culture and carry the patrilineal Han Chinese O-M7 haplogroup, Cham people carry the patrilineal R-M17 haplogroup of South Asian Indian origin from South Asian merchants spreading Hinduism to Champa and marrying Cham females since Chams have no matrilineal South Asian mtdna and this fits with the matrilocal structure of Cham families.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot; Analysis of Vietnamese Kinh people&amp;rsquo;s genetics show that within the last 800 years there was mixture between a Malay like southern Asian and a Chinese ancestral component that happens to fit the time period in which Kinh expanded south from their Red river delta homeland in Nam tiến which also matches the event 700 years ago when the Cham population suffered massive losses.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hindu-expression&#34;&gt;Hindu expression&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Champa principalities underwent the process of Indianization since the early common era as a result of centuries of socio-economic interaction adopted and introduced cultural and institutional elements of pre-Islamic India.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hinduism was established as Champa began to create Sanskrit stone inscriptions and erect red brick Hindu temples. The first king acknowledged in the inscriptions is Bhadravarman, who reigned from AD 380 to AD 413. At Mỹ Sơn, King Bhadravarman established a linga called Bhadresvara. Rudravarman of Champa founded a new dynasty in 529 CE and was succeeded by his son, Shambhuvarman. He reconstructed the temple of Bhadravarman and renamed it to Shambhu-bhadreshvara. He died in 629 and was succeeded by his son, Kandarpadharma, who died in 630-31. Kandarpadharma was succeeded by his son, Prabhasadharma, who died in 645.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is acknowledged that the historical record is not equally rich for each of the regions in every historical period. For example, in the 10th century AD, the record is richest for Indrapura; in the 12th century AD, it is richest for Vijaya; following the 15th century AD, it is richest for Panduranga.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Before the conquest of Champa by the Đại Việt emperor Trần Thánh Tông in 1471, the dominant religion of the Cham people was Hinduism, and the culture was heavily influenced by that of India. The Hinduism of Champa was overwhelmingly Shaiva and it was liberally combined with elements of local religious cults such as the worship of the Earth goddess Lady Po Nagar. The main symbols of Cham Shaivism were the lingam, the mukhalinga, the jaṭāliṅgam, the segmented liṅgam, and the kośa.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;khmer-relations&#34;&gt;Khmer relations&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;In 1177, the Cham and their allies launched an attack from the lake Tonlé Sap and managed to sack the Khmer capital. In 1181, however, they were defeated by the Khmer King Jayavarman VII.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Despite the frequent wars between Champa and Cambodia, the two countries also traded and cultural influences moved in both directions. Royal families of the two countries intermarried frequently.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;srivijaya-relations&#34;&gt;Srivijaya relations&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Champa also had close trade and cultural relations with the powerful maritime empire of Srivijaya and later with the Majapahit of the Malay Archipelago. &amp;hellip;  Aceh confirms that a very strong Champan cultural influence existed in Indonesia; this is indicated by the use of the Chamic language Acehnese as the main language in the coastal regions of Aceh.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;the rising influence of Champa caught the attention of a neighbouring thalassocracy that considered Champa as a rival, the Javanese (Javaka, probably refers to Srivijaya ruler of Malay Peninsula, Sumatra and Java). In AD 767, the Tonkin coast was raided by a Javanese fleet (Daba) and Kunlun pirates &amp;hellip; &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;islamification&#34;&gt;Islamification&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;From the 8th century onward trade and shipping of India came to be increasingly controlled by Muslims from such regions as Gujarat. Islamic ideas became a part of the vast tide of exchange, treading the same path as Hinduism and Buddhism centuries before. &amp;hellip; Ad-Dimashqi writes in 1325, &amp;ldquo;the country of Champa&amp;hellip; is inhabited by Muslims and idolaters. The Muslim religion came there during the time of Caliph Uthman&amp;hellip; and Ali, many Muslims who were expelled by the Umayyads and by Hajjaj, fled there&amp;rdquo;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot; it was not until 17th century that Islam began to attract large numbers of Chams, when some members of the Cham royalty converted to Islam. &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Indonesian 15th century records indicate the influence of Princess Daravati, a Cham, converted to Islam,[38] and influenced her husband, Kertawijaya, Majapahit&amp;rsquo;s seventh ruler to convert the Majapahit royal family to Islam. &amp;hellip; In the 15th to 17th century, Muslim Cham maintained a cordial relationship with the Aceh Sultanate through dynastic marriage.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;History &lt;a href=&#34;../../../paganology/vietnam/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Physical evidence of Cham culture in Vietnam is disappearing. In Binh Thuan Province and elsewhere, Cham temple sites and ancient tombs have been overrun by paddies, dragonfruit plantations, and shrimp farms. In Quang Ngai Province, temple sites have been damaged or destroyed by gravel quarrying. The Vietnamese continue to build Buddhist temples atop the ruins of Cham religious sites and to use bricks from Cham citadels to build their houses. Hill tribes relocated from the far north of Vietnam now live in Champa&amp;rsquo;s last capital, Song Luy, brought down during Minh Mang&amp;rsquo;s purge. &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;khatib-sumat-jihad&#34;&gt;Khatib Sumat jihAd&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Chams were led by a Islamic clergyman from Cambodia named Katip (Khatib) Sumat, who had spent many years studying Islam in Kelantan. Apparently, upon hearing that Champa was under attack by the Nguyen army, Katip Sumat immediately returned. Arriving in Binh Thuan in 1833, he was accompanied by a large force of Malays and Chams from Kelantan. Katip Sumat led the Chams in a series of guerrilla attacks against the Nguyen army. Apart from fighting for the survival of Champa, Katip Sumat invoked the Islamic bond in rallying Malay and Cham support for the cause. In some ways this turned the Cham struggle against the Vietnamese into a form of religious war. 39 The Katip Sumat-led resistance, however, was defeated by the Nguyen army.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Khmer</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austro-asiatic/mon-khmer/khmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austro-asiatic/mon-khmer/khmer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Khmer are Austronesians. ~5% of Cambodian ancestry seems to be Indian. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.unz.com/gnxp/the-indian-ocean-as-humanitys-pond/#comment-1555053&#34;&gt;RK16&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Khmer have historically been a lowland people who lived close to one of the tributaries of the Mekong River.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;legends&#34;&gt;Legends&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;10CE inscription: Khmer race arose from the union of the brahmin Kambu Swayambhuva and the apsara (&amp;ldquo;celestial nymph&amp;rdquo;) Mera. Their marriage is said to have given rise to the name Kambujas/ Khmer and founded the Varman dynasty of ancient Cambodia.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cambodia was created when an Indian Brahmin priest named Kaundinya (commonly referred to as Preah Thoang) married Princess Soma, a Naga (Khmer: neak) princess.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;kingdoms&#34;&gt;Kingdoms&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nokor Phnom / Mountain kingdom / Funan was an ancient (50-500CE) Indianised state—or, rather a loose network of states (Mandala).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Originally one of the regional centers of Funan with an unknown degree of sovereignty, Chenla was recognized by a foreign power as a separate political entity at the end of the sixth century, Bhavavarman I its independent ruler.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The rival Khmer Chenla Kingdom emerged in the fifth century and later conquered the Kingdom of Funan. Chenla was an upland state whose economy was reliant on agriculture whereas Funan was a lowland state with an economy dependent on maritime trade.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jayavarman II(802–830) establishes the named Khmer/ Angkor Empire, founding three capitals—Indrapura, Hariharalaya, and Mahendraparvata&amp;hellip; Suryavarman I (reigned 1002–1050) turned his forces eastward and subjugated the Mon kingdom of Dvaravati. &amp;hellip; After the death of Suryavarman II (1113–50), Cambodia lapsed into chaos until Jayavarman VII (1181–1218) ordered the construction of a new city. He was a Buddhist, and for a time, Buddhism became the dominant religion in Cambodia. As a state religion, however, it was adapted to suit the Deva Raja cult, with a Buddha Raja being substituted for the former Shiva Raja or Vishnu Raja.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;decline&#34;&gt;Decline&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The rise of the Tai kingdoms of Sukhothai (1238) and Ayutthaya (1350) resulted in almost ceaseless wars with the Cambodians and led to the destruction of Angkor in 1431. They are said to have carried off 90,000 prisoners &amp;hellip; The period following 1432, with the Cambodian people bereft of their treasures, documents, and human culture bearers, was one of precipitous decline.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;In 1434, King Ponhea Yat made Phnom Penh his capital, and Angkor was abandoned to the jungle. &amp;hellip; &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Due to continued Siamese and Vietnamese aggression, Cambodia appealed to France for protection in 1863 and became a French protectorate in 1864. During the 1880s, along with southern Vietnam and Laos, Cambodia was drawn into the French-controlled Indochinese Union.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-religion&#34;&gt;Current religion&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Modern Khmer strongly identify their ethnic identity with their religious beliefs and practices, which combine the tenets of Theravada Buddhism with elements of indigenous ancestor-spirit worship, animism and shamanism. &amp;hellip; &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mon</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austro-asiatic/mon-khmer/mon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austro-asiatic/mon-khmer/mon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Aka Talaing, Peguans, Raman (ရာမန်) from pALi Rāmañña(ရာမည)-desha, their heartland in burmese coast. The Tailang name suggests that they may have had some Indian Telanga ancestry.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Mon adapted pallava alphabet.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;religion&#34;&gt;Religion&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They became theravAda bauddha-s.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;spirit-cult&#34;&gt;Spirit cult&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Other than language, the most distinctive cultural characteristic of the Mons was the spirit cult. Halliday said that one of the distinguishiug marks of a Mon, without which one could not be a Mon, was interest in house spirits. 32 These spirits are quite characteristic; the Thais have nothing even remotely similar to the best of my knowledge. They are totemic-like spirits that are inherited in the male line, as indicated above. &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;kingdoms&#34;&gt;Kingdoms&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They founded Dvaravati in Central Thailand (including Lavo or lavapura), Sri Gotapura[16] in central Laos.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Along Andaman sea, they founded the Thaton kingdom.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The legendary Queen Camadevi from the Chao Phraya River Valley, as told in the Northern Thai Chronicle Cāmadevivaṃsa and other sources, came to rule as the first queen of Hariphunchai (modern Lamphun) kingdom around 800 AD.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;decline-in-chao-phraya-valley&#34;&gt;Decline in Chao Phraya Valley&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;After 1000 AD onwards, the Mon were under constant pressure with the Tai peoples migrating from the north and Khmer invasions from the Khmer Empire in the east.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Mons of Dvaravati gave their way to the Lavo Kingdom by around 1000 AD. A significant portion of Mon of the Dvaravati fled west to present-day Lower Burma. Descendants of the Dvaravati Mon people are the Nyah Kur people of present-day Isan (IshAnya-thailand). The Mon as an entity virtually disappeared in Chao Phraya Valley. However, Hariphunchai kingdom survived as a Mon outpost in northern Thailand under repeated harassment by the Northern Thai people.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hariphunchai prospered in the reign of King Aditayaraj (around early twelfth century), who allegedly waged wars with Suryavarman II of Angkor and constructed the Hariphunchai stupa. In 1230, Mangrai, the Northern Thai chief, conquered Hariphunchai and the Mon culture was integrated into Lanna culture. The Lanna adopted the Mon script and religion.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;decline-in-burma&#34;&gt;Decline in Burma&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;In 1057, King Anawrahta of Pagan Kingdom conquered the Thaton Kingdom. The Mon culture and the Mon script were readily absorbed by the Burmese and the Mons, for the first time, came under Bamar rule. The Mon remained a majority in Lower Burma.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wareru, who was born from a Mon mother and a Tai father eloped with the dauther of the (pagan) king&amp;hellip; His Hanthawaddy Kingdom (1287–1539) was a prosperous period for the Mon in both power and culture. The Mon were consolidated under King Rajathiraj (1383–1422), who successfully fended off invasions by the Bamar Ava Kingdom. The reigns of Queen Shin Sawbu (1453–1472) and King Dhammazedi (1472–1492) were a time of peace and prosperity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hanthawaddy fell to the invasion of Bamar King Tabinshwehti of Taungoo in 1539. After the death of the king, the Mon were temporarily freed from Bamar rule by Smim Htaw, but they were defeated by King Bayinnaung in 1551. The Bamar moved their capital to Bago, keeping the Mon in contact with royal authority. Over the next two hundred years, the Mon of Lower Burma came under Bamar rule.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Mon rebelled in 1661 but the rebellion was put down by King Pye Min. &amp;hellip; Mon rebelled again at Bago in 1740 with the help of the Gwe Shan people. A Bamar monk with Taungoo royal lineage was proclaimed king of Bago and was later succeeded by Binnya Dala in 1747&amp;hellip;. Alaungpaya, the Bamar ruler U Aungzeya, invaded and devastated the kingdom, killing tens of thousands of Mon, including learned Mon priests, pregnant women, and children. Over 3000 priests were massacred by the victorious Bamar in the capital city alone.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;thai-refuge&#34;&gt;Thai refuge&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;By 1584, Phraya Kiat and Phraya Ram joined Naresuan’s campaigns against the Bamar&amp;rsquo;s Toungoo court. A Mon monk became a chief advisor to King Naresuan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;During all the setbacks in Burma, Mon, either forced or voluntarily, moved to Ayutthaya (now Siam or Thailand).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mon refugees were granted residence in western Siam by the Siamese king. The Mons then played a major role in Siamese military and politics&amp;hellip; A special regiment was created for the Mon serving the Siamese king.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;On the one hand in Siam side, after the fall of Ayutthaya in 1767, two descendants of Mon aristocrats; Phraya Pichai and Phraya Chakri became the left and right hand man of King Taksin of Thonburi, and they largely helped Taksin&amp;rsquo;s campaigns in the liberation of Siam from Burmese occupation and reunion of Siam. After the collapse of Taksin&amp;rsquo;s Thonburi Kingdom, Phraya Chakri founded the Chakri Dynasty and ascended the throne in 1782 as Rama I. Rama I was born to Thongdi, a leading Mon nobleman serving the royal court in Ayutthaya in 1737. Rama I&amp;rsquo;s queen consort Amarindra was born to a wealthy Mon family who migrated to Siam in the earlier times. &amp;hellip;. When a huge wave of Mon migrations from Burma (now Myanmar) to Siam (now Thailand) happened in 1814, His grandson, the Child-Prince Mongkut (later Rama IV) proceeded to welcome the Mon himself at the Siam-Burma border.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;assimilation-into-thais&#34;&gt;Assimilation into Thais&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Over time, the Mons were effectively integrated into Siamese society and culture, although maintaining some of their traditions and identity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Change was apparently pretty slow&amp;hellip; A nirat of Sun thorn Phu, which deplores the loss of Mon cultural characteristics in Pakret; this would probably have been before 1850. It specifically refers to women&amp;rsquo;s hair style, which does not seem like a very profound change. We know from Halliday and Graham that by the early twentieth century most Mons were bilingual in Thai and Mon 36 ; we also know from Halliday that by the early twentieth century they built their houses like the Thais,37 and that their language had experienced strong lexical influence from the Thai language38 But really rapid change, by which people began to lose the language and to lose virtually all their Mon identity, probably did not begin until World War II. &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;A further revealing aspect of marriage is that the Mons and Thais do not seem to think of each other as of significantly diff erent ethnic groups for purposes of marriage. Many times people have told me that they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have their children marry into a different ethnic group (khon tang chaat} (e.g., Thai-Islam, Cambodian, or Chinese), but that Thai would be all right. &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vietnam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austro-asiatic/mon-khmer/vietnam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austro-asiatic/mon-khmer/vietnam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-history&#34;&gt;Early history&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;../champa/&#34;&gt;Cham page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;christian-invasion&#34;&gt;Christian invasion&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;French navy intervened in 1834 with the aim to free imprisoned Catholic missionaries from a kingdom that was perceived as xenophobic against foreign influence. Vietnam&amp;rsquo;s kingdom independence was then gradually eroded by France which was aided by the Spanish and large Catholic militias in a series of military conquests between 1859 and 1885. In 1862, the southern third of the country became the French colony of Cochinchina. By 1884, the entire country had come under French rule, with the central and northern parts of Vietnam separated in the two protectorates of Annam and Tonkin. The three Vietnamese entities were formally integrated into the union of French Indochina in 1887.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Guerrillas of the royalist Cần Vương movement massacred around a third of Vietnam&amp;rsquo;s Christian population during the colonial period as part of their rebellion against French rule but were defeated in the 1890s.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The French developed a plantation economy, and ignored demands for rights and self-government. This led to a nationalist political movement. Then the the 1930 Yên Bái mutiny. The suppressed mutineers became communists.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After Japanese defeat, France refused freedom. Việt Minh revolted, culminating in the partition and population exchange. Diệm ruled the south. In 1963, Buddhist discontent with Diệm&amp;rsquo;s regime erupted into mass demonstrations, leading to a violent government crackdown. Then there were many military rulers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;North Vietnam fought the south. US intervened, but were forced out by the obstinate vietcong despite bearing heavy losses (including from the use of chemical warfare).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-state&#34;&gt;Current state&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Balamon Chams that adhere to an indigenized form of Hinduism, and Bani Chams that adhere to an indigenized form of Islam. These two groups mostly live in separate villages. Intermarriage was prohibited in former times, and remains rare even nowadays. Both groups are matrilineal and conform to matrilocal residence practice.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The majority of Vietnamese Cham being Hindu while the majority of Cambodian Cham are Muslim, though significant minorities of Mahayana Buddhists continue to exist.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hindus&#34;&gt;Hindus&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Balamon Chams do not have a strict caste system, although previously they may have been divided between the Nagavamshi Kshatriya and the Brahmin castes&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hindu temples are known as Bimong in Cham language, but are commonly referred to as tháp &amp;ldquo;stupa&amp;rdquo;, in Vietnamese. The priests are divided into three levels, where the highest rank are known as Po Adhia or Po Sá, followed by Po Tapáh and the junior priests Po Paséh.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Balamon Cham - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qe2-gvdhqjI&#34;&gt;YT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;muslims&#34;&gt;Muslims&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;All of the Cham Muslims are Sunnis of the Shafi&amp;rsquo;i school. Po Dharma divides the Muslim Cham in Cambodia into a traditionalist branch and an orthodox branch.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Traditional branch: &amp;quot; &amp;hellip; A syncretic form of Islam that blends indigenous practices of matriarchy, ancestor veneration and Hinduism is practiced by the Cham Bani.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Each year some of the Cham go to study the Qur&amp;rsquo;an at Kelantan in Malaysia, and some go on to study in, or make a pilgrimage to, Mecca. According to figures from the late 1950s, about seven percent of the Cham had completed the pilgrimage and could wear the fez or turban as a sign of their accomplishment.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;christians&#34;&gt;Christians&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Christian population in vietnam is closer to 8% due to French colonialism &amp;amp; Catholic dictator Diem regime backed by USA.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
