<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;2 Energy &amp; fossil fuels on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/2_energy_and_fossil_fuels/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;2 Energy &amp; fossil fuels on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/2_energy_and_fossil_fuels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>5 Energy and Power Units</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/2_energy_and_fossil_fuels/5_Energy_and_Power_Units/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/2_energy_and_fossil_fuels/5_Energy_and_Power_Units/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This chapter provides a baseline for understanding the rest of the content in this book, so that students may learn to interpret and convert units, while building a useful intuition in the process. Sec. A.10 (p. 370) in the Appendices offers some tips on manipulating units and performing unit conversions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unlike most chapters, this one does not tell a single story or advance our perspective on the world. But it builds a foundation, putting us in a position to start looking at consequential matters of energy use in our society in chapters to come. Hopefully, patience will be rewarded.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Putting Thermal Energy to Work</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/2_energy_and_fossil_fuels/6_Putting_Thermal_Energy_to_Work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/2_energy_and_fossil_fuels/6_Putting_Thermal_Energy_to_Work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have already encountered thermal energy in two contexts. The first was infrared radiation (Eq. 1.8; p. 10), and the second was in the definition of the kilocalorie (Sec. 5.5; p. 73). Otherwise, heat has often been treated as a form of &amp;ldquo;waste&amp;rdquo; in a chain of energy conversion: friction, air resistance, etc. The insinuation was that heat is an unwanted byproduct of no value.&#xA;Yet 94% of the energy we use today is thermal in nature &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;: we burn a lot of stuff for energy!1 Sometimes heat is what we&amp;rsquo;re after, but how can we use it to fly airplanes, propel cars, and light up our screens? This chapter aims to clarify how heat is used, and explore limits to the efficiency at which heat can perform non-thermal work.&#xA;Like the previous chapter, this topic represents a slight detour from the book&amp;rsquo;s overall trajectory, which otherwise aims to build a steady narrative of what we can&amp;rsquo;t expect to continue doing, what options we might use to change course, and finally how to bring about such change. Nonetheless, the way we utilize thermal energy is a key piece of the story, and relates to both current and future pathways to satisfying our energy demands.&#xA;6.1 Generating Heat 6.2 Heat Capacity&#xA;6.3 Home Heating/Cooling.. 6.4 Heat Engines&#xA;84&#xA;85&#xA;86&#xA;. 88&#xA;Entropy and Efficiency Limits 90 6.5 Heat Pumps ..&#xA;Consumer Metrics.&#xA;.. 95&#xA;97&#xA;6.6 Upshot on Thermal Energy . 99&#xA;99 6.7 Problems..&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 The Energy Landscape</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/2_energy_and_fossil_fuels/7_The_Energy_Landscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/2_energy_and_fossil_fuels/7_The_Energy_Landscape/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that we have a handle on common energy units and thermal processes, we can take a look at various sources of energy data and make sense of the information, allowing meaningful cross-comparisons. In this chapter, we will do exactly that, gaining in the process a perspective on the past and present roles different energy sources play at a national and global level.&#xA;Most of the information in this chapter comes from the U.S. Energy Information Administration&amp;rsquo;s (EIA&amp;rsquo;s) Annual Energy Review [^34], and from a compilation of global data owing to Vaclav Smil and the British Petroleum Statistical Review of World Energy &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Rather than laboriously citing each instance, it is sufficient to assume for this chapter that numbers for the U.S. come from the former and global numbers come from the latter, unless stated otherwise.&#xA;7.1 The Annual Energy Review 102&#xA;Energy Flow.. Source and Sector&#xA;Detailed Mix&#xA;Energy Trends&#xA;7.2 Global Energy&#xA;U.S. Global Share&#xA;7.3 Upshot: Go to the Source&#xA;7.4 Problems.&#xA;103&#xA;104&#xA;106&#xA;107&#xA;108&#xA;.110&#xA;111&#xA;111&#xA;+&#xA;7.1 The Annual Energy Review&#xA;Until 2011, the Annual Energy Review (AER) was compiled for the U.S. as an annual report. Since then, a web interface provides access to many of the same products, but not as a single document. An impressive amount of detail is available in the AER products, and we will only scratch the surface in this book, looking at high-level overviews. Later chapters will sometimes rely on deeper information to provide state-by-state use of hydroelectric, solar, wind, etc. But for now, we stick mostly to section 1 of the Annual Energy Review (AER), labeled Energy Overview.&#xA;An oil pump dominates the foreground, while wind makes a visible presence in the background. Photo credit: Tom Murphy&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Fossil Fuels</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/2_energy_and_fossil_fuels/8_Fossil_Fuels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/2_energy_and_fossil_fuels/8_Fossil_Fuels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are now ready to dive into the core content of the book: assessing global energy demands and prospects. For most of human history, we derived energy from food-supplied muscle power of people and work animals, burning firewood, and harnessing wind and water flow (all deriving from solar energy). Then a most remarkable thing happened: the discovery and widespread utilization of fossil fuels. The abundance of energy delivered by fossil fuels profoundly changed the human condition, such that many elements of our modern world would seem like magic to someone living 200 or even 100 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/2_energy_and_fossil_fuels/9_Climate_Change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/2_energy_and_fossil_fuels/9_Climate_Change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Climate change stands tall among the global scale problems created by our energy appetite caused by the accumulation of carbon dioxide (CO2) in our atmosphere from the burning of fossil fuels. This chapter aims to provide a no-nonsense account of the basis for climate change that leaves little room for the kind of uncertainty often injected by (alarmingly successful) disinformation campaigns. While the response of our complex climate system is more difficult to predict in detail, the core physics is unassailable. We will see that the rise in CO2 is not at all mysterious, stemming from fossil fuels. We will also explore a few scenarios and connect the CO2 rise to temperature consequences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
