<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;05 Part Four - Moulding Men on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/05_Part_Four_-_Moulding_Men/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;05 Part Four - Moulding Men on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/05_Part_Four_-_Moulding_Men/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Ch 33 The Technique That Succeeds</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/05_Part_Four_-_Moulding_Men/01_Ch_33_The_Technique_That_Succeeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/05_Part_Four_-_Moulding_Men/01_Ch_33_The_Technique_That_Succeeds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;FOR TRUE NATIONAL REORGANISATION&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Failings of revolutionary and mass movements - Day-to-day technique for moulding men - Stress on practice - National symbol Bhagava Dhwaj, the Guru - Worship of ideal, not individual or book - Shakha, crucible of national reorganisation - Tradition of national festivals - Dangers of &amp;lsquo;institutionalism&amp;rsquo;- Domination by militant groups, an un-Hindu concept - Sangh for organising whole society&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An ideal requires a method, a process for its realisation in actuality. Today all around us we witness various types of techniques being adopted by several organisations. Even at the time of the founding of our organisation these different methods of work were in vogue. And it was not that Dr. Hedgewar, the founder of the Sangh, was unaware of those systems when he evolved this particular technique for our organisation. On the contrary, for quite a long time before he started the Sangh, he was in the thick of the activities of those organisations and was well acquainted with their techniques.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Ch 34 Character - Personal and National</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/05_Part_Four_-_Moulding_Men/02_Ch_34_Character_-_Personal_and_National/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/05_Part_Four_-_Moulding_Men/02_Ch_34_Character_-_Personal_and_National/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our cultural speciality: Personal Character - Purity of means - Personal laxity, a national danger - Tragedy of passive &amp;lsquo;goodness&amp;rsquo; - National character, the life-breath - Verdict of history - Devotion is not bargaining - Power of devotion- When characters blooms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IN our national tradition character has always occupied the place of foremost importance. Character has two facets: the one, which is personal, and the other, which manifests itself in our relationship with society. Both these aspects of our character should be pure and unsullied. But these days we often hear people saying that if a man is working well in the public field, why should we look at his personal conduct? Maybe he is addicted to a number of vices, but when he is doing good to the people why should we pry into his private life?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Ch 35 - Be Men with Capital &#39;M&#39;</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/05_Part_Four_-_Moulding_Men/03_Ch_35_-_Be_Men_with_Capital_M/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/05_Part_Four_-_Moulding_Men/03_Ch_35_-_Be_Men_with_Capital_M/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Be foundation-stones - Ideal of service - Self-reliance; glowing examples - Curse of careerism - Choosing the right ideal - Avoid two extremes - Serve nation - Shake off inferiority complex, cheap imitations - Secret of world respect; our past heroes- Past tradition - What Mother wants.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ONCE, while I was conversing with a great Sadhu, the subject of frequent student strikes came up. The Sadhu remarked, &amp;ldquo;This is the bitter fruit of dinning into the ears of students by our leaders that they are the pillars of the nation, the leaders of tomorrow and so on. This, coupled with their natural immaturity, has made them swollen-headed. The right attitude to be inculcated in the young minds is of selfless service, where ego has no chance to raise its ugly head. Calling them &amp;lsquo;pillars&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;future leaders&amp;rsquo; and all that has only roused their ego which makes them rise in revolt and indulge in strikes and violence at the slightest touch of injustice or insult, imaginary or otherwise.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Ch 36 Men with Mission</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/05_Part_Four_-_Moulding_Men/04_Ch_36_Men_with_Mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/05_Part_Four_-_Moulding_Men/04_Ch_36_Men_with_Mission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Real greatness, making men out of dust - Genuine spirit of identity - Assert faith in goodness - Building comradeship - Be self-confident, beware of self-conceit - Lesson of great lives - &amp;lsquo;Egoless&amp;rsquo; is success - One life, one mission- Self-introspection, self- reformation - The joy of idealism - The glory of suffering - &amp;lsquo;Excelsior&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE mission of national reorganisation i.e., of uniting in a common abiding brotherhood all our brethren torn asunder for various reasons and making them fit for national service by training each one of them suitably, is a tremendously complex task involving the interplay of countless types of human natures. It naturally defies codification or framing of flat rules of behaviour. Each man has an individuality of his own and requires a distinct approach. So we shall here focus our attention only on the main guidelines of behaviour for a worker devoted to this national mission.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 Ch 37 The Ideal Incarnate (*)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/05_Part_Four_-_Moulding_Men/05_Ch_37_The_Ideal_Incarnate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/05_Part_Four_-_Moulding_Men/05_Ch_37_The_Ideal_Incarnate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Keshav Baliram Hedgewar THE FOUNDER OF RASHTRIYA SWAYAMSEVAK SANGH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Life-long self-crucifixion - Self-transformation - Friend of all, enemy to none - The irresistible - Incomparable unifier - Self-effaced - Living for others - In the fire of endless exertion - The death that enlivens millions - How words derive power- Child of greatness. (*) Compiled from the speech of Sri Guruji at the III year Sangh Siksha Varg at Nagpur&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 Ch 38 His Last Message</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/05_Part_Four_-_Moulding_Men/06_Ch_38_His_Last_Message/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/05_Part_Four_-_Moulding_Men/06_Ch_38_His_Last_Message/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sangh not individual-oriented, but ideal-oriented - Faith in ideal inspires confidence in others also - Instance of people&amp;rsquo;s trust - Beware, dictatorship is coming - Make up for loss of time- Reach the Goal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NOWADAYS people seem to be very much worried about my health. However, I have directed Dr. Thatte to draw up my tour programme for the ensuing Sangh Shiksha Varga Camps. I have a feeling that if the programme is drawn up and kept ready, I may be able to go through it somehow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
