<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;negationism in india on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/negationism_in_india/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;negationism in india on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/negationism_in_india/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00 FROM THE COVER OF &#34;NEGATIONISM IN INDIA - CONCEALING THE RECORD OF ISLAM&#34;</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/negationism_in_india/00_cover/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/negationism_in_india/00_cover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-the-cover-of-negationism-in-india---concealing-the-record-of-islam&#34;&gt;FROM THE COVER OF &amp;ldquo;NEGATIONISM IN INDIA - CONCEALING THE RECORD OF ISLAM&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Negationism usually means the denial of the Nazi genocide of the Jews&#xA;and Gypsies in World War 2. Less well-known is that India has its own&#xA;brand of negationism. A section of the Indian intelligentsia is still&#xA;trying to erase from the Hindus&amp;rsquo; memory the history of their persecution&#xA;by the swordsmen of Islam. The number of victims of this persecution&#xA;surpasses that of the Nazi crimes. The Islamic campaign to wipe out&#xA;Paganism could not be equally thorough, but it has continued for&#xA;centuries without any moral doubts arising in the minds of the&#xA;persecutors and their chroniclers. The Islamic reports on the massacres&#xA;of Hindus, destruction of Hindu temples, the abduction of Hindu women&#xA;and forced conversions, invariably express great glee and pride. They&#xA;leave no doubt that the destruction of Paganism by every means, was&#xA;considered the God-ordained duty of the Moslem community. Yet, today&#xA;many Indian historians, journalists and politicians, deny that there&#xA;ever was a Hindu-Moslem conflict. They shamelessly rewrite history and&#xA;conjure up &lt;em&gt;centuries of Hindu-Moslem amity&lt;/em&gt;; now a growing section of&#xA;the public in India and the West only knows their negationist version of&#xA;history. It is not a pleasant task to rudely shake people out of their&#xA;delusions, especially if these have been wilfully created; but this&#xA;essay does just that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 FOREWORD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/negationism_in_india/01_foreword/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/negationism_in_india/01_foreword/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;foreword&#34;&gt;FOREWORD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is a much-expanded version of an article titled &lt;em&gt;Het&#xA;Islam-negationisme&lt;/em&gt;, published in the September 1992 issue of the&#xA;Flemish Catholic monthly &lt;em&gt;Nucleus&lt;/em&gt;, combined with a review of Sitaram&#xA;Goel&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hindu Temples, What happened to them, vol. 2: The Islamic&#xA;Evidence&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. The review was written for &lt;em&gt;Infoerient&lt;/em&gt;, the Dutch language&#xA;periodical of the Asian and Islamic Studies department of my Alma Mater,&#xA;the Catholic University of Leuven, under the title &lt;em&gt;Een Heiden tegen het&#xA;Negationisme&lt;/em&gt; ( &lt;em&gt;A Pagan&amp;rsquo;s Stand against Negationism&lt;/em&gt;). However, after&#xA;some dilly-dallying and moving it around like a hot potato in the mouth,&#xA;it was decided that publishing this review was too dangerous: the good&#xA;relations with the embassies of Islamic countries might be harmed, aqnd&#xA;the dominant trend in what is called public opinion might object to this&#xA;highlighting of a frank critique of Islam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Some Excerpts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/negationism_in_india/02_excerpts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/negationism_in_india/02_excerpts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-excerpts&#34;&gt;Some Excerpts&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next generation of political leaders, especially the left-wing that&#xA;was to gain control of Congress in the thirties, and complete control in&#xA;the fifties, would profess negationism very explicitly. The &lt;em&gt;radical&#xA;humanist&lt;/em&gt; (i.e. bourgeois Marxist) M.N. Roy wrote that Islam had&#xA;fulfilled a historic mission of equality and abolition of&#xA;discrimination, and that for this, Islam had been welcomed into India by&#xA;the lower castes. If at all any violence had occurred, it was as a&#xA;matter of justified class struggle by the &lt;em&gt;progressive forces&lt;/em&gt; against&#xA;the &lt;em&gt;reactionary forces&lt;/em&gt;, meaning the &lt;em&gt;fedual&lt;/em&gt; Hindu upper castes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 CHAPTER ONE - NEGATIONISM IN GENERAL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/negationism_in_india/03_ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/negationism_in_india/03_ch1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-one---negationism-in-general&#34;&gt;CHAPTER ONE - NEGATIONISM IN GENERAL&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Negationism means the denial of historical crimes against humanity. It&#xA;is not a reinterpretation of known facts, but the denial of known facts.&#xA;The term negationism has gained currency as the name of a movement to&#xA;deny a specific crime against humanity, the Nazi genocide on the Jews in&#xA;1941-45, also known as the holocaust (Greek: fire sacrifice) or the&#xA;Shoah (Hebrew: disaster). Negationism is mostly identified with the&#xA;effort at re-writing history in such a way that the fact of the&#xA;Holocaust is omitted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 CHAPTER TWO - NEGATIONISM IN INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/negationism_in_india/04_ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/negationism_in_india/04_ch2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-two---negationism-in-india&#34;&gt;CHAPTER TWO - NEGATIONISM IN INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The negationism regarding the Nazi crimes has been the object of much&#xA;public discussion. Turkish negationism about the Armenian genocide has&#xA;received some attention. Less well-known is that India has its own brand&#xA;of negationism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since about 1920 an effort has been going on in India to rewrite history&#xA;and to deny the millennium-long attack of Islam on Hinduism. Today, most&#xA;politicians and English- writing intellectuals in India will go out of&#xA;their way to condemn any public reference to this long and painful&#xA;conflict in the strongest terms. They will go to any length to create&#xA;the illusion of a history of &lt;em&gt;communal amity&lt;/em&gt; between Hindus and&#xA;Muslims.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 CHAPTER THREE - EXPOSING AND REFUTING NEGATIONISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/negationism_in_india/05_ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/negationism_in_india/05_ch3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-three---exposing-and-refuting-negationism&#34;&gt;CHAPTER THREE - EXPOSING AND REFUTING NEGATIONISM&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Negationism and history-distortion require a large-scale effort and a&#xA;very strong grip on the media of information and education. As soon as&#xA;the grip loosens, at least the most blatant of the negationist&#xA;concoctions are bound to be exposed, and its propounders lose all&#xA;credibility. In 1988, the schools in the Soviet Union decided to suspend&#xA;the history exams because &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;the history books are full of lies anyway&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&#xA;The great lies and distortions of Soviet historiography are now items in&#xA;the gallery of ridicule.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 CHAPTER FOUR - REPLY TO SOME QUESTIONS AND CRITICISMS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/negationism_in_india/06_ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/negationism_in_india/06_ch4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-four---reply-to-some-questions-and-criticisms&#34;&gt;CHAPTER FOUR - REPLY TO SOME QUESTIONS AND CRITICISMS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After the publication of first edition of this book, and of articles&#xA;containing some of its ideas, I have received some comments to which I&#xA;will reply here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;41-both-sides-of-the-story&#34;&gt;4.1 BOTH SIDES OF THE STORY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;You have been too much influenced by these Hindus among whom you lived&#xA;in Benares and Delhi. You haven&amp;rsquo;t heard the other side of the story.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The other side of the story&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; is not at all unknown to me: it has been&#xA;the object of my rather lengthy criticism all through this essay. It is&#xA;the people who have been taken in by the rosy picture of Islam, who know&#xA;only one side of the story. When they get to hear this side as well, it&#xA;turns out that they just don&amp;rsquo;t want to hear it. After all, the prospect&#xA;of having to deal with an increasingly numerous and increasingly&#xA;aggressive community under the spell of Islam is a bit frightening. We&#xA;would all prefer to live in a world without the threat of Islamic&#xA;fanaticism, but we should not delude ourselves that we are already&#xA;living in such a tolerant and danger-free world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
