<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;21 Italy on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/4_THE_EMPIRE_146_B_C_A_D_192/21_Italy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;21 Italy on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/4_THE_EMPIRE_146_B_C_A_D_192/21_Italy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 A ROSTER OF CITIES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/4_THE_EMPIRE_146_B_C_A_D_192/21_Italy/01_A_ROSTER_OF_CITIES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/4_THE_EMPIRE_146_B_C_A_D_192/21_Italy/01_A_ROSTER_OF_CITIES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LET us stop at this precarious zenith and try to realize that the Empire was greater than Rome.We have lingered unduly at this brilliant center, which hypnotizes historians as it fascinated provincials. In truth the vitality of the great realm no longer dwelt in the corrupt and dying capital; its surviving health and strength, much of its beauty, most of its mental life lay in the provinces and in Italy. We can have no just idea of what Rome meant, nor of its astonishing achievement in organization and pacification, until we leave it and surrender ourselves to a tour of the thousand cities that made up the Roman world.I&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 POMPEII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/4_THE_EMPIRE_146_B_C_A_D_192/21_Italy/02_POMPEII/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/4_THE_EMPIRE_146_B_C_A_D_192/21_Italy/02_POMPEII/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pompeii was one of the minor towns of Italy, hardly noticed in Latin literature except for its fish sauces, its cabbage, and its burial. Founded by Oscans perhaps as early as Rome, peopled by Greek immigrants, captured by Sulla and turned into a Roman colony, it was partly destroyed by an earthquake in A.D. 63 and was being rebuilt when Vesuvius destroyed it again. On August 24, A.D. 79, the volcano exploded and hurled dust and rock high into the air amid clouds of smoke and flashes of flame. A heavy rainfall turned the erupted matter into a torrent of mud and stone, which in six hours covered Pompeii and Herculaneum to a depth of eight or ten feet. All that day and the next the earth shook and buildings fell. Audiences were buried in the ruins of theaters,14 hundreds were choked by dust or fumes, and tidal waves shut off escape by sea. The elder Pliny was at that time commanding the western fleet at Misenum, near Puteoli. Moved by appeals for help and by curiosity to observe the phenomenon at closer range, he boarded a small vessel, landed on the southern shore of the gulf, and rescued several persons; but as the party ran from the advancing hail and smoke, the old scientist was overcome, fell in his tracks, and died.15 The next morning his wife and his nephew joined the desperate crowd that fled down the coast, while from Naples to Sorrento the continuing eruption blackened the day into night. Many refugees, separated in the darkness from their husbands, wives, or children, made the terror worse with their laments and shrieks. Some prayed to divers gods for help; some cried out that all gods were dead and that the long-predicted end of the world had come.16 When, on the third day, the sky cleared at last, lava and mud had covered everything of Pompeii but the rooftops, and Herculaneum had completely disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 MUNICIPAL LIFE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/4_THE_EMPIRE_146_B_C_A_D_192/21_Italy/03_MUNICIPAL_LIFE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/4_THE_EMPIRE_146_B_C_A_D_192/21_Italy/03_MUNICIPAL_LIFE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life, private and public, individual and corporate, has never been lived more intensely than in ancient Italy. But the events of our own time are too vital and absorbing to let us spare interest for the details of municipal organization under the Caesars; the confusing diversities of constitution and the jealous gradations of franchise are no longer a part of that living past which is our matrix and our theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
