<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;03 Annexures on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/education/articles/dharampAl_beautiful-tree_education/03_Annexures/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;03 Annexures on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/education/articles/dharampAl_beautiful-tree_education/03_Annexures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Madras Presidency 1822-26</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/education/articles/dharampAl_beautiful-tree_education/03_Annexures/A_Madras_Presidency_1822-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/education/articles/dharampAl_beautiful-tree_education/03_Annexures/A_Madras_Presidency_1822-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MINUTE OF GOVERNOR SIR THOMAS MUNRO&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ORDERING THE COLLECTION OF DETAILED INFORMATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ON INDIGENOUS EDUCATION:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;25.6.1822*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(TNSA: Revenue Consultations: Vol.920: dated 2.7.1822)&lt;/em&gt; 1. Much has been written both in England and in this country about the ignorance of the people of India and the means of disseminating knowledge among them. But the opinions upon this subject are the mere conjectures of individuals unsupported by any authentic documents and differing so widely from each other as to be entitled to very little attention. Our power in this country and the nature of its own municipal institutions have certainly rendered it practicable to collect material from which a judgment might be formed of the state of the mental cultivation of the people. We have made geographical and agricultural surveys of our provinces. We have investigated their resources and endeavoured to ascertain their population, but little or nothing has been done to learn the state of education. We have no record to show the actual state of education throughout the country. Partial inquiries have been made by individuals, but those have taken place at distant periods—and on a small scale and no inference can be drawn from them with regard to the country in general. There may be some difficulty in obtaining such a record as we want. Some Districts will not—but others probably will furnish it—and if we get it only from two or three it will answer in some degree for all the rest. It cannot be expected to be very accurate, but it will at least enable us to form an estimate of the state of instructions among the people. The only record which can furnish the information required is a list of the schools in which reading and writing are taught in&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B FRA PAOLINO DA BARTOLOMEO ON EDUCATION OF CHILDREN IN INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/education/articles/dharampAl_beautiful-tree_education/03_Annexures/B_FRA_PAOLINO_DA_BARTOLOMEO_ON_EDUCATION_OF_CHILDREN_IN_INDIA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/education/articles/dharampAl_beautiful-tree_education/03_Annexures/B_FRA_PAOLINO_DA_BARTOLOMEO_ON_EDUCATION_OF_CHILDREN_IN_INDIA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Born at Hos, Austria, 1748, as John Phillip Wesdin; in India 1776 to 1789. From &lt;em&gt;Voyages to the East Indies&lt;/em&gt; (Published, Rome, 1796, Berlin, 1798, England, 1880), Book II: Birth and Education of Children (pp.253-268)) All the Grecian historians represent the Indians as people of greater size, and much more robust than those of other nations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Though this is not true in general, it is certain that the purity of the air, wholesome nourishment, temperance and education contribute, in an uncommon degree, to the bodily conformation, and to the increase of these people. Their new-born children lie always on the ground, as if they were thrown away or neglected; and they are never wrapped up with bandages, or confined in any other manner, as is done in Europe. Their limbs, therefore, can expand themselves without the least restraint; their nerves and bones become more solid; and when these children attain the period of youth, they acquire not only a beautiful figure, but a sound, well turned, and robust bodily conformation. The frequent use of the cold bath, repeated rubbing the body with coconut oil and the juice of the &lt;em&gt;Ingia plant&lt;/em&gt;, as well as their exercises, which have a great resemblance to the &lt;em&gt;Juvenilia&lt;/em&gt;, and which I have often seen in Malabar, all contribute to increase their strength and agility. These advantages also are seldom lost, unless some of these young people abandon themselves to debauchery, or weaken their bodies by too great labour or excessive perspiration. However healthful and lively the young Indians may be in general those who marry before the twentieth year of their age, for the most part, soon become feeble and enervated. In a word, I seldom saw in India a person either lame, crooked, or otherwise deformed. The people of Malabar, who live towards the west, are much handsomer and more robust than the natives of Coromandel, or the Tamulians on the eastern coast of India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C Walker Malbar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/education/articles/dharampAl_beautiful-tree_education/03_Annexures/C_Walker_Malbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/education/articles/dharampAl_beautiful-tree_education/03_Annexures/C_Walker_Malbar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MALABAR BIBLIOGRAPHY, THEIR PROGRESS IN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LITERATURE, EDUCATION—SYSTEM BORROWED FROM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IT. ACCOUNT OF IT FROM PETER DELLA VALLE.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CUSTOM IN MALABAR TO TRANSLATE WORKS FROM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SANSCRIT, MANNER OF WRITING OR ENGRAVING ON&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LEAVES. QUOTATION FROM LUSIAD. LIST OF BOOKS.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;( &lt;em&gt;National Library of Scotland Edinburgh: Walker of Bowland&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Papers 184 a 3, Chapter 31: pp.501-27&lt;/em&gt;) I do not propose to give a history of the literature of Malabar; far less to enquire into the origin and progress of the sciences of India. I mean only to preface by a few observations a biblio-graphical list which I obtained many years ago (in 1800) of some of the books and authors whose works are studied in that country (Malabar).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>D William Adam’s State of Education in Bengal</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/education/articles/dharampAl_beautiful-tree_education/03_Annexures/D_William_Adams_State_of_Education_in_Bengal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/education/articles/dharampAl_beautiful-tree_education/03_Annexures/D_William_Adams_State_of_Education_in_Bengal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*Extracts From William Adam’s State of Education in Bengal * 1835-38&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;W. ADAM ON INDIGENOUS ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GENERAL: (pp.6-9)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By this description are meant those schools in which instruction in the elements of knowledge is communicated, and which have been originated and are supported by the natives themselves, in contra-distinction from those that are supported by religious or philanthropic societies. The number of such schools in Bengal is supposed to be very great. A distinguished member of the General Committee of Public Instruction in a minute on the subject expressed the opinion, that if one rupee per mensem were expended on each existing village school in the Lower Provinces, the amount would probably fall little short of 12 lakhs of rupees per annum. This supposes that there are 100,000&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>E Education in the Panjab since Annexation and in 1882</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/education/articles/dharampAl_beautiful-tree_education/03_Annexures/E_Education_in_the_Panjab_since_Annexation_and_in_1882/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/education/articles/dharampAl_beautiful-tree_education/03_Annexures/E_Education_in_the_Panjab_since_Annexation_and_in_1882/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;History of Education in the Panjab since Annexation and in 1882&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LEITNER ON INDIGENOUS EDUCATION IN THE PANJAB&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(EXTRACTS)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GENERAL:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am about to relate—I hope without extenuation or malice—the history of the contact of a form of European with one of Asiatic civilisation; how, in spite of the best intentions, the most public-spirited officers, and a generous Government that had the benefit of the traditions of other provinces, the true education of the Panjab was crippled, checked, and is nearly destroyed; how opportunities for its healthy revival and development were either neglected or perverted; and how, far beyond the blame attaching to individuals, our system stands convicted or worse than official failure. Whether it is possible to rouse to renewed exertion, on behalf of its own education, the most loyal population that has ever been disappointed, is a question which the following pages will only partially attempt to answer. Much will of course, depend on the wise adaptation of the noble principle just propounded—of ‘local self-government’—&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F Mahatma Gandhi on Education</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/education/articles/dharampAl_beautiful-tree_education/03_Annexures/F_Mahatma_Gandhi_on_Education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/education/articles/dharampAl_beautiful-tree_education/03_Annexures/F_Mahatma_Gandhi_on_Education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correspondence between Mahatma Gandhi and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Sir Philip Hartog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MAHATMA GANDHI ON INDIGENOUS EDUCATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;That does not finish the picture. We have education of this future state. I say without fear of my figures being challenged successfully, that today India is more illiterate than it was fifty or a hundred years ago, and so is Burma, because the British administrators, when they came to India, instead of taking hold of things as they were, began to root them out. They scratched the soil and began to look at the root, and left the root like that, and the beautiful tree perished. The village schools were not good enough for the British administrator, so he came out with his programme. Every school must have so much paraphernalia, building, and so forth. Well, there were no such schools at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G Tanjore Revenue</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/education/articles/dharampAl_beautiful-tree_education/03_Annexures/G_Tanjore_Revenue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/education/articles/dharampAl_beautiful-tree_education/03_Annexures/G_Tanjore_Revenue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;List of Tanjore Temples Receiving Revenue Assignments&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;14.4.1843&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No.6: ACCOUNT PARTICULARS OF THE ANNUAL MOHINS TO&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE PAGODAS OF TANJOUR FOR FUSLEE 1222&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No. Name&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Place&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amount&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fs. C&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pagoda&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Combaswara Swamy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;at&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Combaconum&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1,349&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;8&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Naugaswara Swamy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-do-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-do-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;666&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;16&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Somaswara Swamy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-do-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-do-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;100&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cailaheeteeswara Swamy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-do-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-do-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;90&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vissvanauda Swamy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-do-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-do-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;22&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;24&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Govotamaswara Swamy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-do-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-do-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;22&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sodasulinga Swamy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-do-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-do-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;18&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Causevisswanada Swamy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-do-&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
