<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०६ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०६ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The imprisonment</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-30_the-imprisonment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-30_the-imprisonment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/06/30/the-imprisonment/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In wake of the crisis our mantras had failed to produce their full effect. The task that confronted us was so big that the mantras only took us half the way through. Beyond that it was impossible for us to make any progress. As a result we fell in a trap and were now confronted with imprisonment. We were forced to sit worthlessly at a time when we should have surged ahead in battle; furthermore we were subject to tortures on top of that. Nothing is worse that having to sit inactively when battles could be waged with the strength still in our arms. But we were bound shorn of our weapons. What had gone wrong?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our nAga shApa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-29_our-naga-shapa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-29_our-naga-shapa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/06/29/our-naga-shapa/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is said that when pANDus conquered khANDava from the nAgas they got&#xA;the curse of the nAgas. For the sake of khANDava they lost most of their&#xA;sons. In the next generation parIkShit lost his life due to the nAga and&#xA;so on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We had earlier alluded to the seizure of our khANDava in what seemed a&#xA;successful campaign. A little did we know that we were headed to worst&#xA;of the existential crises we had ever faced as result of our possession&#xA;of khANDava. It looked as though our favors from the gods had run out&#xA;now. The attack now extended on all fronts. Jx had said that cell phones&#xA;were harmless devices, but we learned to our horror there were some&#xA;which even came with bombs, leave alone cameras. Jx received a strike.&#xA;The big eater received another but survived after some bad effects. The&#xA;learned muni himself was struck but some how survived. Some of our&#xA;dependents were struck badly and one of our great treasures were robbed.&#xA;pretas issued forth from the floor. When Marc and R had visited&#xA;Hayastanika they obtained the latter’s message for me. The Abrus seeds&#xA;had fallen out of the window and now a deadly grove of plants grew&#xA;there. We were never so bereft of energy and were at our wits end. We&#xA;had then spoken of kumbhakarNa and the missiles failing at him. It was&#xA;now as though we were in a kArAgR^iha of rAvaNa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kR^ityA troubles</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-23_kritya-troubles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-23_kritya-troubles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/06/23/kritya-troubles/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The kR^ityA made a couple of efforts at driving home the mAraNa and&#xA;continues to hover around to strike again. Day after day the attacks&#xA;continue without any respite and most critically they are aiming at&#xA;cutting off our means of performing the appropriate mighty rites. Today&#xA;like mArIcha and subAhu obstructing the rites of vishvAmitra the kR^ityA&#xA;blocked some critical rites of ours. The kR^ityA faced the rebound of&#xA;our rites and was grounded, but the senders had packed the ghaTotkacha&#xA;module into the kR^ityA. How this works is that if the kR^ityA is&#xA;destroyed it would take the destroyer down along with it as it is burned&#xA;out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The mAraNa strike</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-16_the-marana-strike/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-16_the-marana-strike/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/06/16/the-marana-strike/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The dumAvatI agent has a very special means of attack. It tries to&#xA;destroy all the supporting systems and armors, and then zeroes in on the&#xA;victim. It pressed ahead with the attempt at mAraNa. We parleyed with&#xA;the agent: it revealed a peculiar prayoga of the type only known to me&#xA;previously in the bauddha context. The mAraNa was to indirectly achieved&#xA;via a linkage to second person. This was similar to the fate of&#xA;nagArjuna when he met his end. The agent it trying to achieve this&#xA;linkage and finish us off. The kR^ityA hovers endless waiting to the&#xA;first opportunity to make the lunge. We just fled away the first time&#xA;the dart was hurled at us. The second dart now hit us but did not kill&#xA;us due to the past mantra bala. Who knows when the next dart may come.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MJ from the past</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-15_mj-from-the-past/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-15_mj-from-the-past/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/06/15/mj-from-the-past/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;shachIva and amAtya met old and witch-like MJ. MJ was a great adversary&#xA;of ours, but respected our battle skills greatly. She remembered how we&#xA;destroyed the stuff she hurled at us, despite certain nighmarish weapons&#xA;in her possession that shook us. MJ now heard of our situation and&#xA;suddenly reacted very unusually by deciding to work on our side. She&#xA;deployed the vaiShNava weapons. However, the kR^ityA was not countered&#xA;by that and brushing it aside charged on. We temporarily neutralized the&#xA;kR^ityA’s effects due to indra’s aid. Now we shall wait and see what&#xA;happens next.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The kingdom in danger</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-14_the-kingdom-in-danger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-14_the-kingdom-in-danger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/06/14/the-kingdom-in-danger/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the first time in our reign did we find the kingdom in such an&#xA;existential crisis emerging from our earlier conquest of khANDavaprasta.&#xA;We checked all past events- it looked as though most of our mantras had&#xA;worked. But the enemies were very numerous and all it took was a small&#xA;chink in the armour to break through. We have exactly 8 days to grind&#xA;out one of our main adversaries and the kR^ityA is raining hell all the&#xA;while.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The kR^ityA strike</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-14_the-kritya-strike/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-14_the-kritya-strike/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/06/14/the-kritya-strike/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-Our shachiva for the first time was shaken by the hit but could not do&#xA;much useful at all. We still hold on to him as he has always been&#xA;trustworthy at the last ditch attempt, which cannot be achieved without&#xA;his abilities in that direction.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;-Our amAtya made a valiant attempt with the mantras. We saw it take on&#xA;the kR^ityA, but it eventually lost and our amAtya was beaten&#xA;thoroughly.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;-The chera magician’s cryptic spell ran thus: The brain of the tree’s&#xA;root was hacked off; the 2 older male fruits of the plant shall be&#xA;consumed by the two kR^ityAs we have despatched.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;-R warned me that I was descending deep in to a pile of shit. It looks&#xA;as though she was right.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pAshupata vrata</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-10_pashupata-vrata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-10_pashupata-vrata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/06/10/pashupata-vrata/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having had a major struggle with the forces of fate, and having been&#xA;reduced to the condition of Jx in a certain sense, and having dropped&#xA;the proverbial last wick of bhairavAnanda he was wandering around with&#xA;the wheel spinning on his head. They wanted that most tasty fruit that&#xA;grew atop the nR^i trees. But unfortunately for them they did not know&#xA;how to nurture such trees. Hence they spoiled their sapling quite badly&#xA;and there was no great success in getting the fruit. There was that talk&#xA;between the urvan of the tree and varuNa much like talk between the&#xA;urvan of the cow and Ahura Mazda. Hopefully varuNa answers the tree’s&#xA;call. In the mean time as he wandered at the brink of the desert and the&#xA;khANDava jungle. At this point he wondered what if anything may save&#xA;him. He was asked to perform the pAshupata vrata. If pashupati wishes he&#xA;may be saved the itinerant pAshupata told. Thus, he lapsed into the&#xA;pAshupata yoga state.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The kR^ityAstra strike</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-08_the-krityastra-strike/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-08_the-krityastra-strike/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/06/08/the-krityastra-strike/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We saw that kR^ityAstra course towards us and hit us even before we&#xA;could do much. The muni’s efforts were blown to bits, the amAtya was&#xA;tossed aside like a twig in a storm, the shachiva simply ran away from&#xA;the scene. The effects are rather sapping- it just wears you out, and&#xA;tries to eat out and completely destroy your mantra bala. For sometime&#xA;we did not know what hit us, as though the deadly dhUmAvatI had been&#xA;sent to devour us. Our kavacha seemed to be fragmented to bits. Our&#xA;energy seemed to flow out of us like three rivers. It was indeed the&#xA;mahAyuddha as we had feared in the past.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for the worst</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-07_preparing-for-the-worst/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/06/2005-06-07_preparing-for-the-worst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/06/07/preparing-for-the-worst/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we remarked earlier we were taking the last step before the&#xA;kAlaChidra. We have taken it and now hang like trisha~Nku in the median&#xA;of descent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We decided that shall boldly face the attack and die like Dattaji Shinde&#xA;or emerge at the other end with what ever scars the battle gives us.&#xA;Like yayAti we had fallen head long from svarga before. But now we did&#xA;not know where our fall was taking us. We were leading a relatively easy&#xA;life before, but now we were unexpectedly struck by the new missile. We&#xA;were forced into a crisis before we realized what was happening. We had&#xA;been specifically targeted at the weakest link in our armor. Our&#xA;shachiva, amAtya and the learned muni were all overthrown. The muni was&#xA;learned and knew everything through the jAnashruteya birds but just as&#xA;we were unable to help him in his crisis he was also unable to do so due&#xA;his own engagments with the three. Our amAtya and shachiva were too&#xA;naieve for their posts and made many blunders and were pounded. We&#xA;feared our shachiva may even neglect his current duties and compromise&#xA;us futher- this was his nature. They have their own mantraic&#xA;accomplishments which we have learned to respect despite its&#xA;insufficiencies. We asked to take recourse to them in the last stand.&#xA;But we were cornered precisely in weakest spots. Our friends who were&#xA;always beside us in happy times had deserted us. We felt like Das and&#xA;Dasgupta made to open on a Perth green top early on a dewy morning. We&#xA;told ourself not to fear death and be prepared to face up for the worst&#xA;of battles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
