<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Late-tsArist-peasantry Ransel &amp; Levine on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Late-tsArist-peasantry Ransel &amp; Levine on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 IVAN’S PARENTS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/01_IVANS_PARENTS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/01_IVANS_PARENTS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Semyonova begins her story with a description of the peasant Ivan’s parents at the time they married and began their family. By contrasting the customs at that time (about 1863) with the time of her observations of Ivan the adult (about 1900), she is able to illustrate the rapid changes that were taking place in Russian peasant society in the late nineteenth century&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ivan’s parents were known as Stepan and Akulina. Stepan, a peasant of average means, was born under serfdom. Ivan was his third son and was born a year or two after the emancipation of privately owned peasants in 1861. Stepan and Akulina’s livestock at the time of Ivan’s birth included three horses (one of which was a yearling), fifteen sheep, one cow, a heifer, and a pig. Their hut, which was wooden, had three windows and an enclosed entryway (&lt;em&gt;sentsa&lt;/em&gt;). Nearby were a workyard, a small granary, and a threshing barn.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 CHILDBIRTH, CHRISTENING, WIFE BEATING</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/02_CHILDBIRTH_CHRISTENING_WIFE_BEATING/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/02_CHILDBIRTH_CHRISTENING_WIFE_BEATING/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This chapter begins with the grim subject of infant death. It was an everyday occurrence in Russian villages at the time Semyonova was writing. Nearly half of Russian babies failed to survive to age five, an infant mortality rate among the highest ever recorded anywhere. Most of these deaths were caused by diarrhea and respiratory illnesses, but the lying-over deaths that Semyonova reports here also made an important contribution. These were deaths caused by mothers who, presumably in their sleep, rolled over on and smothered the babies they had placed in bed with them during the night for convenience in breastfeeding. In Europe generally at the time of rising fertility in the eighteenth century, these lying-over deaths became epidemic, so much so that it is difficult to believe that they were wholly accidental. Although Semyonova seems to say here that the deaths were accidental, at another point in her notes she asserts that some babies were purposely killed in this way (see below, p.&lt;/em&gt; 98*). At this time, Russian villages were experiencing very high fertility, and youthful clumsiness alone seems an inadequate explanation of why more than half the mothers were lying over their infants*.1 &lt;em&gt;More likely, the women were asserting control, with the limited means at their command, over a chaotic and dangerous population growth. We will see other examples of their efforts at control later&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 CHILDHOOD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/03_CHILDHOOD/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/03_CHILDHOOD/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After discussing basic child care, Semyonova enters into a discussion of the psychology of peasant youngsters. She sees their attitudes and behavior as conditioned by the promiscuous intimacy of peasant life. The precocious shrewdness of peasant children led her to the belief (so implausible to our modern way of thinking) that children saw the world in the same terms as adults. She also makes some comparisons of peasant children and “our children,” that is, the children of educated urbanized people. While she no doubt idealized the conditions of children in educated families, her attitude reveals the chasm she sensed between the world of peasant family life and that of educated society&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 COURTSHIP AND SEXUAL RELATIONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/04_COURTSHIP_AND_SEXUAL_RELATIONS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/04_COURTSHIP_AND_SEXUAL_RELATIONS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Most ethnographic accounts of Russian villagers in the nineteenth century indicate fairly strong sanctions against premarital intercourse. Standards for extramarital intercourse were more flexible for married women or even for unmarried women of the age of most married women. Attitudes apparently varied from place to place as well, and, as Semyonova’s descriptions reveal, they were changing rapidly in the late nineteenth century under the impact of migrant labor and rising age at first marriage&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 IVAN PREPARES FOR MARRIAGE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/05_IVAN_PREPARES_FOR_MARRIAGE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/05_IVAN_PREPARES_FOR_MARRIAGE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Another realm in which women played a central role was the arrangement of marriages. In theory, the timing of marriage, the choice of partners, and the content of the ceremony and accompanying celebrations were almost entirely in the hands of women. This amounted to power over the establishment of kinship bonds, an altogether critical function in peasant society, one on which the survival of the family could ultimately depend. Semyonova states this view of things at the start of this chapter, but the stories she tells later show young men proposing to women; the role of the women of the young man’s household is not presented. At the end of the chapter, I have inserted unpublished descriptions of four actual marriages taken from Semyonova’s field notes. While women clearly played a directing role in the last two cases, their influence in the first two instances is less obviously determining&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 PLEDGING THE BRIDE, THE BRIDE-SHOW, AND MARRIAGE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/06_PLEDGING_THE_BRIDE_THE_BRIDE-SHOW_AND_MARRIAGE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/06_PLEDGING_THE_BRIDE_THE_BRIDE-SHOW_AND_MARRIAGE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Once a young couple or the family of an eligible man decided to initiate an official proposal of marriage, one or more matchmakers had to be engaged to make the initial approaches to the family of the bride-to-be. Assuming everyone agreed, the pledging was then followed by a bride-show, and finally the official church marriage ceremony. Some scholars believe that the betrothal (or the betrothal and bride-show together) represented the pre-Christian rites, and these rites sealed the marriage from the peasant point of view (“the wine is drunk”), for the couple at that point could begin sexual relations. This view strikes me as romanticized, for the essence of the bargain was the transfer of the bride to a new household, and this did not occur until after the church ceremony. The marriage bond clearly required all three steps in order to enjoy the sanction of the village community&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 INFANTICIDE, EMOTION, SEXUAL DISORDER, DRINK AND FOOD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/07_INFANTICIDE_EMOTION_SEXUAL_DISORDER_DRINK_AND_FOOD/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/07_INFANTICIDE_EMOTION_SEXUAL_DISORDER_DRINK_AND_FOOD/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As its title reveals, this chapter covers a variety of subjects. Not only the chapter itself but subsections of it have been built out of widely scattered pieces of Semyonova’s account and notes. The result, though still a hodge-podge, has the virtue of greater coherence than the original text. Nevertheless, I occasionally have had to insert transitional comments to avoid too sharp a turn in the discussion&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Among a new wife’s most important tasks was to reproduce a new generation. Not until she had a surviving child was she regarded as a full-fledged member of her new household. Since Semyonova has already dealt with the issue of childbirth and with child rearing, such as it was in Russian peasant life, she writes little about it in her subsequent notes. But here I wanted to include a few comments she makes on the length of confinement for birthing mothers, sexual contacts between husband and wife, illegitimacy, lullabies, and related topics&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 HOUSING, PROPERTY, TRADES, BUDGETS, AND RELIGIOUS BELIEF</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/08_HOUSING_PROPERTY_TRADES_BUDGETS_AND_RELIGIOUS_BELIEF/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/08_HOUSING_PROPERTY_TRADES_BUDGETS_AND_RELIGIOUS_BELIEF/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This chapter begins with a description of peasant living quarters, but Semyonova quickly gets caught up in telling about the stifling atmosphere of houses heated by “black stoves.” (Such chimneyless homes, called in Russian “smokey houses”&lt;/em&gt; [kurnye izby], &lt;em&gt;were quite common in central and especially northern Russia until the end of the nineteenth century.) Note that the principal fuel in this instance was straw, because Semyonova’s village was in the lightly forested Black Earth region. Here the roofs were often thatched, and chimneyless stoves may have been a necessity because burning straw could drift up the flue and land on the thatched roof&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 PEASANT IDEALS, WORK HABITS, AND CAUSES OF POVERTY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/09_PEASANT_IDEALS_WORK_HABITS_AND_CAUSES_OF_POVERTY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/09_PEASANT_IDEALS_WORK_HABITS_AND_CAUSES_OF_POVERTY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Russian village was changing. Contact with the big city was becoming the common experience of many villagers, as the first vignette in this chapter makes clear. It also reveals two of the characteristics Semyonova thought that she could discern in the peasant way of thinking. The first is a very short time horizon, the inability of the peasant to project plans and expectations far into the future. Nothing could be counted on, not even the ordinary expectation in modern society that most children will reach adulthood. The second is the lack of interest in saving money. This characteristic is related to the first; if there is no future, at least none that can be counted on and into which one can project hopes and plans, then why sacrifice anything for it? It makes more sense to work only as much as necessary to make it through the current year and to consume whatever extra comes one’s way&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 COURT CASES AND POLITICAL STRUCTURE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/10_COURT_CASES_AND_POLITICAL_STRUCTURE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/late-tsArist-peasantry_ransel-levine/10_COURT_CASES_AND_POLITICAL_STRUCTURE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One consequence of the village’s increasing interaction with the urban society and the national government was a greater use by the peasants of the courts. Semyonova records a number of typical court cases she observed; she regards the more frequent use of courts by peasants as destructive of community life. Suits were deployed as weapons against persons one disliked or from whom one could expect to gain some monetary advantage. Peasants, of course, were hardly alone in using the courts in this way. The end of serfdom and the accompanying abolition of the legal authority of the serf owner meant that peasants had to find new methods for settling their disputes. The results may have been a messier, more litigious village life, but it was a school in modern institution building as well. Semyonova also remarks on punishments and the peasants’ attitudes toward corporal as opposed to monetary penalties. Here we see an example of the continuing power of patriarchal authority in the family and how it affected dependent males as well as females&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
