<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;muslim state theory practice on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;muslim state theory practice on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00 Preface</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/00_preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/00_preface/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Preface&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My first article, &amp;ldquo;The Spirit of Muslim Government in India&amp;rdquo;, was&#xA;published in the Annual Bulletin of the Nagpur University Historical&#xA;Society, No. 2, October 1947. It was revised and published under the&#xA;title &lt;em&gt;Muslim State in India&lt;/em&gt; by Vichar Prakashan, Allahabad, in 1950 in&#xA;the form of a small book. Chapters on Muslim administration and&#xA;government are also included in my &lt;em&gt;History of the Khaljis&lt;/em&gt; (1950),&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Twilight of the Sultanate&lt;/em&gt; (1963), &lt;em&gt;Studies in Medieval Indian History&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;(1966), &lt;em&gt;Early Muslims in India&lt;/em&gt; (1984), and &lt;em&gt;The Legacy of Muslim Rule&#xA;in India&lt;/em&gt; (1992).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 Abbreviations          used in References For orgplete titles of works see Bibliography </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/01_abbreviation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/01_abbreviation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[TABLE]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02  I         Introduction</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/02_ch01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/02_ch01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1.1. THE RISE OF ISLAM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Professor R.P. Tripathi begins his famous monograph entitled &lt;em&gt;Some&#xA;Aspects of Muslim Administration&lt;/em&gt;, by writing that the Muslim &amp;ldquo;invaders&#xA;gradually wormed themselves into the heart of India, and finally assumed&#xA;the role of the earlier Hindu Empire-builders like Chandra Gupta,&#xA;Samudra Gupta and even Harsha&amp;hellip; The Muslim Sultan, however, differed&#xA;from the earlier Hindu sovereigns in two respects. He did not belong to&#xA;the country over which he had come to rule&amp;hellip; Secondly, he believed in a&#xA;religion whose outlook on social and political questions was very&#xA;different from that of the Hindus. He did not come&amp;hellip; simply for&#xA;conquest. With him he had brought a well-defined religion, a highly&#xA;developed civilization, and a set of institutions to which he clung with&#xA;all his faith. Indeed, it was an avowed principle with him to maintain&#xA;their purity and to establish them in lands under his sway.&amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03  II         The State</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/03_ch02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/03_ch02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;II&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The State&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Muslim rule in India has been conveniently divided into two periods, the&#xA;Sultanate of Delhi (1206-1526) and the Mughal empire (1526-1707). it&#xA;continued up to 1857, though in the later stages only nominally. When&#xA;the Sultanate was established, it carried with it the experience gained&#xA;by the Arab rule in Sindh and the Ghaznavid rule in Punjab of about two&#xA;centuries. Meanwhile a well-developed statecraft had sprung up in Muslim&#xA;countries during the seventh to the twelfth centuries. This was mainly&#xA;due to the universality of Islamic law. The Ghazni and Delhi sultanates&#xA;cannot be isolated from the rest of the Muslim states particularly in&#xA;the functioning of their institutions. There were parallel and sometimes&#xA;identical institutions under the kingdoms of Ghazni and Delhi. The&#xA;Sultanate of Delhi may not have possessed uninterrupted political&#xA;continuity; its boundaries also constantly changed. As political entity,&#xA;however, the Sultanate received sustenance from the evolution of&#xA;institutions abroad and at home. The Mughal empire too in its early&#xA;years lacked stability. But from Akbar (1556-1605) onwards there was&#xA;undisturbed one dynasty rule. Its geographical boundaries also expanded&#xA;and there was further growth of Islamic administrative institutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04  III         Obligations of the State</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/04_ch03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/04_ch03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;III&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Obligations of the State&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to Ruben Levy, &amp;ldquo;the functions which the lawyers and theorists&#xA;lay down for the Caliphate, the duties of the ruler in Islam are four&amp;rdquo; -&#xA;(1) Judgement (or justice), (2) Taxation, (3) Friday service and (4)&#xA;Jihad.&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; We shall take up Jihad first.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3.1. ISLAMIC WAR OR JIHAD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;War against non-Muslims is called Jihad in Islamic scriptures. The first&#xA;Jihads were fought in Arabia against the Pagans, Jews and Christians.&#xA;Later on they were fought wherever Muslims went to spread their&#xA;religion. Jihad is fought to serve Allah. According to a Pakistani army&#xA;scholar, Brigadier S.K. Malik,&lt;a href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;the fountain-head of the Quranic&#xA;dimensions of war lies in the fact that war is waged for the cause of&#xA;Allah&amp;hellip; To those who fight for this noblest heavenly cause, the Book&#xA;promises handsome heavenly assistance. The index of fighting for Allah&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;cause is Man&amp;rsquo;s total submission to his Will. Those who fail to submit&#xA;themselves fully and completely to the Will of God run the risk of&#xA;incurring heavenly wrath&amp;hellip; Fighting involves risk of life and property&#xA;that must be accepted willingly and cheerfully.&amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;#3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt; Said the Book,&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Not equal are believers who sit (at home) and receive no hurt, and&#xA;those who strive and fight in the cause of Allah with their goods and&#xA;their persons. Allah hath granted a grade higher to those who strive and&#xA;fight with their goods and persons than those who sit (at home).&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;The&#xA;central theme behind the causes of wars, as spelt out by the Holy Quran,&#xA;was the cause of Allah&amp;hellip; in the pursuit of this cause, the Muslims were&#xA;first granted the &lt;em&gt;permission&lt;/em&gt; to fight but were later &lt;em&gt;commanded&lt;/em&gt; to&#xA;fight in the way of God as a matter of religious obligation and&#xA;duty.&amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;#4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05  IV         Income of the State</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/05_ch04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/05_ch04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IV&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Income of the State&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the main functions of the state was collection of taxes. No&#xA;scheme of conquest or defence or administration was possible without&#xA;regular inflow of revenue. Muslim jurists divide the revenue of a Muslim&#xA;state into two categories - religious and secular. The principal&#xA;religious tax was Zakat and it was collected from the Muslims only. The&#xA;secular taxes comprised Khams, Jiziyah and Kharaj; these were levied on&#xA;the non-Muslims. So these were four major taxes - Khams, Jiziyah, Kharaj&#xA;and Zakat. Besides these there were a few other sources of revenue. The&#xA;importance of sound state finance was widely recognized by Muslim&#xA;political thinkers and administrators. The financial system of the&#xA;Muslim state was laid down by the Shariat and the Abbasid tradition. By&#xA;the time the Muslim state was established in India, its revenue system&#xA;had been carefully elaborated and its principles clearly set.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06  V         Expenditure of the State</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/06_ch05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/06_ch05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;V&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Expenditure of the State&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The income of the state was expended on various branches of government&#xA;and administration, on the harems of kings and nobles, and on forts,&#xA;palaces, mosques and tombs. Large amounts were sent abroad to Muslim&#xA;holy places like Mecca and Medina and for the Caliphs. At home, men of&#xA;letters and men of religion were given handsome awards and grants,&#xA;pensions and lump sum amounts. Salaries and scholarships were given to&#xA;students and mendicants. Dowries were distributed among the indigent for&#xA;marriage of their daughters and free kitchens established for&#xA;distribution of food among the poor. The most important and recurring&#xA;item of expenditure was on the army and construction of buildings. All&#xA;this information is provided by medieval chroniclers. What is not&#xA;mentioned is the actual amount of money spent on them. These, if ever,&#xA;are given sparingly. We shall, therefore, mention the actual amounts&#xA;wherever given; about other items of expenditure a sort of probable&#xA;assessment alone would be surmised. Expenditure was incurred on all the&#xA;above mentioned items simultaneously. But we can assess the expenditure&#xA;only item-wise. Architectural activity of the state may be taken up&#xA;first. it was a major activity of the Muslim government. While the&#xA;armies, the palaces and the harems have all disappeared with the&#xA;disappearance of Muslim rule, the one thing that strikes the eye in&#xA;Delhi and Agra and many other towns and cities is the buildings of the&#xA;Muslim period called monuments today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07  VI         Muslim State in India Today</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/07_ch06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/07_ch06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;VI&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Muslim State in India Today&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The invasions of Muhammad bin Qasim, Mahmud of Ghazni and Amir Timur&#xA;seem to have happened yesterday. The Qutb Minar in Delhi reminds one of&#xA;Aibak and Iltutmish. One who visits the Taj Mahal of Agra, remembers&#xA;Shahjahan. Akbar and Aurangzeb are still the talk of the town. Truly has&#xA;Bernard Croce said that all history is contemporary. Our living present&#xA;is the extension of the past which in many ways is still with us. No&#xA;wonder then that Muslim state in India has not ceased to exist. It is&#xA;not known as Nizam-i-Mustafa, as, in the Indian secular democracy, it&#xA;cannot be known by that nomenclature. But it has been internalised in&#xA;the Muslim psyche and is expressed in a number of euphemistic phrases&#xA;like Muslim Identity, Muslim Personal Law, (Muslim) Minorities&#xA;Commission, Muslim Waqf Board, Muslim (Madrasa) Education, and so on.&#xA;All in all, Muslims by their personal law and separate identity&#xA;represent a separate system within the secular Indian state, if not a&#xA;separate state within the Indian state.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08  VII         A Riposte on Reviews</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/08_ch07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/08_ch07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;VII&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A Riposte on Reviews&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the preliminary pages, the list of books &amp;ldquo;by the same author&amp;rdquo; shows&#xA;that during the past fifty years I have written a dozen books on&#xA;medieval Indian history beginning from 1950 onwards. As usual these have&#xA;been reviewed in journals in India and abroad, bestowing both praise and&#xA;blame as per the custom of the reviewers. However, during the last&#xA;fifteen years or so, some of my books have received special attention of&#xA;a &lt;em&gt;certain brand of scholars&lt;/em&gt; for adverse criticism. Although this gives&#xA;me publicity and raises demand for my books because such reviews arouse&#xA;curiosity of readers, it also provides me with an opportunity to defend&#xA;myself from my detractors determined to denigrate my work. It is not&#xA;customary to answer the reviewers - they have their right of judgement -&#xA;but when a systematic smear campaign is launched criticising everything&#xA;that I say, without a single word of appreciation for anything, a&#xA;rebuttal is called for, more so when a connection and not mere&#xA;coincidence is discernible between the uncharitable review of one of my&#xA;books in a British journal and some other harsh reviews by a group of&#xA;Aligarh historians in Indian historical journals. In some Western&#xA;universities, Aligarh is known to be the only centre of research on&#xA;medieval Indian history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 Bibliography</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/09_bib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/09_bib/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bibliography&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Original Sources&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abdullah, &lt;em&gt;Tarikh-i-Daudi&lt;/em&gt;, Bankipore Ms. Text, ed. by SA. Rashid,&#xA;Aligarh, 1954.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abdul Hamid Lahori, &lt;em&gt;Badshah Nama&lt;/em&gt;, Bib. Ind., 2 vols., Calcutta, 1898.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abul Fazl, Allami, &lt;em&gt;Ain-i-Akbari&lt;/em&gt;, 3 vols., vol. I trs. by H. Blochmann&#xA;and ed. by D.C. Phillot, Calcutta, 1939; vol. II trs. by H. S. Jarret&#xA;and annotated by Jadunath Sarkar, Calcutta, 1939; vol. III trs. by&#xA;Jarret and Sarkar, Calcutta, 1948.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abul Fazl, Allami, &lt;em&gt;Akbar Nama&lt;/em&gt;, Bib. Ind. Text, 3 vols., English trs.&#xA;by Henry Beveridge, Calcutta, 1948.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>books</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/11_books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_state_theory_practice/11_books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[TABLE]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WWW  This Site&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;images/header.gif&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;images/header.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;images/shim.gif&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;images/shim.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;images/shim.gif&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;images/shim.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Featured Books&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[TABLE]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;images/shim.gif&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;images/shim.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Other Books&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;books/ayodhya/&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;images/bookcover_ayodhya.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;images/bookcover_ayodhya.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;books/ayodhya/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ayodhya and After: Issues Before Hindu Society&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Koenraad Elst&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Published By Voice of India&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, India&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;images/shim.gif&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;images/shim.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;books/acat/&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;images/bookcover_acat.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;images/bookcover_acat.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;books/acat/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ayodhya: The Case against the Temple&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Koenraad Elst&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Published By Voice of India&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, India&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;images/shim.gif&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;images/shim.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;books/bjp/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BJP vis-à-vis Hindu Resurgence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Koenraad Elst&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Leuven, Netherlands&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright ©, Dr.Koenraad Elst, 1997&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Published By Voice of India&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, India&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
