<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;interviews on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;interviews on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>359 MIRACLES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/359_miracles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/359_miracles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;miracles&#34;&gt;MIRACLES&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;The Memphis Commercial, 15th January, 1894&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Asked by the reporter for his impressions of America, he said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have a good impression of this country especially of the American&#xA;women. I have especially remarked on the absence of poverty in America.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The conversation afterward turned to the subject of religions. Swami&#xA;Vive Kananda expressed the opinion that the World&amp;rsquo;s Parliament of&#xA;Religions had been beneficial in that it had done much toward broadening&#xA;ideas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>360 AN INDIAN YOGI IN LONDON</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/360_an_indian_yogi_in_london/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/360_an_indian_yogi_in_london/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-indian-yogi-in-london&#34;&gt;AN INDIAN YOGI IN LONDON&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;The Westminster Gazette, 23rd October, 1895&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Indian philosophy has in recent years had a deep and growing fascination&#xA;for many minds, though up to the present time its exponents in this&#xA;country have been entirely Western in their thought and training, with&#xA;the result that very little is really known of the deeper mysteries of&#xA;the Vedanta wisdom, and that little only by a select few. Not many have&#xA;the courage or the intuition to seek in heavy translations, made greatly&#xA;in the interests of philologists, for that sublime knowledge which they&#xA;really reveal to an able exponent brought up in all the traditions of&#xA;the East.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>361 INDIA&#39;S MISSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/361_indias_mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/361_indias_mission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;indias-mission&#34;&gt;INDIA&amp;rsquo;S MISSION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Sunday Times, London, 1896&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;English people are well acquainted with the fact that they send&#xA;missionaries to India&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;coral strands&amp;rdquo;. Indeed, so thoroughly do they&#xA;obey the behest, &amp;ldquo;Go ye forth into all the world and preach the Gospel&amp;rdquo;,&#xA;that none of the chief British sects are behindhand in obedience to the&#xA;call to spread Christ&amp;rsquo;s teaching. People are not so well aware that&#xA;India also sends missionaries to England.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;By accident, if the term may be allowed, I fell across the Swami&#xA;Vivekananda in his temporary home at 63 St. George&amp;rsquo;s Road, S. W., and as&#xA;he did not object to discuss the nature of his work and visit to&#xA;England, I sought him there and began our talk with an expression of&#xA;surprise at his assent to my request.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>362 INDIA AND ENGLAND</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/362_india_and_england/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/362_india_and_england/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;india-and-england&#34;&gt;INDIA AND ENGLAND&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;India, London, 1896&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the London season, Swami Vivekananda has been teaching and&#xA;lecturing to considerable numbers of people who have been attracted by&#xA;his doctrine and philosophy. Most English people fancy that England has&#xA;the practical monopoly of missionary enterprise, almost unbroken save&#xA;for a small effort on the part of France. I therefore sought the Swami&#xA;in his temporary home in South Belgravia to enquire what message India&#xA;could possibly send to England, apart from the remonstrances she has too&#xA;often had to make on the subject of home charges, judicial and executive&#xA;functions combined in one person, the settlement of expenses connected&#xA;with Sudanese and other expeditions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>363 INDIAN MISSIONARY&#39;S MISSION TO ENGLAND</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/363_indian_missionarys_mission_to_england/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/363_indian_missionarys_mission_to_england/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;indian-missionarys-mission-to-england&#34;&gt;INDIAN MISSIONARY&amp;rsquo;S MISSION TO ENGLAND&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;The Echo, London, 1896&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;. . . I presume that in his own country the Swami would live under a&#xA;tree, or at most in the precincts of a temple, his head shaved, dressed&#xA;in the costume of his country. But these things are not done in London,&#xA;so that I found the Swami located much like other people, and, save that&#xA;he wears a long coat of a dark orange shade, dressed like other mortals&#xA;likewise. He laughingly related that his dress, especially when he wears&#xA;a turban, does not commend itself to the London street arab, whose&#xA;observations are scarcely worth repeating. I began by asking the Indian&#xA;Yogi to spell his name very slowly. . . .&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>364 WITH THE SWAMI VIVEKANANDA AT MADURA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/364_with_the_swami_vivekananda_at_madura/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/364_with_the_swami_vivekananda_at_madura/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;with-the-swami-vivekananda-at-madura&#34;&gt;WITH THE SWAMI VIVEKANANDA AT MADURA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;The Hindu, Madras, February, 1897&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q&lt;/em&gt;. — The theory that the universe is false seems to be understood in&#xA;the following senses: (a) the sense in which the duration of perishing&#xA;forms and names is infinitesimally small with reference to eternity; (b)&#xA;the sense in which the period between any two Pralayas (involution of&#xA;the universe) is infinitesimally small with reference to eternity; (c)&#xA;the sense in which the universe is ultimately false though it has an&#xA;apparent reality at present, depending upon one sort of consciousness,&#xA;in the same way as the idea of silver superimposed on a shell or that of&#xA;a serpent on a rope, is true for the time being, and, in effect, is&#xA;dependent upon a particular condition of mind; (d) the sense in which&#xA;the universe is a phantom just like the son of a barren woman or like&#xA;the horns of a hare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>365 THE ABROAD AND THE PROBLEMS AT HOME</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/365_the_abroad_and_the_problems_at_home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/365_the_abroad_and_the_problems_at_home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-abroad-and-the-problems-at-home&#34;&gt;THE ABROAD AND THE PROBLEMS AT HOME&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;The Hindu, Madras, February, 1897&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our representative met the Swami Vivekananda in the train at the&#xA;Chingleput Station and travelled with him to Madras. The following is&#xA;the report of the interview:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What made you go to America, Swamiji?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Rather a serious question to answer in brief. I can only answer it&#xA;partly now. Because I travelled all over India, I wanted to go over to&#xA;other countries. I went to America by the Far East.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>366 THE MISSIONARY WORK OF THE FIRST HINDU
SANNYASIN TO THE WEST 
AND
HIS PLAN
OF REGENERATION OF INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/366_the_missionary_work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/366_the_missionary_work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-missionary-work-of-the-first-hindu-sannyasin-to-the-west-and-his-plan-of-regeneration-of-india&#34;&gt;THE MISSIONARY WORK OF THE FIRST HINDU SANNYASIN TO THE WEST AND HIS PLAN OF REGENERATION OF INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Madras Times, February, 1897&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the past few weeks, the Hindu public of Madras have been most&#xA;eagerly expecting the arrival of Swami Vivekananda, the great Hindu monk&#xA;of world-wide fame. At the present moment his name is on everybody&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;lips. In the school, in the college, in the High Court, on the marina,&#xA;and in the streets and bazars of Madras, hundreds of inquisitive spirits&#xA;may be seen asking when the Swami will be coming. Large numbers of&#xA;students from the mofussil, who have come up for the University&#xA;examinations are staying here, awaiting the Swami, and increasing their&#xA;hostelry bills, despite the urgent call of their parents to return home&#xA;immediately. In a few days the Swami will be in our midst. From the&#xA;nature of the receptions received elsewhere in this Presidency, from the&#xA;preparations being made here, from the triumphal arches erected at&#xA;Castle Kernan, where the &amp;ldquo;Prophet&amp;rdquo; is to be lodged at the cost of the&#xA;Hindu public, and from the interest taken in the movement by the leading&#xA;Hindu gentlemen of this city, like the Hon&amp;rsquo;ble Mr. Justice Subramaniya&#xA;Iyer, there is no doubt that the Swami will have a grand reception. It&#xA;was Madras that first recognised the superior merits of the Swami and&#xA;equipped him for Chicago. Madras will now have again the honour of&#xA;welcoming the undoubtedly great man who has done so much to raise the&#xA;prestige of his motherland. Four year ago, when the Swami arrived here,&#xA;he was practically an obscure individual. In an unknown bungalow at St.&#xA;Thome he spent nearly two months, all along holding conversations on&#xA;religious topics and teaching and instructing all comers who cared to&#xA;listen to him. Even then a few educated young men with &amp;ldquo;a keener eye&amp;rdquo;&#xA;predicted that there was something in the man, &amp;ldquo;a power&amp;rdquo;, that would&#xA;lift him above all others, that would pre-eminently enable him to be the&#xA;leader of men. These young men, who were then despised as &amp;ldquo;misguided&#xA;enthusiasts&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;dreamy revivalists&amp;rdquo;, have now the supreme satisfaction of&#xA;seeing their Swami, as they love to call him, return to them with a&#xA;great European and American fame. The mission of the Swami is&#xA;essentially spiritual. He firmly believes that India, the motherland of&#xA;spirituality, has a great future before her. He is sanguine that the&#xA;West will more and more come to appreciate what he regards as the&#xA;sublime truths of Vedanta. His great motto is &amp;ldquo;Help, and not Fight&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Assimilation, and not Destruction&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Harmony and Peace, and not&#xA;Dissension&amp;rdquo;. Whatever difference of opinion followers of other creeds&#xA;may have with him, few will venture to deny that the Swami has done&#xA;yeoman&amp;rsquo;s service to his country in opening the eyes of the Western world&#xA;to &amp;ldquo;the good in the Hindu&amp;rdquo;. He will always be remembered as the first&#xA;Hindu Sannyāsin who dared to cross the sea to carry to the West the&#xA;message of what he believes in as a religious peace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>367 REAWAKENING OF HINDUISM ON A NATIONAL BASIS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/367_reawakening_of_hinduism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/367_reawakening_of_hinduism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reawakening-of-hinduism-on-a-national-basis&#34;&gt;REAWAKENING OF HINDUISM ON A NATIONAL BASIS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Prabuddha Bharata, September, 1898&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In an interview which a representative of &lt;em&gt;Prabuddha Bharata&lt;/em&gt; had&#xA;recently with the Swami Vivekananda, that great Teacher was asked: &amp;ldquo;What&#xA;do you consider the distinguishing feature of your movement, Swamiji?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aggression,&amp;rdquo; said the Swami promptly, &amp;ldquo;aggression in a religious sense&#xA;only. Other sects and parties have carried spirituality all over India,&#xA;but since the days of Buddha we have been the first to break bounds and&#xA;try to flood the world with missionary zeal.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>368 ON INDIAN WOMEN — THEIR PAST, PRESENT AND FUTURE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/368_on_indian_women/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/368_on_indian_women/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-indian-women--their-past-present-and-future&#34;&gt;ON INDIAN WOMEN — THEIR PAST, PRESENT AND FUTURE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Prabuddha Bharata, December, 1898&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was early one Sunday morning, writes our representative, in a&#xA;beautiful Himalayan valley, that I was at last able to carry out the&#xA;order of the Editor, and call on the Swami Vivekananda, to ascertain&#xA;something of his views on the position and prospects of Indian Women.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let us go for a walk&amp;rdquo;, said the Swami, when I had announced my errand,&#xA;and we set out at once amongst some of the most lovely scenery in the&#xA;world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>369 ON THE BOUNDS OF HINDUISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/369_on_the_bounds_of_hinduism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/interviews/369_on_the_bounds_of_hinduism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-the-bounds-of-hinduism&#34;&gt;ON THE BOUNDS OF HINDUISM&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Prabuddha Bharata, April, 1899&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having been directed by the Editor, writes our representative, to&#xA;interview Swami Vivekananda on the question of converts to Hinduism, I&#xA;found an opportunity one evening on the roof of a Ganga houseboat. It&#xA;was after nightfall, and we had stopped at the embankment of the&#xA;Ramakrishna Math, and there the Swami came down to speak with me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Time and place were alike delightful. Overhead the stars, and around —&#xA;the rolling Ganga; and on one side stood the dimly lighted building,&#xA;with its background of palms and lofty shade-trees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
