<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Crime on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/society/crime/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Crime on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/society/crime/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Criminal orgs</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/society/crime/orgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/society/crime/orgs/</guid>
      <description>Intro Sometimes criminals form organizations with internal rules and hierarchies. Organization may vary from loose to tight. Big criminal organizations, based on their geographic origin and organization, can be classified into Mafia (Sicily), &amp;lsquo;Ndranghetta (Calabria), Yakuza (Japan), Triad (China), Mexican cartels, Columbian cartels and others. Sometimes, as in the case of Yakuza, they are semi-open.
Some avoid particular endeavours - like drugs.
Administration In order to guard against prosecution by maintaining plausible deniability, orders are often passed down through a strict hierarchy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Law Enforcement</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/society/crime/law_enforcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/society/crime/law_enforcement/</guid>
      <description>Forensics Police visit a crime scene, collect and record evidence. Then they speculate events which might account for the evidence - the speculation may be done by professional &amp;lsquo;profilers&amp;rsquo;.
Arrest Entrapment The aim is sometimes to prevent, rather than punish crime after the fact. Entrapment can lead to confession of plans; but it can also act as a way by which police informants encourage people, who would otherwise not be competent or coherent to do so, to plan and very nearly commit a crime.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>