<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Real time communication on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/communication/real-time/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Real time communication on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/communication/real-time/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Body language</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/communication/real-time/body-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/communication/real-time/body-language/</guid>
      <description>Intro The body language is indeed a language with words and phrases. The body can communicate even when there are no spoken words. The primary function of body language is to express emotions and status among surrounding animals; and its vocabulary is specialized for that. Using body language, one can speak multiple words simultaneously.
Importance of mastering it Body language is widely understood, often unconsciously. Bad skill at it is often results in miscommunication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Composure</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/communication/real-time/composure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/communication/real-time/composure/</guid>
      <description>Prepare content in advance if necessary.
Importance This is especially important while meeting strangers.
Most people do not want to be burdened by an unsettled, harried individual - they are wary of getting tangled in unsavoury business.
General technique Concentrate on the high order bits: the important matter. Solemnly recognize that exchange of information/ expectations is the most important point of the meeting and determinedly focus the intellect on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/communication/real-time/content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/communication/real-time/content/</guid>
      <description>In conversation, it is better to talk about others’ work and learn, than to talk about oneself.
Ask questions that require more than a simple &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; answer to subtly encourage a shy or introverted person to keep talking.
Conduct interviews. Make them talk about themselves and their work.
Be prepared - try not to ask questions which could have been answered by other means. Special questions: How did you get your job?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courtesy, Formality</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/communication/real-time/formality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/communication/real-time/formality/</guid>
      <description>Be courteous. Discourtesy implies not wanting friendship. Formality in politics and diplomacy was not invented without reason.
Courtesy is required for smooth operation, without misunderstandings, in the society of strangers. This is particularly useful, if help or information is later required from those strangers.
Common courtesys: Hold heavy doors open for people who are just behind you. Follow the queue system. Shake hands. Stand when others are standing.
Say please. But, don’t overdo it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delivery voice</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/communication/real-time/delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/communication/real-time/delivery/</guid>
      <description>Use an accent understandable by them.
Use the language closest to their native language.
Voices Confidential voice Drop defenses, smile. Adapt a calm, soft/ confidential voice.
Commanding voice Adapt a deep tone, clear and easily heard voice, act as if it is your right to be obeyed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>