<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Docs on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Docs on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>abdAlI to Ottoman</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/abdAlI_to_ottoman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/abdAlI_to_ottoman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Sourcde&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Translated Letter of Durrani Shahenshah Ahmad Shah Abdali to Ottoman Gazavat-E-Sultan Mustafa III&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: Mahmud-Nadir Şah Mektuplaşmaları 3 numaralı Hümayun Defteri (Mahmud to Nadir Shah Era Correspondences Volume - 3, Humayun Daftar), Letter no. 70. pg. 241 to 245.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Summary&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ahmad Shah Abdali describes his career before his engagement with the Maratha Empire. He credits himself with saving the Timurid Dynasty and saving Islam in India from the Maratha conquerors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ch pratApa-siMha to rango bApUjI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/Chatrapati-pratApa-siMha_to_rango-bApUjI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/Chatrapati-pratApa-siMha_to_rango-bApUjI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Raja Pratap Singh wrote the following letter to Rungo Bapoojee on 30th August 1839 :&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our ancestor Sewajee Maharaj, founded the Mabratta Empire by his own valour, and protected the Hindoo religion as it exists to this day.+++(5)+++ Our ministers, great officers, and other servants of the State have hitherto performed their several duties. It now appears, that the English Company&amp;rsquo;s Resident, Colonel Ovans, having taken Ballajee Punt Natoo under his protection, has been concocting a conspiracy for the purpose of effecting our overthrow. In order to accomplish this more successfully, be has induced our younger brother, Appa Sahib, to proceed to his residence. He has also succeeded in shaking the allegiance of several oficers of State, and prevailed on them to look upon Appa Sahib as their master. I can now only depend upon my two Ranees, my daughter, and Bulwant Raje Bhonsley Senaputtee, as those who yet remaia faithful to me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Govinda rAv to nAnA 1792</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/govinda-rAv_to_nAnA-phaDnavis_1792/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/govinda-rAv_to_nAnA-phaDnavis_1792/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Govindrao Kale, who long resided at the Court of Haidarabad, thus writes to Nana Phadnis, and congratulates the Maratha Government on the signal achievements of Mahadji Sindia in regulating the affairs of the Emperor at Delhi, and fulfilling the objects of Maratha policy. 2nd July 1792.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I were to adequately express what I have felt, upon reading your most inspiring letter, giving an account of the crowning glories achieved by Mahadji at Delhi, I should have to write volumes ; still I cannot repress my enthusiasm, and I make myself so bold as to transgress the ordinary limit, and write some of the uppermost thoughts of my mind. Each single item gives occasion for a separate congratulation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ismail beg battle report</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/ismail-beg-battle-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/ismail-beg-battle-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Jyeshta Shuddha 15 Pournima (18 June 1788), Wednesday, we fought a battle with Ismail Beg. From dawn to evening the battle continued. Mons. Lestinau and Deboigne&amp;rsquo;s battalions were combined in the center, along with all the artillery. Our cavalry was on both wings, and one more detachment was sent to flank the enemy in their rear. Shrimant&amp;rsquo;s good fortune and God&amp;rsquo;s will has granted Mahadji a great victory. Our cavalry and battalions fought very well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jayasiMha to ChatrasAla</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/jaya-siMha-to-ChatrasAla/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/jaya-siMha-to-ChatrasAla/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/in.ernet.dli.2015.119126/page/n73/mode/2up?view=theater&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(In his letter dated October 16, 1708 to Chhatrasal, Jai Singh wrote that the trouble started when the Emperor, while granting them mansabs, incorporated the parganas of their watans into khalisa.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your Highness hnows well as to how one can live, without a watan and what is (the importance) of a mansab without the watan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Informing Chhatrasal about the Rajput victory at Sambhar in which three thousand of the enemy were killed, and expressing his confidence that similar victories would be gained by them in future also, he wrote,)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jayasiMha to shAhu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/jaya-siMha-to-shAhu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/jaya-siMha-to-shAhu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source- &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/in.ernet.dli.2015.119126/page/n67/mode/2up?view=theater&#34;&gt;https://archive.org/details/in.ernet.dli.2015.119126/page/n67/mode/2up?view=theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A draft letter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your Highness must be aware of the cordial ties that existed among our elders. I hope, by the kindness of Shri Ramji, the ties between us shall grow still closer. Shah Alam, after becoming the Emperor, resumed my watan, and called Maharaja Ajit Singh to the Court assuring him that Jodhpur would be restored to him, but did not do so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This news must have reached Your Highness. I, on my part, spared no effort, to serve the Patshah, but he harbours malice towards the Hindus, and on one pretext or another wants to ruin them.+++(5)+++ For this reason, and as it was considered necessary, we broke off from the Emperor and came to Rana Amar Singh at Udaipur, and after (full) deliberations decided that if the Patshah even now becomes favourable towards the Hindus and restores mansabs and watam, as had been enjoyed by their ancestors, then it is all right, otherwise the Hindus will also do what they can.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quanlong to Abdali</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/qianlong_to_abdAli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/qianlong_to_abdAli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;English translation (Qianlong to Abdali)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You say in your memorial that the Ma-er-ta Khan Na-bala-chi (nAnAsaheb balAjI) heard that you had taken the city/fortress of Zha-ha-naba-te (and thus) collected together his neighboring tribes/polities, totaling several hundred thousand each of cavalry and infantry, to come fight with you. When he reached Qi-li-na-le he heard that you were leading a mass (of troops) to come meet him. They all then took refuge in the fortress of Pani-pa-te. You attacked and besieged them for six months, obliterated scores of their great commanders (bo-ke = beg), over a hundred thousand of their partisans, and seized gold, silver, and precious vessels beyond count. Now, since Na-bala-chi was able to join together a mass of partisans, how is it possible that he would enter at once into a strong fortress without having first joined battle, sitting and waiting for his execution? This matter is truly impossible to fathom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sadAshivarAv to abdAli</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/sadAshivarAv_to_abdAlI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/sadAshivarAv_to_abdAlI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the paatshahi of the Hindus. We will make all arrangements here. You have left your country and taking counsel from Shuja ud daulah and Najib Khan and come here with earnest ardor (to take over this country). Earlier too you came and completely subjugated the paatshahi. Now you come with the advice of Mirabubu begum. This is not the way of justice. When you came last time, had we been present here, we would have ensured the paatshahi would not have been disturbed. Who are you to set the rules? We will do what we please.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
