<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;1 Becoming Temujin on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/1_Becoming_Temujin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;1 Becoming Temujin on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/1_Becoming_Temujin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 The Teeth That Eat Men</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/1_Becoming_Temujin/1_The_Teeth_That_Eat_Men/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/1_Becoming_Temujin/1_The_Teeth_That_Eat_Men/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The boy who would become Genghis Khan was born in a small encampment at the head of the Onon River in the fall of 1162, in the busy season of the year between the processing of dairy products from summer and the slaughtering of meat for winter. This was a time for gathering cedar nuts, wild onions, forest mushrooms, medicinal seeds, and wilted flowers to flavor winter soup and tea. It was the season when the herders could drink a constant supply of fermented mare’s milk and enjoy the final wild strawberries and raspberries with sheep or goat yogurt. It was, in short, the best time of year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 The Golden Whip of Heaven</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/1_Becoming_Temujin/2_The_Golden_Whip_of_Heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/1_Becoming_Temujin/2_The_Golden_Whip_of_Heaven/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Secret History&lt;/em&gt; rarely presents the events or thoughts of family members preceding a major conflict; the words simply explode into unforeseen and inexplicable violence. When Temujin was in his early teens he came into conflict with his half brother Begter, Sochigel’s elder son, who was probably only two or three years older than he. The only provocation seemed to be that Begter had snatched a small fish from the hook of Temujin’s fishing line, demonstrating that he was the older, stronger brother and, in the absence of their father, he planned to take charge of the household.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Wisdom of the Steppe</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/1_Becoming_Temujin/3_Wisdom_of_the_Steppe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/1_Becoming_Temujin/3_Wisdom_of_the_Steppe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Burkhan Khaldun, one wise person such as Old Jarchigudai could know everything there was to be known, but hidden in the tall standing grass of the steppe were traces of men who had built empires that stretched beyond the realms of Temujin’s imagination. They had left accounts of their successes and failures and advice to future inhabitants carved on the stones across the steppe. Temujin could not read the stone inscriptions, but he was mesmerized by them and knew he would need to learn from their valuable lessons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Conflicting Selves</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/1_Becoming_Temujin/4_Conflicting_Selves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/1_Becoming_Temujin/4_Conflicting_Selves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Each person contains within them a multitude of selves, and within these various incarnations conflict and contradiction are inevitable. A certain part of one’s character seems to be set at birth, but gradually, with the experience of life, new aspects emerge and compete for dominance. Such a struggle marks the beginning of an independent personality, as we choose the person we wish to become. The constellation of conflicting selves changes over time, with different selves struggling to the fore while older ones fade away or stubbornly cling to their former importance. In the midst of these converging and competing claims one can sometimes hear the voices of one’s past, the phrases, stories, myths, and songs that the child learns and that remain in the adult as artifacts of an abandoned past.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
