<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/matter/history/hindu/articles/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/matter/history/hindu/articles/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The sound and wave theories of the Hindus</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/matter/history/hindu/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-11-11_the-sound-and-wave-theories-of-the-hindus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/matter/history/hindu/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-11-11_the-sound-and-wave-theories-of-the-hindus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/11/11/the-sound-and-wave-theories-of-the-hindus/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The achievements early Hindu science are hardly known in an objective form. They are either being neglected due to the efforts of the leftist Anti-Hindu academics from the West and India or exaggerated by uneducated Hindus. One of the great Hindu theories of which we get some limited glimpses are the ideas on sound propagation which are discussed at length in the mImAsa text of shabara svAmin. In short they include the following idea for the transmission of sound:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>chemistry-ed</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/matter/history/hindu/articles/MT_lekhAH/chemistry-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/matter/history/hindu/articles/MT_lekhAH/chemistry-ed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another longish thread on education in light of the mlechCha-liberal fake news that the periodic table had been removed from the Indian curriculum. Here again, I take a similar view to evolution that it should be introduced early.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I acknowledge that chemistry is a difficult subject to introduce. After starting with the atomic theory do you make the students go down the route of gas laws, moles and the foundations of thermodynamics; or do you make them study the basic types of compounds, or do you introduce them to the diversity of elements and their properties?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
