<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2023-attack</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/MT/2023-attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/MT/2023-attack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1710905676141146570.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is unclear if the marUnmatta-s had any strategy in their current ghazwat. It was heavy on tactical effervescence &amp;ndash; something also previously seen with their coreligionist from the occupied pA~nchanada &amp;amp; sindhu &amp;ndash; but not clear if it aimed to achieve anything strategically. It that sense it was just like the 9/11 attack &amp;ndash; mass civilian deaths for shock value that will draw the attention of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive selection 2024</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/MT/cognitive-selection_2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/MT/cognitive-selection_2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.palladiummag.com/2024/01/26/the-u-s-can-learn-from-israels-cognitive-meritocracy/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृत् - टिप्पनी&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Israeli program to make best use of the high cognitive capacity of their people&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Such a plan might work to some degree even among peoples with much lower pop. density of cognitive capacity but what they may lack is the necessary cohesion via @Rjrasva&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Can Learn From Israel’s Cognitive Meritocracy&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.palladiummag.com/2024/01/26/the-u-s-can-learn-from-israels-cognitive-meritocracy/&#34;&gt;https://www.palladiummag.com/2024/01/26/the-u-s-can-learn-from-israels-cognitive-meritocracy/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many of the cognitive elite &amp;amp; their descendants who played a key role in the Soviet Rus programs moved Isr &amp;amp; added mental muscle to their capacity in the 1990s. I&amp;rsquo;ll mention one admittedly anecdotal case: met an individual who had served in the above. He was politically a mild guy: was ready to concede 2-state solution, wanted to sign treaties with the Mohds, was quite critical of his own politicians etc. An equivalent H guy would be typically rank against H interests. But this guy was not against the interests of his people. He was v.invested &amp;amp; keen in the survival of his people and his tradition which despite certain criticisms he had deep respect for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>el yahoo</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/MT/el_yahoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/MT/el_yahoo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1632398509512052741&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Mar1 conjunction of Jupiter (above) and Venus (below) over a palm tree seen from a beach in Jaffa, Isr.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our theological rather adventurous guide (but probably closer to the original religious situation) remarked that it is like the 2 Semitic deities El from the North (with a prAjApatya character &amp;ndash; my comment) &amp;amp; Yahoo from the south with an aindravAyava character) being conflated into a mono-deity with the rise of monolatrous religion among the tribes of the region. He remarks that the Southern predecessors of the modern paleo-Abrahamists were Yahoo focal whereas the northern ones were more El focal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kishinev-riot</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/MT/kishinev-riot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/MT/kishinev-riot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A riot in rUs empire in the obscure town of Kishinev breaking out over a rumor of u1s using a u2&amp;rsquo;s blood in a ritual resulted in several of the former being killed by the latter. This event had a direct role in origin of the modern state of ISR. A u1 poet laments their weakness&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Come, now, and I will bring thee to their lairs&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The privies, jakes and pigpens where the heirs&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Of Hasmoneans lay, with trembling knees,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Concealed and cowering, the sons of the Maccabees!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The seed of saints, the scions of the lions!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Who, crammed by scores in all the sanctuaries of their shame,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;So sanctified My name!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It was the flight of mice they fled,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The scurrying of roaches was their flight;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;They died like dogs, and they were dead!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And on the next morn, after the terrible night&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The son who was not murdered found&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The spurned cadaver of his father on the ground.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Now wherefore cost thou weep, O son of man?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pre-independence-hindu-comparison</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/MT/pre-independence-hindu-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/canaanite/yehUda_yahUda/articles/MT/pre-independence-hindu-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1713806212473536697.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Comparing the J and the H responses in the final phase of their movements for independence, the armed struggle played a critical role in both cases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Savarkar was correct in urging the H youth “to gain practice” for the impending war by participating in WW2. In the case of the J a related idea went back to Trumpeldor, who gained experience serving the Russians. Later, many J gained experience in Polish units during WW2. This really gave their armed struggle considerable muscle and allowed them to form the ISR military as soon as the English left.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
