<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;5 The Consolidation of Mughal Rule, 1526–1605 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/5_The_Consolidation_of_Mughal_Rule_15261605/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;5 The Consolidation of Mughal Rule, 1526–1605 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/5_The_Consolidation_of_Mughal_Rule_15261605/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 OVERVIEW</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/5_The_Consolidation_of_Mughal_Rule_15261605/01_OVERVIEW/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/5_The_Consolidation_of_Mughal_Rule_15261605/01_OVERVIEW/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rise of the Mughal empire centres on the career of an extraordinary personality, Zahir al-Din Babur (d. 1530). Deprived of his father’s kingdom in the Central Asian highlands, Babur famously descended on the plains of India from his base in Kabul and, in a celebrated battle fought in 1526, defeated Ibrahim Lodi, the last ruler of the last dynasty of Delhi sultans. He then went on to launch India’s most splendid empire, which at its height would dominate nearly all of South Asia. Babur’s place in Indian history is rendered even more vivid thanks to his very personal and self-revealing memoir, the &lt;em&gt;Babur-nama&lt;/em&gt;, which combines elements of a diary, a gazetteer, a chronicle and a father’s advice to his son. Much of this fascinating text was drafted by lamplight or a flickering campfire before being packed in saddlebags, as Babur and his men rode from Samarqand to Kabul, and then on to Delhi [see Map 5].&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 BABUR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/5_The_Consolidation_of_Mughal_Rule_15261605/02_BABUR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/5_The_Consolidation_of_Mughal_Rule_15261605/02_BABUR/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Babur was just eleven years old in 1494 when, on his father’s death, he ascended the throne of Ferghana, a small Central Asian principality 350 kilometres east of Samarqand, the jewel of Timurid Central Asia. From the very start, young Babur faced fierce resistance from his nobles and even his uncles, who tried to replace him with his more malleable younger brother. Nonetheless, when only fifteen he managed to seize control of Timur’s former capital of Samarqand. It proved a brief reign, however, for within just a few months he lost the city to a rival while trying to recover his base at Ferghana, which hostile elements had meanwhile snatched from his grasp. Finding himself now with no territory to rule, he spent several dismal years wandering about hills and valleys seeking kinsmen and supporters. In 1501 he made a second attempt at Samarqand, but was repulsed this time by a powerful confederation of ascendant Uzbeks, Turkish-speakers ethnically distinct from Timur’s Chagatai lineage of Turko-Mongols. One by one, Uzbek armies commanded by Muhammad Shaybani Khan (r. 1500–10) overthrew Babur’s kinsmen in the successor states of Timur’s former empire. Shaybani Khan had seized Samarqand just a year before Babur’s second attempt to recover the city, and in several years’ time he would take other flourishing centres of Persianate culture formerly under Timurid control, notably Bukhara. For his part, Babur was reduced to utter destitution, accompanied by a small band of loyal retainers and his mother, Qutlugh Nigar Khanum, who in their worst times was given the use of the only tent they possessed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 HUMAYUN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/5_The_Consolidation_of_Mughal_Rule_15261605/03_HUMAYUN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/5_The_Consolidation_of_Mughal_Rule_15261605/03_HUMAYUN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although repeatedly dismayed with his behaviour, in the end Babur favoured Humayun over his younger sons to manage the newly won kingdom. On one occasion, when Humayun lay seriously ill, he even vowed to offer his own life for that of his ailing son. Upon praying while thrice circumambulating Humayun’s bed, he sensed that Humayun’s illness had passed. He was right about that, but soon thereafter Babur himself was stricken by a severe illness to which he succumbed in December 1530. According to his wishes, he was buried in a magnificent garden he had earlier laid out on a Kabul hillside.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 AKBAR’S EARLY YEARS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/5_The_Consolidation_of_Mughal_Rule_15261605/04_AKBARS_EARLY_YEARS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/5_The_Consolidation_of_Mughal_Rule_15261605/04_AKBARS_EARLY_YEARS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No succession struggle followed Humayun’s death. At the time, Akbar was thirteen and already in the capital of Delhi, whereas his half-brother Mirza Hakim was a two-year old child and in distant Kabul. It was apparent, moreover, that Akbar was blessed with a gift for memory and remarkable intelligence, even though his tutors were unable to teach him to read or write, as he was apparently dyslexic. Fortuitously, the young heir was placed under the regency of Bairam Khan, whose competent generalship had facilitated Humayun’s restoration of Mughal rule. On the other hand, his father’s short tenure after the restoration had given him little opportunity to consolidate his rule, as a result of which the countryside in upper India still abounded with disaffected Afghans. In late 1556 Hemu, a Hindu general who had formerly served the dislodged Afghan regime, seized Delhi and set himself up as the city’s ‘liberator’ and new sovereign. Bairam Khan met Hemu at the historic battlefield at Panipat, using the youthful Akbar to rally support for the Mughal cause. He also allowed his charge, barely fourteen years of age, his first taste of military combat, even letting him behead Hemu so that he could claim the title of &lt;em&gt;ghazi&lt;/em&gt;.16 Thanks to Bairam Khan’s exertions so early in Akbar’s reign, Hemu’s uprising had been quashed, and the heartland of upper India had fallen securely under Mughal control. The last two prominent princes of Sher Shah’s dynasty, Sikandar and Ibrahim, were soon defeated and driven away, while the stronghold of Gwalior, 100 kilometres south of Agra, was secured after a two-year siege.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 EMERGING IDENTITIES: RAJPUTS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/5_The_Consolidation_of_Mughal_Rule_15261605/05_EMERGING_IDENTITIES_RAJPUTS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/5_The_Consolidation_of_Mughal_Rule_15261605/05_EMERGING_IDENTITIES_RAJPUTS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;However, lying between upper India and Gujarat, and controlling the major trade routes passing between the two regions, was Rajasthan, the hilly, semi-arid tract home to powerful warrior lineages known since Akbar’s day as Rajputs. Despite the occasional successful siege of one of its famous strongholds, neither the slave sultans nor the Khalajis, Tughluqs, Lodis or Surs had been able to subdue these chieftains, much less annex their territories. Nor had any of the sultans of Delhi enlisted into their service Rajasthan’s major warrior lineages, who for centuries had remained Delhi’s obdurate foes. The mutual enmity had continued with Babur’s 1527 defeat of Rana Sanga at Khanua, a debacle still within living memory when Akbar rose to power. In view of this background, Akbar’s signature policy of integrating these lineages into Mughal service was all the more dramatic. This bold break with the past had far-reaching consequences for both Mughals and Rajputs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 MUGHAL EXPANSION UNDER AKBAR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/5_The_Consolidation_of_Mughal_Rule_15261605/06_MUGHAL_EXPANSION_UNDER_AKBAR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/5_The_Consolidation_of_Mughal_Rule_15261605/06_MUGHAL_EXPANSION_UNDER_AKBAR/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While enrolling Rajput warriors into his service, Akbar and his advisers refined and elaborated the decimal military organization they had inherited from Delhi sultanate, Timurid and Mongol traditions. By 1574 a rationalized system had emerged in which all state servants were classified into fixed ranks pegged to specified salaries and duties, and in most cases to specified assignments of land, or &lt;em&gt;jagir&lt;/em&gt;s, from whose revenues they were expected to recruit, train and support specified numbers of mounted cavalry. This was new. Whereas appointments and pay under previous regimes had been rather ad hoc, officers were now assigned a numerical rank, or &lt;em&gt;mansab&lt;/em&gt;, which could rise or fall according to assessments of the performance of the rank-holder, or &lt;em&gt;mansabdar&lt;/em&gt;. The number associated with each rank originally ranged anywhere from ten to 10,000, indicating how many soldiers a given &lt;em&gt;mansabdar&lt;/em&gt; was expected to maintain. Soon, however, ranks were expressed in two numbers: the first, &lt;em&gt;zat&lt;/em&gt;, was the &lt;em&gt;mansabdar&lt;/em&gt;’s personal salary; and the second, &lt;em&gt;sawar&lt;/em&gt;, the number of cavalrymen that the &lt;em&gt;mansabdar&lt;/em&gt; was expected to recruit, train, pay and command. The system therefore required matching a &lt;em&gt;mansabdar&lt;/em&gt;’s rank with a &lt;em&gt;jagir&lt;/em&gt; sufficient in size to support his required level of troops. &lt;em&gt;Jagir&lt;/em&gt;s were also uninheritable and temporary, as both &lt;em&gt;mansabdar&lt;/em&gt;s and their land assignments were regularly rotated through the realm every few years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 AKBAR’S RELIGIOUS IDEAS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/5_The_Consolidation_of_Mughal_Rule_15261605/07_AKBARS_RELIGIOUS_IDEAS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/5_The_Consolidation_of_Mughal_Rule_15261605/07_AKBARS_RELIGIOUS_IDEAS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Akbar’s views and policies regarding institutional religions evolved throughout his lifetime, swinging from one position to another in ways that puzzled or shocked contemporary observers. Both in his own day and in modern times he has been called everything from a strict Muslim to an apostate, from a free-thinker to a crypto-Hindu, from a Zoroastrian to a proto-Christian, from an atheist to a radical innovator, even a prophet. Each of these assessments contains a degree of truth, depending on which phase of his long forty-nine-year reign one considers. But through it all, the one constant was the emperor’s unquenchable curiosity regarding all things religious. This was abetted by his awareness that the turn of the first Islamic millennium, 1000 AH (AD 1591), would occur in the thirty-fifth year of his reign. Because that year also saw the height of his political successes and the maturity of his courtly style, some of his courtiers viewed Akbar as a millennial figure – as did the emperor himself for a while.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 CONCLUSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/5_The_Consolidation_of_Mughal_Rule_15261605/08_CONCLUSION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/5_The_Consolidation_of_Mughal_Rule_15261605/08_CONCLUSION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Between Babur’s arrival in Delhi in 1526 and Akbar’s death in 1605, the Mughal dynasty had become rooted in the heart of north India. In the intervening period, three monarchs consolidated their rule in a great swathe of territory where the regime’s governing institutions and cultural traditions became firmly established. Yet the state that Babur founded differed vastly from the one Akbar left behind. Having captured Ibrahim Lodi’s capital and treasury, Babur did little more than replace the defeated Afghans with his own people, without substantially altering the Lodis’ governing structure. After Babur’s brief reign, his son Humayun was driven from India before he could consolidate his rule. Ironically, it was another Indo-Afghan, the capable Sher Shah Sur (r. 1540–45), who established many of the administrative traditions that Humayun and his son Akbar would then inherit and elaborate. In his long, nearly half-century reign, Akbar put in place the empire’s most enduring ruling institutions, while the dynasty’s character completed its transition from a mobile ruling group steeped in semi-pastoral Central Asian traditions to a sedentary empire based on the economic, political and cultural traditions of agrarian India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
