<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beef taboo</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/beef-taboo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/beef-taboo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1782707743272394914.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;until early 20th cent Chinese had a strong taboo against beef (including male buffaloes), especially in southern China. To quote Mao on this &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is because oxen helped the Chinese peasant plough &amp;amp; came to be seen as family. The 2 groups most strongly associated with beef in 19th cent Qing were Mohammedans &amp;amp; Westerners.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will still find remnants of this taboo in Taiwan, old Chinese songs against beef eating.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Late Joseon Korean intellectuals argued for a ban on beef in Korea citing Qing laws as a model on both ethical &amp;amp; agricultural grounds.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This comes from late Qing stelae of 1877 found in Yunnan:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demographics</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/chinese-demographics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/chinese-demographics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Rjrasva&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;rate&#34;&gt;Rate&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Calculating based on births reported by NBS gives a fertility rate of 1.15-1.16 for China in 2021. Going by the # given by Ministry of Public Security (likely to be more accurate) gives a fertility rate below 1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read better sources than outlandish CIA estimates &amp;amp; projections. Start with China&amp;rsquo;s own NBS, then move onto Fuxian Yi, Jianzhang Liang, Wenzheng Huang, Zhigang Guo, &amp;amp; Baochang Gu. Better because their projections match up better with latest #&amp;rsquo;s CCP released (still inflated though). You claim there r 1000 ppl in auditorium when there r only 950, most ppl won&amp;rsquo;t notice but what if its only 500, so better to slowly adjust #&amp;rsquo;s to reflect reality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>fertility-intentions 2023</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/fertility-intentions_2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/fertility-intentions_2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Only 38% of Chinese college students want to EVER have children. 34% among women. Guessing at true desires of &amp;ldquo;uncertain&amp;rdquo; respondents, average Chinese college women desires just 0.94 kids. College men 1.05.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&amp;ldquo;Fertility Intentions, Parenting Attitudes, and Fear of Childbirth among College&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chinese pronatalism will fail.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The only paths forward for China are either:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cope&amp;ndash; very very hard given China&amp;rsquo;s constellation of finance, local government, welfare, and migration policies&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coerce&amp;ndash; BIG YIKES, but they may try it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Convince&amp;ndash; they aren&amp;rsquo;t even trying this yet&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;ll be interesting to see if China attempts any big &amp;ldquo;cultural interventions&amp;rdquo; aimed at shifting desired family size and the social prestige attendant on parenthood and large families. So far they haven&amp;rsquo;t even gestured in that direction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>gao-assassination</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/gao-assassination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/gao-assassination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.rattibha.com/thread/1616685462436954117&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first Emperor of Han, Liu Bang or Emperor Gao, once narrowly avoided an assassination plot. But the real story came after the plot was foiled&amp;hellip;&#xA;After the collapse of Qin, the Chinese realm was divided up into many domains. In his subsequent war to dominate the whole realm, Liu Bang allied with one of these leaders: the King of Zhao, Zhang Er. At one point Zhang Er lost his domain, but thanks to Liu Bang he recovered it.&#xA;Soon after Liu Bang&amp;rsquo;s final victory and acclamation as Emperor, Zhang Er passed away. He was succeeded as King of Zhao by his son, Zhang Ao, who was also Emperor Gao&amp;rsquo;s son-in-law.&#xA;Following his conquest of the realm, Emperor Gao attempted to fight the Xiongnu to the north, but suffered a strategic defeat. He stayed in Zhao for a while on his way home, and although Zhang Ao showed him the utmost courtesy, Emperor Gao acted extremely rude and crude to him.&#xA;Offended both by Emperor Gao&amp;rsquo;s behavior and by Zhang Ao&amp;rsquo;s meek acceptance of his humiliation, several of Zhang Ao&amp;rsquo;s ministers, including Guan Gao, asked his permission to kill Emperor Gao. But Zhang Ao refused, saying that this would be the height of ingratitude.&#xA;Although their king&amp;rsquo;s virtue moved Guan Gao and the others, they resolved to instead carry out the plot on their own initiative without involving Zhang Ao at all, in order to cleanse the stain on their own honor as proud subjects of Zhao.&#xA;Later, when Emperor Gao was returning south from fighting a rebel in the north, he was passing by a certain county. Unbeknownst to him, Guan Gao and the others had predicted his movements and had arranged for an assassin to lie in wait inside the local lodge.&#xA;However, Emperor Gao had a sudden premonition, and upon being told the name of the county, he felt it was too similar to an ominous phrase (along the lines of having a &amp;ldquo;Gacha/Gotcha&amp;rdquo; county) and decided not to spend the night there instead.&#xA;The government was later tipped off about the plot leaders. Orders were sent out to arrest both them and Zhang Ao, as it was naturally assumed that he must have been the mastermind behind the whole conspiracy.&#xA;When the other plot leaders realized they were about to be arrested (likely resulting in torture and execution), they were all about to kill themselves instead. But Guan Gao scolded them, arguing that they had to live to prove Zhang Ao&amp;rsquo;s innocence, so they submitted.&#xA;Zhang Ao and the plot leaders were then sent to the capital; Zhang Ao remained under house arrest until his involvement could be ascertained, while the rest were harshly interrogated in prison.&#xA;Yet despite being so tortured and beaten that &amp;ldquo;no spot on his entire body remained unwounded&amp;rdquo;, Guan Gao remained adamant that Zhang Ao was innocent. Since pain wasn&amp;rsquo;t working, Emperor Gao tried a different approach.&#xA;He found an old neighbor of Guan Gao&amp;rsquo;s and sent him to bring him some creature comforts while tending to his injuries. Then the neighbor took the chance to ask, &amp;ldquo;But Zhang Ao isn&amp;rsquo;t really innocent, is he?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Guan Gao responded, &amp;ldquo;Who in this world does not love their wife and children? Yet because of my testimony, my own are facing the threat of associated execution. Would I really go so far as that to cover up for my king, if it were just a lie? I swear, he had no hand in it.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Finally convinced, Emperor Gao decided to pardon Zhang Ao and send him back to his fief; however, just to be sure, he still had Zhang Ao demoted in rank from king to marquis. He was even so impressed by Guan Gao&amp;rsquo;s resolve that he decided to pardon him as well.&#xA;Yet when his neighbor informed him of these developments, Guan Gao replied,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goujian repopulation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/goujian_repopulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/goujian_repopulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[King Goujian] ordered young men not to marry old women, and he commanded old men not to marry young women. If a girl reached the age of seventeen without being wed then her parents were committing a crime; if a man reached the age of twenty without taking a wife then his parents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Virtually every text that mentions King Goujian refers to the way in which he transformed his kingdom. To a certain extent the facts speak for themselves: twenty years after his crushing defeat at Kuaiji, King Goujian invaded Wu and conquered it. According to the Zuozhuan, Wu Zixu realised that this was all part of King Goujian’s grand plan:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>keju-elite-persistence</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/keju-elite-persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/keju-elite-persistence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Elite Persistence Improves Society&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zichao Zhang/Hanfu attire&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executing-cheats&#34;&gt;Executing cheats&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1781, the Qing Emperor executed 56 officials in the Gansu province for selling fake exam certificates. Their crime was not only one of corruption. In imperial China, the bureaucracy was seen as a fair one that promoted its members based on achievement. And for fifteen centuries, the foundation of that system had been the imperial exams. The Gansu officials had threatened the legitimacy of the imperial state itself—only the most severe of penalties would do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mencius deforestation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/mencius_deforestation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/mencius_deforestation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ctext.org/mengzi/gaozi-i#n1762&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mencius said,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;The trees of the Niu mountain were once beautiful.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Being situated, however, in the borders of a large State,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;they were hewn down with axes and bills -&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and could they retain their beauty?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Still through the activity of the vegetative life day and night,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and the nourishing influence of the rain and dew,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;they were not without buds and sprouts springing forth,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;but then came the cattle and goats and browsed upon them.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To these things is owing the bare and stripped appearance of the mountain,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and when people now see it,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;they think it was never finely wooded.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;But is this the nature of the mountain?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PLA flop 2015</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/pla_peacekeeper-flop_2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/pla_peacekeeper-flop_2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://cestmoizblog.com/2017/08/12/peoples-liberation-army-calling-the-bluff/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People’s Liberation Army – Calling the Bluff&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3611&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/oct/06/un-peacekeepers-refused-to-help-south-sudan-rebels-raped-aid-workers-report&#34;&gt;THIS&lt;/a&gt; 2015 news report, some days ago. A piece that I found V.E.R.Y interesting. The headline is catchy enough – ‘UN peacekeepers refused to help as aid workers were raped in South Sudan’. But it is the second part of the headline that caught my eye – Chinese troops abandoned their posts rather than engage in fighting and protect civilians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qing vs japan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/qing_vs_japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/qing_vs_japan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Japan-Qing war, history is rewritten as decaying Qing inevitably destined to be beaten by Japan by monday morning quarterbacks. In reality, before war, many westerners &amp;amp; Qing thought they would win, the Beiyang fleet was seen as more than a match for J navy. China, it was widely and confidently asserted, could absorb Japanese armies as she would a duststorm. They must simply melt away, leaving their island homes. In Europe, numbers were still believed to be decisive: China was big, therefore it would win. The Chinese navy possessed twice as many warships, the best two of which were superior in armaments and armor to anything possessed by Japan, and its naval bases were nearer the war theater.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tang minister vs buddhism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/tang_minister_vs_buddhism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/tang_minister_vs_buddhism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Chinese Minister Han Yu protests against the imperial concessions offered to Buddhism by the Tang Emperor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your servant has now heard that instructions have been issued to the priestly community to proceed to Feng-hsiang and receive a bone of Buddha, and that from a high tower your Majesty will view its introduction into the Imperial Palace; also that orders have been sent to the various temples, commanding that the relic be received with the proper ceremonies. Now, foolish though your servant may be, he is well aware that your Majesty does not do this in the vain hope of deriving advantages therefrom; but that in the fulness of our present plenty, and in the joy which reigns in the heart of all, there is a desire to fall in with the wishes of the people in the celebration at the capital of this delusive mummery.+++(4)+++&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
