<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Muslim attack: punjab on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Muslim attack: punjab on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 INTRODUCTION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/01_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/01_intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The volume in hand is a reprint of an old book compiled in 1947 by&#xA;Sardar Gurbachan Singh Talib, Principal of the Lyallpur Khalsa College,&#xA;Jullundur, and published in 1950 by the Shiromani Gurdwara Parbandhak&#xA;Committee (SGPC).  It records the story of 7-million Hindus and Sikhs&#xA;who were uprooted from their homes in the West Punjab, the North-Western&#xA;Frontier, Sind and parts of Kashmir.  It tells the story of political&#xA;parleys that preceded this event, their inevitable failure, and the&#xA;barbarity that immediately followed - barbarity that had elements of&#xA;pre-planning.  The book records the atrocities of this period - the&#xA;carnage, killings, abductions and forced conversions that took place&#xA;particularly in 194 6-47, forcing Hindus and Sikhs to leave their&#xA;hearths and homes and start on the “biggest mass migration of humanity,”&#xA;as the author describes it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 PREFACE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/02_pre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/02_pre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PREFACE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is intended to reveal the grim and tragic story of the&#xA;uprooting of more than seven million Hindus and Sikhs from their homes&#xA;in West Punjab, in the North-Western Frontier Province, in Sind and in&#xA;raider-occupied Kashmir.  The outlines of this story are well-known all&#xA;over the world, and have formed the subject of debate before the&#xA;representatives of the major portion of mankind, assembled in the United&#xA;Nations.  This biggest mass migration of humanity in history under&#xA;extreme duress has received the attention and active sympathy due to it&#xA;from the rest of India, and the world is keenly aware of the existence&#xA;of this large portion of uprooted humanity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 PAKISTAN-BIRTH AND OBJECTIVES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/03_ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/03_ch1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAKISTAN-BIRTH AND OBJECTIVES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pakistan grew out of the two-nation theory of the Muslim League, which&#xA;for the last twenty years or more has been synonymous with its permanent&#xA;president, the late Mohamed Ali Jinnah, called by the Muslims&#xA;Qaid-i-Azam or the Supreme Leader.  The career of Qaid-i-Azam Jinnah&#xA;indicates a curious and. ironic development from being ‘the apostle of&#xA;Hindu-Muslim Unity, as he was called by admiring Congressmen, to being&#xA;the chief exponent, advocate and creator of Pakistan-a state based upon&#xA;the thesis that the Muslims of India are a separate nation, and a,, such&#xA;need a homeland and state for themselves, separate from Hindu-land.&#xA;Pakistan is now a predominantly Muslim state, so predominantly Muslim in&#xA;its population that its western and more important portion has in the&#xA;course of a few months of its establishment, been almost completely rid&#xA;of its Hindu, Sikh and to a great extent of its Christian and&#xA;untouchable populations.  By what processes this development has been&#xA;brought about is what this booklet is designed to relate.  The present&#xA;overlords of Pakistan have declared times out of number that Pakistan is&#xA;&lt;em&gt;in character&lt;/em&gt; a Muslim State-the largest Muslim State in the world.&#xA;This description of its character, when placed side by side with the&#xA;declared character of India as a secular state, which she is also sought&#xA;to be made in effect, has unnerved the Hindu population of faraway East&#xA;Bengal, where alone now in Pakistan Hindus in any appreciable numbers&#xA;are found.  Since October last a deliberate policy on the part of the&#xA;Muslim majority in East Bengal, with the connivance of the East Bengal&#xA;Muslim League Government, forced the Hindus out of that Province.  This&#xA;exodus of Hindus became such a vast movement of emigration, that in&#xA;October, 1948 official estimates put the number of Hindu immigrants from&#xA;Eastern Pakistan into India at fifteen lakhs.  More and more were&#xA;following over the border into Assam and West Bengal everyday, and the&#xA;refugee problem for the Indian Government already preoccupied with the&#xA;rehabilitation of about a crore of people from Western Pakistan and&#xA;Kashmir, began to assume a desperate look.  That is what made Sardar&#xA;Patel to declare that if the Pakistan Government did not take effective&#xA;steps to stop the exodus of Hindus from East Bengal the India Government&#xA;would claim proportionate territory from East Bengal for the&#xA;resettlement of the Hindus immigrants.  This exodus is only an&#xA;illustration of the fact that the driving out of minorities and&#xA;non-Muslim populations is something inherent in the very nature,&#xA;conception and scope of the kind of state which the Muslims have&#xA;achieved through the good offices of the British in the shape of&#xA;Pakistan.  No amount of reasonableness and accommodation, no attempts at&#xA;friendship and understanding on the part of India could avert what&#xA;occurred in West Punjab, in the North-Western Frontier Province, in&#xA;Sind, in Bahawalpur, in raider-occupied Kashmir and is at present&#xA;occurring in East Bengal.  The thing is inevitable and inherent in the&#xA;nature of the State of Pakistan and the entire attitude and mentality of&#xA;which this State is the result.  It is a significant fact that while in&#xA;India, the Government discourages &lt;em&gt;communal&lt;/em&gt; groups and parties, in&#xA;Pakistan no group or parties other than communal are encouraged.  A&#xA;Pakistan Peoples’ Congress is inconceivable.  When the Hindu leaders of&#xA;Sind planned the establishment of a political party which might draw its&#xA;membership from people belonging to various religions, the reply of the&#xA;Pakistan Government was characteristic.  The Hindus of Sind, (such of&#xA;them as are still there) might have a Hindu Party, but not one which&#xA;Muslims also might join.  In the &lt;em&gt;Muslim State&lt;/em&gt; of Pakistan, no Muslim&#xA;may join any organization other than a purely Muslim one.  It is such an&#xA;attitude which bred the riots of 1946 and 1947-Calcutta, Noakhali, N.-W.&#xA;F. P., the Punjab, Sind and Bahawalpur.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 THE CABINET MISSION AND THE MUSLIM LEAGUE DIRECT ACTION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/04_ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/04_ch2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE CABINET MISSION AND THE MUSLIM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;LEAGUE DIRECT ACTION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the later months of the year 1945 and early 1946 the temper of&#xA;the Muslim masses was kept up by the propaganda of hate emanating from&#xA;the official pronouncements of the Muslim League, the speeches of its&#xA;leaders and the unrestrained articles of the pro-League press.  Muslims&#xA;had everywhere in the Punjab and Bengal begin to look upon the&#xA;minorities as their subjects in prospect.  Provocative acts against&#xA;non-Muslims by the Muslims were beginning to be frequent.  By this time&#xA;the police and the officials were so thoroughly saturated with the&#xA;poisonous propaganda of the Muslim League against the Hindus and Sikhs,&#xA;that it was not easy for a Hindu or Sikh to find a Muslim policeman or&#xA;civilian impartial in his attitude where the conflict lay between a&#xA;Muslim and a non-Muslim.  This attitude on the part of the police was a&#xA;great hardship, especially as more than 70% of the police force in the&#xA;Punjab, for example, was made up of Muslims.  In the people’s daily&#xA;lives the police could do much to make them happy or miserable.  That&#xA;the police and the officialdom had gone thoroughly Muslim League was&#xA;demonstrated by three successive events: The Provincial Assembly&#xA;elections in the Punjab early in 1946; the Muslim League agitation&#xA;against the Khizar Ministry in January-February, 1947 and the Punjab&#xA;Riots which began early in March, 1947 and continued in Pakistan as late&#xA;as January of 1948, till which month incidents of glaring brutality on a&#xA;colossal magnitude against the Hindu and Sikh remnants of the population&#xA;continued to be reported.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 PRELUDE TO GENOCIDE OF HINDUS AND SIKHS N.-W. FRONTIER PROVINCE MASSACRIES AND THE PUNJAB MUSLIM LEAGUE AGITATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/05_ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/05_ch3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRELUDE TO GENOCIDE OF HINDUS AND SIKHS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;N.-W. FRONTIER PROVINCE MASSACRIES AND THE&lt;br&gt;&#xA;PUNJAB MUSLIM LEAGUE AGITATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the North-Western Frontier Province a Congress Ministry came into&#xA;power after defeating a Muslim League Ministry on the floor of the&#xA;Provincial Legislature.  The Muslim League regarded this Province as one&#xA;of its especial preserves, for the population was overwhelmingly&#xA;Muslim.  But the freedom-loving Pathan character under the guidance of&#xA;Khan Abdul Ghaffar Khan and his brother, Dr. Khan Sahib, had preferred&#xA;the Congress way over the League way, which was known to be working in&#xA;collusion with the British bureaucracy, and which moreover, was&#xA;dominated by reactionary feudal elements-the nawabs and title-holders&#xA;and the fanatical mullahs.  When the Muslim League Direct Action&#xA;campaign was started, the League leaders naturally thought of stirring&#xA;up trouble in the North-Western Frontier Province, and thus turning the&#xA;tide against the Congress ministry, which would naturally pursue a&#xA;policy of cementing the good relations between Muslims and non-Muslims.&#xA;As early as July 28, 1946 as narrated earlier, trouble of quite serious&#xA;nature had occurred in Hazara district-an area which was particularly&#xA;susceptible to Muslim League propaganda.  Hazara is not properly&#xA;speaking a Pathan area; it is Punjabi-speaking, and not Pushtu, and in&#xA;its political character takes more after the Punjab, to which it is&#xA;cognate, than to the rest of the Frontier Province, which is trans-Indus&#xA;in respect of geography.  Local Muslims, along with fanatical marauders&#xA;from the tribal areas, whom loot and the desire for attacking&#xA;‘infidels’-be they Hindu, Sikh, Christian or any other-would always&#xA;bring hurtling down the valleys, looted and burnt Hindu and Sikh shops&#xA;and terrorized the Hindu and Sikh population of the Hazara district.&#xA;Gurdwaras were attacked, their inmates killed and the holy. places&#xA;themselves desecrated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 MARCH, 1947. BLITZ ON THE HINDU AND SIKH MINORITIES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/06_ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/06_ch4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MARCH, 1947.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BLITZ ON THE HINDU AND SIKH MINORITIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As has been told above, there was a complete concert between the Muslim&#xA;League and the Muslim masses which followed its programme and policy on&#xA;the one hand, and Muslim officials and police on the other.  The British&#xA;bureaucracy which still held supreme power, was perhaps inclined to&#xA;favour the Muslim League-not as such, but as the one force in the&#xA;country which could be relied upon to pursue a policy of dissension and&#xA;strife, and thus create in the country such a mood as would make a&#xA;politically united India, at least a politically united Punjab,&#xA;impossible So in this background came the fruition and consummation of&#xA;the Muslim League plan to dominate the Punjab, to form in this Province&#xA;its ministry, which with the consent of Hindus and Sikhs could not be&#xA;done, but which might be established after beating them down.  Only this&#xA;beating had to be swift, continual and thorough.  Without a ministry of&#xA;its own in the Punjab, the Muslim League would not be able to receive&#xA;power from the British Government in June, 1948, the target date by&#xA;which according to the February, 20 statement of H. M. G. power must be&#xA;transferred to Indian hands.  Without a Muslim League Government in the&#xA;Punjab, Pakistan would remain not only lopsided, but might even topple&#xA;altogether as a practical scheme.  This was the situation in which the&#xA;Muslim League attack on the Punjab minorities was inevitably launched.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 NOTE ON ATTACK ON GURDWARA DEHRA SAHIB</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/07_ch5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/07_ch5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE ON ATTACK ON GURDWARA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;DEHRA SAHIB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Firing continued to be directed against the famous Dehra Sahib Gurdwara&#xA;of Lahore, site of the martyrdom of Sri Guru Arjan Dev, fifth Guru of&#xA;the Sikhs.  This, in spite of the fact that this place is situated at a&#xA;distance of hardly five yards from the Lahore Fort, Headquarters of the&#xA;Additional Police and military pickets for the city.  Water-taps&#xA;supplying water to the Gurdwara estate were cut off, so that the inmates&#xA;about 150 in number, should be left to die through sheer thirst.  After&#xA;firing for some time, the Muslim National Guards advanced towards the&#xA;Gurdwara, and set fire to the building adjoining the Gurdwara.  The&#xA;whole area was ablaze in a few minutes’ time.  Some Sikhs had taken&#xA;shelter in the Samadh (Mausoleum) of Maharaja Ranjit Singh, which is&#xA;separated from the Gurdwara by a distance of about 30 yards.  Here the&#xA;Muslim crowd, amid cries of “Pakistan zindabad” etc. and filthy abuse&#xA;directed against the Sikhs battered at the Gates of the Samadh.  Several&#xA;Sikhs were shot dead.  The gates of the Gurdwara and Samadh were&#xA;perforated with bullets.  These happenings occurred on the 13th August.&#xA;On the 14th the Gurdwara was put under the guard of the Boundary Force&#xA;of General Rees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 THE GANDHI - JINNAH APPEAL FOR PEACE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/08_ch6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/08_ch6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE GANDHI - JINNAH APPEAL FOR PEACE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The new Viceroy, Lord Mountbatten, who took over from Lord Wavell in&#xA;March, 1947 arrived upon a terrible scene of carnage and destruction in&#xA;the Punjab, the effects of which were soon to envelop the Frontier&#xA;Province in a carnage and destruction equally severe and were to spread&#xA;out into most parts of Northern, Eastern and Central India in the form&#xA;of serious communal rioting.  The Viceroy sincerely wanted this&#xA;bloodshed to end and an atmosphere of calm negotiation and preparation&#xA;for the transfer of power to be created.  So, in the midst of the&#xA;recrudesence of communal attacks in Amritsar, following upon the&#xA;uprooting of a large part of the Hindu and Sikh population of the&#xA;Rawalpindi division and Multan, he initiated a peace appeal to be&#xA;addressed by Mahatma Gandhi and Mr. Jinnah to the country.  This appeal,&#xA;the text of which was publicized all over the country in dozens of ways&#xA;known to the modern technique of publicity, was carried to the farthest&#xA;corners of the country.  Especially in the Punjab the publicity given to&#xA;it was tremendous indeed.  The &lt;em&gt;communique&lt;/em&gt; announcing the appeal,&#xA;bearing the signatures of the two leaders, ran as follows&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 FRONTIER PROVINCE AND D. I. KHAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/09_ch7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/09_ch7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRONTIER PROVINCE AND D. I. KHAN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The wave of attacks on Hindus and Sikhs, travelling from the Rawalpindi&#xA;and Multan Divisions, spread in a wild and virulent form to the N.-W.&#xA;Frontier Province and especially to the Trans-Indus Frontier District of&#xA;Dera Ismail Khan, in which as all over this area, Hindus and Sikhs were&#xA;in microscopic minority.  The Frontier adherents of the Muslim League&#xA;fell upon the handful of Hindus and Sikhs with the primitive fanaticism&#xA;characteristic of the Muslims of this area.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 ROUND ABOUT AUGUST 15, 1947</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/10_ch8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/10_ch8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROUND ABOUT AUGUST 15, 1947&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The big attacks on the Hindus and Sikhs of Lahore began to be delivered&#xA;from third June.  The destruction wrought in the city was so horrible&#xA;and appalling that in a desperate effort to save the city from complete&#xA;devastation a meeting of the three communities was called in the Town&#xA;Hall on the 27th June.  At this meeting, the leaders of the Hindus and&#xA;Sikhs gave assurances of keeping the peace.  So did the leaders of the&#xA;Muslims.  These latter spoke very emphatic and reassuring words, which&#xA;however, were belied by their followers as soon as they were uttered.&#xA;Lahore continued to bum in spite of what the Muslim League leaders&#xA;said.  Khan Iftikhar Husain Khan of Momdot, then President of the Punjab&#xA;Muslim League, pledged his community to peace in these words:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 AMRITSAR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/11_ch9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/11_ch9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMRITSAR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the history of the Muslim League War on the Hindus and Sikhs of the&#xA;Punjab in 1947, Amritsar occupies an outstanding position.  It was in&#xA;this city, along with Lahore, though with an intensity even greater than&#xA;in the latter town, that the most sustained war, lasting for over five&#xA;months was waged on the Hindus and Sikhs, especially the latter, by the&#xA;Amritsar Muslims.  In the scheme of the Muslim League, Amritsar appears&#xA;to have been Theatre of War No. 1. On the degree of success achieved in&#xA;Amritsar would depend the League measure of success in cowing down the&#xA;minorities in the Punjab and the prospect of the establishment of&#xA;Pakistan.  While in Lahore the Muslim population was quite a large&#xA;majority, in Amritsar it was almost balanced by the Hindus and Sikhs&#xA;combined.  Amritsar was the spiritual capital of the Sikhs, and Sikh&#xA;history is full of wars waged by Sikhs in the pre-Ranjit Singh Era for&#xA;the recovery of Amritsar from the hands of Muslims who desecrated the&#xA;holy Hari Mandir (the Golden Temple of, later days) and filled the&#xA;sacred Tank with sand.  The Muslim League knew that Sikhs might be&#xA;uprooted and even exterminated in Rawalpindi and the West, they might be&#xA;driven out of Lahore, but they would make a determined, last-ditch stand&#xA;in Amritsar.  To surrender Amritsar to the Muslims would mean&#xA;practically the writing off of Sikh history and admitting a status&#xA;inferior to that of the Muslims in the Punjab-a status, in view of the&#xA;past record and declared ambitions and methods of the Muslim League, of&#xA;serfdom.  To break the Sikh resistance and morale in Amritsar was,&#xA;therefore, of the first importance.  And it was in Amritsar that the&#xA;League poured all its strength and resources.  It, was in Amritsar again&#xA;that the Sikhs staked their lives during the long months of agony and&#xA;unequal fighting from March to August, 1947.  Amritsar, to use a not&#xA;inappropriate parallel, became a kind of Stalingrad of this Muslim&#xA;League-Sikh War.  The Sikhs did live it through.  They ‘took it’ as&#xA;London did in 1940 and 1941, or as Stalingrad did till 1944.  And then&#xA;the tide turned.  The Sikhs successfully stood the Muslim onslaught for&#xA;four months or more.  And with the approach of August 15, the Muslims&#xA;fearing the inevitable counter-attack on the part of the Hindus and&#xA;Sikhs, rendered inevitable in this case by the accumulated sufferings&#xA;and helplessness, hate and anger of months of destruction in Amritsar,&#xA;Lahore, Multan, Rawalpindi, the Frontier Province and other places, lied&#xA;Amritsar in panic.  It was a wonderful sight to see how within the space&#xA;of a day and a night, almost no Muslim was to be seen in Amritsar when&#xA;freedom dawned on August 15, expecting those who had entrenched&#xA;themselves in the notorious area of Sharifpura, expecting what they knew&#xA;to be well-deserved punishment for brutal and inhuman crimes against&#xA;their fellow-men.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 WEST PUNJAB ABLAZE SHEIKHUPURA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/12_ch10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/12_ch10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WEST PUNJAB ABLAZE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SHEIKHUPURA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sheikhupura is the district next to Lahore on the Western side. Just&#xA;three miles out of Lahore, after crossing the River Ravi, one enters the&#xA;boundary of this district.  This district contains Nankana Sahib, the&#xA;birthplace of Sri Guru Nanak Dev, and the huge estate attached to this&#xA;Gurdwara which before partition yielded a revenue of about twenty lakh&#xA;rupees annually to the Sikh people.  Most of the proprietors of land in&#xA;this district were Sikhs who had fine lands and had made them rich and&#xA;productive by lavishing on this land such hard labour as only the Sikh&#xA;agriculturist appears to be capable of.  Besides, the urban Hindu and&#xA;Sikh population of this district had industrial enterprise and had set&#xA;up business houses, factories and works.  Sikhs and Hindus were,&#xA;however, in a minority in this district, the population proportions&#xA;being:-&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 SIND</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/13_ch11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/13_ch11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIND&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Sind the Sikh population was not large, though the Hindus formed&#xA;about 30% of-the population of the province.  Out of the total&#xA;non-Muslim population of 14 Lakhs, now^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) only about 2 lakhs are&#xA;left in Sind, the rest having come to India as refugees.  The turning&#xA;out of non-Muslims from Sind is very amply illustrative of the naked&#xA;policy of turning out of Hindus and Sikhs from Pakistan, for no other&#xA;reason whatever except that they were not Muslims.  There was a policy&#xA;of systematic terrorization of Hindus.  Their business premises were&#xA;looted, their womenfolk molested, and the avenues of normal respectable&#xA;life entirely closed to them.  Thus, through terror and intimidation,&#xA;within the period of less than a year twelve lakhs out of the fourteen&#xA;lakhs of Hindus in Sind have been forced to migrate to India.  This has&#xA;happened in spite of the fact that in the words of Shri Mansukhani,&#xA;Secretary, Sind Congress Refugee Relief Committee, New Delhi, “not one&#xA;single Muslim lost his life at the hands of Hindus in any act of&#xA;retaliation or self-defence, not to talk of any act of aggression; but&#xA;where from the first day of the birth of Pakistan, Hindus have been&#xA;systematically done to death, by the knife, by the bullet. by the&#xA;throwing out of the windows and doors of running trains.  The object has&#xA;been one and the goal clear.  Pakistan has desired that it should be a&#xA;theocratic state in the sense that all its citizens should be Muslims.&#xA;This battle has been remorselessly waged on one long front of Western&#xA;Pakistan.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 DID SIKHS (AND HINDUS) VOLUNTARILY LEAVE PAKISTAN? I</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/14_ch12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/14_ch12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DID SIKHS (AND HINDUS) VOLUNTARILY LEAVE PAKISTAN?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pakistan propagandists, in order to hide the shameful crimes of the&#xA;Muslim League leaders, a part of whose programme it was to carve out a&#xA;purely Muslim State and to eliminate religious minorities from it, have&#xA;put forth a mischievous piece of propaganda that Sikhs (and by&#xA;implication Hindus as well) left Pakistan by a design.  Mat this&#xA;‘Design’ could have been passes ordinary human comprehension.  The&#xA;official Pakistan propaganda pamphlet contains this fantastic view:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 DID THE SIKHS HAVE A ‘PLAN’? “AN OVER-BLAMED PEOPLE” - I.xa0 STEPHENS I</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/15_ch13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/15_ch13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DID THE SIKHS HAVE A ‘PLAN’?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“AN OVER-BLAMED PEOPLE” - I.  STEPHENS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pakistan propaganda has sought to make the world believe that the&#xA;happenings of 1947 in the Punjab were the result of what it calls ‘Some&#xA;specific Plan’ on the part of Sikhs. -What this ‘Plan’ exactly was, what&#xA;were the specific objectives which it set out to achieve is not made&#xA;exactly clear, but nevertheless it is asserted that a Sikh ‘Plan’&#xA;existed to destroy Muslim life.  Barefaced lying has been known to go&#xA;quite far in the affairs of the world but such a high degree of it as&#xA;has manifested itself in Pakistan propaganda against Sikhs in particular&#xA;and against India in general, is a rare treat and is hard to beat.  It&#xA;must be a very stupid world which Pakistan expected would swallow the&#xA;stuff put forth by its propagandists.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 THE KAMOKE MASSACRE I</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/16_ap1-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/16_ap1-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE KAMOKE MASSACRE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Statement of Shrimati Laj Wanti, widow of Shri Manak Chand Age 23&#xA;years, caste Khatri, resident of Nurpur Sethi, District Jhelum, to the&#xA;Chief Liaison Officer, Lahore.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My husband Shri Manak Chand was employed in the Workshop of Alkali&#xA;Chemical Corporation of India, Limited at, Khewra.  We were living in&#xA;the quarters attached to the Company.  Towards the end of Bhadon (August&#xA;1947) a Muslim mob attacked Khewra and a large number of houses were&#xA;burnt.  The Manager of the Alkali Chemical Corporation of India, Limited&#xA;being a European, the premises of the Company were not attacked and&#xA;employees and quarters in which they were living were saved.  The&#xA;Manager, however, asked all Hindu employees to get ready for evacuation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 XI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/18_ap11-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/18_ap11-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Statement made by Lt. B. W. O’Connor of 2 Marhattas.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recovered two married ladies from a Muslim house in Chak No. 32,&#xA;District Sargodha.  Actually they had been taken away from the Lalian&#xA;Camp by the police guard of the camp at 2 p.m. on the 31st October,&#xA;1947.  On my arrival, I received reports about this abduction from their&#xA;husbands and went in search of them. I searched the above chak and&#xA;recovered them at about 10-30 a.m. on the 1st November, 1947.  I have&#xA;now brought them to the D. A.-V. College Camp.  Their statements should&#xA;also be taken separately if it is so desired.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 XXI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/20_ap21-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/20_ap21-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XXI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tales of Abductions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Statement of Shrimati Viranwati, Daughter of Shri Sewa Singh aged 16/17&#xA;years, village Ilbhagwan, Tehsil Mirpur, to the Chief Liaison Officer,&#xA;Lahore.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;About 2½ months ago a Muslim mob attacked my village.  My father and&#xA;mother were killed in this attack.  Nawab Pathan one of the raiders&#xA;abducted me and took me to Hoti Mardan.  My younger sister Gian Kaur,&#xA;aged about 6 years also accompanied me.  The attack took place on the&#xA;refugee camp at Mirpur where lots of people from the neighbouring&#xA;villages were gathered.  The raiders took away 4500 girls with them.&#xA;From Hoti Mardan he took me to Maj Garhi.  I remained with him for over&#xA;a month.  I was married to him at Maj Garhi.  He was hiding me from&#xA;place to place as the police was in search of me.  The police afterwards&#xA;caught hold of me and brought me to Rawalpindi and put me in the Camp.&#xA;Nawab asked me whether I wanted to go back to India but I under fear&#xA;told him that as my parents had been killed I would not go to India and&#xA;thus agreed to the &lt;em&gt;Nikah&lt;/em&gt; with him.  In the camp at Rawalpindi there&#xA;were 51 girls.  These girls are from the Poonch State and from Kahuta&#xA;Tehsil.  This Camp is guarded by the police.  This Camp is visited by&#xA;those Muslims who are married to the girls lodged in it, but the police&#xA;does not permit the girls to go with these Muslims.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 XXXI ATTACKS ON CONVOYS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/22_ap31-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/22_ap31-40/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XXXI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ATTACKS ON CONVOYS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the 28th January, 1948, four trucks were sent from Gujranwala to&#xA;Nowshera Vikram police station for local (Pocket) evacuation.  When one&#xA;truck had been loaded with the luggage of the evacuees, a mob of one&#xA;thousand local Muslims collected with axes, etc. and attacked the party&#xA;and looted the property.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XXXII&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Letter dated 5-9-47 from Sir Francis Mudie&lt;/em&gt;^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;em&gt;to the&#xA;Quid-i-Azam.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No. 2&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Government House, Lahore.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;5th September, 1947&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 XXXXI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/24_ap41-49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/24_ap41-49/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XXXXI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pt. Chuni Lal Jaitli, S. D. O. Canals living in Chichoki Malian Canal&#xA;Rest House, Distt.  Sheikhupura with members of his family was murdered&#xA;by Muslims.  On 27.8.47 they were attacked by Muslims and looted and&#xA;abducted as under:-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jiwan Devi (40) Shiv Devi (70) Rajeshwari (20) Nirmala Devi (18)&#xA;Kalawanti Devi (40) Harkishen Lal (14) Har Parkash (4) Darshan Kumar&#xA;(12) Inder Mohan (6) Manmohan (2½).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pt. Nand Lal, brother of Pt.  Chuni Lal who went to complain to Police&#xA;was thrown into the Upper Chenab canal by police and drowned.  Pt.&#xA;Chuni Lal was shot dead later by Ali Mohd., Lambardar, of Nokrian&#xA;village with the help of police.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 XXXXI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/25_ap41-49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/25_ap41-49/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XXXXI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pt. Chuni Lal Jaitli, S. D. O. Canals living in Chichoki Malian Canal&#xA;Rest House, Distt.  Sheikhupura with members of his family was murdered&#xA;by Muslims.  On 27.8.47 they were attacked by Muslims and looted and&#xA;abducted as under:-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jiwan Devi (40) Shiv Devi (70) Rajeshwari (20) Nirmala Devi (18)&#xA;Kalawanti Devi (40) Harkishen Lal (14) Har Parkash (4) Darshan Kumar&#xA;(12) Inder Mohan (6) Manmohan (2½).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pt. Nand Lal, brother of Pt.  Chuni Lal who went to complain to Police&#xA;was thrown into the Upper Chenab canal by police and drowned.  Pt.&#xA;Chuni Lal was shot dead later by Ali Mohd., Lambardar, of Nokrian&#xA;village with the help of police.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 XXXXI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/26_ap41-49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/26_ap41-49/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XXXXI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pt. Chuni Lal Jaitli, S. D. O. Canals living in Chichoki Malian Canal&#xA;Rest House, Distt.  Sheikhupura with members of his family was murdered&#xA;by Muslims.  On 27.8.47 they were attacked by Muslims and looted and&#xA;abducted as under:-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jiwan Devi (40) Shiv Devi (70) Rajeshwari (20) Nirmala Devi (18)&#xA;Kalawanti Devi (40) Harkishen Lal (14) Har Parkash (4) Darshan Kumar&#xA;(12) Inder Mohan (6) Manmohan (2½).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pt. Nand Lal, brother of Pt.  Chuni Lal who went to complain to Police&#xA;was thrown into the Upper Chenab canal by police and drowned.  Pt.&#xA;Chuni Lal was shot dead later by Ali Mohd., Lambardar, of Nokrian&#xA;village with the help of police.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Serial</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/27_atro1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/27_atro1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[TABLE]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 XXXXI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/28_ap41-49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/28_ap41-49/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XXXXI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pt. Chuni Lal Jaitli, S. D. O. Canals living in Chichoki Malian Canal&#xA;Rest House, Distt.  Sheikhupura with members of his family was murdered&#xA;by Muslims.  On 27.8.47 they were attacked by Muslims and looted and&#xA;abducted as under:-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jiwan Devi (40) Shiv Devi (70) Rajeshwari (20) Nirmala Devi (18)&#xA;Kalawanti Devi (40) Harkishen Lal (14) Har Parkash (4) Darshan Kumar&#xA;(12) Inder Mohan (6) Manmohan (2½).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pt. Nand Lal, brother of Pt.  Chuni Lal who went to complain to Police&#xA;was thrown into the Upper Chenab canal by police and drowned.  Pt.&#xA;Chuni Lal was shot dead later by Ali Mohd., Lambardar, of Nokrian&#xA;village with the help of police.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Serial</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/29_atro2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/29_atro2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[TABLE]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 XXXXI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/30_ap41-49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/30_ap41-49/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XXXXI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pt. Chuni Lal Jaitli, S. D. O. Canals living in Chichoki Malian Canal&#xA;Rest House, Distt.  Sheikhupura with members of his family was murdered&#xA;by Muslims.  On 27.8.47 they were attacked by Muslims and looted and&#xA;abducted as under:-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jiwan Devi (40) Shiv Devi (70) Rajeshwari (20) Nirmala Devi (18)&#xA;Kalawanti Devi (40) Harkishen Lal (14) Har Parkash (4) Darshan Kumar&#xA;(12) Inder Mohan (6) Manmohan (2½).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pt. Nand Lal, brother of Pt.  Chuni Lal who went to complain to Police&#xA;was thrown into the Upper Chenab canal by police and drowned.  Pt.&#xA;Chuni Lal was shot dead later by Ali Mohd., Lambardar, of Nokrian&#xA;village with the help of police.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 Serial</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/31_atro3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/muslim_attack_punjab/31_atro3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[TABLE]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
