<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Islamic army hierarchy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2005-11-02_islamic-army-hierarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2005-11-02_islamic-army-hierarchy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/11/02/islamic-army-hierarchy/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Khan-10 Maliqs&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Maliq-10 Amirs&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Amir-10 sipehsalars&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sipehsalara-10 Sarkhails&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sarkhail-10 Gudsavars&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sultani Khasa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2005-10-31_sultani-khasa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2005-10-31_sultani-khasa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/10/31/sultani-khasa/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Moslem tyrants of India ate as though there was no tommorow. Of the tyrants only Akbar was somewhat moderate due to his chronic bellyache. The special dinner of the Sultans of Delhi was the Khasa attended by about 20 guests. The participants were the chief clansmen of the Sultan, the chief Amirs and the Islamists, namely the Fuckih, Qazi, Khatib, Sharif and the Shaikh (usually a Sufi Jihadist).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The latest Jihad</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2005-10-31_the-latest-jihad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2005-10-31_the-latest-jihad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/10/31/the-latest-jihad/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We were having a chat with R and her aunt about the recent attacks on the Indian capital. Are the Hindus going react at least now asked her aunt. I opined it was unlikely. In the past the west used to ask the Hindus to show restraint when ever one of their Moslem stooges caused mayhem in India. When Mumbai was similarly bombed, the US actively obstructed justice by destroying the evidence collected by the Indian police. Then, when the Moslems hijacked a plane, attacked the Indian parliament, attacked a Gujarati temple and slew Hindus in each of these events, the Indian government hardly did anything and the west asked them again to show restraint. When the Hindus decided to put the Moslems in place after their heinous crime in the railway station, the West blamed the Hindus and turned the whole incident into an event of Hindus tormenting Moslems. After all Hindus were merely administering the Moslems a taste of their own pill, especially given that the elected government did hardly anything to protect Hindus from the Turushkas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Jihads of Shihabuddin, the Sultankalka of Ghur</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2005-07-19_the-jihads-of-shihabuddin-the-sultankalka-of-ghur/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2005-07-19_the-jihads-of-shihabuddin-the-sultankalka-of-ghur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/07/19/the-jihads-of-shihabuddin-the-sultankalka-of-ghur/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Around 1140, the Islamized Turko-Mongol chiefs of the Shansabanid tribe occupied Ghor in Afghanistan. Initially it was a vassal of the Ghaznavid Sultans, but around 1130 it came into conflict with them, after one of the leading Shansabanid nobles was murdered by the Ghaznavid Sultan, Bahram. A ferocious war ensued between the Sultans of Ghor and Ghazni, till Alla-ud-din Ghori invaded Ghazni with his entire cavalry and wrested it from Bahram. Alla-ud-din sacked the Indian spoils that Mahmud had placed there, massacred the city’s population in a 7-day killing spree and subsequently burnt it down. The next Ghaznavid Sultan, Khushro Maliq was driven out of Afghanistan by a coalition of Oghuz Turks and the Ghorids in 1157, and the Oghuz took Ghazni.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deeds of the Bahmanid Sultans-II</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2004-12-18_deeds-of-the-bahmanid-sultans-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2004-12-18_deeds-of-the-bahmanid-sultans-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/18/deeds-of-the-bahmanid-sultans-ii/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Continues from &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/13/some-deeds-of-bahmanid-sultans-i/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ahmad was a superstitious Moslem who supported all kinds of foreign Islamists and fraudulent Sufi preachers in his court. He invited the bigoted Islamist poet, Azari from Khorasan to his court and asked him to composed paens on the Bahmanid dynasty. For this he endowed the poet with a huge payment of gold. Ahmad had converted two of the young Brahmin boys from Northern Tamil Nad he had captured and named them Maliq Hasan and Fathullah Imad-al-Mulq.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some deeds of Bahmanid Sultans-I</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2004-12-13_some-deeds-of-bahmanid-sultans-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2004-12-13_some-deeds-of-bahmanid-sultans-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/13/some-deeds-of-bahmanid-sultans-i/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Bahmanid sultans were amongst the most monstrous Islamic rulers in world history. While people tend to talk of the massacres of Timur-i-lang in Inner Asia, the violence of the Bahamanids is hardly touched upon. We shall briefly outline some of the acts of these Sultans, which represent one of the most blood stained phases on Indian history. It is hardly surprising given the current political proclivities in India that this period of history is not properly described. We shall confine ourselves here to the core Bahmanid dynasty and not the 5 successor Sultanates of the later period. As KAN Shastri mentions, there were few among the line of 18 Sultans, who were not drunkards or debauches and their courts were teeming with Islamic adventurers from all over the Moslem world (compare with modern terrorist havens in Pakistan and now Iraq) seeking fortune in Jihad and pleasures derived from the riches of India. The condition of Hindus in their reign was very pitiable as explicitly mentioned by the Russian observer Athanasius Nikitin who visited during the late Sultanate period.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Islamic vandalism in Gujarat</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2004-07-11_islamic-vandalism-in-gujarat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2004-07-11_islamic-vandalism-in-gujarat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/07/11/islamic-vandalism-in-gujarat/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Rudramahalaya temple complex in Siddhapura in Gujarat was one of the greatest temples ever built in India north of Maharashtra. Its is supposed to have housed 11 separate temples of rudra and many more of other gods.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One of these housed a sixteen-armed, 5 headed image of shiva with his right foot upraised and placed on a lotus. A gaNa with a sword is shown below the lotus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Another is supposed to have contained a 4-armed naTarAja.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Another had a li~nga while and yet another had a umA-maheshvara on a bull.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The complex also contained shrines of:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;indranI with 4 arms in seated lalitAsana; gaNapati with 4 arms;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;kubera with his wife, holding a purse;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;8 armed chAmuNDA; 4 armed kumAra,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;temples of vAyu, varuNa and yama, each depicted with 4 arms;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;and one of viShNu near a river.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clearly this complex was one of the most magnificant pieces of chAlukya architecture and built by siddharAja jayasiMha and kumArapAla. It was considered one of the holiest shrines of Hindu pilgrimage and by all descriptions it appears to have been a marvel of Indian art. Importantly it shows that even in Northern India there were shrines with depicitions similar to the southern ones (eg. naTarAja, li~nga with nandi, kumAra and the like, were not exclusive to the south). Its glory is borne out in a testimony of a twelth century poem:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The early Post-Mahmud struggle</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2004-06-20_the-early-post-mahmud-struggle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2004-06-20_the-early-post-mahmud-struggle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/06/20/the-early-post-mahmud-struggle/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One area where most Indian historians and writers of history text books have remained woefully silent is the issue of what steps the Indians took, if any, in the post-Mahmud period to counter the challenge of the Islamic Jihad on Hind. Most accounts of history pass this period and go on straight to the disastrous clash between the chAhamAna and Shihabbudin Ghori. But understanding this period was most critical to decipher the real dynamics of the events that from which the Hindu civilization may never really recover.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Al Qaeda revival and India</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2004-05-26_al-qaeda-revival-and-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2004-05-26_al-qaeda-revival-and-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/05/26/al-qaeda-revival-and-india/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently Americans have been making noise that the Al Qaeda has been regrouping. It may be somewhat fair to state that the Americans only partly understood Al Qaeda both before and after 9/11. Some people say that this is due to the weakness of American intelligence. I personally find that somewhat strange, especially given the close ties with the formidable Mossad of the Israelis. But it is possible that the CIA was deliberately ignoring intelligence from the Mossad due to closeness of some American elite to the Arabs of Saudi and also the need to cultivate the terrorist state of Pakistan to play the 0-sum game against India. It is also possible that the Mossad did not communicate everything with the US. What ever the case the US did not show much finesse in tackling Islamism in the aftermath of the attacks, beyond defeating the Taliban. The US fixation on Iraq has only strengthened the possibility that the Islamic terrorists may regroup for major action. Al Qaeda is merely the tip of the ice-berg of a larger pan-gaean Islamic movement and a symptom of the deeper deviltry in the making.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Khusroo waxing eloquent</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2004-04-20_khusroo-waxing-eloquent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/2004-04-20_khusroo-waxing-eloquent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/04/20/khusroo-waxing-eloquent/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(The excerpt from Amir Khusroo’s florid prose of the savage attack on the Hindus by Maliq Kafr, the general of Alla-ad-din Khalji (Tarikh-i-Allai). Facts that are denied by many Indians themselves.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The tongue of the sword of the Khalifat of the era, which is the tongue of the flame of Islam, has imparted light to the entire pagan darkness of Hindustan by the illumination of its guidance. On one side an iron wall of royal swords has been raised before the Kafirs of Mongolia, the Magog-like Tatars, so that all of the Mongolian tribe, deserted by Allah, drew their feet within their skirts amongst the hills of Ghazni, and even their advance-arrows had not strength enough to reach into Sind which was conquered by the sword of Islam. On the other side so, much dust arose from the battered temple of Somnath that even the sea was not able to settle it. On the right hand and on the left hand the army of Islam has conquered Hindustan from sea to sea, and several capitals of the rulers of the Hindus, in which the worship of the fire and their devilish gods and had prevailed since the time of the Jinns, have all been demolished. All these impurities of infidelity have been cleansed by the Sultan Alla-ad-din’s destruction of idols and temples, beginning with his first Jihad against Devgir (Devagiri in Maharashtra). Now the flames of the light of the Shariat and the righteous Fatwa illuminate all these unholy Hindu lands, and places for the callers to Namaz occupy the high places and the and Namaz is read in mosques. Allah be praised!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>khalji-alla-jihAd</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/khalji-alla-jihAd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/khalji-alla-jihAd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Jihads of Alla-ud-din Khalji&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The one time when it appeared that the sanAtana dharma might vanish off the face of bhArata was during the ferocious jihads of Alla-ud-din of the Khalji tribe. The Khaljis entered India from Ghazna during the reign of the Mamluq Sultan Qutub-ud-din Aibak. The first of them to make his mark Bakhtiyar Khalji, whose savage jihad in Bihar and destruction of the Indian centers of learning like Nalanda is only well known. Jalal-ud-din Khalji, another member of this tribe, was accepted as the Sultan of Delhi by a confederation of Turkic tribes, after the collapse of the Mamluq Balban’s regime. Jalal opened his innings by consolidating the Turkic regime in India by suppressing other competing Maliqs and appointed his nephew, Alla-ud-din to expand his domains. We shall briefly consider his campaigns:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setback of centuries</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/centuries-setback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/MT/centuries-setback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1564443062524313602.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why the Fall of Rome set Europe back 1,000 years (with Bryan Ward-Perkins) - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rt0uBzYf4N8&#34;&gt;YT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some parallels might be seen jambudvIpa: the success of the Turk-led jihad set the H back by at least several 100 years. While I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen an comparable analysis of pottery or tiling, 1 can look at technological proxies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The va&lt;del&gt;Nga country &amp;ndash; One of the most productive provinces at the height of H power (e.g., look at gupta &amp;amp; post gupta inscriptions down to the sena-s) had some distinctive metal work that survived partly in Nepal &amp;amp; chIna. It completely became extinct in core va&lt;/del&gt;Nga &amp;amp; magadha where the pAla-s once held sway.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Irrigation works in both north &amp;amp; south collapsed for several centuries. e.g. see &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2010/07/31/mahasamanta-feudalism/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Loss of metal technologies that were seen 1000 years ago under mahArAja bhoja&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kashmir&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;compare the references in the rAjataraMgiNi to the actual evidence for the transport of blocks weighing several tons in (&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2010/07/31/mahasamanta-feudalism/&#34;&gt;mAhAsamanta “feudalism”&lt;/a&gt;) constructions throughout kAshmira. Post-jihad it completely vanishes. I think one could do an objective study of the weight of stone blocks used in kAshmira.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Also irrigations works like that of suyya. This was quite different from an intrinsic civilizational collapse.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
