<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;muslim slave system on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;muslim slave system on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 PREFACE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/01_pre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/01_pre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PREFACE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my book &lt;em&gt;The Legacy of Muslim Rule in India&lt;/em&gt;, I had said that “It is&#xA;not, pertinent here to make a detailed study of the Muslim slave system&#xA;which was an institution as peculiar as it was unique.” A detailed study&#xA;of the Muslim slave system in medieval India is being made here. In &lt;em&gt;The&#xA;Legacy&lt;/em&gt; I had also said that “the best way to understand the content and&#xA;spirit of Muslim rule in India… is by going through Muslim scriptures&#xA;(as) all medieval chroniclers were scholars of Muslim law.” In their&#xA;writings they often quote from their holy books to vindicate the actions&#xA;of their conquerors and kings. Hence Muslim scriptural sources are&#xA;referred to quite often in the present work which is a study both in the&#xA;theory and practice of Islamic slavery&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 ABBREVIATIONS USED IN REFERENCES TO TITLES OF WORKS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/02_abbr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/02_abbr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABBREVIATIONS USED IN REFERENCES TO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;TITLES OF WORKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Afif.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tarikh-i-Firoz Shahi&lt;/em&gt; by Shams Siraj Afif&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Ain.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ain-i-Akbari&lt;/em&gt; by Abul Fazl&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ashraful Hidayah&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Urdu trs. by &lt;em&gt;Hidayah&lt;/em&gt; done at Deoband&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Barani.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tarikh-i-Firoz Shahi&lt;/em&gt; by Ziyauddin Barani&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Badaoni.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Muntakhab-ut-Tawarikh&lt;/em&gt; by Abdul Qadir Badaoni&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Bernier.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Travels in the Mogul Empire&lt;/em&gt; by Francois Bernier&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;C.H.I.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cambridge History of India&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;E.D.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;History of India as told by its own Historians&lt;/em&gt; by Henry M. Elliot and John Dowson&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Farishtah.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tarikh-i-Farishtah&lt;/em&gt; by Muhammad Qasim Hindu Shah Farishtah&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fatawa-i-Alamgiri&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Urdu trs. of Aurangzeb’s &lt;em&gt;Fatawa-i-Alamgiri&lt;/em&gt;, Deoband&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Hamilton.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;English trs. of the &lt;em&gt;Hedaya&lt;/em&gt; by Charles Hamilton&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Hodivala.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Studies in Indo-Muslim History&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Ibn Battuta.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Rehla&lt;/em&gt;, English trs. by Dr. Mehdi Husain&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Isami.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Futuh-us-Salatin&lt;/em&gt; by Khwaja Abdullah Malik&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Manucci.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Storia do Mogor&lt;/em&gt; by Niccolao Manucci&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Minhaj.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tabqat-i-Nasiri&lt;/em&gt; by Minhaj Siraj Jurjani&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Pelsaert.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jahangir’s India&lt;/em&gt; by Francisco Pelsaert&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Tuzuk.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tuzuk-i-Jahangiri&lt;/em&gt; or Memoirs of Emperor Jahangir&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Utbi.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tarikh-i-Yamini&lt;/em&gt; by Abu Nasr Muhammad&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Yahiya.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tarikh-i-Mubarak Shahi&lt;/em&gt; by Yahiya bin Ahmad bin Abdullah&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 CHAPTER I INTRODUCTION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/03_ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/03_ch1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER I&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Slavery is the system by which certain persons are kept as the property&#xA;of others - a system of great antiquity and wide prevalence. Slavery&#xA;originated during the age of savagery and continued into ancient&#xA;civilizations. As Nieboer has said, “the taming of animals naturally&#xA;leads to taming of men.” it is supposed that the nomadic herdsman who&#xA;domesticated animals also began to domesticate, to enslave, men. Slavery&#xA;was there in Babylon and elsewhere in Mesopotamia; it was widely&#xA;prevalent in ancient Egypt, Greece and Rome, centuries before the coming&#xA;of Christ. Slaves were mainly prisoners of war, but destitutes, debtors&#xA;and convicted criminals were also sometimes drafted into slavery and&#xA;commandeered for specific assignments. The history of ancient&#xA;civilizations in various countries is divided into dynasties, periods&#xA;and kingdoms. We need not go into details of these; for our limited&#xA;purpose we shall only attempt a general survey of the state of slavery&#xA;in ancient Egypt, Greece, Rome etc. till the advent of Islam when&#xA;slavery became inalienable with religion and culture and was accorded a&#xA;permanent place in society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 CHAPTER II THE ORIGINS OF MUSLIM SLAVE SYSTEM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/04_ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/04_ch2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER II&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;THE ORIGINS OF MUSLIM SLAVE SYSTEM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the day India became a target of Muslim invaders its people began&#xA;to be enslaved in droves to be sold in foreign lands or employed in&#xA;various capacities on menial and not-so-menial jobs within the country.&#xA;To understand this phenomenon it is necessary to go into the origins and&#xA;development of the Islamic system of slavery.  For, wherever the Muslims&#xA;went, mostly as conquerors but also as traders, there developed a system&#xA;of slavery peculiar to the clime, terrain and populace of the place. For&#xA;example, simultaneously with Muhammad bin Qasim’s invasion of Sindh in&#xA;early 8th century, the expansion of Arab Islam had gone apace as far as&#xA;Egypt, North Africa and the Iberian Peninsula in the West, as well as in&#xA;Syria, Asia Minor, Palestine, Iraq, Iran, Khurasan, Sistan and&#xA;Transoxiana. In all these countries Muslim slave system grew and&#xA;developed in its own way. There was constant contact between India and&#xA;most of these countries in the medieval times. For example, as early as&#xA;during the reigns of the slave sultans Iltutmish and Balban (1210-86),&#xA;there arrived at their courts in Delhi a large number of princes with&#xA;their followers from Iraq, Khurasan and Mawar-un-Nahr because of the&#xA;Mongol upheaval.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) Many localities in Delhi and its environs&#xA;were settled by these elites and their slaves, soldiers and scholars. In&#xA;Balban’s royal procession 500 Sistani, Ghauri and Samarqandi&#xA;slave-troops with drawn swords used to march by his side pointing to the&#xA;fact that a large number of foreign slaves from these lands had come to&#xA;India in 13th-14th centuries.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;) When the Mughals launched their&#xA;conquest of India, there was the establishment of the Ottoman Empire in&#xA;Turkey which at its height included present-day Albania, Greece,&#xA;Bulgaria, Serbia, Romania and several other contiguous countries. Then&#xA;there was the Safavid empire in Iran. The Ottoman Empire traded with&#xA;Europe and imported “there indispensable stock of slaves. (Slav, as the&#xA;word indicates), supplied by merchants, sometimes Jewish, from Verdun,&#xA;Venice or elsewhere in Italy. Other slaves were brought from black&#xA;Africa, eastern Europe and Turkish Central Asia.”^(&lt;a href=&#34;#3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;) The Mughals&#xA;of India had very close contacts with the Turkish Ottoman and Iranian&#xA;Safavid empires. This contact certainly included exchange of slaves and&#xA;ideas on slavery. But any attempt in this area of study, which is so&#xA;vast and labyrinthine, is bound to deflect us from our main theme which&#xA;is restricted to India. We shall therefore confine ourselves to the&#xA;barest particulars of the beginnings of the institution outside India&#xA;which will suffice for understanding the Muslim slave system in India in&#xA;the medieval period.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 CHAPTER III ENSLAVEMENT OF HINDUS BY ARAB AND TURKISH INVADERS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/05_ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/05_ch3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER III&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;ENSLAVEMENT OF HINDUS BY ARAB AND&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;TURKISH INVADERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Turks were not the first Muslims to invade India. Prior to the coming of&#xA;Turks the Arab general Muhammad bin Qasim invaded Sindh in the early&#xA;years of the eighth century. In conformity with the Muslim tradition,&#xA;the Arabs captured and enslaved Indians in large numbers. Indeed from&#xA;the days of Muhammad bin Qasim in the eighth century to those of Ahmad&#xA;Shah Abdali in the eighteenth, enslavement, distribution, and sale of&#xA;Hindu prisoners was systematically practised by Muslim invaders and&#xA;rulers of India. It is but natural that the exertion of a thousand years&#xA;of slave-taking can only be briefly recounted with a few salient&#xA;features of the system highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 CHAPTER IV SLAVE SULTANS OF HINDUSTAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/06_ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/06_ch4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER IV&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;SLAVE SULTANS OF HINDUSTAN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Slavery was wide-spread in Islam. The early Turkish invaders and rulers&#xA;of India were slaves or scions of slaves.  Mahmud of Ghazni was the son&#xA;of a purchased slave, Subuktigin. Subuktigin in his turn had been bought&#xA;by one Alptigin who himself was a purchased slave. Alptigin was the&#xA;first Turkish slave-warrior-ruler who carried his arms into Hindustan.&#xA;His career and resourcefulness are symbolic of the Turkish slaves as a&#xA;whole.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 CHAPTER V SLAVE-TAKING DURING MUSLIM RULE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/07_ch5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/07_ch5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER V&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;SLAVE-TAKING DURING MUSLIM RULE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Slavery forms an integral part of the history of Islam. The Turks&#xA;practised it on a large scale before they entered India as invaders.&#xA;Slaves were abducted or captured by marauders (Subuktigin, Balban), they&#xA;were sold by jealous or needy relatives (Iltutmish), and they were&#xA;purchased by slave-traders to be sold for profit (Aibak). These methods&#xA;were known to Muslim rulers in India. All these and many other methods&#xA;were employed by them and their nobles in making slaves in India. The&#xA;phenomenon and its application was shocking to the Hindu mind; the&#xA;Muslims, however, thought otherwise. According to Ibn Khaldun, the&#xA;captives were “brought from the House of War to the House of Islam under&#xA;the rule of slavery, which hides in itself a divine providence; cured by&#xA;slavery, they enter the Muslim religion with the firm resolve of true&#xA;believers…”^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) Muslims took pride in enslaving people; the&#xA;feelings of Hindu victims were just the opposite.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 CHAPTER VI ENSLAVEMENT AND PROSELYTIZATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/08_ch6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/08_ch6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER VI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;ENSLAVEMENT AND PROSELYTIZATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wherever the Muslims conquered - in West Asia, Eastern Europe, Africa&#xA;and India - there they made people slaves and converted them to Islam.&#xA;In this mission they were most successful in Africa and the least in&#xA;India.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the advent of Islam, part of Arabia was under Abyssinian rule. When&#xA;Arabia was Islamized, the tide turned and the Abyssinians came under the&#xA;Arabs and they made slaves of Abyssinians and Ethiopians without much&#xA;opposition. Muslims have been quite satisfied with their achievements in&#xA;slave-making in Africa. Many Western scholars also have romanticised and&#xA;even defended black slavery in the Islamic world. Bernard Lewis quotes&#xA;many European historians to say that “slavery is a divine boon to&#xA;mankind, by means of which pagan and barbarous people are brought to&#xA;Islam and civilization… Slavery in the East has an elevating influence&#xA;over thousands of human beings, and but for it hundreds of thousands of&#xA;souls must pass their existence in this world as wild savages, little&#xA;better than animals; it, at least, makes men of them, &lt;em&gt;useful men&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;too…”^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) T.W. Arnold also writes that “devout minds have even&#xA;recognised in enslavement God’s guidance to the true faith, as the&#xA;Negroes from the Upper Nile countries… In those Africans there is no&#xA;resentment that they have been made slaves… even though cruel&#xA;men-stealers rent them from their parentage… freedom is in many&#xA;instances the reward of conversion… The patrons who paid their price&#xA;have adopted them in their households, the males are circumcised and…&#xA;God has visited them in their mishap; they can say &lt;em&gt;‘it was His grace’&lt;/em&gt;,&#xA;since they are thereby entered into the saving&#xA;religion.”^(&lt;a href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;) Lewis, however admits “that there are evils in Arab&#xA;slavery” and that even emancipated blacks are “rarely able to rise above&#xA;the lowest level.”^(&lt;a href=&#34;#3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;) Slavery is a degrading condition, and many&#xA;people do lose their dignity when they are kept in this condition for a&#xA;long time. It has been universally acknowledged that the later Western&#xA;managed slave trade in which Muslim Arabs were often the intermediaries,&#xA;has had a devastating consequence for African countries. There is no&#xA;reason to assume that the consequences of the earlier Islamic slavery in&#xA;Africa had more benign results for the Africans.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 CHAPTER VII STRUGGLE FOR POWER AMONG SLAVE NOBLES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/09_ch7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/09_ch7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER VII&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;STRUGGLE FOR POWER AMONG SLAVE NOBLES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abdulla Khan’s words were prophetic. The population of Indian Muslims&#xA;grew rapidly through enslavement. This rapid growth gave rise to new&#xA;problems. One was a tussle for power between foreign slave-Amirs and&#xA;Indian slaves some of whom also attained to the position of nobles. As&#xA;among the Turkish Amirs themselves, a bitter struggle for clout also&#xA;raged between foreign Turks and Indian Muslims. The Hindus resisted&#xA;enslavement and conversion. But once made Musalmans, they asserted their&#xA;claim to equality with foreign Muslims. Distinction between the two has&#xA;always been there and it is reflected in the writings of medieval&#xA;chroniclers like Minhaj and Barani and the observations of Europeans&#xA;like Bernier and Robert Orme.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) The Turks asserted that they&#xA;belonged to the blue blood and were founders of Muslim rule in India.&#xA;The India Muslims knew that the Turks were good fighters, but for&#xA;administrative work indigenous Muslims were better suited. To keep them&#xA;under control the sultans resorted to the time honoured policy of&#xA;playing the one against the other. On one occasion Sultan Iltutmish&#xA;dismissed thirty-three persons from service on account of their low&#xA;birth, or their Indian ancestry.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;) On the other hand Sultan&#xA;Nasiruddin raised Indian-born Imad-ud-din Rayhan to the position of&#xA;Vakil-i-Dar (Custodian of the keys of Palace Gates) after dismissing the&#xA;all powerful foreign Turk Ghiyasuddin Balban. Minhaj Siraj’s description&#xA;of the situation shows how high the feelings ran between the foreign&#xA;Turkish and Indian ‘Julaha’ nobles. “The Maliks and servants of the&#xA;Sultan’s Court were all Turks of pure lineage” (&lt;em&gt;Turkan-i-pak&lt;/em&gt;) writes&#xA;he, and Taziks of noble birth (&lt;em&gt;Tazikan-i-guzida was&lt;/em&gt;). “Imad-ud-Din&#xA;Rayhan (who) was castrated and mutilated, and of the tribe of Hind, was&#xA;ruling over the heads of lords of high descent, and the whole of them&#xA;were loathing that state, and were unable to suffer any longer that&#xA;degradation.”^(&lt;a href=&#34;#3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;) The Turkish nobles rose in arms and the Sultan&#xA;was persuaded to order the dismissal of Rayhan and recall of Ulugh&#xA;Khan-i-Azam Balban (February, 1254). The language of Ziyauddin Barani is&#xA;not less vituperative. He was a staunch believer in the racial&#xA;superiority of the Turks and the baseness of Indian Muslims. He&#xA;recommended that “Teachers of every kind are to be sternly ordered not&#xA;to thrust precious stones down the throats of dogs… that is, to the&#xA;mean, the ignoble, the worthless… To the low-born they are to teach&#xA;nothing more than the rules about prayer, fasting, religious charity and&#xA;the Hajj pilgrimage along with some chapters of the Quran and some&#xA;doctrines of the faith… They (Indian Muslims) are not to be taught&#xA;reading and writing for plenty of disorders arise owing to the skill of&#xA;the low-born in knowledge… the low-born are capable only of vices… so&#xA;they are called low-born, worthless, plebeian, shameless and of dirty&#xA;birth.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 CHAPTER VIII EMPLOYMENT OF SLAVES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/10_ch8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/10_ch8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER VIII&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;EMPLOYMENT OF SLAVES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Muslim regime in medieval times drafted slaves in every sphere of&#xA;activity. Slaves were needed in thousands for any large enterprise&#xA;which, in modern technological age, would be accomplished by a few&#xA;machines or even gadgets. There was no dearth of slaves either. Muslim&#xA;victories in India had provided kings and nobles with innumerable&#xA;slaves. From government affairs to domestic errands slaves were employed&#xA;on every work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 CHAPTER IX GHILMANS AND EUNUCHS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/11_ch9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/11_ch9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER IX&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;GHILMANS AND EUNUCHS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The treatment meted out to the slaves depended upon the temperament,&#xA;whim and caprice of the master. Some masters were kind hearted and&#xA;treated their slaves kindly, many others cruelly, a few abominably. But&#xA;one class of slaves who were very well looked after were &lt;em&gt;ghilman&lt;/em&gt; and&#xA;&lt;em&gt;mamalik&lt;/em&gt;. The eunuchs also, because of the nature of their duties,&#xA;received sort of a special treatment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ghilman va Mamalik&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 CHAPTER X SLAVE TRADE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/12_ch10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/12_ch10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER X&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;SLAVE TRADE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is nowhere mentioned in medieval chronicles how slaves, captured in&#xA;war, were sorted out and separated for the purpose of being sold,&#xA;drafted into the army, given as gifts to princes and nobles or set apart&#xA;for domestic service. All that is known is that slaves were disposed of&#xA;on all these counts and many more. It appears that the sorting was done&#xA;on the basis of the looks of the females, physical fitness of the males,&#xA;intuition of the master, as well as the specific work that a slave was&#xA;deemed fit to do. An early example is about the capture of Brahmanabad&#xA;by Muhammad bin Qasim. Of the prisoners captured a selection was made&#xA;from the slaves and other spoils, “in order to detach the usual&#xA;one-fifth share of the State. The number of the selected slaves came to&#xA;about 20,000. The rest were distributed among the troops.”^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) But&#xA;the criterion of selection has not been specified. Another instance is&#xA;about Amir Timur who invaded India in 1399, and took a large number of&#xA;prisoners. He writes “I ordered that all the artisans and clever&#xA;mechanics, who were masters of their respective crafts, should be picked&#xA;out from among the prisoners and set aside, and accordingly some&#xA;thousands of craftsmen were selected to await my command. All these I&#xA;distributed among the princes and &lt;em&gt;amirs&lt;/em&gt; who were present, or who were&#xA;engaged officially in other parts of my dominions (to take care of&#xA;them). I had determined to build a &lt;em&gt;Majid-i-Jami&lt;/em&gt; in Samarkand, the seat&#xA;of my empire, which should be without rival in any country; so I ordered&#xA;that all builders and stone-masons should be set apart for my own&#xA;especial service.”^(&lt;a href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;) But such details are not available in most&#xA;cases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 CHAPTER XI RULES REGARDING MANUMISSION AND SALE OF SLAVES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/13_ch11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/13_ch11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER XI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;RULES REGARDING MANUMISSION AND SALE OF SLAVES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It has been seen in the preceding pages that a very prominent feature of&#xA;Muslim polity, society and economy in this country was its slave system.&#xA;Muslim history throughout the country and indeed in this world is&#xA;incomplete without its slaves. The two main sources of obtaining slaves&#xA;were by capture and purchase. The two main means of their disposal were&#xA;by manumission and sale. We shall here briefly discuss the problems and&#xA;rules associated with these two aspects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 CHAPTER XII SEX SLAVERY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/14_ch12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/14_ch12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER XII&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;SEX SLAVERY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the preceding pages it has been seen how women and children were&#xA;special targets for enslavement throughout the medieval period, that is,&#xA;during Muslim invasions and Muslim rule. Captive children of both sexes&#xA;grew up as Muslims and served the sultans, nobles and men of means in&#xA;various captives. Enslavement of young women was also due to many&#xA;reasons; their being sex objects was the primary consideration and hence&#xA;concentration on their captivity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 POSTSCRIPT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/15_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/15_post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;POSTSCRIPT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We began by quoting Thomas Patrick Hughes to say that “slavery of Islam&#xA;is interwoven with the Law of marriage, the Law of sale, and the Law of&#xA;inheritance… and its abolition would strike at the very foundation of&#xA;the code of Muhammadanism”.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) The statement holds as good today&#xA;as in the early years of Islam. The rules of Islam remain the same for&#xA;all time, for Islam is changeless and unchangeable. As I.H. Qureshi puts&#xA;it: “The Muslim jurists and theologians believe in the supremacy of the&#xA;&lt;em&gt;shar&lt;/em&gt; and hold that it is eternal and immutable in its essence. It is&#xA;based on the Quran which is believed by every Muslim to be the Word of&#xA;God revealed to His prophet Muhammad. Not even the Prophet could change&#xA;the revelation…”^(&lt;a href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;) Muhammad could not change the revelation; he&#xA;could only explain and interpret it. So do the Muslims do today. There&#xA;are liberal Muslims and conservative Muslims, there are Muslims learned&#xA;in theology and Muslims devoid of learning. They discuss, they&#xA;interpret, they rationalize, but all by going round and round within the&#xA;closed circle of Islam. There is no possibility of getting out of the&#xA;fundamentals of Islam; there is no provision of introducing any&#xA;innovation. So, Muslim slave system could not remain confined to the&#xA;Middle Ages. Muhammad legitimized slavery in the Quran and therefore it&#xA;is recognized to be in complete conformity with Islam. Slavery is&#xA;considered an integral part of Islam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 BIBLIOGRAPHY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/16_bib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lal_ks/muslim_slave_system/16_bib/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BIBLIOGRAPHY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Sources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abdullah, &lt;em&gt;Tarikh-i-Daudi&lt;/em&gt;, Bankipore Ms. Text, ed. by S.A. Rashid,&#xA;Aligarh.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abdul Hamid Lahori, &lt;em&gt;Badshah Nama&lt;/em&gt;, Bib. Ind., 2 vols., Calcutta, 1898.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abul Fazl, Allami, &lt;em&gt;Ain-i-Akbari&lt;/em&gt;, 3 vols., Vol.I trs. by H. Blochmann&#xA;and ed. by D.C. Phillot, Calcutta, 1939; Vol.II trs. by H.S. Jarret and&#xA;annotated by Jadunath Sarkar, Calcutta, 1939; Vol.III trs. by Jarret and&#xA;Sarkar, Calcutta, 1948.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abul Fazl, Allami, &lt;em&gt;Akbar Nama&lt;/em&gt;, Bib. Ind. Text, 3 vols., English trs.&#xA;by Henry Beveridge, Calcutta, 1948.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
