<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;kachChAva on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/kachChAva/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;kachChAva on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/kachChAva/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>mAna siMha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/kachChAva/mAna-siMha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/kachChAva/mAna-siMha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overviews&#34;&gt;Overviews&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cUghBY8wKeY&#34;&gt;YT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;capitulation-to-mogols&#34;&gt;Capitulation to mogols&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gradson of Bharmal, son of Prithviraj. The kachChAva-s capiulation came due to the following factors:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Unlike the Amer kingdom – which was mere days march away from Agra and Delhi – Mewar had a strategic upper hand, the Aravalli range - so the latter could afford to resist.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Raja Bharmal of the same line faced a desperately dangerous challenge – Muhammad Sharifuddin Hussain, the Mughal governor of Mewat, who was very keen on extending his territory at the cost of Amer. Raja took to the alliance with Mughal emperor Akbar in 1562. Akbar ordered Sharifuddin to return war booty, hostages and leave the kingdom of Amer. Raja Bharmal’s eldest son and grandson, Bhagwant Das and Man Singh, were given high offices in imperial nobility.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The capitulation was unusually abject: Most Rajput treaties with Akbar had a clause that they would not be asked to join arms against Mewar. Prof K S Gupta shows how 1569 Bundi-Mughal treaty which has only two stipulations from Bundi side. One of those is that Bundi army will never help Mughals should they fight against Mewar. Jodhpur, Jaisalmer etc states also had more or less the similar conditions, some times explicitly in the treaties.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pRthvIrAjaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/kachChAva/pRthvIrAjaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/kachChAva/pRthvIrAjaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Raja Prithviraj I Kachwaha of Amer/Amber kingdom - who fought for Hindus against Mughals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1503 CE: Prithviraj Kachwaha ascended the throne of Amer. His reign was marked by stability and progress for the Jaipur kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During his reign, he cultivated marital alliances with many neighbouring Rajput states. This contributed to making Amber a major regional political player. Even the sister of Maharana Sanga was married to Prithviraj Kachwaha, thereby uniting with Mewar under Hindu banner!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rAma-simha (Ram Singh) of amber</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/kachChAva/rAma-simha_Ram_Singh_of_amber/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/kachChAva/rAma-simha_Ram_Singh_of_amber/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;son of mogol general jayasimha, received a proper Hindu education in Kashi and was well-versed in various shAstra-s and was a practicing vaidika Hindu in the most fanatic Islamic court, just like his father.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;helped shivAjI escape from Delhi, prevented his assassination by the Qazi of Delhi, helped at his own cost the sikh guru tej bAhadUr.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Awrangzeb wanted to execute the guru, but rAm singh interceded and enabled him to escape a month after tej bAhadUr was given to his custody.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Awrangzeb clearly saw rAm singh as being partial to the Hindus and sent rAm singh as punishment with a mere 8000 men against the rAjA of Assam chakradhvaja singh-deva and his most valiant commander-in-chief lachit barphukan. &amp;hellip; Initially, the Mogol viceroy in Assam, Rashid Khan turned against rAm singh himself, who had to drive him out by deploying a specially trained force of large war dogs. &amp;hellip; &amp;quot; Lachit and co defeated them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Awrangzeb too feared that if the rAm singh, who had returned from Assam, joined hands with his coethnics, who were up in arms against the Mohammedan oppression, he could be cut off from Delhi. Hence, he sent off rAm singh under a Mohammedan general to fight the Afridis in Afghanistan.&amp;rdquo; He took his son kRShNa singh to the deccan, but &amp;ldquo;was conspiring with the durgAdas and the marATha-s, so Awrangzeb assassinated him by means of a Pathan servant in his camp. rAm singh was completely broken by this and was shaken even further when Awrangzeb next asked him to send his grandson viShNu singh to the Deccan.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Famous addressee of &lt;a href=&#34;../docs/sambhAji-letter/&#34;&gt;sambhAji&amp;rsquo;s letter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
