<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Orgs on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Orgs on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bankruptcy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/bankruptcy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/bankruptcy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;definition&#34;&gt;Definition&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When a company declares bankruptcy, it says that it is incapable of meeting all of its financial commitments/ liabilities. All of its agreements with trade-unions are then also canceled.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The business’s assets can be liquidated (seized, valued and sold) to satisfy its liabilities. Also, the company may be taken over and restructured; and the new owner can repay outstanding debts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;rescue&#34;&gt;Rescue&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The government is often motivated to rescue failing businesses to prevent negative consequences like job loss, reduction in national pride etc..&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Funding</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/funding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Entrepreneurship. The effect of governments on business operations and running is described elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;funding-stages&#34;&gt;Funding stages&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;prototyping&#34;&gt;Prototyping&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People with a good business idea may get ’seed money’ from an ’angel investor’ to make a prototype. The angel investors may well be governments or university funds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;launch&#34;&gt;Launch&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then, they pitch it to venture capitalists who provide two rounds of funding in return for a share in the company.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;expansion&#34;&gt;Expansion&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A third round of funding, called the mezzannine funding, is then sought for a possible expansion phase, usually after the company is profitable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ownership</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/ownership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/ownership/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At any given point in time, it is clear from documentation/ declaration who the owners of a business are, what portion of the business they own.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Owners usually get a portion of profit as ’dividends’. They have a say in appointing the highest level/ board of executives/ managers who run the company on their behalf.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;shares-equity&#34;&gt;Shares/ Equity&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;public-offerings&#34;&gt;Public offerings&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Existing owners or executives can effectively divide the company’s ownership into a certain number of shares. A common way of expanding the ownership of a company is to sell these shares to the general public at a price which is either preset or determined automatically by an auction. This process is called the initial public offering/ IPO.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scale</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/scale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;per unit cost of a product drops with rising scale of production.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Concentration of activity in industry and agriculture (even coffee shops!) is justified by economic theory on the grounds of economies of scale (aka &amp;ldquo;marginal cost of production&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Via S Vembu.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The costs drop rapidly with scale at first but beyond a certain scale (let&amp;rsquo;s call it &amp;ldquo;optimal scale&amp;rdquo;), stop dropping or even start increasing as dis-economies of scale kick in.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The second point is crucial: the optimal scale, the scale at which unit costs stop dropping, itself is decreasing with technology advances. This is true for many industries. Translated into plain language, it means that smaller scale production is viable in many sectors. As an example, software development needed expensive computers at first but today is accessible to anyone. Smaller scale production became viable in software.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;As anyone who works for a large company knows, there are real dis-economies of scale that come with size due to communication and coordination issues that grow faster than linearly with size.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Finally concentration of production and economic activity ends up gifting more and more of the productivity gains to land owners and real estate operators.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;illegal-monopolies-vs-scale-factor&#34;&gt;Illegal monopolies vs scale factor&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;As an example, software development needed expensive computers at first but today is accessible to anyone. Smaller scale production became viable in software. This is true across many industries.  In America, very many industries have been consolidated, far beyond any real economic rationale,  as @matthewstoller explains in his book Goliath.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
