<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Orgs on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Orgs on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bankruptcy</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/bankruptcy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/bankruptcy/</guid>
      <description>Definition When a company declares bankruptcy, it says that it is incapable of meeting all of its financial commitments/ liabilities. All of its agreements with trade-unions are then also canceled.
The business’s assets can be liquidated (seized, valued and sold) to satisfy its liabilities. Also, the company may be taken over and restructured; and the new owner can repay outstanding debts.
Rescue Motivation The government is often motivated to rescue failing businesses to prevent negative consequences like job loss, reduction in national pride etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funding</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/funding/</guid>
      <description>Entrepreneurship. The effect of governments on business operations and running is described elsewhere.
Funding stages Prototyping People with a good business idea may get ’seed money’ from an ’angel investor’ to make a prototype. The angel investors may well be governments or university funds.
Launch Then, they pitch it to venture capitalists who provide two rounds of funding in return for a share in the company.
Expansion A third round of funding, called the mezzannine funding, is then sought for a possible expansion phase, usually after the company is profitable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ownership</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/ownership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/ownership/</guid>
      <description>At any given point in time, it is clear from documentation/ declaration who the owners of a business are, what portion of the business they own.
Owners usually get a portion of profit as ’dividends’. They have a say in appointing the highest level/ board of executives/ managers who run the company on their behalf.
Shares/ Equity Public offerings Existing owners or executives can effectively divide the company’s ownership into a certain number of shares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/orgs/scale/</guid>
      <description>Intro  per unit cost of a product drops with rising scale of production. Concentration of activity in industry and agriculture (even coffee shops!) is justified by economic theory on the grounds of economies of scale (aka &amp;ldquo;marginal cost of production&amp;rdquo;).  Limitations  Via S Vembu. The costs drop rapidly with scale at first but beyond a certain scale (let&amp;rsquo;s call it &amp;ldquo;optimal scale&amp;rdquo;), stop dropping or even start increasing as dis-economies of scale kick in.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>