<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Infection on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Infection on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apparel</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/Apparel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/Apparel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eye glasses - Wear any, but prefer full eye covering.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;masks&#34;&gt;Masks&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Even cloth masks help.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Refer - &lt;a href=&#34;https://masks4all.org/&#34;&gt;masks4all1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://masks4all.co/&#34;&gt;masks4all2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;WHO was retarded: &amp;ldquo;The WHO also recommends public mask usage during high-severity influenza pandemics – just not during this Coronavirus pandemic.&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;WHO describes a MINIMAL standard. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that we couldn&amp;rsquo;t do MORE.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Errors in reasoning about masks by NN Taleb &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/incerto/the-masks-masquerade-7de897b517b7&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Suprising demo of effectiveness of masks: &amp;quot; the salon story where two infected stylists failed to infect all their 140 clients (making the probability of infection for bilateral mask wearing safely below 1% for a salon-style exposure) — we know the probability of infection for non mask wearers from tens of thousands of data points and the various R0 estimations) plus&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Herd immunity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/herd-immunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/herd-immunity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;india&#34;&gt;India&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The third national sero surveillance indicates only 20% of the population is exposed to the virus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Only 1 out 15 aged 10 years and above in India were exposed to the virus by Aug 18 2020.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;vaccination-rate&#34;&gt;Vaccination rate&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;202101: India has been vaccinating at 2.2 lakh/ day. 0.21% of the population have been vaccinated in 13 days.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human persistence</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/human_persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/human_persistence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;infectivity&#34;&gt;Infectivity&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Available data suggest that patients with mild-to-moderate COVID-19 remain infectious no longer than 10 days after symptom onset.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most patients with more severe-to-critical illness likely remain infectious no longer than 20 days after symptom onset.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There have been numerous reports of moderately or severely immunocompromised people shedding replication-competent virus beyond 20 days.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/duration-isolation.html&#34;&gt;CDC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;immuno-compromised-folks&#34;&gt;Immuno-compromised folks&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cancer patients and those who have a compromised immune system keep shedding viruses for long. Example: a cancer patient who had chemotherapy kept shedding virus till 105 days( 3 months) despite twice being titrated with Remdesivir and plasma therapy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Other resistance</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/anti-virals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/anti-virals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use safe anti-virals at lower doses (see treatment page).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gargling&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prophylactic prescription</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/prophylactic-prescription/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/prophylactic-prescription/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;adults-50kg&#34;&gt;Adults (50kg)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ivermectin 12 mg, 2 tablets per week for 4 weeks&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1% povidone/iodine solution for gargling - 500ml&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Calcitriol (vitamin D) .25mcg, 1 tablet daily for 1 week&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zinc 100mg daily for 1 week&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;kids-25-kg&#34;&gt;Kids (25 kg)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ivermectin 12 mg, 1 tablets per week for 4 weeks&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1% povidone/iodine solution for gargling - 500ml&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reinfection</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/reinfection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/reinfection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;uncommon-cases&#34;&gt;Uncommon cases&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Protection from prior infection (Mar’20 until Dec‘20): 91%&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There have been re-infections of the Corona virus have been described around the world.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Not all reinfections seen so far are milder.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 1 in 5 or even 1 in 3 of those infected during the first wave in India had declining antibodies 6 months later.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-antibody-persistence&#34;&gt;General antibody persistence&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Even mild Covid infection induces a robust antigen-specific, long-lived plasma cells in the bone marrow that lasts &amp;gt;12 months.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Reinfections with the four coronaviruses that cause the common cold occur after an average of 12 months, a team led by virologist Lia van der Hoek at Amsterdam University Medical Center recently showed. Van der Hoek thinks COVID-19 may follow that pattern.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2020/11/more-people-are-getting-covid-19-twice-suggesting-immunity-wanes-quickly-some&#34;&gt;SM2011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you are a healthcare worker and found to have antibodies (IgG anti spike antibodies), unlikely to develop re-infection for atleast 6 months as this study from Oxford has demonstrated.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Although antibodies can wane substantially within months—particularly in patients with less severe disease—they sometimes persist, even in mild cases. Neutralizing antibodies, the most important kind, as well as memory B cells and T cells seem to be relatively stable over at least 6 months, a preprint posted on 16 November shows, which “would likely prevent the vast majority of people from getting hospitalized disease, severe disease, for many years,”&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;mutations&#34;&gt;Mutations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The data really are quite suggestive: The level of immunity that you get from natural infection — either the degree of immunity, the intensity of the immunity or the breadth of immunity — is obviously not enough to protect against infection with the mutant”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risk models</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/risk_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/risk_models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Adjustible simulations/ models: natgeo &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/science/2020/08/how-to-measure-risk-airborne-coronavirus-your-office-classroom-bus-ride-cvd/?cmpid=org=ngp::mc=social::src=twitter::cmp=editorial::add=tw20200811science-measurecoronavirusriskmodel::rid=&amp;amp;sf236722474=1&#34;&gt;202008&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Successful Infection = &lt;strong&gt;Virus Dose x Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;alternate&#34;&gt;Alternate&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;\(I_r = \dfrac{N t C_q (Q_b)^2 p_m^2}{\gl_a V}\)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Their key result is boiled down to this equation for Risk Index \(I_r\).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;N is the number of people in the enclosed space, t is the time spent therein.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;\(C_q\) is the concentration of exhaled infection quanta (virions) per cubic meter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;\(Q_b\) is the exhaled volume in cubic meters per hour.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;\(Q_b\) exhaled volume rate is also square scaling: Hence, talking, shouting, singing are all increase the risk by square.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;\(p_m\) is mask penetration factor, \(0 &amp;lt;= p_m &amp;lt;= 1\), where 1 is no mask &amp;amp; 0 is theoretical total blockade of particles of virion size or higher.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it scales as the square of mask penetration: hence, some mask makes a notable difference relative to no mask. Better the mask square gain in risk reduction.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;\(\lambda_a\) is ventilation outflow rate per unit volume in m^3. V is volume of enclosed space.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;indoor-spaces&#34;&gt;Indoor spaces&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Indoor spaces&lt;/strong&gt;, with limited air exchange or recycled air and lots of people, are concerning from a transmission standpoint. We know that 60 people in a volleyball court-sized room (choir) results in massive infections. Same situation with the restaurant and the call center. &lt;strong&gt;Social distancing guidelines don&amp;rsquo;t hold&lt;/strong&gt; in indoor spaces where you spend a lot of time, as people on the opposite side of the room were infected. ..&amp;rdquo; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.erinbromage.com/post/the-risks-know-them-avoid-them&#34;&gt;EB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When weather conditions allow, increase fresh outdoor air by opening windows and doors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use fans to increase the effectiveness of open windows. Avoid placing fans in a way that could potentially cause contaminated air to flow directly from one person over another. One helpful strategy is to use a window fan, placed safely and securely in a window, to exhaust room air to the outdoors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Decrease occupancy in areas where outdoor ventilation cannot be increased.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Consider portable high-efficiency particulate air (HEPA) fan/filtration systems to help enhance air cleaning (especially in higher risk areas)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;earlier, 30 minute exposure to a crowded store could infect you. Now (with UK strain), 20 minute exposure is enough to infect you.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;ac-systems&#34;&gt;AC systems&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Turn off any demand-controlled ventilation (DCV) controls that reduce air supply based on occupancy or temperature during occupied hours.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In homes and buildings where the HVAC fan operation can be controlled at the thermostat, set the fan to the “on” position instead of “auto,” which will operate the fan continuously, even when heating or air-conditioning is not required.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Open outdoor air dampers beyond minimum settings to reduce or eliminate HVAC air recirculation. In mild weather, this will not affect thermal comfort or humidity. However, this may be difficult to do in cold, hot, or humid weather.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Consider using ultraviolet germicidal irradiation (UVGI) as a supplement to help inactivate SARS-CoV-2, especially if options for increasing room ventilation are limited.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;outdoor-spaces&#34;&gt;Outdoor spaces&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Social distancing&lt;/strong&gt; rules are really to protect you with &lt;strong&gt;brief exposures&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;outdoor exposures&lt;/strong&gt;. In these situations there is not enough time to achieve the infectious viral load when you are standing 6 feet apart or where wind and the infinite outdoor space for viral dilution reduces viral load. &amp;hellip; If I am outside, and I walk past someone, remember it is “dose and time” needed for infection. You would have to be in their airstream for 5+ minutes (optimistically assuming 20VP per minute) for a chance of infection.  While joggers may be releasing more virus due to deep breathing, remember the exposure time is also less due to their speed.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;location&#34;&gt;Location&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The main sources for infection are home, workplace, public transport, social gatherings, and restaurants. This accounts for 90% of all transmission events. In contrast, outbreaks spread from shopping appear to be responsible for a small percentage of traced infections. &amp;hellip; When assessing the risk of infection (via respiration) at the grocery store or mall, you need to consider the &lt;strong&gt;volume of the air space&lt;/strong&gt; (very large), the &lt;strong&gt;number of people&lt;/strong&gt; (restricted), how long people are spending in the store (workers - all day; customers - an hour).&amp;rdquo; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.erinbromage.com/post/the-risks-know-them-avoid-them&#34;&gt;EB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;travel&#34;&gt;Travel&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;India: Risk of getting infected from another household is 9% but that becomes 79% while travelling with another infected for more than 6 hours.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Air Travel: Mask is a must. Hand hygene essential.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Air travel is safer than train or bus travel - but still risky. Modern airlines have started installing HEPA filters that suck air from outside through wings, mixes with inside air in 50:50 mix,warms it up and filters off any bacteria,fungus and Viruses.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;children&#34;&gt;Children&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wave 2 India and Brazil&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In Brazil,many children are dying. In India too Pediatricians are reporting wards getting filled with young kids presenting with very high fever and bowel disturbances which mimic like appendicitis.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is the inflammation of the terminal part of small bowel called ileum that are typically presenting with pain in abdomen and diarrhea.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Many children are requiring intravenous immunoglobulins to salvage them from multi system inflammation resulted from the virus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;70% of confirmed children carry active virus without symptoms, and the duration of a case lasts as long as 36 days.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;dead-body&#34;&gt;Dead body&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CDC guidelines &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/daily-life-coping/funeral-guidance.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CDC &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/global-covid-19/COVID19-vs-Ebola-burial-guide.html&#34;&gt;2020&lt;/a&gt; said that risk from dead body is low (no respiratory droplets).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Avoid touching the deceased person’s body. Wash your hands with soap and water for at least 20 seconds after any contact with the body.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;super-spreader--single-source-events&#34;&gt;Super-spreader / single-source events&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-175 attendees attended a Biogen conference at Boston In February. A week later 99 people fell ill. Now,300,000 infections around the world and 1.6% of all the US infections can be traced back to this single gathering at Boston. The infection from this conference jumped to 29 countries and almost every part of USA.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seasonality</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/seasonality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/seasonality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cold / indoor weather increases death rate even without Wuhan epidemic. Cold and low humidity air is good for the virus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Most experts believe: it will run a seasonal course for next 5 years despite vaccination.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transmission mechanics</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/Transmission_mechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/Transmission_mechanics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;We know that at least 44% of all infections&amp;ndash;and the majority of community-acquired transmissions&amp;ndash;occur from people without any symptoms (asymptomatic or pre-symptomatic people).&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It turns out it takes 2 days to become infectious, not 5 days.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Some experts estimate that as few as 1000 SARS-CoV2 infectious viral particles are all that will be needed.&amp;rdquo; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.erinbromage.com/post/the-risks-know-them-avoid-them&#34;&gt;EB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;thumbnail&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;../../../../saMskAra/mantraH/rogAH/images/corona-growth-visualization.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;../../../../saMskAra/mantraH/rogAH/images/corona-growth-visualization.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;virus-expulsion-mechanics&#34;&gt;Virus expulsion mechanics&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;A single &lt;strong&gt;breath&lt;/strong&gt; releases 50 - 5000 droplets. Most of these droplets are low velocity and fall to the ground quickly. There are even fewer droplets released through nose-breathing. Importantly, due to the lack of exhalation force with a breath, viral particles from the lower respiratory areas are not expelled. &amp;hellip; We don&amp;rsquo;t have a number for SARS-CoV2 yet, but we can use influenza as a guide. Studies have shown that a person infected with influenza can releases up to 33 infectious viral particles per minute.&amp;rdquo; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.erinbromage.com/post/the-risks-know-them-avoid-them&#34;&gt;EB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Speaking normally releases around 10x more - 330 (flu) VP per minute.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yelling, speaking or singing especially in closed spaces is a big transmitter!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;cough-and-sneeze&#34;&gt;Cough and sneeze&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;But even if that cough or sneeze was not directed at you, some infected droplets&amp;ndash;the smallest of small&amp;ndash;can hang in the air for a few minutes, filling every corner of a modest sized room with infectious viral particles.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;A single &lt;strong&gt;cough&lt;/strong&gt; releases about 3,000 droplets and droplets travels at 50 miles per hour.&amp;rdquo; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.erinbromage.com/post/the-risks-know-them-avoid-them&#34;&gt;EB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;A single &lt;strong&gt;sneeze&lt;/strong&gt; releases about 30,000 droplets, with droplets traveling at up to 200 miles per hour. Most droplets are small and travel great distances (easily across a room). If a person is infected, the droplets in a single cough or sneeze may contain as many as 200,000,000 (two hundred million) virus particles which can all be dispersed into the environment around them.&amp;rdquo; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.erinbromage.com/post/the-risks-know-them-avoid-them&#34;&gt;EB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;entering-cells&#34;&gt;Entering cells&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Entry of the virus which happens through binding of Spike (S) protein of the virus with ACE2 receptors found in the lungs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
