<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;nAnAsAheb bAlAjI bAji rAv on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/nAnAsAheb_bAlAjI-bAjI-rAv/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;nAnAsAheb bAlAjI bAji rAv on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/nAnAsAheb_bAlAjI-bAjI-rAv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Final-advice to rAghoba</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/nAnAsAheb_bAlAjI-bAjI-rAv/final-advice-to-rAghoba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/nAnAsAheb_bAlAjI-bAjI-rAv/final-advice-to-rAghoba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nana&amp;rsquo;s final advice to Raghoba, after pAnIpaT.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do not abandon the righteous path or ethical conduct. If Marathas or Muslims behave as per the traditions of their caste or community, do not discriminate against them. The Kingdom should not discriminate on the basis of the person&amp;rsquo;s faith or his deity&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hindu Marathe, Musalman yaani aaple aaple reetine vartalyas dvesh sahasa konhe hi jaaticha na karava, va jyacha jo dharm, jyache je daivat tyaaj vishaii dvesh rajya neetis nasava&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ibrahim Khan recruitment</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/nAnAsAheb_bAlAjI-bAjI-rAv/ibrAhim-khAn-recruitment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/nAnAsAheb_bAlAjI-bAjI-rAv/ibrAhim-khAn-recruitment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Via mulamutha&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During this period, Nanasaheb and Sadashiv rao witnessed the impact artillery had on Indian warfare. Since an attempt to recruit Muzaffar Khan Gardi had failed, and the Peshwa was keen to employ a disciple of Bussy into his army, he decided to try and recruit Ibrahim Khan. On 4 November 1757, during the battle, Nanasaheb wrote to Dattaji and asked him to offer Ibrahim Khan a job in the Maratha army. This unpublished letter in Nanasaheb&amp;rsquo;s own hand reached Dattaji Scindia on 14 November 1757.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pAnIpat-bakhar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/nAnAsAheb_bAlAjI-bAjI-rAv/pAnIpat-bakhar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/nAnAsAheb_bAlAjI-bAjI-rAv/pAnIpat-bakhar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;written in 1761 by an eye witness of the entire campaign of the battle of Panipat between Ahmed Shah Abdali and the Marathas. It was written within an year of the battle and begins with the Maratha Peshwa&amp;rsquo;s desire to conquer the earth and ends with the accession of Madhav rao as Peshwa. The battle of Panipat forms the main subject of the document.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hindus Marathas, Moghuls, Pathans, Rajputs, Brahmins, Prabhus, Shenvis - all served the kingdom with their community. Their descendants are being looked after by us. In like manner, they ought to be looked after by you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revenue seepage</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/nAnAsAheb_bAlAjI-bAjI-rAv/revenue-seepage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/nAnAsAheb_bAlAjI-bAjI-rAv/revenue-seepage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: The Extraordinary Epoch of Nanasaheb Peshwa - @mulamutha&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1743, Nanasaheb wrote a letter from the north that is a shining example of Marathi prose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this province, the ancient Hindu kings are proficient in Sanskrit, deplore the company of courtesans and liquor, are wealthy for seven generations, are well versed in the arts, have consorts from their own castes, who are also experts and have won over their senses. They extend courtesies to Gods and Brahmins, they sing as per the shastras, they know some Veda-shastra, they are primarily shorn of desire, and wish prosperity for all, have many disciples, and with discipline and efforts these are learned, although appear un-entertaining. The gardens and flowers and lotuses here, one cannot count. Seeing their bright appearance, one feels one should pray that they come to our own country. However, perceiving our land to be alien to theirs, even after our prayers, they do not agree to come!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sindkhed account</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/nAnAsAheb_bAlAjI-bAjI-rAv/sindkhed-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/nAnAsAheb_bAlAjI-bAjI-rAv/sindkhed-account/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nana Purandare to Balwantrao Mehendale describing the battle of Sindkhed 29 December, 1757 (Gregorian)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Mughal (Nizam) marched out with his vanguard. Baburao Fadnis was the Karbhari, but was unwell. He eventually left as he felt he could not be of use. The same day, the Mughal army was sighted. Our artillery batteries were in position, and we fired 5 to 7 volleys. Along with cannons, we also bombarded them with rockets. Gopalrao Patwardhan was on my right wing. Left wing was Malharrao Raste, and center was Mahipatrao Kavde.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To dattAjI 1759</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/nAnAsAheb_bAlAjI-bAjI-rAv/to_dattAjI_1759/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/nAnAsAheb_bAlAjI-bAjI-rAv/to_dattAjI_1759/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: @mulamutha&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At this very time, when Holkar advised Dattaji to take help from Najib Khan, one finds the Peshwa writing to Dattaji to deal with Najib Khan sternly, urging him to &amp;lsquo;crush him&amp;rsquo; and that helping him is akin to feeding milk to a serpent&amp;rsquo;. Nanasaheb&amp;rsquo;s long letter of 21 March 1759 to Dattaji, shows the way the Peshwa was thinking and his overall Maratha policy in the north.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To dattAjI after assassination</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/nAnAsAheb_bAlAjI-bAjI-rAv/to_dattAjI_after_assassination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/nAnAsAheb_bAlAjI-bAjI-rAv/to_dattAjI_after_assassination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: The Extraordinary Epoch of Nanasaheb Peshwa - @mulamutha&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nanasaheb Peshwa&amp;rsquo;s advice to Dattaji Scindia after Jayappa Scindia was assassinated at Nagaur in his battle with Bijay Singh of Jodhpur in 1755.  Jayappa was supporting Ram Singh&amp;rsquo;s claim to a share of the kingdom. Nanasaheb advised Dattaji to act like a chief rather than a soldier.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Appa had quite unnecessarily taken this up like an unpaid job. He acted like a soldier, not a chief. When he won the first major battle, he should have used that pressure on the enemy to dictate a favourable treaty. Keeping in mind future goals, if this had been resolved, we could have obtained the territory in the doab, won Prayag, Khechiwada and emerged with credit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To paTTavardhana</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/nAnAsAheb_bAlAjI-bAjI-rAv/to_paTTavardhana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/nAnAsAheb_bAlAjI-bAjI-rAv/to_paTTavardhana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: The Extraordinary Epoch of Nanasaheb Peshwa - @mulamutha&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nanasaheb Peshwa&amp;rsquo;s letter to Gopalrao Patwardhan was a private reprimand goading him into action and taking the all-important fort of Daulatabad in 1760. The letter amply reflects his language, style &amp;amp; strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over and over again you write that the places are difficult to capture, that one cannot get involved in prolonged sieges, that one has to obtain one&amp;rsquo;s ends by planning - and therefore you have not attacked. This is indeed unprecedented! I have now entirely understood that only you have the gift of a long-term view. That this is politics, and initially one should be a little soft, one should not cut off supplies - is much appreciated by other clever Extraordinary people, and Bhau.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
