<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 THE AGENCIES OF CHANGE on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2 THE AGENCIES OF CHANGE on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>12 ROADS, ROADS, AND STILL MORE ROADS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/12_ROADS_ROADS_AND_STILL_MORE_ROADS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/12_ROADS_ROADS_AND_STILL_MORE_ROADS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Les routes, les chemins de fer, ces grands moteurs de la civilisation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-IMPERIAL PROSECUTOR, Agen, 1867&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;ROADS, MORE ROADS and always roads,&amp;rdquo; wrote the prefect of Loiret in September 1867, &amp;ldquo;this sums up the political economy of the countryside.&amp;rdquo; Until roads spread, many rural communities remained imprisoned in semi-isolation, limited participants in the economy and politics of the nation: France.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Historical geography is in large part the tale of men struggling against space, and of the efforts made to tame space by creating ever more efficient, more reliable means of communication. In the beginning space is the master; its distances run wild, overwhelming man. Gradually space is conquered, distances are tamed, brought to heel or, rather, increasingly to wheel. Space becomes manageable. This process was still in progress through much of the nineteenth century. Many who lived when the century ended remembered the days when familiar places were farther, vaster, and more daunting too. That was what Eugène Le Roy remarked in 1899: &amp;ldquo;All these lands now are full of roads and highways&amp;hellip; but in the days I speak of [and they were not far off] the forest was a great deal bigger than it is today&amp;hellip; and one could discern only two bad roads that skirted it.&amp;rdquo; Everything is in that passage: the novelty in 1899 of a land crisscrossed by new thoroughfares, the old untamed order of yesterday and its more chilling scale, the paucity of the old roads and their discouraging state.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 KEEPING UP WITH YESTERDAY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/13_KEEPING_UP_WITH_YESTERDAY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/13_KEEPING_UP_WITH_YESTERDAY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before the cherry orchard was sold everybody was worried and upset, but as soon as it was all settled finally and once and for all, everybody calmed down, and felt quite cheerful in fact.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ANTON CHEKOV&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE STORY OF France&amp;rsquo;s entry into the industrial age has generally been told in terms of the numbers of engines moved by steam.* As a practical matter, the spread of roads and railroads would be a sounder indicator, for it was they, particularly the local roads and lines of the late century, that created a truly national market in which the wares that the machines turned out could be sold and bought. More, they were crucial in spreading the relative prosperity that sustained that market. Until this happened, or rather until the effects of a wide-reaching communication network made themselves felt, &amp;ldquo;industry” for most Frenchmen was home and local. Its representative was the artisan. There were more people engaged in artisanal production than in large-scale industry. This was true in the 1860&amp;rsquo;s, when they outnumbered all those engaged in industry, workers, managers, and proprietors alike, by almost three to one. It remained true ten years later, when their number was still double that of industrial workers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 RUS IN URBE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/14_RUS_IN_URBE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/14_RUS_IN_URBE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I shall say nothing just now of the peasantry because they live in a world of their own, with its own uses and traditions, which must be studied separately.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-P. G. HAMERTON&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;IT WASN&amp;rsquo;T THE countryside, there were houses; it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a city, the streets had ruts like turnpikes and the grass grew upon them; it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a village, the houses were too high.&amp;rdquo; Victor Hugo&amp;rsquo;s description of the Faubourg Saint- Marcel, valid for the July Monarchy, could easily apply to many a country town one generation later—and even two! Country and town interpenetrated in small, sleepy centers like Cérilly (Allier), Millau (Aveyron), Brioude and Yssingeaux (Haute-Loire), Florac and Marvejols (Lozère), Saint-Flour (Cantal). Such towns, which acted as &amp;ldquo;tiny capitals” for perhaps half a dozen communes, were sleeping not-quite-beauties periodically awakened when the brief bustle of the weekly market or seasonal fair broke their quiet. Yet it was through these towns that the national culture and the changes it suggested were transmitted to the surrounding countryside. &amp;ldquo;Laboratories,&amp;rdquo; Adolphe Blanqui called them, &amp;ldquo;where the enterprising spirit of the bourgeoisie prepares the experiments from which the country people benefit.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 PEASANTS AND POLITICS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/15_PEASANTS_AND_POLITICS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/15_PEASANTS_AND_POLITICS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ce qui est grave pour ce régime et pour sa gloire, c&amp;rsquo;est qu&amp;rsquo;il risque fort de n&amp;rsquo;être raconté que d&amp;rsquo;après les publications du Journal Officiel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-LOUIS CHEVALIER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE POLITICIZATION of the French peasantry has been variously assigned to the French Revolution and its aftermath or to the feverish days of 1848 and the bustling propaganda of the years that culminated in the rising of December 1851. Maurice Agulhon has written a seminal work showing how the rural and small-town population of up-country Var awoke to national politics, how the politics of the bourgeoisie became the politics of the peasants; and Philippe Vigier has traced similar developments a little to the north, in the Alpine regions. Despite Agulhon&amp;rsquo;s warning that the prehistory of modern democracy in France runs well into the 1860&amp;rsquo;s,1 it is still commonly assumed that, somehow, political tendencies that were suspended during the imperial interlude revived and expressed themselves when they were freed at last after 1871 and 1877. Stabilities in political orientation, which François Goguel and his followers have carefully plotted on maps, as well as evolutions explained by André Siegfried and others, appear to confirm such views.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 MIGRATION: AN INDUSTRY OF THE POOR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/16_MIGRATION_AN_INDUSTRY_OF_THE_POOR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/16_MIGRATION_AN_INDUSTRY_OF_THE_POOR/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Partir c&amp;rsquo;est mourir un peu.-EDMOND HARAUCOURT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IT WAS AN Obscure French writer of the late nineteenth century who said that to go away is to die a little. For many in France, staying put would have been more likely to threaten their lives: leaving home was the price paid for survival. In those parts difficult of access, where roads were scarce and railroads late in coming, the only easy export was men. The poor sought out the richer regions, the mountaineers went down into the plains.* Their earnings supplemented scarce resources, their absence eased the pressure of a population too numerous for the land to feed. Where the pattern of temporary and seasonal migration in the 100 years or so from the late seventeenth century on has been studied, for instance, in Auvergne, we find an expectably close relationship between misery and the search for resources, between the high price of bread and the number of passports delivered in a given year. Similarly, in the Morvan it was the pressure of need, the endless search for a bit of cash to make ends meet, to pay an outstanding debt, to buy a tempting field, to re-roof a house or build one, that drove peasants out as carters, herdsmen, harvesters, thatchers, and domestics, going away from home because that was the only way to keep the home going.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 MIGRATION OF ANOTHER SORT: MILITARY SERVICE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/17_MIGRATION_OF_ANOTHER_SORT_MILITARY_SERVICE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/17_MIGRATION_OF_ANOTHER_SORT_MILITARY_SERVICE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Honneur! Honneur aux conscrios!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Honneur à notro patrio,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Accourons à sa voix chério&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Servir notro payo!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Catineto ploures pos,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Toun galant partira pos.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CONSCRIPT SONGS OF ARIÈGE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SYSTEMATIC CONSCRIPTION in France dates back to 1798. Its general lines for the first four score years were set under the Empire, when Napoleon introduced the draft lottery (tirage au sort) and defined the basis of exemption from service. Every canton of France was responsible for a certain number of recruits. The lots were drawn annually, and the youths with numbers higher than the required contingent were exempt. So were married men, priests, and those who could afford to pay for a substitute to serve in their stead. Once the law was set in motion, there ensued a great many religious vocations, and the rate of marriages among eighteen-year-olds increased considerably. A new job opportunity also appeared: hiring oneself out as substitute for those who could afford to pay the fluctuating price that would save them from hard and dangerous service.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 CIVILIZING IN EARNEST: SCHOOLS AND SCHOOLING</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/18_CIVILIZING_IN_EARNEST_SCHOOLS_AND_SCHOOLING/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/18_CIVILIZING_IN_EARNEST_SCHOOLS_AND_SCHOOLING/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;La République a fondé des écoles,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aussi maint&amp;rsquo;nant le peuple sait compter, L&amp;rsquo;peupl&amp;rsquo; ne veut plus qu&amp;rsquo;on lui donn&amp;rsquo;un obole, Il veut son compt&amp;rsquo; et non la charité.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-MONTÉHUS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE SCHOOL, notably the village school, compulsory and free, has been credited with the ultimate acculturation process that made the French people French-finally civilized them, as many nineteenth-century educators liked to say. The schoolteachers, in their worn, dark suits, appear as the militia of the new age, harbingers of enlightenment and of the Republican message that reconciled the benighted masses with a new world, superior in wellbeing and democracy. Observers have pointed out that there were schools before the 1880&amp;rsquo;s, and have quarreled with implicit assumptions or explicit statements that there was no popular education under the Ancien Régime. But we shall see that the now-classic image of a profound change of pace, tone, and impact under the Third Republic is roughly correct if it is placed in the proper context. The context matters because schools did in fact exist before Jules Ferry, indeed were numerous; and so, to a large extent, did free education. What made the Republic&amp;rsquo;s laws so effective was not just that they required all children to attend school and granted them the right to do so free. It was the attendant circumstances that made adequate facilities and teachers more accessible; that provided roads on which children could get to school; that, above all, made school meaningful and profitable, once what the school offered made sense in terms of altered values and perceptions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 DIEU EST-IL FRANÇAIS?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/19_DIEU_EST-IL_FRANCAIS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/19_DIEU_EST-IL_FRANCAIS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s good and evil, God and the devil. God is good, we pray to him in church, we give him his due, that is religion. But religion does not allow us to ask God for earthly goods-at most, one can pray for everybody. Now, what&amp;rsquo;s good for one isn&amp;rsquo;t good for the others; for if my neighbor&amp;rsquo;s land is struck by hail that&amp;rsquo;s so much less [grain] on his land and my wheat, if I save it, will be worth double. Thus religion is about saving our souls from the eternal fire by observing the prayers and the services of Sundays and feastdays. But religion has nothing to do with our private interests. In the same way, the priest preaches that our happiness is not of this world and that we have been put here to suffer. That&amp;rsquo;s well said, but too much is too much!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 THE PRIESTS AND THE PEOPLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/20_THE_PRIESTS_AND_THE_PEOPLE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/2_AGENCIES_OF_CHANGE/20_THE_PRIESTS_AND_THE_PEOPLE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A corpse was going sadly To its rest under the loam. A priest was going gladly To bury it quick and go home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So SANG LA FONTAINE with his usual feeling for popular realities. We cannot be certain what kind of religion it was that decayed. But we can tell that the declining role of its representatives was fairly wide and welcome. Sympathy for men of the cloth was either lukewarm or downright bitter. The &amp;ldquo;good priest,&amp;rdquo; charitable and kindly, whom we occasionally encounter in nineteenth-century novels, has found no place in popular lore, which provides no proverbs in praise of the clergy, but dozens that criticize its members. If your son is clever, advised one Corrèze proverb, make him a mason; if he is nasty make him a priest.1 Many Basque proverbs make reference to money-grubbing priests; and there is a story that Avarice, having killed a man, sought sanctu-&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
