<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Witzel M on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/witzel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Witzel M on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/witzel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nepal journey</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/witzel/nepal-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/witzel/nepal-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Memories of a Hindu Nepal: Accounts of a Personal Journey. Swadharma.  Harvard’s Hinduism Journal, I, May 2006:18-24&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I arrived in Kathmandu in September 1972, on my first visit to the subcontinent. None of my colleagues were at the airport to collect me - the postcard announcing my intended visit arrived a week later. So I went to the only telephone then available at Gauchar (&amp;ldquo;cow pasture&amp;rdquo;) airport and called my colleagues at the Nepal Research Centre. In the evening, all three of us, members of the Nepal-German Manuscript Preservation Project, went to a Krishna puja in a temple near the old Hanuman Dhoka palace in the center of town and participated in a little bhajan-singing and playing of cymbals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Veda in nepal - 1976</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/witzel/veda_in_nepal_1976/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/articles/witzel/veda_in_nepal_1976/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the History and the Present State of Vedic Tradition in Nepal&#xA;By Dr. Michael Witzel*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;* Dr. Witzel is currently associated with the Nepal-German Manuscript Preservation Project, Department of Archaeology, HMG. VASUDHA (Kathmandu) Vol. XV No. 12, October-November 1976, 17-24, 35-39 17&#xA;[Printing mistakes have been corrected, endnotes set as footnotes, and diacritical mark are added for convenience sake].&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Already the earliest written evidence from the Nepālamaṇḍala, i.e. the inscriptions of the Lichavi kings, show the co-existence of the various sects and forms of both Buddhism and Hinduism. Both forms of Aryan belief were followed by the populace and honoured by the kings .&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Vedic traditions, too, occasionally are mentioned along with Hindu and Buddhist religious practices. The Vedic religion, which preceded both Buddhism and medieval Hinduism, had already in Lichavi time largely been superseded by Pauranic and Tantric elements, yet this oldest form of Aryan worship and learning has come down to the present age and was prominently displayed in some of the rites performed at the coronation ceremony of H.M. the King. It is this tradition which will be traced through Nepalese history in the following pages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
