<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Austro Asiatic on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austro-asiatic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Austro Asiatic on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austro-asiatic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Austro-asiatic influx</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austro-asiatic/orissa-invasion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austro-asiatic/orissa-invasion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not to be confused with Austronesian (a distinct sister language branch).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This was the male-biased Munda influx (likely via sea route into Orissa region) dated to be approximately around 3000 YBP with a lower bound of 3800 YBP.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1107890973311451136&#34;&gt;MT19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;observations&#34;&gt;Observations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;../images/austro-asiatic-asi-pca.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;../images/austro-asiatic-asi-pca.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Southeast Asian component is stronger in the southern cluster of Munda groups than in the northern cluster.&amp;rdquo; &lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;../images/munda-o2a1-m95.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;../images/munda-o2a1-m95.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Austroasiatic languages are a coherent family like IE with populations in India and East Asia like Vietnam, Cambodia, Thailand and Malaysia. In India there are multiple branches in Meghalaya/greater Bengal like Khasic; Munda like Santhal; and Nicobaric of the Nicobar Islands.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Munda populations are Indian populations with a Southeast Asian component that was introduced by a small male Austroasiatic founder population, with no particular connection to Khasi. The indigenous South Asian population was less influenced from ANI populations from the Northwest than all current dominantly ASI populations. The admixture has been dated to either the Neolithic or Chalcolithic in a location that had not yet experienced Indo-Aryan influx.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The genomic data indicates that the core Indian group Munda is primarily acquired their Austroasiatic ancestry from SouthEast Asia perhaps from the same group that also reached the Malaysia. The Indian movement was clearly male-biased. The position of the Indian AA people position in the above PCA overlaps with the Dravidian Gond and the related Asur people of Jharkhand who speak an AA language.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They lie close to one end of the so called Ancestral South Indian cline which includes several other Dravidian speaking tribes like the Paniyan and other tribes of the Tamil country with little west Asian Iranian farmer type ancestry which rises towards the other end of the ASI cline. Of course being at the end of this cline they have hardly any steppe ancestry. Thus, they appear to have emerged from an East Asian center and mixed with the mostly unmixed old Indian hunter-gatherers still represented by the Gond and various Drav-speaking tribe of TN.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Munda Maritime Hypothesis&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://evols.library.manoa.hawaii.edu/handle/10524/52454&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;) seems most plausible. &amp;ldquo;A small Austroasiatic population then brought pre-Proto-Munda by means of a maritime route across the Bay of Bengal to the Mahanadi Delta region – an important hub location for maritime trade in historic and pre-historic times. The interaction with a local South Asian population gave rise to proto-Munda and the Munda branch of Austroasiatic. The Maritime Hypothesis accounts for the linguistic evidence better than other scenarios such as an Indian origin of Austroasiatic or a migration from Southeast Asia through the Brahmaputra basin. The available evidence from archaeology and genetics further supports the hypothesis of a small founder population of Austroasiatic speakers arriving in Odisha from Southeast Asia before the Aryan conquest in the Iron-Age.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The AA incursion is dated to be approximately around 3000 YBP with a lower bound of 3800 YBP. Thus, they are unlikely to have been there before the Aryans in India. This puts a conclusive end to the Para-Munda hypothesis for Harappan and also suggests that the &amp;ldquo;ka-ki-ku&amp;rdquo; substrate in Indo-Aryan is likely from a Harappan language and not Munda or para-Munda. Thus we can now say Munda did not play any role in the formation of the core Indic system in the Northwest. &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>khAsi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austro-asiatic/khAsi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austro-asiatic/khAsi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;influx&#34;&gt;Influx&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;48% of meghAlaya. 85% Christian.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pnar/ jaintia were their royalty.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Munda sarna</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austro-asiatic/munda_sarnaism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austro-asiatic/munda_sarnaism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Y. Philip Barjo: &amp;ldquo;The religious life of the Sarna tribes&amp;rdquo;, Indian Missiological Review, June 1997 twists this religion into some monotheism - &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Sarna spirituality is marked by a strong belief in one God.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;gods-pitrs-and-asuras&#34;&gt;Gods, pitRs and asuras&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Singbonga&lt;/strong&gt; = sun God. In character, Singbonga seems to have more in common with the charitable God of the New Testament than with the vindictive one of the Old. Though Singbonga is the Great God of His Munda people, He is not a jealous. Though all-pervading and benevolent, Singbonga is also an ethnocentric God, like Jahweh.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Singbonga, unlike spirits, is worshipped for his own sake. His purity demands that he be offered sacrifices only of things that are white. Hence he is given sacrifices of white goats, white fowls, white gulainchi flowers, white cloth, sugar, milk, etc.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Besides Singbonga, the Munda pantheon includes a number of other deities and spirits whom they call &lt;strong&gt;Bongas&lt;/strong&gt;. (&amp;hellip;) There are both benevolent spirits (&lt;strong&gt;Manitabongas&lt;/strong&gt;) and malevolent spirits (&lt;strong&gt;Banitabongas&lt;/strong&gt;). (&amp;hellip;) Accordingly the benevolent spirits are worshipped and the malevolent spirits are only appeased or propitiated.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Besides the Singbonga the Mundas generally worship a host of other spirits including their own ancestors. &amp;hellip; Cult or worship is mostly directed to the spirits and the ancestors.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The first in order of dignity comes the &lt;strong&gt;Burubonga&lt;/strong&gt;, Marang Buru or Pat Sarna. This spirit is a mountain-god or the highest hill or rock in the neighbourhood. He is represented by no visible object.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Next in order come the &lt;strong&gt;Hatu Bongako&lt;/strong&gt; or the Village spirits. (&amp;hellip;) They are worshipped by the Pahan on behalf of the whole village at specific times in the sacred grove or the Sarna of each village.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The third group of spirits in the Munda pantheon are the &lt;strong&gt;Ora Bongako&lt;/strong&gt; or the House-spirits. These are the spirits of the deceased ancestors of each family. They are worshipped in the house-sanctuary called Ading, by the head of every family. Sometimes they are referred to as Haparomko (the ancestral spirits). Ancestor worship finds an important place in the religious belief of the Mundas. They believe that after the death of a person his spirit/shade (roa/umbul) has no house to live in. As an outcast it roams about in the neighborhood of the grave. After an odd number of days, the Umbul-ader (homebringing of the shade) ceremony is performed by which the &amp;lsquo;shade&amp;rsquo; of the deceased is brought into the ading of the house and enshrined there. Henceforth the man&amp;rsquo;s spirit is called no longer umbul but Ora Bonga (House Spirit). This important ceremony is a way of re-introducing the deceased member into the tribe. It is believed that they in turn are the real benefactors of the family or the tribe to which they belong.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Asurs were like the bad angels who revolted against God. They were greedy iron smelters, who even after repeated warning from Singbonga kept on smelting day and night. Because of their disobedience Singbonga destroyed all the male members of the tribe.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom&#34;&gt;Custom&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Sarna people do not have a written code of moral law. Their idea of right and wrong comes from their tradition. Tradition is their measure of truth. Their way to salvation is the tribe. &amp;hellip; These include exogamy [between families], endogamy [within the tribe], and monogamy in marriage and conjugal fidelity. &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;karma-vipaka&#34;&gt;karma-vipAka&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The punishment is not carried over to the life beyond the grave.&amp;rdquo; They believe in reincarnation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
