<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;hindu christian encounters on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;hindu christian encounters on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Preface to the Second Edition</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/01_pre1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/01_pre1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preface to the Second Edition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first edition of this book, published in 1986, had 16 chapters and an appendix. This second edition has 25 chapters. The appendix - Encounter at Pondicherry - has been fitted in the chronology of encounters and forms Chapter 7 of the new edition. Chapter 14 of the old edition has been split into two chapters, 15 and 16, separating the debate on the Fundamental Right to Propagate Religion from the debate in the Constituent Assembly. Similarly, Chapter 16 of the old edition has been split into three chapters - 18, 19 and 20 - separating the three subjects dealt with. Chapter 19 which formed Section II of Chapter 16 in the old edition has been expanded by incorporation of a dialogue between Ram Swarup and Bede Griffiths. Five chapters, 21 to 25, are entirely new and cover Hindu-Christian encounters that have come to my knowledge since the first edition was compiled.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Preface to the First Edition</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/02_pre2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/02_pre2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preface to the First Edition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christian historians, in India and abroad, have written many accounts of how Christian theologians, missionaries and warlords have looked at Hinduism&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in different phases of Christian aggression against this ancient religion and culture. But there is no connected account of how Hindu thinkers, saints and sages have viewed Christianity and its exclusive claims. The present study is an attempt to fill that gap. It is far from being exhaustive. it seeks to cover only some of the high spots in a prolonged encounter starting with the Christian attack on Hindu temples in the Roman Empire, a few years before Constantine enthroned Christianity as the state religion of Rome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 1 Encounter on the Euphrates</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/03_Ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/03_Ch1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Encounter on the Euphrates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christian historians will have us believe that Hinduism first came in contact with Christianity in AD 52 when St. Thomas, an apostle of Jesus Christ, landed in Malabar. He is supposed to have travelled in South India and founded seven churches before he was. “murdered” by the “malicious” Brahmanas. The old Christians in Kerala, who knew as well as introduced themselves as Syrian Christians till the other day, now take pride in calling themselves St. Thomas Christians. We have examined this story elsewhere&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; as also the motives for floating it. Here it should suffice to say that the more scrupulous Christian historians have found the story too fanciful to be taken seriously.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 2 Encounter in Malabar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/04_Ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/04_Ch2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Encounter in Malabar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is not known whether the news of the Christian onslaught on Hinduism in the Roman Empire reached India. One wonders whether the merchants and monks who survived and returned home grasped the import of what was happening. If they gave to their countrymen an account of what they had witnessed in a distant land, the record has not survived or is not yet known. Nor do we know how the Hindus at home reacted, if at all. What we do know, however, is that Hinduism in India had not heard of Christianity when the two had their second encounter, this time inside the homeland of Hinduism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 3 Hallucinations of the Devil’s Devotees</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/05_Ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/05_Ch3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Hallucinations of the Devil’s Devotees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a long time, the Syrian Christians provided the only contact which Hinduism had with Christianity. India lost touch with the Christian West for well-nigh seven centuries because Islamic empires in the Middle East and Central Asia, had raised a barrier between the two. Christians and Muslims were involved in mortal combat soon after the death of prophet Muhammad in AD 632. Christian travellers ran the risk of death if they tried to come east through Muslim dominated routes on land and sea. Hindu merchants, too, lost the incentive for going to Europe. Muslim merchants had monopolised all trade between the East and the West. Hindu sages and savants could hardly think of going abroad; they were having a very difficult time at home where Islam was heaping humiliations on them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 4 Pirates in Priest’s Clothing</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/06_Ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/06_Ch4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Pirates in Priest’s Clothing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next encounter between Hinduism and Christianity commenced with the coming of Christian missionaries to Malabar after Vasco da Gama found his way to Calicut in AD 1498. It took a serious turn in AD 1542 when Francis Xavier, a rapacious pirate dressed up as a priest, arrived on the scene. The proceedings have been preserved by the Christian participants. They make the most painful reading in the history of Christianity in India. Francis Xavier had come with the firm resolve of “uprooting paganism” from the soil of India and planting Christianity in its place. His sayings and doings have been documented in his numerous biographies and cited by every historian of the Portuguese episode in the history of India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 5 From Monologue to Dialogue</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/07_Ch5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/07_Ch5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;From Monologue to Dialogue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is no known evidence of a dialogue between Hinduism and Christianity before the end of the seventeenth century, though by that time they had come into contact with one another on as many as four occasions. If individual Hindus and Christians ever exchanged any notes on the nature of God and soul and human destiny, the record was not kept or has not survived or is yet to surface.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 6 Encounter in Tamil Nadu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/08_Ch6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/08_Ch6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Encounter in Tamil Nadu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ziegenbalg who was “the most aggressive evangelist of this period”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; came from the Lutheran seminary at Halle in Germany.&#xA;Ostensibly, the Lutheran mission to Tranquebar was patronised by Frederick IV, King of Denmark.  But its real sponsor was the British Government who financed it through the Society for the Propagation of Christian Knowledge (SPCK), floated in 1798.  This is obvious from &lt;em&gt;The Epistle Dedicatory&lt;/em&gt; which J. Thomas Philipps attached to his English translation of Ziegenbalg’s &lt;em&gt;Conferences&lt;/em&gt; with Brahmanas.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Epistle&lt;/em&gt; is addressed to the King of England.  “The following&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Conferences&lt;/em&gt;,” wrote Philipps, “being an essay to recommend to the&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Heathens&lt;/em&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;East Indies&lt;/em&gt; that faith, of which Your Majesty is the&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Glorious Defender&lt;/em&gt;, I have humbly presumed to lay them at your Royal&#xA;Feet, as a pledge of the indefatigable labours of the &lt;em&gt;Protestant Missionaries&lt;/em&gt; sent thither by the King of Denmark.  One of the&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Missionaries&lt;/em&gt; had the honour to be graciously received by Your Majesty&#xA;here in &lt;em&gt;London&lt;/em&gt; on his return to India.  They have already acknowledged the charitable assistances they have received from Your Majesty’s subjects both in &lt;em&gt;Europe&lt;/em&gt; and in the &lt;em&gt;East Indies&lt;/em&gt;.” The British invaders of India did not want to be known as patrons of Christianity till a more opportune time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 7 Encounter at Pondicherry</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/09_Ch7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/09_Ch7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Encounter at Pondicherry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following account of what the Christians did to Hindus in Pondicherry has been taken from the Diary maintained by Anand Ranga Pillai, scion of a Tamil merchant family from Madras.  His family along with several others had migrated to Pondicherry at the invitation of the French who occupied that town as the headquarters of their possessions in India.  These families had brought considerable prosperity to it.&#xA;Pillai was appointed Chief Dubash towards the end of 1747, five years after M. Dupleix became the Governor of Pondicherry.  He held the post till 1756, two years after Dupleix’s departure.  He had, however, kept an account of what he saw and heard since September 1736.  His Diary which was written in Tamil continued till 1761 when he died.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 8 Encounter with Raja Ram Mohun Roy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/10_Ch8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/10_Ch8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Encounter with Raja Ram Mohun Roy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next significant dialogue between Hinduism and Christianity commenced more than a hundred years later, in 1820 to be exact.  The venue was Calcutta.  Raja Ram Mohun Roy was ranged on one side and the Serampore Missionaries on the other.  By that time, British arms had subdued the whole of India except Ranjit Singh’s Sikh state beyond the Satlaj.  Calcutta had emerged not only as the premier city of the British empire in India but also as the storm centre of Christianity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 9 Encounter in Maharashtra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/11_Ch9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/11_Ch9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Encounter in Maharashtra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another dialogue between Hinduism and Christianity was held soon after the one in Calcutta.  This time the venue was Bombay, the second most important city founded by the British and another storm centre of missionary activity against Hinduism.  John Wilson, after whom the Wilson College in Bombay is named, was an important Presbyterian missionary from Scotland.  He “debated for six successive evenings with a pandit named Morabhatta Dandekara” in February, 1831.  “John Wilson’s knowledge of Hindu literature,” we are told, “was first-rate, but he did not hesitate to subject what he read to withering ridicule from his perspective as a Christian.  Inconsistencies in the Puranas were among his special targets.” He held debates with Zoroastrians and Muslims also.  But “Hindus proved to be his dogged opponents.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 10 Encounter with Sariskrit Pandits</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/12_Ch10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/12_Ch10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Encounter with Sariskrit Pandits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yet another dialogue between Hinduism and Christianity was held from 1839 to 1845.  It is particularly interesting because it took place through the medium of Sanskrit.  John Muir (1810-1882) published the first draft of his &lt;em&gt;MataparikshA&lt;/em&gt; in 1839 and the final in 1840.  It drew three rejoinders from Hindu Pandits.  SomanAtha, whose real name was Subaji Bapu, published his &lt;em&gt;MatataparIkshAsikshA&lt;/em&gt; in 1839.&#xA;Harachandra &lt;em&gt;TarkapañchAnana&lt;/em&gt; came out with his &lt;em&gt;MataparIkshottara&lt;/em&gt; in 1840.  NIlakaNTha Goreh reacted somewhat late and published his&#xA;&lt;em&gt;ShAstratattvavinirNaya&lt;/em&gt; at the end of 1844.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 11 Encounter with Maharshi Dayananda</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/13_Ch11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/13_Ch11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Encounter with Maharshi Dayananda&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Compared to the intervals between the encounters narrated so far, the next encounter between Hinduism and Christianity took a much longer time in coming.  John Muir had published the third and final edition of his&#xA;&lt;em&gt;MataparIkshA&lt;/em&gt; in 1854.  Before Hindu Pandits could take notice of any&#xA;new points raised in it, the Great Rebellion broke out in 1857.&#xA;Christianity was no longer a subject of public debate.  It became one of the issues in the war that ensued.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 12 Second Encounter in Tamil Nadu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/14_Ch12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/14_Ch12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Second Encounter in Tamil Nadu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While a heated dialogue between Hinduism and Christianity was going on in the North, with Maharshi Dayananda in the forefront, another dialogue was taking shape in South India.  Its centre was in the Cauvery Delta, particularly the District of Tiruchirapally, which had witnessed the first Hindu-Christian dialogue nearly 175 years earlier.  This stronghold of Hindu learning had invited concentrated missionary attention since the days of the Portuguese pirates.  One foreign mission after another had descended on the scene and mounted assaults on Hinduism in various forms.  The flow of Christian finance and manpower from abroad was unceasing and in ever-increasing quantities, as it remains today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 13 Encounter with Swami Vivekananda</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/15_Ch13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/15_Ch13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Encounter with Swami Vivekananda&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The spokesman for Hinduism in the next dialogue between Hinduism and Christianity was Swami Vivekananda (1863-1902).  A significant feature of this dialogue was that, for the most part, it was held in the homelands of Christianity.  Vivekananda not only carried the message of Hinduism to the USA and Europe during his two trips from 1893 to 1897 and from 1899 to 1900, he also turned the tide against Christianity in India so far as educated, upper class Hindus were concerned.&#xA;Henceforward, Christian missionaries would reap a harvest either in the tribal belts or during famines when charitable organisations abroad and a patronising government at home placed funds for relief at their disposal and Hindu orphans fell into their hands in large numbers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 14 Encounter with Mahatma Gandhi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/16_Ch14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/16_Ch14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Encounter with Mahatma Gandhi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next dialogue between Hinduism and Christianity was the longest in duration and the richest in content. The spokesman for Hinduism was Mahatma Gandhi. Christianity was represented by many men and women from India and abroad. Some of them occupied high positions in the worldwide Christian mission.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The dialogue started in 1893 when Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi reached South Africa as a barrister and discovered that the Christians who befriended him were looking forward to his conversion. It ended on December 24, 1947 when Mahatma Gandhi, the father figure in independent India, offered Christmas greetings to Christians in India and abroad, wishing them well and hoping that they “will pursue the path of sacrifice and martyrdom shown by Jesus Christ.” At the same time he asked his Christian countrymen to shed fears about their future in independent India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 15 The Hoax of Human Rights</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/17_Ch15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/17_Ch15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;The Hoax of Human Rights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next encounter between Hinduism and Christianity took place in the Constituent Assembly which started framing independent India’s Constitution in 1947 and completed the work by the end of 1949. The dialogue centred round what the Christian participants proclaimed as the their fundamental human right, namely, to propagate their religion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Christians were quite clear in their mind as well as pronouncements that the “right to propagate” religion entitled them to 1) receive massive financial help from foreign sources; 2) maintain and multiply churches and missions; 3) train and mobilize an ever expanding army of missionaries, native and foreign; 4) enlarge the mission infrastructure of seminaries, social service institutions and mass media; and 5) convert an increasing number of Hindus to Christianity by every means including fraud and material inducements. They had been holding meetings and passing resolutions on all these points even before the Constituent Assembly was mentioned in the negotiations between the Congress leaders and the British Cabinet Mission.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 16 Debate in the Constituent Assembly</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/18_Ch16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/18_Ch16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Debate in the Constituent Assembly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On April 29, 1947, Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel presented to the Constituent Assembly the interim report on Fundamental Rights as submitted by the Advisory Committee. Clause 13 and 17 among the ‘Rights relating to religion’ generated a debate which took place on May I. It was started by Shri K. M. Munshi who moved an amendment for rewording Clause 17 to read as follows: “Any conversion from one religion to another of any person brought about by fraud, coercion or undue influence or of a minor under the age of 18 shall not be recognised by law.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Explaining the amendment with regard to “conversion of a minor”, Shri Munshi said, “As a matter of fact, it was proposed by one or the other Committee in some form or other, and it is the general feeling that this clause should be restored in this form, - any conversion of a minor under the age of 18 shall not be recognised by law. The only effect of non-recognition by law would mean that even though a person is converted by fraud or coercion or undue influence or be converted during his minority he will still in law be deemed to continue to belong to the old religion and his legal rights will remain unaffected by reason of his conversion. The idea behind this proposal is that very often, if there are conversions by fraud or undue influence or during minority, certain changes in the legal status take place, certain rights are lost. This will have only this effect that the rights will remain exactly the same as at the moment a person was converted by fraud or coercion or undue influence and in the case of a minor at the moment of conversion.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 17 Missions Since Independence</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/19_Ch17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/19_Ch17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Missions Since Independence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Constitution of independent India adopted in January 1950 made things quite smooth for the Christian missions.  They surged forward with renewed vigour.  Nationalist resistance to what had been viewed as an imperialist incubus during the Struggle for Freedom, broke down when the very leaders who had frowned upon it started speaking in its favour.  Voices which still remained ‘recalcitrant’ were sought to be silenced by being branded as those of ‘Hindu communalism’.  Nehruvian Secularism had stolen a march under the cover of Mahatma Gandhi’s&#xA;&lt;em&gt;sarva-dharma-sambhAva&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 18 Dethroning Monotheism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/20_Ch18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/20_Ch18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Dethroning Monotheism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another dialogue between Hinduism and Christianity commenced with the publication of Shri Ram Swarup’s magnum opus, &lt;em&gt;The Word As Revelation: Names of Gods&lt;/em&gt;, in September 1980. It is still continuing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The dialogue which Raja Ram Mohun Roy had started in the third decade of the nineteenth century stopped abruptly with the passing away of Mahatma Gandhi in January 1948. The Hindu leadership or what passed for it in post-independence India was neither equipped for nor interested in the battle for men’s minds. It believed in ‘organising’ the Hindus without bothering about what they carried inside their heads. It neither knew nor cared to know what Hinduism stood for. Its history of India began with the advent of the Islamic invaders. The spiritual traditions, ways of worship, scriptures and thought systems of pre-Islamic India were beyond its mental horizon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 19 Sannyasins or Swindlers?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/21_Ch19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/21_Ch19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Sannyasins or Swindlers?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hinduism Today&lt;/em&gt;, a bimonthly&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; published by the Saiva Siddhanta&#xA;Church with headquarters in Hawaii, U.S.A., carried an article, ‘Catholic Ashrams: Adopting and Adapting Hindu Dharma’, in its issue of November-December, 1986. It noticed particularly the Saccidananda Ashram at Shantivanam in the Tiruchirapally District of Tamil Nadu. “The Shantivanam Ashram,” it said, “looks like a rishi’s home transported from Vedic times to the bank of sacred Cauvery River… A pilgrim’s first impressions are strong, and very Hindu; the elaborately colorful Hindu shrine; the bearded, saffron-robed ‘swami’ seated cross-legged on a straw mat; devotees practising yogic meditation, even chanting Hindu scriptures. But these impressions gradually prove false. First, the eye detects that the courtyard shrine is for Saint Paul and that ‘puja’ is actually a daily mass, complete with incense, arati, lamps, flower offerings and prasadam. Finally, one meets the ‘swami’, learning he is Father Bede ‘Dayananda’ Griffiths, a Christian ‘sannyasin’ of impeccable British background.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 20 A Hornet’s Nest</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/22_Ch20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/22_Ch20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;A Hornet’s Nest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One wonders whether it is a virtue or vice, but the Christian missionaries have been and remain compulsive record-keepers and plan-publishers. By now there are literally hundreds of thousands of publications providing details of what the Christian missions did or plan to do, where, to whom, in which manner and with what resources in money and manpower. “Each year,” says a recent publication on the subject, “some 10,000 new books and articles on mission and evangelization are published, involving seventy or so major languages.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Besides, we have well-researched and thoroughly documented studies produced mostly by Western scholars, many of them believing Christians, on the spread of Christianity in the past. The story is blood-soaked. In America, Asia and Africa, Christianity has been an unashamed and active accomplice of Western imperialism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 21 Exploding a Mischievous Myth</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/23_Ch21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/23_Ch21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Exploding a Mischievous Myth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The history of Christianity, crowded as it is with crimes of the most horrendous kind, provides a running commentary on the Christian doctrine. And the biggest share in Christian crimes down the centuries can safely be alloted to the Roman Catholic Church, its head, its hierarchy, its theologians, its religious orders, and its missionaries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is, however, one criminal field in which the Roman Catholic Church has remained unrivalled. No other Christian denomination - these are as many as 23,000 of them comes anywhere near the Roman Catholic Church when it concerns committing of blatant forgeries and foisting of pious frauds. It is no exaggeration to say that starting with Jesus Christ, the entire doctrinal and institutional edifice of Catholicism rests on a series of staggering swindles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 22 Plea for Rejecting Jesus as junk</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/24_Ch22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/24_Ch22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Plea for Rejecting Jesus as junk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jesus Christ has been the stock-in-trade of Christian missions down the ages. He has been packed in all shapes and sizes depending upon the gullibility of the clients to be duped. And he has been rammed down the throats of those who have refused to be hoodwinked by the hoax. As one surveys the history of Christian missions in lands where this hoax has been hawked or imposed, one comes across no end of force and fraud employed in its service by a variety of soldiers and salesmen most of whom are presented as saints. It can be said without exaggeration that if one is in search of a hardened criminal with a clean conscience, one should reach out for the first available Christian saint and one will not miss the mark. St. Francis Xavier, the Paron Saint of the East according to the Roman Catholic Church, provides an excellent example.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 23 Encounter with Arun Shourie</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/25_Ch23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/25_Ch23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Encounter with Arun Shourie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Missiology is a meticulous discipline developed quite early in the history of Christianity as auxiliary to an exclusivist and aggressive doctrine - Jesus Christ is the only saviour; there is no salvation outside the Church; and infidels should be compelled to come in. By now the discipline has become rather rich with experience gained over several centuries and in all parts of the world. Many universities in Europe and the Americas teach Missiology in their faculties of Catholic and Protestant theologies. And there are a large number of Christian seminaries spread over many countries where Missiology is studied in great depth and detail by the soldiers of Christ before they commence their prowl in search of prey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 24 Fixing a Christian Windbag</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/26_Ch24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/26_Ch24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Fixing a Christian Windbag&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The United States of America is a land of sharp contradictions when it comes to matters of faith. On the one hand, it is the land of Thomas Jefferson, Tom Paine, James Madison and Mark Twain who distrusted or denounced or ridiculed the Christian dogma and scripture in unmistakable words. On the other hand, it is the land of the most fanatical and fundamentalist Christian sects each one of which will have not only the USA but the whole world exclusively for itself. On the one hand, it is a land where the spiritual vision of Hinduism and Buddhism finds ready audience, and flourishes. On the other hand, it is a land where blind belief systems like Christianity and Islam whine and whimper, and brainwash any number of victims. The key to understanding the scene lies in the history of this land.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 25 Calling the Pope’s Bluff</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/27_Ch25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/27_Ch25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Calling the Pope’s Bluff&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Papacy started as a crimes cartel which it has remained throughout its long career. But the collapse of Christianity in the West and the retreat of Western imperialism has forced it to change its methods, and function more and more like a multinational corporation. Buyers for its stale and discredited merchandise -Jesus Christ, the only son of the only God and the only saviour from eternal perdition - are becoming increasingly scarce, and it is no more in a position to thrust the garbage down people’s throats. Earlier, the pope spoke and the others had to listen. Now the pope is, prepared to answer question. He is, however, not yet ready nor equipped to go beyond his copybook.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 Bibliography</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/28_bib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_christian_encounters/28_bib/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bibliography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Arun Shourie and his Christian Critic&lt;/em&gt;, Voice of India, New Delhi,&#xA;1995.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bates, M. Searle, &lt;em&gt;Religious Liberty: An Enquiry&lt;/em&gt;, New York 1945.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Barrett David B. et al, &lt;em&gt;Seven Hundred Plans to Evangelize the World&lt;/em&gt;, Birmingham, Alabama, U.S.A. 1988.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Buchanan, Claudius, &lt;em&gt;Memoirs&lt;/em&gt;, London, 1805.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Burke, Marie Louis, &lt;em&gt;Swami Vivekananda in America&lt;/em&gt;, Calcutta, 1958.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chuvin, Pierre, &lt;em&gt;A Chronicle of the Last Pagans&lt;/em&gt;, Cambridge, Mass, USA, 1990.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Constituent Assembly Debates&lt;/em&gt;, Volumes III, V and VII, New Delhi&#xA;1947-49.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
