<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;lectures and discourses on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;lectures and discourses on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>030 SOUL, GOD AND RELIGION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/030_soul_god_and_religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/030_soul_god_and_religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;soul-god-and-religion&#34;&gt;SOUL, GOD AND RELIGION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Through the vistas of the past the voice of the centuries is coming down&#xA;to us; the voice of the sages of the Himalayas and the recluses of the&#xA;forest; the voice that came to the Semitic races; the voice that spoke&#xA;through Buddha and other spiritual giants; the voice that comes from&#xA;those who live in the light that accompanied man in the beginning of the&#xA;earth — the light that shines wherever man goes and lives with him for&#xA;ever — is coming to us even now. This voice is like the little rivulets;&#xA;that come from the mountains. Now they disappear, and now they appear&#xA;again in stronger flow till finally they unite in one mighty majestic&#xA;flood. The messages that are coming down to us from the prophets and&#xA;holy men and women of all sects and nations are joining their forces and&#xA;speaking to us with the trumpet voice of the past. And the first message&#xA;it brings us is: Peace be unto you and to all religions. It is not a&#xA;message of antagonism, but of one united religion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>031 THE HINDU RELIGION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/031_the_hindu_religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/031_the_hindu_religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-hindu-religion&#34;&gt;THE HINDU RELIGION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My religion is to learn. I read my Bible better in the light of your&#xA;Bible and the dark prophecies of my religion become brighter when&#xA;compared with those of your prophets. Truth has always been universal.&#xA;If I alone were to have six fingers on my hand while all of you had only&#xA;five, you would not think that my hand was the true intent of nature,&#xA;but rather that it was abnormal and diseased. Just so with religion. If&#xA;one creed alone were to be true and all the others untrue, you would&#xA;have a right to say that that religion was diseased; if one religion is&#xA;true, all the others must be true. Thus the Hindu religion is your&#xA;property as well as mine. Of the two hundred and ninety millions of&#xA;people inhabiting India, only two millions are Christians, sixty&#xA;millions Mohammedans and all the rest are Hindus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>032 WHAT IS RELIGION?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/032_what_is_religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/032_what_is_religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-religion&#34;&gt;WHAT IS RELIGION?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A huge locomotive has rushed on over the line and a small worm that was&#xA;creeping upon one of the rails saved its life by crawling out of the&#xA;path of the locomotive. Yet this little worm, so insignificant that it&#xA;can be crushed in a moment, is a living something, while this&#xA;locomotive, so huge, so immense, is only an engine, a machine. You say&#xA;the one has life and the other is only dead matter and all its powers&#xA;and strength and speed are only those of a dead machine, a mechanical&#xA;contrivance. Yet the poor little worm which moved upon the rail and&#xA;which the least touch of the engine would have deprived of its life is a&#xA;majestic being compared to that huge locomotive. It is a small part of&#xA;the Infinite and, therefore, it is greater than this powerful engine.&#xA;Why should that be so? How do we know the living from the dead? The&#xA;machine mechanically performs all the movements its maker made it to&#xA;perform, its movements are not those of life. How can we make the&#xA;distinction between the living and the dead, then? In the living there&#xA;is freedom, there is intelligence; in the dead all is bound and no&#xA;freedom is possible, because there is no intelligence. This freedom that&#xA;distinguishes us from mere machines is what we are all striving for. To&#xA;be more free is the goal of all our efforts, for only in perfect freedom&#xA;can there be perfection. This effort to attain freedom underlies all&#xA;forms of worship, whether we know it or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>033 VEDIC RELIGIOUS IDEALS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/033_vedic_religious_ideals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/033_vedic_religious_ideals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vedic-religious-ideals&#34;&gt;VEDIC RELIGIOUS IDEALS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What concerns us most is the religious thought — on soul and God and all&#xA;that appertains to religion. We will take the Samhitās. These are&#xA;collections of hymns forming, as it were, the oldest Aryan literature,&#xA;properly speaking, the oldest literature in the world. There may have&#xA;been some scraps of literature of older date here and there, older than&#xA;that even, but not books, or literature properly so called. As a&#xA;collected book, this is the oldest the world has, and herein is&#xA;portrayed the earliest feeling of the Aryans, their aspirations, the&#xA;questions that arose about their manners and methods, and so on. At the&#xA;very outset we find a very curious idea. These hymns are sung in praise&#xA;of different gods, Devas as they are called, the bright ones. There is&#xA;quite a number of them. One is called Indra, another Varuna, another&#xA;Mitra, Parjanya, and so on. Various mythological and allegorical figures&#xA;come before us one after the other — for instance, Indra the thunderer,&#xA;striking the serpent who has withheld the rains from mankind. Then he&#xA;lets fly his thunderbolt, the serpent is killed, and rain comes down in&#xA;showers. The people are pleased, and they worship Indra with oblations.&#xA;They make a sacrificial pyre, kill some animals, roast their flesh upon&#xA;spits, and offer that meat to Indra. And they had a popular plant called&#xA;Soma. What plant it was nobody knows now; it has entirely disappeared,&#xA;but from the books we gather that, when crushed, it produced a sort of&#xA;milky juice, and that was fermented; and it can also be gathered that&#xA;this fermented Soma juice was intoxicating. This also they offered to&#xA;Indra and the other gods, and they also drank it themselves. Sometimes&#xA;they drank a little too much, and so did the gods. Indra on occasions&#xA;got drunk. There are passages to show that Indra at one time drank so&#xA;much of this Soma juice that he talked irrelevant words. So with Varuna.&#xA;He is another god, very powerful, and is in the same way protecting his&#xA;votaries, and they are praising him with their libations of Soma. So is&#xA;the god of war, and so on. But the popular idea that strikes one as&#xA;making the mythologies of the Samhitas entirely different from the other&#xA;mythologies is, that along with every one of these gods is the idea of&#xA;an infinity. This infinite is abstracted, and sometimes described as&#xA;Âditya. At other times it is affixed, as it were, to all the other gods.&#xA;Take, for example, Indra. In some of the books you will find that Indra&#xA;has a body, is very strong, sometimes is wearing golden armour, and&#xA;comes down, lives and eats with his votaries, fights the demons, fights&#xA;the snakes, and so on. Again, in one hymn we find that Indra has been&#xA;given a very high position; he is omnipresent and omnipotent, and Indra&#xA;sees the heart of every being. So with Varuna. This Varuna is god of the&#xA;air and is in charge of the water, just as Indra was previously; and&#xA;then, all of a sudden, we find him raised up and said to be omnipresent,&#xA;omnipotent, and so on. I will read one passage about this Varuna in his&#xA;highest form, and you will understand what I mean. It has been&#xA;translated into English poetry, so it is better that I read it in that&#xA;form.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>034 THE VEDANTA PHILOSOPHY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/034_the_vedanta_philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/034_the_vedanta_philosophy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-vedanta-philosophy&#34;&gt;THE VEDANTA PHILOSOPHY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Vedanta philosophy, as it is generally called at the present day,&#xA;really comprises all the various sects that now exist in India. Thus&#xA;there have been various interpretations, and to my mind they have been&#xA;progressive, beginning with the dualistic or Dvaita and ending with the&#xA;non-dualistic or Advaita. The word Vedanta literally means the end of&#xA;the Vedas — the Vedas being the scriptures of the Hindus.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;Sometimes in the West by the Vedas are meant only the hymns and rituals&#xA;of the Vedas. But at the present time these parts have almost gone out&#xA;of use, and usually by the word Vedas in India, the Vedanta is meant.&#xA;All our commentators, when they want to quote a passage from the&#xA;scriptures, as a rule, quote from the Vedanta, which has another&#xA;technical name with the commentators — the Shrutis. (The term Shruti —&#xA;meaning &amp;ldquo;that which is heard&amp;rdquo; — though including the whole of the Vedic&#xA;literature, is chiefly applied by the commentators to the Upanishads.)&#xA;Now, all the books known by the name of the Vedanta were not entirely&#xA;written after the ritualistic portions of the Vedas. For instance, one&#xA;of them — the Ishā Upanishad — forms the fortieth chapter of the&#xA;Yajur-Veda, that being one of the oldest parts of the Vedas. There are&#xA;other Upanishads&lt;a href=&#34;#fn2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; which form portions of the Brahmanas or&#xA;ritualistic writings; and the rest of the Upanishads are independent,&#xA;not comprised in any of the Brahmanas or other parts of the Vedas; but&#xA;there is no reason to suppose that they were entirely independent of&#xA;other parts, for, as we well know, many of these have been lost entirely&#xA;and many of the Brahmanas have become extinct. So it is quite possible&#xA;that the independent Upanishads belonged to some Brahmanas, which in&#xA;course of time fell into disuse, while the Upanishads remained. These&#xA;Upanishads are also called Forest Books or Aranyakas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>035 REASON AND RELIGION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/035_reason_and_religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/035_reason_and_religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reason-and-religion&#34;&gt;REASON AND RELIGION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in England&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A sage called Nārada went to another sage named Sanatkumāra to learn&#xA;about truth, and Sanatkumara inquired what he had studied already.&#xA;Narada answered that he had studied the Vedas, Astronomy, and various&#xA;other things, yet he had got no satisfaction. Then there was a&#xA;conversation between the two, in the course of which Sanatkumara&#xA;remarked that all this knowledge of the Vedas, of Astronomy, and of&#xA;Philosophy, was but secondary; sciences were but secondary. That which&#xA;made us realise the Brahman was the supreme, the highest knowledge. This&#xA;idea we find in every religion, and that is why religion always claimed&#xA;to be supreme knowledge. Knowledge of the sciences covers, as it were,&#xA;only part of our lives, but the knowledge which religion brings to us is&#xA;eternal, as infinite as the truth it preaches. Claiming this&#xA;superiority, religions have many times looked down, unfortunately, on&#xA;all secular knowledge, and not only so, but many times have refused to&#xA;be justified by the aid of secular knowledge. In consequence, all the&#xA;world over there have been fights between secular knowledge and&#xA;religious knowledge, the one claiming infallible authority as its guide,&#xA;refusing to listen to anything that secular knowledge has to say on the&#xA;point, the other, with its shining instrument of reason, wanting to cut&#xA;to pieces everything religion could bring forward. This fight has been&#xA;and is still waged in every country. Religions have been again and again&#xA;defeated, and almost exterminated. The worship of the goddess of Reason&#xA;during the French Revolution was not the first manifestation of that&#xA;phenomenon in the history of humanity, it was a re-enactment of what had&#xA;happened in ancient times, but in modern times it has assumed greater&#xA;proportions. The physical sciences are better equipped now than&#xA;formerly, and religions have become less and less equipped. The&#xA;foundations have been all undermined, and the modern man, whatever he&#xA;may say in public, knows in the privacy of his heart that he can no more&#xA;&amp;ldquo;believe&amp;rdquo;. Believing certain things because an organised body of priests&#xA;tells him to believe, believing because it is written in certain books,&#xA;believing because his people like him to believe, the modern man knows&#xA;to be impossible for him. There are, of course, a number of people who&#xA;seem to acquiesce in the so-called popular faith, but we also know for&#xA;certain that they do not think. Their idea of belief may be better&#xA;translated as &amp;ldquo;not-thinking-carelessness&amp;rdquo;. This fight cannot last much&#xA;longer without breaking to pieces all the buildings of religion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>036 VEDANTA AS A FACTOR IN CIVILISATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/036_vedanta_as_a_factor_in_civilisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/036_vedanta_as_a_factor_in_civilisation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vedanta-as-a-factor-in-civilisation&#34;&gt;VEDANTA AS A FACTOR IN CIVILISATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Extract from an address delivered at Airlie Lodge, Ridgeway Gardens,&#xA;England&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People who are capable of seeing only the gross external aspect of&#xA;things can perceive in the Indian nation only a conquered and suffering&#xA;people, a race of dreamers and philosophers. They seem to be incapable&#xA;of perceiving that in the spiritual realm India conquers the world. No&#xA;doubt it is true that just as the too active Western mind would profit&#xA;by an admixture of Eastern introspect ion and the meditative habit, so&#xA;the Eastern would benefit by a somewhat greater activity and energy.&#xA;Still we must ask: What may be that force which causes this afflicted&#xA;and suffering people, the Hindu, and the Jewish too (the two races from&#xA;which have originated all the great religions of the world) to survive,&#xA;when other nations perish? The cause can only be their spiritual force.&#xA;The Hindus are still living though silent, the Jews are more numerous&#xA;today than when they lived in Palestine. The philosophy of India&#xA;percolates throughout the whole civilised world, modifying and&#xA;permeating as it goes. So also in ancient times, her trade reached the&#xA;shores of Africa before Europe was known, and opened communication with&#xA;the rest of the world, thus disproving the belief that Indians never&#xA;went outside of their own country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>037 THE SPIRIT AND INFLUENCE OF VEDANTA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/037_the_spirit_and_influence_of_vedanta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/037_the_spirit_and_influence_of_vedanta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-spirit-and-influence-of-vedanta&#34;&gt;THE SPIRIT AND INFLUENCE OF VEDANTA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at the Twentieth Century Club, Boston&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before going into the subject of this afternoon, will you allow me to&#xA;say a few words of thanks, now that I have the opportunity? I have lived&#xA;three years amongst you. I have travelled over nearly the whole of&#xA;America, and as I am going back from here to my own country, it is meet&#xA;that I should take this opportunity of expressing my gratitude in this&#xA;Athens of America. When I first came to this country, after a few days I&#xA;thought I would be able to write a book on the nation. But after three&#xA;years&amp;rsquo; stay here, I find I am not able to write even a page. On the&#xA;other hand, I find in travelling in various countries that beneath the&#xA;surface differences that we find in dress and food and little details of&#xA;manners, man is man all the world over; the same wonderful human nature&#xA;is everywhere represented. Yet there are certain characteristics, and in&#xA;a few words I would like to sum up all my experiences here. In this land&#xA;of America, no question is asked about a man&amp;rsquo;s peculiarities. If a man&#xA;is a man, that is enough, and they take him into their hearts, and that&#xA;is one thing I have never seen in any other country in the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>038 STEPS OF HINDU PHILOSOPHIC THOUGHT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/038_steps_of_hindu_philosophic_thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/038_steps_of_hindu_philosophic_thought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;steps-of-hindu-philosophic-thought&#34;&gt;STEPS OF HINDU PHILOSOPHIC THOUGHT&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first group of religious ideas that we see coming up — I mean&#xA;recognised religious ideas, and not the very low ideas, which do not&#xA;deserve the name of religion — all include the idea of inspiration and&#xA;revealed books and so forth. The first group of religious ideas starts&#xA;with the idea of God. Here is the universe, and this universe is created&#xA;by a certain Being. Everything that is in this universe has been created&#xA;by Him. Along with that, at a later stage, comes the idea of soul — that&#xA;there is this body, and something inside this body which is not the&#xA;body. This is the most primitive idea of religion that we know. We can&#xA;find a few followers of that in India, but it was given up very early.&#xA;The Indian religions take a peculiar start. It is only by strict&#xA;analysis, and much calculation and conjecture, that we can ever think&#xA;that that stage existed in Indian religions. The tangible state in which&#xA;we find them is the next step, not the first one. At the earliest step&#xA;the idea of creation is very peculiar, and it is that the whole universe&#xA;is created out of zero, at the will of God; that all this universe did&#xA;not exist, and out of this nothingness all this has come. In the next&#xA;stage we find this conclusion is questioned. How can existence be&#xA;produced out of nonexistence? At the first step in the Vedanta this&#xA;question is asked. If this universe is existent it must have come out of&#xA;something, because it was very easy to see that nothing comes out of&#xA;nothing, anywhere. All work that is done by human hands requires&#xA;materials. If a house is built, the material was existing before; if a&#xA;boat is made the material existed before; if any implements are made,&#xA;the materials were existing before. So the effect is produced.&#xA;Naturally, therefore, the first idea that this world was created out of&#xA;nothing was rejected, and some material out of which this world was&#xA;created was wanted. The whole history of religion, in fact, is this&#xA;search after that material.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>039 STEPS TO REALISATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/039_steps_to_realisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/039_steps_to_realisation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;steps-to-realisation&#34;&gt;STEPS TO REALISATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;A class-lecture delivered in America&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First among the qualifications required of the aspirant for Jnāna, or&#xA;wisdom, come Shama and Dama, which may be taken together. They mean the&#xA;keeping of the organs in their own centres without allowing them to&#xA;stray out. I shall explain to you first what the word &amp;ldquo;organ&amp;rdquo; means.&#xA;Here are the eyes; the eyes are not the organs of vision but only the&#xA;instruments. Unless the organs also are present, I cannot see, even if I&#xA;have eyes. But, given both the organs and the instruments, unless the&#xA;mind attaches itself to these two, no vision takes place. So, in each&#xA;act of perception, three things are necessary — first, the external&#xA;instruments, then, the internal organs, and lastly, the mind. If any one&#xA;of them be absent, then there will be no perception. Thus the mind acts&#xA;through two agencies — one external, and the other internal. When I see&#xA;things, my mind goes out, becomes externalised; but suppose I close my&#xA;eyes and begin to think, the mind does not go out, it is internally&#xA;active. But, in either case, there is activity of the organs. When I&#xA;look at you and speak to you, both the organs and the instruments are&#xA;active. When I close my eyes and begin to think, the organs are active,&#xA;but not the instruments. Without the activity of these organs, there&#xA;will be no thought. You will find that none of you can think without&#xA;some symbol. In the case of the blind man, he has also to think through&#xA;some figure. The organs of sight and hearing are generally very active.&#xA;You must bear in mind that by the word &amp;ldquo;organ&amp;rdquo; is meant the nerve centre&#xA;in the brain. The eyes and ears are only the instruments of seeing and&#xA;hearing, and the organs are inside. If the organs are destroyed by any&#xA;means, even if the eyes or the ears be there, we shall not see or hear.&#xA;So in order to control the mind, we must first be able to control these&#xA;organs. To restrain the mind from wandering outward or inward, and keep&#xA;the organs in their respective centres, is what is meant by the words&#xA;Shama and Dama. Shama consists in not allowing the mind to externalise,&#xA;and Dama, in checking the external instruments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>040 VEDANTA AND PRIVILEGE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/040_vedanta_and_privilege/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/040_vedanta_and_privilege/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vedanta-and-privilege&#34;&gt;VEDANTA AND PRIVILEGE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in London&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have nearly finished the metaphysical portion of the Advaita. One&#xA;point, and perhaps the most difficult to understand, remains. We have&#xA;seen so far that, according to the Advaita theory, all we see around us,&#xA;and the whole universe in fact, is the evolution of that one Absolute.&#xA;This is called, in Sanskrit, Brahman. The Absolute has become changed&#xA;into the whole of nature. But here comes a difficulty. How is it&#xA;possible for the Absolute to change? What made the Absolute to change?&#xA;By its very definition, the Absolute is unchangeable. Change of the&#xA;unchangeable would be a contradiction. The same difficulty applies to&#xA;those who believe in a Personal God. For instance, how did this creation&#xA;arise? It could not have arisen out of nothing; that would be a&#xA;contradiction — something coming out of nothing can never be. The effect&#xA;is the cause in another form. Out of the seed, the big tree grows; the&#xA;tree is the seed, plus air and water taken in. And if there were any&#xA;method of testing the amount of the air, and water taken to make the&#xA;body of the tree, we should find that it is exactly the same as the&#xA;effect, the tree. Modern science has proved beyond doubt that it is so,&#xA;that the cause is the effect in another form. The adjustment of the&#xA;parts of the cause changes and becomes the effect. So, we have to avoid&#xA;this difficulty of having a universe without a cause, and we are bound&#xA;to admit that God has become the universe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>041 PRIVILEGE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/041_privilege/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/041_privilege/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;privilege&#34;&gt;PRIVILEGE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at the Sesame Club, London&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two forces seem to be working throughout nature. One of these is&#xA;constantly differentiating, and the other is as constantly unifying; the&#xA;one making more and more for separate individuals, the other, as it&#xA;were, bringing the individuals into a mass, bringing out sameness in the&#xA;midst of all this differentiation. It seems that the action of these two&#xA;forces enters into every department of nature and of human life. On the&#xA;physical plane, we always find the two forces most distinctly at work,&#xA;separating the individuals, making them more and more distinct from&#xA;other individuals, and again making them into species and classes, and&#xA;bringing out similarities of expressions, and form. The same holds good&#xA;as regards the social life of man. Since the time when society began,&#xA;these two forces have been at work, differentiating and unifying. Their&#xA;action appears in various forms, and is called by various names, in&#xA;different places, and at different times. But the essence is present in&#xA;all, one making for differentiation, and the other for sameness; the one&#xA;making for caste, and the other breaking it down; one making for classes&#xA;and privileges, and the other destroying them. The whole universe seems&#xA;to be the battle-ground of these two forces. On the one hand, it is&#xA;urged, that though this unifying process exists, we ought to resist it&#xA;with all our might, because it leads towards death, that perfect unity&#xA;is perfect annihilation, and that when the differentiating process that&#xA;is at work in this universe ceases, the universe comes to an end. It is&#xA;differentiation that causes the phenomena that are before us;&#xA;unification would reduce them all to a homogeneous and lifeless matter.&#xA;Such a thing, of course, mankind wants to avoid. The same argument is&#xA;applied to all the things and facts that we see around us. It is urged&#xA;that even in physical body and social classification, absolute sameness&#xA;would produce natural death and social death. Absolute sameness of&#xA;thought and feeling would produce mental decay and degeneration.&#xA;Sameness, therefore, is to be avoided. This has been the argument on the&#xA;one side, and it has been urged in every country and in various times,&#xA;with only a change of language. Practically it is the same argument&#xA;which is urged by the Brahmins of India, when they want to uphold the&#xA;divisions and castes, when they want to uphold the privileges of a&#xA;certain portion of the community, against everybody else. The&#xA;destruction of caste, they declare, would lead to destruction of&#xA;society, and boldly they produce the historical fact that theirs has&#xA;been the longest-lived society. So they, with some show of force, appeal&#xA;to this argument. With some show of authority they declare that that&#xA;alone which makes the individual live the longest life must certainly be&#xA;better than that which produces shorter lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>042 KRISHNA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/042_krishna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/042_krishna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;krishna&#34;&gt;KRISHNA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article was recorded by Ida Ansell in shorthand. As, however,&#xA;Swamiji&amp;rsquo;s speed was too great for her in her early days, dots are put in&#xA;the articles to indicate the omissions, while the words within square&#xA;brackets are added by way of linking up the disconnected parts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in California, on April 1, 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Almost the same circumstances which gave birth to Buddhism in India&#xA;surrounded the rise of Krishna. Not only this, the events of that day we&#xA;find happening in our own times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>043 THE GITA I</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/043_the_gita_i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/043_the_gita_i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-gita-i&#34;&gt;THE GITA I&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article was recorded by Ida Ansell in shorthand. As, however,&#xA;Swamiji&amp;rsquo;s speed was too great for her in her early days, dots are put in&#xA;the articles to indicate the omissions, while the words within square&#xA;brackets are added by way of linking up the disconnected parts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in San Francisco, on May 26, 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To understand the Gita requires its historical background. The Gita is a&#xA;commentary on the Upanishads. The Upanishads are the Bible of India.&#xA;They occupy the same place as the New Testament does. There are [more&#xA;than] a hundred books comprising the Upanishads, some very small and&#xA;some big, each a separate treatise. The Upanishads do not reveal the&#xA;life of any teacher, but simply teach principles. They are [as it&#xA;were] shorthand notes taken down of discussion in [learned&#xA;assemblies], generally in the courts of kings. The word Upanishad may&#xA;mean &amp;ldquo;sittings&amp;rdquo; [or &amp;ldquo;sitting near a teacher&amp;rdquo;]. Those of you who may&#xA;have studied some of the Upanishads can understand how they are&#xA;condensed shorthand sketches. After long discussions had been held, they&#xA;were taken down, possibly from memory. The difficulty is that you get&#xA;very little of the background. Only the luminous points are mentioned&#xA;there. The origin of ancient Sanskrit is 5000 B.C.; the Upanishads [are&#xA;at least] two thousand years before that. Nobody knows [exactly] how&#xA;old they are. The Gita takes the ideas of the Upanishads and in [some]&#xA;cases the very words. They are strung together with the idea of bringing&#xA;out, in a compact, condensed, and systematic form, the whole subject the&#xA;Upanishads deal with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>044 THE GITA II</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/044_the_gita_ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/044_the_gita_ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-gita-ii&#34;&gt;THE GITA II&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article was recorded by Ida Ansell in shorthand. As, however,&#xA;Swamiji&amp;rsquo;s speed was too great for her in her early days, dots are put in&#xA;the articles to indicate the omissions, while the words within square&#xA;brackets are added by way of linking up the disconnected parts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in San Francisco, on May 28, 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Gitā requires a little preliminary introduction. The scene is laid&#xA;on the battlefield of Kurukshetra. There were two branches of the same&#xA;race fighting for the empire of India about five thousand years ago. The&#xA;Pāndavas had the right, but the Kauravas had the might. The Pandavas&#xA;were five brothers, and they were living in a forest. Krishna was the&#xA;friend of the Pandavas. The Kauravas would not grant them as much land&#xA;as would cover the point of a needle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>045 THE GITA III</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/045_the_gita_iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/045_the_gita_iii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-gita-iii&#34;&gt;THE GITA III&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article was recorded by Ida Ansell in shorthand. As, however,&#xA;Swamiji&amp;rsquo;s speed was too great for her in her early days, dots are put in&#xA;the articles to indicate the omissions, while the words within square&#xA;brackets are added by way of linking up the disconnected parts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in San Francisco, on May 29, 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arjuna asks: &amp;ldquo;You just advised action, and yet you uphold knowledge of&#xA;Brahman as the highest form of life. Krishna, if you think that&#xA;knowledge is better than action, why do you tell me to act?&amp;rdquo; (Gita III.&#xA;1.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>046 MOHAMMED</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/046_mohammed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/046_mohammed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;mohammed&#34;&gt;MOHAMMED&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article was recorded by Ida Ansell in shorthand. As, however,&#xA;Swamiji&amp;rsquo;s speed was too great for her in her early days, dots are put in&#xA;the articles to indicate the omissions, while the words within square&#xA;brackets are added by way of linking up the disconnected parts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered on March 25, 1900, in the San Francisco Bay Area)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ancient message of Krishna is one harmonising three — Buddha&amp;rsquo;s,&#xA;Christ&amp;rsquo;s and Mohammed&amp;rsquo;s. Each of the three started an idea and carried&#xA;it to its extreme. Krishna antedates all the other prophets. [Yet, we&#xA;might say,] Krishna takes the old ideas and synthesises them,&#xA;[although] his is the most ancient message. His message was for the&#xA;time being submerged by the advance wave of Buddhism. Today it is the&#xA;message peculiar to India. If you will have it so, this afternoon I will&#xA;take Mohammed and bring out the particular work of the great Arabian&#xA;prophet&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>047 VILVAMANGALA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/047_vilvamangala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/047_vilvamangala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vilvamangala&#34;&gt;VILVAMANGALA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Found in the papers of Miss S. E. Waldo by Swami Raghavananda when he&#xA;was in the U.S.A.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a story from one of the books of India, called &amp;ldquo;Lives of&#xA;Saints&amp;rdquo;. There was a young man, a Brahmin by birth, in a certain&#xA;village. The man fell in love with a bad woman in another village. There&#xA;was a big river between the two villages, and this man, every day, used&#xA;to go to that girl, crossing this river in a ferry boat. Now, one day he&#xA;had to perform the obsequies of his father, and so, although he was&#xA;longing, almost dying to go to the girl, he could not. The ceremonies&#xA;had to be performed, and all those things had to be undergone; it is&#xA;absolutely necessary in Hindu society. He was fretting and fuming and&#xA;all that, but could not help it. At last the ceremony ended, and night&#xA;came, and with the night, a tremendous howling storm arose. The rain was&#xA;pouring down, and the river was lashed into gigantic waves. It was very&#xA;dangerous to cross. Yet he went to the bank of the river. There was no&#xA;ferry boat. The ferrymen were afraid to cross, but he would go; his&#xA;heart was becoming mad with love for the girl, so he would go. There was&#xA;a log floating down, and he got that, and with the help of it, crossed&#xA;the river, and getting to the other side dragged the log up, threw it on&#xA;the bank, and went to the house. The doors were closed. He knocked at&#xA;the door, but the wind was howling, and nobody heard him. So he went&#xA;round the walls and at last found what he thought to be a rope, hanging&#xA;from the wall. He clutched at it, saying to himself, &amp;ldquo;Oh, my love has&#xA;left a rope for me to climb.&amp;rdquo; By the help of that rope he climbed over&#xA;the wall, got to the other side, missed his footing, and fell, and noise&#xA;aroused the inmates of the house, and the girl came out and found the&#xA;man there in a faint. She revived him, and noticing that he was smelling&#xA;very unpleasantly, she said, &amp;ldquo;What is the matter with you? Why this&#xA;stench on your body? How did you come into the house?&amp;rdquo; He said, &amp;ldquo;Why,&#xA;did not my love put that rope there?&amp;rdquo; She smiled, and said, &amp;ldquo;What love?&#xA;We are for money, and do you think that I let down a rope for you, fool&#xA;that you are? How did you cross the river?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Why, I got hold of a log of&#xA;wood.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Let us go and see,&amp;rdquo; said the girl. The rope was a cobra, a&#xA;tremendously poisonous serpent, whose least touch is death. It had its&#xA;head in a hole, and was getting in when the man caught hold of its tail,&#xA;and he thought it was a rope. The madness of love made him do it. When&#xA;the serpent has its head in its hole, and its body out, and you catch&#xA;hold of it, it will not let its head come out; so the man climbed up by&#xA;it, but the force of the pull killed the serpent. &amp;ldquo;Where did you get the&#xA;log?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;It was floating down the river.&amp;rdquo; It was a festering dead body;&#xA;the stream had washed it down and that he took for a log, which&#xA;explained why he had such an unpleasant odour. The woman looked at him&#xA;and said, &amp;ldquo;I never believed in love; we never do; but, if this is not&#xA;love, the Lord have mercy on me. We do not know what love is. But, my&#xA;friend, why do you give that heart to a woman like me? Why do you not&#xA;give it to God? You will be perfect.&amp;rdquo; It was a thunderbolt to the man&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;brain. He got a glimpse of the beyond for a moment. &amp;ldquo;Is there a God?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Yes, yes, my friend, there is,&amp;rdquo; said the woman. And the man walked on,&#xA;went into a forest, began to weep and pray. &amp;ldquo;I want Thee, Oh Lord! This&#xA;tide of my love cannot find a receptacle in little human beings. I want&#xA;to love where this mighty river of my love can go, the ocean of love;&#xA;this rushing tremendous river of my love cannot enter into little pools,&#xA;it wants the infinite ocean. Thou art there; come Thou to me.&amp;rdquo; So he&#xA;remained there for years. After years he thought he had succeeded, he&#xA;became a Sannyasin and he came into the cities. One day he was sitting&#xA;on the bank of a river, at one of the bathing places, and a beautiful&#xA;young girl, the wife of a merchant of the city, with her servant, came&#xA;and passed the place. The old man was again up in him, the beautiful&#xA;face again attracted him. The Yogi looked and looked, stood up and&#xA;followed the girl to her home. Presently the husband came by, and seeing&#xA;the Sannyasin in the yellow garb he said to him, &amp;ldquo;Come in, sir, what can&#xA;I do for you?&amp;rdquo; The Yogi said, &amp;ldquo;I will ask you a terrible thing.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Ask&#xA;anything, sir, I am a Grihastha (householder), and anything that one&#xA;asks I am ready to give.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;I want to see your wife.&amp;rdquo; The man said,&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Lord, what is this! Well, I am pure, and my wife is pure, and the Lord&#xA;is a protection to all. Welcome; come in sir.&amp;rdquo; He came in, and the&#xA;husband introduced him to his wife. &amp;ldquo;What can I do for you?&amp;rdquo; asked the&#xA;lady. He looked and looked, and then said, &amp;ldquo;Mother, will you give me two&#xA;pins from your hair?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Here they are.&amp;rdquo; He thrust them into his two eyes&#xA;saying &amp;ldquo;Get away, you rascals! Henceforth no fleshy things for you. If&#xA;you are to see, see the Shepherd of the groves of Vrindaban with the&#xA;eyes of the soul. Those are all the eyes you have.&amp;rdquo; So he went back into&#xA;the forest. There again he wept and wept and wept. It was all that great&#xA;flow of love in the man that was struggling to get at the truth, and at&#xA;last he succeeded; he gave his soul, the river of his love, the right&#xA;direction, and it came to the Shepherd. The story goes that he saw God&#xA;in the form of Krishna. Then, for once, he was sorry that he had lost&#xA;his eyes, and that he could only have the internal vision. He wrote some&#xA;beautiful poems of love. In all Sanskrit books, the writers first of all&#xA;salute their Gurus. So he saluted that girl as his first Guru.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>048 THE SOUL AND GOD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/048_the_soul_and_god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/048_the_soul_and_god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-soul-and-god&#34;&gt;THE SOUL AND GOD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article was recorded by Ida Ansell in shorthand. As, however,&#xA;Swamiji&amp;rsquo;s speed was too great for her in her early days, dots are put in&#xA;the articles to indicate the omissions, while the words within square&#xA;brackets are added by way of linking up the disconnected parts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in San Francisco, March 23, 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whether it was fear or mere inquisitiveness which first led man to think&#xA;of powers superior to himself, we need not discuss. &amp;hellip; These raised in&#xA;the mind peculiar worship tendencies, and so on. There never have been&#xA;[times in the history of mankind] without [some ideal] of worship.&#xA;Why? What makes us all struggle for something beyond what we see —&#xA;whether it be a beautiful morning or a fear of dead spirits? &amp;hellip; We need&#xA;not go back into prehistoric times, for it is a fact present today as it&#xA;was two thousand years ago. We do not find satisfaction here. Whatever&#xA;our station in life — [even if we are] powerful and wealthy — we&#xA;cannot find satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>049 BREATHING</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/049_breathing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/049_breathing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;breathing&#34;&gt;BREATHING&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article was recorded by Ida Ansell in shorthand. As, however,&#xA;Swamiji&amp;rsquo;s speed was too great for her in her early days, dots are put in&#xA;the articles to indicate the omissions, while the words within square&#xA;brackets are added by way of linking up the disconnected parts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in San Francisco, March 28, 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Breathing exercises have been very popular in India from the most&#xA;ancient times, so much so [that] they form a part of their religion,&#xA;just as going to church and repeating certain prayers&amp;hellip;. I will try to&#xA;bring those ideas before you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>050 PRACTICAL RELIGION: BREATHING AND MEDITATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/050_practical_religion_breathing_and_meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/lectures_and_discourses/050_practical_religion_breathing_and_meditation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;practical-religion-breathing-and-meditation&#34;&gt;PRACTICAL RELIGION: BREATHING AND MEDITATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article was recorded by Ida Ansell in shorthand. As, however,&#xA;Swamiji&amp;rsquo;s speed was too great for her in her early days, dots are put in&#xA;the articles to indicate the omissions, while the words within square&#xA;brackets are added by way of linking up the disconnected parts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in San Francisco, April 5, 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everyone&amp;rsquo;s idea of practical religion is according to his theory of&#xA;practicality and the standpoint he starts from. There is work. There is&#xA;the system of worship. There is knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
