<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>17ce deforestation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/17ce_deforestation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/17ce_deforestation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twenty-first-century ecology lessons from seventeenth-century Japan: climate change, deforestation, and moral regeneration&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JAMES McMULLEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The article sketches the views on ecology of the seventeenth-century Japanese Confucian scholar Kumazawa Banzan, concentrating on his thinking on forestry and climate change. At the same time his views suggest resonances with our twenty-first century discourse around ecology and moral leadership. Banzan applied Chinese cyclical cosmology and thought on the relation of man to nature to diagnose an ecological crisis in the exploitation of nature in his own world. He diagnosed the threat of imminent climate change and, with that, social and political upheaval. His views on political morality and material con sumption were underpinned by a Neo-Confucian emphasis on the primacy of agriculture and concept of man’s position that recognized the ontological inter dependence of man and nature. Human activity, particularly that of the ruler, impinged on the natural order. Towards the end of his life, he felt impelled to remonstrate against the misgovernment of the Tokugawa regime. He made rad ical proposals for the restoration of a materially frugal but culturally rich and politically devolved physiocratic socio-political order. Complementing his pro posals for institutional reform was a concern with individual self-cultivation that stressed man’s ontological position in the natural order and the need for moral regeneration at individual and social levels. The text was subsequently pub lished in Japanese translation (McMullen 2011). I am grateful to Professor Komuro Masamichi and Professor Ikeda Yoshihiro, his colleague in the Faculty of Economics and coordinator of the lecture series, for kind permission to pub lish this revised version. Many themes merely sketched here are discussed in greater detail in my Banzan biography (McMullen 1999).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excess problem</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/excess_problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/excess_problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Via shrIdhara vembu: When Japan went from poverty to be a leading industrial power, they let export surpluses pile up. Why is that a problem? Isn&amp;rsquo;t too much of a good thing a better thing? Such massive export surpluses have two issues, a) financial and b) real economy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;happiness-and-demographics&#34;&gt;Happiness and demographics&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now the real economy effect of piling up export surpluses. Japan then (and broader East Asia now) developed what I call &amp;ldquo;over-employment&amp;rdquo; - my term for an obsessive focus on putting everyone to work. The trouble is no one has any time for kids and that destroys demographics. Japanese invented the concept of &amp;ldquo;karoshi&amp;rdquo; (death due the overwork) and South Koreans work even harder. Recently Jack Ma of Alibaba exhorted the Chinese to work even harder, export more! That leaves no time for kids. South Korea now has the lowest birthrate in the world.&#xA;That&amp;rsquo;s the real economic consequence of piling up export surpluses, leading to &amp;ldquo;over-employment&amp;rdquo; and overwork.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>init-train-dirt</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/init-train-dirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/init-train-dirt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite such conveniences, a railway journey in this country is apt to be anything but a joy. Owing to some cause not yet explained, the Japanese who, when abiding in their own native ways, are the very pink of neatness, become slipshod, not to say dirty, when introduced to certain conditions of European life. On stepping into even a first-class car, one as often as not has to pick one&amp;rsquo;s way among orange-peel, spilt tea, cigar ends, beer- bottles overturned. The travellers are wallowing semi-recumbent along the seats, in untidy habiliments and dishabiliments. We have even seen a man-he was a military officer, and his dutiful spouse assisted him-change all his clothes in the car, though to be sure he availed himself of a friendly tunnel for the more adventurous portion of the enterprise. On another recent occasion, being ourselves somewhat short-sighted, we could not at first make out the nature of the occupation of an old gentleman who had just finished a good lunch. Closer scrutiny showed that he held his artificial teeth in his hand, and was busy picking and wiping them! Then, too, there is inordinate crowding, and whole batches of second-class passengers are, on the slightest provoca- tion, transferred to the first. In fact, the whole thing is queer and unpleasant, unless of course the traveller be a philosopher to whom every novel experience supplies welcome material for meditation. Such a philosopher will perhaps enquire the reason of the stripe of white paint across the windows of the third-class cars on certain lines. It is a precautionary measure adopted for the safety of country bumpkins; for it has happened that some of these, lacking personal experience of glass, have mistaken it for air, and gashed themselves horribly in the attempt to shove their heads through what, in their innocence, they supposed to be that non-resisting medium.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>shingen-levees</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/shingen-levees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/economy/articles/shingen-levees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1638667030827257856.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Takeda Shingen (1521-1573) was a Japanese feudal lord and probably one of the most accomplished leaders ever. An excellent military commander he was also a great administrator and inventor of flood control engineering methods that are still in use: the broken levee (Kasumitei).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A normal levee is closed and depends on forcing flood water to stay in a certain channel. A break is catastrophic. Kasumitei is staggered, with sloped openings. Normally, water flows past the openings, in floods it pushes backwards, inundates sacrificial fields before returning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
