<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Conclusion and Epilogue on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/Conclusion_and_Epilogue/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Conclusion and Epilogue on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/Conclusion_and_Epilogue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 INDIA IN THE PERSIANATE WORLD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/Conclusion_and_Epilogue/01_INDIA_IN_THE_PERSIANATE_WORLD/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/Conclusion_and_Epilogue/01_INDIA_IN_THE_PERSIANATE_WORLD/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;India has never been isolated. Jutting into the heart of the Indian Ocean – the world’s oldest maritime zone – and connected to the Iranian plateau by several strategic mountain passes, the Indo-Gangetic plain and the great peninsula to its south have long been a major crossroads of transregional movement and exchange. Pathways leading to and across the subcontinent have carried a wide range of global flows, while migrating populations brought or took away diverse cultural traditions embracing statecraft, architecture, warfare, cuisine, religion and much more. Although some of these flows had very deep roots in time, they all moved with a quickening pace between the eleventh and eighteenth centuries, the period of this book’s concern.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 THE MUGHALS IN THE SANSKRIT WORLD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/Conclusion_and_Epilogue/02_THE_MUGHALS_IN_THE_SANSKRIT_WORLD/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/Conclusion_and_Epilogue/02_THE_MUGHALS_IN_THE_SANSKRIT_WORLD/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Persianate was not the only cosmopolitan tradition that flourished in the Mughal period. More than any of the Indian sultanates that preceded them, the Mughals staked their claims to sovereignty by engaging with Sanskrit literary traditions. By appropriating a culture deeply rooted in India’s pre-Persianate past, they saw themselves as Indian kings and wished to be seen as such by others. It is therefore hardly surprising that both Brahmin and Jain scholars maintained a significant presence in the Mughal court in the latter decades of Akbar’s reign and continuing through those of Jahangir and Shah Jahan.29&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 THE LOTUS AND THE LION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/Conclusion_and_Epilogue/03_THE_LOTUS_AND_THE_LION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/Conclusion_and_Epilogue/03_THE_LOTUS_AND_THE_LION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When considering the pre-colonial evidence in such fields as architecture, art, language, literature, religion or the sciences, one might ask whether the Sanskritic universe had assimilated its Persianate counterpart, or whether it had been the other way around. But perhaps the question is misplaced. At the moment of their initial encounter, to be sure, each literary tradition and the fields it elaborated were mutually opposed in nearly every respect. That was certainly how it seemed to the eleventh-century Persian polymath Abu Rayhan al-Biruni (d. 1048), who registered one of the most thoughtful and articulate responses to the Sanskrit world ever voiced by an educated Persian. Having travelled extensively in north India, learnt Sanskrit and immersed himself in the study of all aspects of Indian culture, Biruni wrote a comprehensive survey of Indian knowledge, &lt;em&gt;Kitab ta’rikh al-Hind&lt;/em&gt;, at the dawn of the encounter between the Persianate and Sanskritic worlds. The book’s very first chapter emphasized the stark opposition he perceived between the Indian scholarly and cultural universe and his own, which had synthesized Greek, Arabic and Persian intellectual traditions.42 And yet already in 1027 Biruni’s own patron, Mahmud of Ghazni, minted coins bearing a Sanskrit translation of the Islamic confession of faith in which the Prophet Muhammad was presented as an &lt;em&gt;avatar&lt;/em&gt; of God, translated as &lt;em&gt;avyaktam&lt;/em&gt;, ‘the Unmanifested’.43 By using Sanskrit terms that roughly approximated the meaning of the Arabic, Mahmud was already blurring two very different theological spheres.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 TOWARDS MODERNITY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/Conclusion_and_Epilogue/04_TOWARDS_MODERNITY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/Conclusion_and_Epilogue/04_TOWARDS_MODERNITY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Contrary to the claims of British imperial propagandists or apologists, modernity in India did not commence with the arrival of European merchants or colonial rulers. That story goes back to their Mughal predecessors. The reigns of two Mughal emperors in particular – Akbar and ‘Alamgir – saw distinctive, but very different, harbingers of what people in the twenty-first century might call modernity. Akbar’s reign exhibited a spirit of rational self-control and a nearly obsessive preoccupation with order in all spheres of experience, especially in governance and administration. Abu’l-fazl’s monumental imperial gazetteer, the &lt;em&gt;A’in-i Akbari&lt;/em&gt; or ‘Institutes of Akbar’ (&lt;em&gt;c&lt;/em&gt;.1595), shows a determined effort to standardize and impose the most minute regulations over nearly everything: the manner of cleaning matchlock firearms, the daily allowance for feeding mules, the wages for imperial glass-cutters, the rearing and care of pigeons, the expenses for the maintenance of different classes of war-horses, etc. Every plot of the empire’s cultivated area was subjected to careful surveys using standard units of measurement. Corruption, while endemic in most large state systems, was minimized by the Mughals’ promoting an ethic of efficiency, while standard monetary units – the silver rupee, the gold &lt;em&gt;muhr&lt;/em&gt; and the copper &lt;em&gt;dam&lt;/em&gt; – helped regularize the most basic of governmental functions: the collection of revenue. Record-keeping from Akbar’s reign onwards was meticulous, as strict rules were established for maintaining data and auditing accounts. Soldiers under the charge of a &lt;em&gt;mansabdar&lt;/em&gt; were listed by name, place of residence, age, race and physical descriptions; war-horses were carefully identified by their types and their distinguishing features – all with a view to promoting military efficiency.53&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
