<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;HAGAKURE IN CONTEXT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/bennet-translation/0/HAGAKURE_IN_CONTEXT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;HAGAKURE IN CONTEXT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/bennet-translation/0/HAGAKURE_IN_CONTEXT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 INTRODUCTION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/bennet-translation/0/HAGAKURE_IN_CONTEXT/01_INTRODUCTION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/bennet-translation/0/HAGAKURE_IN_CONTEXT/01_INTRODUCTION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bushido&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; tends to stir people’s imaginations. The term is synonymous on the one hand with strength, masculinity, fearlessness, honor, and transcendence, and on the other, callousness and cold-hearted brutality. The most visible vestige of samurai culture in the modern age is budo, that is, the Japanese traditional martial arts, and these are indisputably Japan’s most successful cultural exports, with literally tens of millions of enthusiasts around the world. People practice these arts not only as a means of self-defense or as competitive sports, but also in the pursuit of spiritual development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 The Hagakure phenomenon</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/bennet-translation/0/HAGAKURE_IN_CONTEXT/02_The_Hagakure_phenomenon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/bennet-translation/0/HAGAKURE_IN_CONTEXT/02_The_Hagakure_phenomenon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HAGAKURE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;PHENOMENON&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Properly titled &lt;em&gt;Hagakure-kikigaki&lt;/em&gt; (literally “Dictations given hidden by leaves”), &lt;em&gt;Hagakure&lt;/em&gt; is now one of the most famous treatises on &lt;em&gt;bushido&lt;/em&gt;. Completed in 1716, the content consists of approximately 1,300 vignettes and contemplations of varying lengths, divided into 11 books. It covers the people, history, and traditions of the Saga domain&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in the southern Japanese island of Kyushu, and also records anecdotes about warriors from other provinces. Although some of the content is abstract in nature, the pages are filled with engaging stories about the feats of individual samurai and the maelstrom of retainership, premised by a balance of insanity and equanimity, rather than a convoluted philosophical discourse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 CONTEXTUALIZING THE HISTORICAL SETTING AND SOCIAL MILIEU</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/bennet-translation/0/HAGAKURE_IN_CONTEXT/03_CONTEXTUALIZING_THE_HISTORICAL_SETTING_AND_SOCIAL_MILIEU/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/bennet-translation/0/HAGAKURE_IN_CONTEXT/03_CONTEXTUALIZING_THE_HISTORICAL_SETTING_AND_SOCIAL_MILIEU/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As professional warriors, samurai were distinctive from peasant or civilian conscript soldiers of the ancient (&lt;em&gt;kodai&lt;/em&gt;) and modern (&lt;em&gt;kindai&lt;/em&gt;) periods. Their existence differed greatly to the officials who were merely assigned military duty in ancient times, and also to the modern career soldier.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The gradual rise of the samurai to political prominence on a national scale was activated by the on-going dismantling of military obligations forced upon the general populace under the &lt;em&gt;ritsuryō&lt;/em&gt; system. The system encouraged a rigid hierarchy in court, where certain offices became hereditary among a select but small group of nobles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 CONTEXTUALIZING THE CONTENT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/bennet-translation/0/HAGAKURE_IN_CONTEXT/04_CONTEXTUALIZING_THE_CONTENT/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/bennet-translation/0/HAGAKURE_IN_CONTEXT/04_CONTEXTUALIZING_THE_CONTENT/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The subject matter of &lt;em&gt;Hagakure&lt;/em&gt; was dictated by Yamamoto Jōchō. He was born on the eleventh day of the sixth month in 1659 to Yamamoto Jin’uemon Shigezumi, a retainer of the Saga domain. Jōchō talks of his childhood days in Book 2. He mentions that his father was 70 years old when he was born, and given the encumbrance of rearing a child at his age, Jin’uemon quipped that he should like to off-load his new child to a salt merchant. His unit captain, Taku Zusho, advised against such rash disposal of the lad, as his illustrious lineage guaranteed usefulness as a retainer in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 UNRAVELING THE ESSENCE OF HAGAKURE*</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/bennet-translation/0/HAGAKURE_IN_CONTEXT/05_UNRAVELING_THE_ESSENCE_OF_HAGAKURE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/bennet-translation/0/HAGAKURE_IN_CONTEXT/05_UNRAVELING_THE_ESSENCE_OF_HAGAKURE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The content of &lt;em&gt;Hagakure&lt;/em&gt; is complicated, and unashamedly contradictory and ambiguous in places. Even the origin of the book’s name is open for conjecture. One theory cites a poem by the famous Buddhist bard Saigyō Hōshi (1118–1190) in the &lt;em&gt;Sanka-shū&lt;/em&gt;. “&lt;em&gt;Hagakure ni chiri-todomareru hana nomi zo, shinobishi hito ni au kokochi suru&lt;/em&gt;” (“Hidden away under leaves, a blossom still left over makes me yearn to chance upon my secret love this way.”)&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Another hypothesis suggests that “hidden by leaves” was a reference to the secluded environment in which Tsuramoto interviewed Jōchō. Other scholars allude to the fact that Jōchō often makes reference to stalwart service from behind the scenes, or “service from the shadows,” with no desire for recognition. It has even been postulated that the fifth Nabeshima lord, Muneshige, visited Tsuramoto and conferred the title himself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 CONCLUSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/bennet-translation/0/HAGAKURE_IN_CONTEXT/06_CONCLUSION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/bennet-translation/0/HAGAKURE_IN_CONTEXT/06_CONCLUSION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This introductory chapter was written with the intention of contextualizing the myriad of influences that resulted in the writing of, and subsequent fascination with, this collection of guileless but sometimes quixotic aphorisms known as &lt;em&gt;Hagakure&lt;/em&gt;. Controversial from the beginning, modified interpretations of the text’s mentality in the twentieth century made the book particularly useful for stirring ultra-nationalistic sentiment and inculcating militarism. Consequently, &lt;em&gt;Hagakure&lt;/em&gt; temporarily became a “forbidden text” of sorts again in the aftermath of World War II. Gradually, though, Japan entered a period of renewed interest in &lt;em&gt;Hagakure&lt;/em&gt; from the 1960s. Renowned historians such as Furukawa Tetsushi and authors such as Mishima Yukio acclaimed &lt;em&gt;Hagakure&lt;/em&gt; as representing the most exquisitely “beautiful” aspects of Japanese culture that had been indiscriminately purged in the immediate post-war period.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
