<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;vembu-shrIdharaH on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/geo/articles/svembu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;vembu-shrIdharaH on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/geo/articles/svembu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>China job market down</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/geo/articles/svembu/china-job-market-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/geo/articles/svembu/china-job-market-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://unrollthread.com/t/1523520634311315456/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;China, &amp;ldquo;the factory for the world&amp;rdquo;, faces a grim job market, while the US, massive net importer and consumer, has a booming job market. I will explore this in this thread. How can a country export so much and still have an employment problem?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chinese economy is structurally distorted towards&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;a) running a massive trade surplus&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;b) which is achieved by keeping wages, consumption and imports lower than what productivity warrants&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;c) with the resulting savings fueling debt driven real estate &amp;amp; infrastructure spending.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The factors a, b, c above also feed into each other and hence reinforce each other which is why it becomes &amp;ldquo;structural distortion&amp;rdquo;, by which I mean that this pattern is very hard to reverse, as @michaelxpettis often points out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Colombia</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/geo/articles/svembu/colombia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/geo/articles/svembu/colombia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1657182108152913920.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Very interesting &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/michaelxpettis/status/1657116393924624384&#34;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt; on Colombia (pop. 52 million) wanting to restore basic industries and jobs and restore balance in their external trade.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is it possible? Yes. There are some trade-offs (!) they would have to make but their goal is doable. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the trade-offs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most critical trade off is this. Consider the iPhone, which I will use as code to represent &amp;ldquo;goods with the most sophisticated tech available&amp;rdquo;. If Colombians want to buy a lot of iPhones, they may not have enough exports to pay for them and achieve trade balance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>East asian tigers</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/geo/articles/svembu/east-asian-tigers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/geo/articles/svembu/east-asian-tigers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hugely respect East Asia&amp;rsquo;s achievement in lifting people from poverty. There is a lot to learn from the experience of Japan, South Korea, Taiwan and later China. In this thread, I will outline what I respectfully disagree about the East Asian model (respectfully stressed!) I will use Japan as my example because it is the quintessential East Asian success story. South Korea, Taiwan and later China were all influenced heavily by Japan&amp;rsquo;s development experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>German advantage</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/geo/articles/svembu/german-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/geo/articles/svembu/german-advantage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am afraid I have to disagree with Prof Pettis. Higher German wages could actually &lt;em&gt;increase&lt;/em&gt; the German trade surplus (and increase German savings), rather than decrease them as he argues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why? Germany exports superbly engineered goods that are not easily substitutable. His widget example assumes that Germany and Spain make substitutable kind of widgets. They don&amp;rsquo;t. German capital goods as well as German cars are coveted around the world and the price premium paid for those goods mean high German wages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On China</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/geo/articles/svembu/on-china/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/geo/articles/svembu/on-china/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;China has built far more housing and infrastructure than needed and far more factories than needed for her own consumption. China has overworked her people &amp;amp; as a result has destroyed her demographics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;India needs more factories, housing &amp;amp; infrastructure but needs balance. India must aim for balance between imports and exports and there is no sense trying to become the &amp;ldquo;factory for the world&amp;rdquo; like China. We also must spend time nurturing our families, our cultural and civilizational roots. Development does not have to mean losing ourselves. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
