<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Guru Anaerobic on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Guru Anaerobic on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aging</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/aging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/aging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1640451181733629952.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;decline-pattern&#34;&gt;Decline pattern&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How physical qualities degrade as you age.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been fit all my life. From late twenties to fifty I trained competitively. &lt;em&gt;In my experience&lt;/em&gt; here&amp;rsquo;s the order in which physical performance degrades.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 Recovery takes longer. You can train just as hard but are achy for longer. Sooner or later this means that frequency of hard sessions must decrease.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 You become more prone to injury.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3 Need for a good warm-up increases.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4 Speed degrades.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;5 Reactivity and agility degrades.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;6 Tolerance to acidosis and hard repeats degrades.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;7 Power degrades.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;8 Strength degrades.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;9 Endurance degrades.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Top performance starts to degrade when recovery takes longer and injury strikes - this means that quality volume and frequency is reduced; the start of long-term slow performance decline. For a while one can retain qualities by being more intelligent with training, knowing your body, and erring on the side of caution. Eventually, the inevitable decline in performance has to be accepted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explosive exercise &amp; age</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/explosive_exercise_age/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/explosive_exercise_age/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GuruAnaerobic/status/1786601726121804140&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The way to protect your body from the stress of fast explosive movements is to do fast explosive movements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve increased the variety and the amount of jumps, weighted jumps, bounds, fast concentrics, heavy explosive leg extensions&amp;hellip;lower limb work. But I&amp;rsquo;ve added explosive chin-ups and dips, hypers - weighted and unweighted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I aggressively attack all gym exercises and have only a short rest between sets, as long rests dissipate psychological energy. I workout mid-morning which I realise is when I have the highest psychological attack mentality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knee</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/knee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/knee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;single-leg-exercises&#34;&gt;Single leg exercises&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve got older squatting feels more natural and less harmful than single-leg exercises.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Single leg stuff hurts my knees - it doesnt matter how strong you are if your knees are wrecked.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m certain that heavy single leg exercises and knees over toes are going to mess up a lot of people. Either way, try things out for yourself and find out what suits you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>physical-standards</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/physical-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/physical-standards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 Deadlift: One-rep max of 2 x body weight (general strength)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 Chin-ups: 20 (usable upper body strength)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3 100m sprint: Under 13 seconds (speed)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4 One mile: Under 6 minutes (endurance)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;5 Body-fat: 10-12% - a six-pack is just visible (health)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These are not elite standards, but achieving all five would likely take you into the top 1% of the population. You&amp;rsquo;d be in tremendous physical shape.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most challenging for an older person (60yrs+) to achieve is a sub-13sec sprint; sub-14secs would be more appropriate (the others are not too difficult). Retaining the ability, as you age, to generate dynamic muscular contractions provides solid information about the general physical state of the muscles, tendons, ligaments and nerves. If you can do it without a warm-up, even better. Being able to turn on strength, quickness and agility without any warm-up is the pure expression of youth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recreate Wildness</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/Recreate_Wildness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/Recreate_Wildness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Think of running for the bus as earning your calories. Think of physical work as hunting for your food. Think of cycling fifty miles as tracking an antelope. Climbing trees, jumping over walls, running up stairs, fighting, throwing, sprinting – they&amp;rsquo;re reproducing things your ancient ancestors had to do to survive. Again; you have to expend your calories to get calories because the modern environment no longer forces you do it. &amp;hellip; Make your normal life physically harder. Purposely, create physical challenges and expend energy. Run for the bus, run across the road, jump walls; whatever - you do it because you can. You do it because you are recreating a wild environment. You do it because the fossils around you can&amp;rsquo;t, and you don&amp;rsquo;t want to be like them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running reveals fragility</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/running-fragility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/running-fragility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Running reveals your fragility.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Years ago an overweight friend of mine started running (v.slowly). During the second run he hurt his back, so he stopped running because it was bad for him.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Someone tries to sprint after 20years of not running fast - they pull a hamstring&amp;hellip;&amp;ldquo;sprinting is dangerous at my age&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another person resumes running after a decade off, within two weeks they get achilles tendonitis, so they stop running and take up rucking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vo2-max</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/vo2-max/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/vo2-max/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Top milers have a VO2 max of 65 to 85 ml/kg/min. You can compare your VO2 max to the normal population using the chart below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Four factors which affect VO2 max:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Training: Of course!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Age: After around age 30, VO2 max declines at a rate of 1-2% per year&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gender: Males naturally have a higher VO2 max than females&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Altitude: The decrease in oxygen content at altitude reduces aerobic capacity&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weight loss</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/weight-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/weight-loss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1418653006933921793&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1418653006933921793&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A WAY TO LOSE FAT (My way - not the only way)): The worst way to lose fat is to eat less and go jogging – this hardly works and makes you a moron.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 Eating less makes you hungry – eventually you’ll cave-in.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2: Never jog. Never, ever, jog. Run or sprint but never jog. You want to get lean. right? Jogging won’t help you. Jogging hardly uses any calories (might as well walk).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Generally,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World class age &amp; training</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/world-class-age-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/guruAnaerobic/world-class-age-training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1476963919927422981.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HOW TO BE WORLD CLASS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I went from average to world-class – this is how I did it, and how you can do it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[Hint: Age is your friend]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is me in 1988 – 27yrs old. Slim, light build. Not long before this photo my girlfriend persuaded me to join a running club. I always liked running but never took it seriously, but I had taken part in a few ‘fun runs’. So I start training at an athletics track with a coach but also designing my own sessions and weekly/monthly programme. My first 800m race a few weeks after I joined was 2:14, ok, but nothing to write home about. Around about the same time I took part in an undulating 8mile New Year’s Day race (West Bay to Beaminster, in Dorset. UK) after a bet on New Year’s eve. I was 4th in 46:50 – again, ok – but nothing special. My VO2 max ~63ml/kg/min (Bleep test)Not long after (my late 20’s) I ran 4:21 for one mile, in The Westminster Mile open road race in London. I quickly got down to 2 minutes flat for 800m – a semi-decent &lt;em&gt;club level&lt;/em&gt; performance. With more (very hard) training, I took a few seconds off this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
