<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Cosmos on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Cosmos on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 THE SHORES OF THE COSMIC OCEAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/01_THE_SHORES_OF_THE_COSMIC_OCEAN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/01_THE_SHORES_OF_THE_COSMIC_OCEAN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first men to be created and formed were called the Sorcerer of Fatal Laughter, the Sorcerer of Night, Unkempt, and the Black Sorcerer…They were endowed with intelligence, they succeeded in knowing all that there is in the world. When they looked, instantly they saw all that is around them, and they contemplated in turn the arc of heaven and the round face of the earth…[Then the Creator said]: “They know all…what shall we do with them now? Let their sight reach only to that which is near; let them see only a little of the face of the earth!…Are they not by nature simple creatures of our making? Must they also be gods?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 ONE VOICE IN THE COSMIC FUGUE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/02_ONE_VOICE_IN_THE_COSMIC_FUGUE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/02_ONE_VOICE_IN_THE_COSMIC_FUGUE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Probably all the organic beings which have ever lived on this earth have descended from some one primordial form, into which life was first breathed.… There is grandeur in this view of life…that, whilst this planet has gone cycling on according to the fixed law of gravity, from so simple a beginning endless forms most beautiful and most wonderful have been, and are being, evolved.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—Charles Darwin, &lt;em&gt;The Origin of Species&lt;/em&gt;, 1859&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 THE HARMONY OF WORLDS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/03_THE_HARMONY_OF_WORLDS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/03_THE_HARMONY_OF_WORLDS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We do not ask for what useful purpose the birds do sing, for song is their pleasure since they were created for singing. Similarly, we ought not to ask why the human mind troubles to fathom the secrets of the heavens.… The diversity of the phenomena of Nature is so great, and the treasures hidden in the heavens so rich, precisely in order that the human mind shall never be lacking in fresh nourishment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 HEAVEN AND HELL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/04_HEAVEN_AND_HELL/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/04_HEAVEN_AND_HELL/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The doors of heaven and hell are adjacent and identical.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—Nikos Kazantzakis, &lt;em&gt;The Last Temptation of Christ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Earth is a lovely and more or less placid place. Things change, but slowly. We can lead a full life and never personally encounter a natural disaster more violent than a storm. And so we become complacent, relaxed, unconcerned. But in the history of Nature, the record is clear. Worlds have been devastated. Even we humans have achieved the dubious technical distinction of being able to make our own disasters, both intentional and inadvertent. On the landscapes of other planets where the records of the past have been preserved, there is abundant evidence of major catastrophes. It is all a matter of time scale. An event that would be unthinkable in a hundred years may be inevitable in a hundred million. Even on the Earth, even in our own century, bizarre natural events have occurred.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 BLUES FOR A RED PLANET</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/05_BLUES_FOR_A_RED_PLANET/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/05_BLUES_FOR_A_RED_PLANET/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the orchards of the gods, he watches the canals…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;—Enuma Elish&lt;/em&gt;, Sumer, c. 2500 B.C.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A man that is of Copernicus’ Opinion, that this Earth of ours is a Planet, carry’d round and enlightn’d by the Sun, like the rest of them, cannot but sometimes have a fancy…that the rest of the Planets have their Dress and Furniture, nay and their Inhabitants too as well as this Earth of ours.… But we were always apt to conclude, that ’twas in vain to enquire after what Nature had been pleased to do there, seeing there was no likelihood of ever coming to an end of the Enquiry…but a while ago, thinking somewhat seriously on this matter (not that I count my self quicker sighted than those great Men [of the past], but that I had the happiness to live after most of them) me thoughts the Enquiry was not so impracticable nor the way so stopt up with Difficulties, but that there was very good room left for probable Conjectures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 TRAVELERS’ TALES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/06_TRAVELERS_TALES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/06_TRAVELERS_TALES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do there exist many worlds, or is there but a single world? This is one of the most noble and exalted questions in the study of Nature.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—Albertus Magnus, thirteenth century&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We may mount from this dull Earth, and viewing it from on high, consider whether Nature has laid out all her cost and finery upon this small speck of Dirt. So, like Travellers into other distant countries, we shall be better able to judge of what’s done at home, know how to make a true estimate of, and set its own value upon every thing. We shall be less apt to admire what this World calls great, shall nobly despise those Trifles the generality of Men set their Affections on, when we know that there are a multitude of such Earths inhabited and adorn’d as well as our own.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 THE BACKBONE OF NIGHT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/07_THE_BACKBONE_OF_NIGHT/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/07_THE_BACKBONE_OF_NIGHT/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I would rather understand one cause than be King of Persia.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—Democritus of Abdera&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If a faithful account was rendered of Man’s ideas upon Divinity, he would be obliged to acknowledge, that for the most part the word “gods” has been used to express the concealed, remote, unknown causes of the effects he witnessed; that he applies this term when the spring of the natural, the source of known causes, ceases to be visible: as soon as he loses the thread of these causes, or as soon as his mind can no longer follow the chain, he solves the difficulty, terminates his research, by ascribing it to his gods…When, therefore, he ascribes to his gods the production of some phenomenon…does he, in fact, do any thing more than substitute for the darkness of his own mind, a sound to which he has been accustomed to listen with reverential awe?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 TRAVELS IN SPACE AND TIME</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/08_TRAVELS_IN_SPACE_AND_TIME/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/08_TRAVELS_IN_SPACE_AND_TIME/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have loved the stars too fondly to be fearful of the night.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—Tombstone epitaph of two amateur astronomers&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rising and falling of the surf is produced in part by tides. The Moon and the Sun are far away. But their gravitational influence is very real and noticeable back here on Earth. The beach reminds us of space. Fine sand grains, all more or less uniform in size, have been produced from larger rocks through ages of jostling and rubbing, abrasion and erosion, again driven through waves and weather by the distant Moon and Sun. The beach also reminds us of time. The world is much older than the human species.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 THE LIVES OF THE STARS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/09_THE_LIVES_OF_THE_STARS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/09_THE_LIVES_OF_THE_STARS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We had the sky, up there, all speckled with stars, and we used to lay on our backs and look up at them, and discuss about whether they was made, or only just happened.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—Mark Twain, &lt;em&gt;Huckleberry Finn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have…a terrible need…shall I say the word?…of religion. Then I go out at night and paint the stars.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—Vincent van Gogh&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To make an apple pie, you need wheat, apples, a pinch of this and that, and the heat of the oven. The ingredients are made of molecules—sugar, say, or water. The molecules, in turn, are made of atoms—carbon, oxygen, hydrogen and a few others. Where do these atoms come from? Except for hydrogen, they are all made in stars. A star is a kind of cosmic kitchen inside which atoms of hydrogen are cooked into heavier atoms. Stars condense from interstellar gas and dust, which are composed mostly of hydrogen. But the hydrogen was made in the Big Bang, the explosion that began the Cosmos. If you wish to make an apple pie from scratch, you must first invent the universe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 THE EDGE OF FOREVER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/10_THE_EDGE_OF_FOREVER/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/10_THE_EDGE_OF_FOREVER/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a way on high, conspicuous in the clear heavens, called the Milky Way, brilliant with its own brightness. By it the gods go to the dwelling of the great Thunderer and his royal abode…Here the famous and mighty inhabitants of heaven have their homes. This is the region which I might make bold to call the Palatine [Way] of the Great Sky.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—Ovid, &lt;em&gt;Metamorphoses&lt;/em&gt; (Rome, first century)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some foolish men declare that a Creator made the world. The doctrine that the world was created is ill-advised, and should be rejected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 THE PERSISTENCE OF MEMORY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/11_THE_PERSISTENCE_OF_MEMORY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/11_THE_PERSISTENCE_OF_MEMORY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that the destinies of Heaven and Earth have been fixed;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Trench and canal have been given their proper course;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The banks of the Tigris and the Euphrates&lt;br&gt;&#xA;have been established;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;What else shall we do?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;What else shall we create?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Oh Anunaki, you great gods of the sky,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;what else shall we do?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—The Assyrian account of the creation of Man, 800 B.C.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When he, whoever of the gods it was, had thus arranged in order and resolved that chaotic mass, and reduced it, thus resolved, to cosmic parts, he first moulded the Earth into the form of a mighty ball so that it might be of like form on every side…And, that no region might be without its own forms of animate life, the stars and divine forms occupied the floor of heaven, the sea fell to the shining fishes for their home, Earth received the beasts, and the mobile air the birds…Then Man was born:…though all other animals are prone, and fix their gaze upon the earth, he gave to Man an uplifted face and bade him stand erect and turn his eyes to heaven.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 ENCYCLOPAEDIA GALACTICA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/12_ENCYCLOPAEDIA_GALACTICA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/12_ENCYCLOPAEDIA_GALACTICA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“What are you? From where did you come? I have never seen anything like you.” The Creator Raven looked at Man and was…surprised to find that this strange new being was so much like himself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—An Eskimo creation myth&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The author of Nature…has made it impossible for us to have any communication from this earth with the other great bodies of the universe, in our present state; and it is highly possible that he has likewise cut off all communication betwixt the other planets, and betwixt the different systems.… We observe, in all of them, enough to raise our curiosity, but not to satisfy it…It does not appear to be suitable to the wisdom that shines throughout all nature, to suppose that we should see so far, and have our curiosity so much raised…only to be disappointed at the end…This, therefore, naturally leads us to consider our present state as only the dawn or beginning of our existence, and as a state of preparation or probation for farther advancement.…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 WHO SPEAKS FOR EARTH?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/13_WHO_SPEAKS_FOR_EARTH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/13_WHO_SPEAKS_FOR_EARTH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To what purpose should I trouble myself in searching out the secrets of the stars, having death or slavery continually before my eyes?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—A question put to Pythagoras by Anaximenes (c. 600 B.C.),&lt;br&gt;&#xA;according to Montaigne&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How vast those Orbs must be, and how inconsiderable this Earth, the Theatre upon which all our mighty Designs, all our Navigations, and all our Wars are transacted, is when compared to them. A very fit consideration, and matter of Reflection, for those Kings and Princes who sacrifice the Lives of so many People, only to flatter their Ambition in being Masters of some pitiful corner of this small Spot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
