<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;APPENDIX on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/APPENDIX/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;APPENDIX on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/APPENDIX/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Reductio ad Absurdum and the Square Root of Two</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/APPENDIX/01_Reductio_ad_Absurdum_and_the_Square_Root_of_Two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/APPENDIX/01_Reductio_ad_Absurdum_and_the_Square_Root_of_Two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The original Pythagorean argument on the irrationality of the square root of 2 depended on a kind of argument called &lt;em&gt;reductio ad absurdum&lt;/em&gt;, a reduction to absurdity: we assume the truth of a statement, follow its consequences and come upon a contradiction, thereby establishing its falsity. To take a modern example, consider the aphorism by the great twentieth-century physicist, Niels Bohr: “The opposite of every great idea is another great idea.” If the statement were true, its consequences might be at least a little perilous. For example, consider the opposite of the Golden Rule, or proscriptions against lying or “Thou shalt not kill.” So let us consider whether Bohr’s aphorism is itself a great idea. If so, then the converse statement, “The opposite of every great idea is not a great idea,” must also be true. Then we have reached a &lt;em&gt;reductio ad absurdum&lt;/em&gt;. If the converse statement is false, the aphorism need not detain us long, since it stands self-confessed as not a great idea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 The Five Pythagorean Solids</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/APPENDIX/02_The_Five_Pythagorean_Solids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/APPENDIX/02_The_Five_Pythagorean_Solids/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A regular polygon (Greek for “many-angled”) is a two-dimensional figure with some number, n, of equal sides. So n = 3 is an equilateral triangle, n = 4 is a square, n = 5 is a pentagon, and so on. A polyhedron (Greek for “many-sided”) is a three-dimensional figure, all of whose faces are polygons: a cube, for example, with 6 squares for faces. A simple polyhedron, or regular solid, is one with no holes in it. Fundamental to the work of the Pythagoreans and of Johannes Kepler was the fact that there can be 5 and only 5 regular solids. The easiest proof comes from a relationship discovered much later by Descartes and by Leonhard Euler which relates the number of faces, F, the number of edges, E, and the number of corners or vertices, V, of a regular solid:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
