<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;3 The Global Awakening: 1262–1962 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/3_The_Global_Awakening_12621962/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;3 The Global Awakening: 1262–1962 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/3_The_Global_Awakening_12621962/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>08 Khubilai Khan and the New Mongol Empire</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/3_The_Global_Awakening_12621962/08_Khubilai_Khan_and_the_New_Mongol_Empi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/3_The_Global_Awakening_12621962/08_Khubilai_Khan_and_the_New_Mongol_Empi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This Great Khan is the mightiest man, whether in&lt;br&gt;&#xA;respects of subjects or of territory or of treasure.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MARCO POLO&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;KHUBILAI KHAN’S GENIUS DERIVED from his recognition that he could not conquer all of China by mere force, no matter how large his army or sophisticated his weapons. Even without the military skills of his grandfather, he had clearly outsmarted everyone in his family. He possessed a keen strategic talent and the ability not merely to have good ideas but to implement them as well; he applied these skills to the management of his territory and, most important, to its expansion toward the south. In the end, he proved able to achieve through public politics what his grandfather had not been able to achieve through brute force—the conquest and unification of all China, the most populous country on earth. He won over the population by skillful manipulation of public opinion, in which martial prowess was an important, but not exclusive, factor. He built a Chinese capital, took Chinese names, created a Chinese dynasty, and set up a Chinese administration. He won control of China by appearing to be more Chinese than the Chinese, or at least more Chinese than the Sung.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 Their Golden Light</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/3_The_Global_Awakening_12621962/09_Their_Golden_Light/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/3_The_Global_Awakening_12621962/09_Their_Golden_Light/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The artists of China and Paris vied with each other&lt;br&gt;&#xA;in the service of the great Khan.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;EDWARD GIBBON&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DURING MASS ONE DAY in the winter of 1287–1288, King Edward I of England rose up from his throne to stand in honor of Rabban Bar Sawma, the newly arrived envoy from the Mongol Emperor Khubilai Khan. When he reached the court of the English king, Rabban Bar Sawma had probably traveled farther than any official envoy in history, covering some seven thousand miles on the circuitous land route from the Mongol capital, through the major cities of the Middle East, and on to the capitals of Europe. King Edward stood before the envoy not to offer submission to the Mongol Khan, but to accept bread from the hand of the Mongol envoy as part of the Christian sacrament of communion. Since the early European envoys to the Mongols had been priests, Khubilai Khan had chosen Rabban Bar Sawma because, although a loyal Mongol, he was also a Christian priest, albeit of the Assyrian rite.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 The Empire of Illusion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/3_The_Global_Awakening_12621962/10_The_Empire_of_Illusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/3_The_Global_Awakening_12621962/10_The_Empire_of_Illusion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When Christopher Columbus set sail from Spain in 1492,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;he was heading for Cathay, the land of the Great Khan.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DAVID MORGAN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IN 1332, CONFUSION, ALARM, and pain ran amok in the pleasure palaces of Xanadu, the Mongol summer capital of Shangdu. The royal family remained there well past the end of summer, and despite efforts to keep the crisis secret, it became apparent that the Mongol rulers were in a turmoil so deep that it threatened continuation of the dynasty. The surviving information offers muddled accounts of what was happening, but it appears that the office of the Great Khan bounced from brother to brother and from father to son in a flurry of assassinations, disappearances, and inexplicable deaths. From 1328 to 1332, at least four members of the Golden Family occupied the throne, and one, the seven-year-old Rinchinbal Khan, had it for only two months in 1332. Fear gripped everyone. In the household, everyone from the young to the old, from the lowest servant to the Great Khan, seemed in danger of dying a horrible death.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
