<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/hispanic/americas/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/hispanic/americas/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bukele war 2024</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/hispanic/americas/articles/bukele-war_2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/hispanic/americas/articles/bukele-war_2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BUKELE&amp;rsquo;S WAR FOR PEACE&#xA;By Benjamin Braddock · 7 February 2024&#xA;How El Salvador Fought the Gangs and Won&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2019&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;El Salvador’s new president Nayib Bukele faces a staggering challenge. In office barely a month, his country is in international headlines again. For decades, El Salvador had never made international headlines because of good news. This time was no different. A Salvadoran father and daughter had drowned in the Rio Grande attempting to cross into the United States. Immigration activists in the US were using the tragedy to accuse the Trump administration of endangering migrants by pacing the number of asylum seekers being processed at the border. Instead of going along with blaming the US, or suggesting that perhaps the US government should send them more aid, as a typical developing-world politician would do, the young president had taken the responsibility squarely on his own shoulders:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“We can speak blame to any other country, but what about our blame? I mean, what country did they flee? Did they flee the United States? They fled El Salvador. They fled our country. It is our fault. We haven’t been able to provide anything, not a decent job, not a decent school.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
