<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;P Jenkins on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/pjenkins/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;P Jenkins on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/pjenkins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Christian apostasy- Jenkins</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/pjenkins/pjenkings_christian-apostacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/pjenkins/pjenkings_christian-apostacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I posted about the deadly Japanese persecution of Christians in the thirty years or so after 1614, and how this violence effectively destroyed organized Christianity in that nation. In 2014, we are commemorating the four hundredth anniversary of the beginning of the worst of the persecution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In describing Japanese acts against the Christians, I am not of course denying that contemporary Christians could be just as brutal in their way. Coincidentally, 1614 also marks the culmination of Spain’s expulsion of its Moriscos, former Muslims who had accepted conversion to Christianity. In Germany, meanwhile, the same year saw anti-Jewish riots. Intolerance, obviously, was the prerogative of no one faith.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Destroying Japanese Xtianity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/pjenkins/destroying_japanese_christianity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/pjenkins/destroying_japanese_christianity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2014, it is exactly four hundred years since the start of the horrific persecution that destroyed the once flourishing church in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we think of persecutions on this scale, we normally tend to set them in an ancient or medieval context. The world of 1614, though, was in some ways remarkably modern, not least in terms of its literature and culture. Shakespeare had just retired, and Cervantes was about to publish the second volume of Don Quijote. Colonial North America already existed in crude form: St. Augustine, Santa Fe, Jamestown and Quebec City were already in existence, and the Dutch would soon be settling New Amsterdam. Yet contemporary events in eastern Asia seem to take us back to the earliest church.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
