<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;14 The Silver Age A D 14-96 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/14_The_Silver_Age_A_D_14-96/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;14 The Silver Age A D 14-96 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/14_The_Silver_Age_A_D_14-96/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 THE DILETTANTES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/14_The_Silver_Age_A_D_14-96/01_THE_DILETTANTES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/14_The_Silver_Age_A_D_14-96/01_THE_DILETTANTES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TRADITION has given to Latin letters from A.D. 14 to 117 the name of Silver Age, implying a fall from the cultural excellence of the Augustan Age. Tradition is the voice of time, and time is the medium of selection; a cautious mind will respect their verdict, for only youth knows better than twenty centuries. We may be permitted, however, to suspend judgment, to give Lucan, Petronius, Seneca, the elder Pliny, Celsus, Statius, Martial, Quintilian—and, in later chapters, Tacitus, Juvenal, Pliny the Younger, and Epictetus—an unbiased hearing, and enjoy them as if we had never heard that they belonged to a decadent period. In every epoch something is decaying and something is growing. In epigram, satire, the novel, history, and philosophy the Silver Age marks the zenith of Roman literature, as it represents in realistic sculpture and mass architecture the climax of Roman art.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 PETRONIUS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/14_The_Silver_Age_A_D_14-96/02_PETRONIUS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/14_The_Silver_Age_A_D_14-96/02_PETRONIUS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are not certain—it is only the general opinion—that the Petronius whose &lt;em&gt;Satyricon&lt;/em&gt; still finds many readers was the Caius Petronius who died by Nero’s orders a year after Lucan. The book itself contains not a word to serve as a clue; and Tacitus, who describes the &lt;em&gt;arbiter elegantiarum&lt;/em&gt; with pithy eloquence, makes no mention of the disreputable masterpiece. Some forty epigrams are ascribed to a Petronius, including a line that almost sums up Lucretius: &lt;em&gt;primus in orbe deos fecit timor—“it&lt;/em&gt; was fear that first in the world made gods”;3 but these fragments too are silent about the author’s identity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 THE PHILOSOPHERS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/14_The_Silver_Age_A_D_14-96/03_THE_PHILOSOPHERS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/14_The_Silver_Age_A_D_14-96/03_THE_PHILOSOPHERS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this loose and complex age, when freedom was so limited and life was so free, philosophy flourished alongside of sensuality, and the two were not above joining hands. The decay of the native religion had left a moral vacuum which philosophy sought to fill. Parents sent their sons, and themselves often went, to hear the lectures of men who offered to provide a rational code of civilized conduct, or a formal dress for naked desire. Those who could afford it paid philosophers to live with them, partly as educators, partly as spiritual counselors, partly as learned company; so Augustus had Areus, consulted him on almost everything, and for his sake (if we may believe a ruler) was lenient to Alexandria. When Drusus died Livia called in “her husband’s philosopher”—so Seneca phrases it—“to help her bear her grief.”9 Nero, Trajan, and of course Aurelius had philosophers residing with them at court, as kings have chaplains now. In their last moments men would summon philosophers to chart their passing, as centuries later they would ask for a priest.10&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 SENECA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/14_The_Silver_Age_A_D_14-96/04_SENECA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/14_The_Silver_Age_A_D_14-96/04_SENECA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Stoic philosophy found its most doubtful expression in the life, its most perfect expression in the writings, of Lucius Annaeus Seneca. Born at Corduba about 4 B.C., he was soon taken to Rome, and received all the education available there. He imbibed rhetoric from his father, Stoicism from Attalus, Pythagoreanism from Sotion, and practical politics from his aunt’s husband, the Roman governor of Egypt. He tried vegetarianism for a year, then gave it up, but remained always abstemious in food and drink; he was a millionaire in his surroundings rather than in his habits. He suffered so much from asthma and weak lungs that he often contemplated suicide. He practiced law, and was chosen quaestor about A.D. 33. Two years later he married Pompeia Paulina, with whom he lived in remarkable continuity until his death.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 ROMAN SCIENCE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/14_The_Silver_Age_A_D_14-96/05_ROMAN_SCIENCE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/14_The_Silver_Age_A_D_14-96/05_ROMAN_SCIENCE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Therefore we have given him too much space; nevertheless, we have not finished with him yet, for he was also a scientist. In those fertile years between his retirement and his death he amused himself with &lt;em&gt;Quaestiones Naturales,&lt;/em&gt; and sought natural explanations of rain, hail, snow, wind, comets, rainbows, earthquakes, rivers, springs. In his drama &lt;em&gt;Medea&lt;/em&gt; he had suggested the existence of another continent beyond the Atlantic.60 With similar intuition, contemplating the overwhelming multitude of stars, he wrote, “How many an orb, moving in the depths of space, has never yet reached the eyes of men!”61 And he adds, clairvoyantly, “How many things our sons will learn that we cannot now suspect!—what others await centuries when our names will be forgotten! . . . Our descendants will marvel at our ignorance.”62 We do. Seneca, though always eloquent, adds little to Aristotle and Aratus, and borrows abundantly from Poseidonius. He believes in divination despite Cicero, lapses into ludicrous teleology despite Lucretius, and interrupts his science at every turn to inculcate morality; he passes skillfully from mussels to luxury, and from comets to degeneration. The Fathers of the Church liked this mixture of meteorology and morals, and made the &lt;em&gt;Quaestiones Naturales&lt;/em&gt; the most popular textbook of science in the Middle Ages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 ROMAN MEDICINE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/14_The_Silver_Age_A_D_14-96/06_ROMAN_MEDICINE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/14_The_Silver_Age_A_D_14-96/06_ROMAN_MEDICINE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;They did better in medicine. Medical science too they borrowed from the Greeks, but they formulated it well, and applied it ably to personal and public hygiene. Rome, almost surrounded by marshes, and subject to mephitic floods, had particular need of public sanitation. About the second century B.C. we hear of malaria in Rome; the anopheles mosquito had settled down in the Pontine swamps.95 Gout spread as luxury increased; the younger Pliny tells how his friend Corellius Rufus suffered its pains from his thirty-third to his sixty-seventh year before committing suicide, just to have the pleasure of outliving by one day “that brigand Domitian.”96 Some passages in the Roman satirists suggest the appearance of syphilis in the first century A.D.97 Great epidemics swept central Italy in 23 B.C., A.D. 65, 79, and &lt;em&gt;166.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 QUINTILIAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/14_The_Silver_Age_A_D_14-96/07_QUINTILIAN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/14_The_Silver_Age_A_D_14-96/07_QUINTILIAN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Vespasian established a state professorship of rhetoric in Rome he appointed to it a man who, like so many authors of this Silver Age, was of Spanish birth. Marcus Fabius Quintilianus was born at Calagurris (A.D. 35?), went to Rome to study oratory, and opened a school of rhetoric there which numbered Tacitus and the younger Pliny among its pupils. Juvenal describes him in his prime as handsome, noble, wise, well bred, with a fine voice and delivery, and a senatorial dignity. In old age he retired to write for the guidance of his son the classic treatment of his subject, the &lt;em&gt;Institutio Oratoria&lt;/em&gt; (96).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 STATIUS AND MARTIAL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/14_The_Silver_Age_A_D_14-96/08_STATIUS_AND_MARTIAL/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/14_The_Silver_Age_A_D_14-96/08_STATIUS_AND_MARTIAL/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have left to the last two poets who belonged to the same epoch, sought the favor of the same emperor and the same patrons, and yet never mention each other: one the purest, the other the coarsest, poet in the history of imperial Rome. Publius Papinius Statius was the son of a Neapolitan poet and grammarian; his environment and his education gave him everything but money and genius. He lisped in numbers, startled &lt;em&gt;salons&lt;/em&gt; with poetical improvisations, and wrote an epic, the &lt;em&gt;Thebaid,&lt;/em&gt; on the war of the Seven against Thebes. We cannot read it today, for its movement is obstructed with dead gods, and its smooth verses have an overpowering &lt;em&gt;virtus dormitiva.&lt;/em&gt; But his contemporaries liked it; crowds gathered to hear him recite it in a Naples theater; they understood his mythological machinery, welcomed the delicacy of his sentiment, and found that his lines ran trippingly on the tongue. The judges in the Alban poetry contest gave him the first prize; rich men became his friends and helped him stave off penury;124 Domitian himself invited him to dinner in the &lt;em&gt;domus Flavia,&lt;/em&gt; and Statius repaid him by describing the palace as heaven and the Emperor as god.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
