<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;00 Meta on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/00_Meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;00 Meta on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/00_Meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Note about the Author</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/00_Meta/A_Note_about_the_Author/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/00_Meta/A_Note_about_the_Author/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Daniel L. Everett is Chair of the Department of Languages, Literatures, and Cultures at Illinois State University in Normal, Illinois. He has taught at the State University of Campinas, Brazil; the University of Pittsburgh; the University of North Dakota; and the University of Manchester. In addition he has been a visiting scientist at the Max Planck Institute and a visiting scholar at MIT. He has spent much of the last thirty years living with the Pirahãs and learning their language.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acknowledgments</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/00_Meta/Acknowledgments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/00_Meta/Acknowledgments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I would like to thank the people who have made the experiences recounted in this book and the writing of it possible. Foremost among all are the Pirahãs. They have taught me many things over the past decades of my life. Their brilliance, their beauty, their patience, their faithful friendship, and their love for me and my family have made my world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Next I would like to thank the employees of the Brazilian National Indian Foundation (FUNAI) in Pôrto Velho, especially Seu Osman and Seu Rómulo, for their support of my research for many years. Osman and I began working with Amazonian Indians at nearly the same time. I have always been impressed by his selfless dedication to the cause of Brazil’s Indians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contents</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/00_Meta/Contents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/00_Meta/Contents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Title Page&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dedication&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Epigraph&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some Notes on the Pirahã Language as Used in This Book&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Preface&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prologue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part One: LIFE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Discovering the World of the Pirahãs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The Amazon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The Cost of Discipleship&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Sometimes You Make Mistakes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Material Culture and the Absence of Ritual&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Families and Community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Nature and the Immediacy of Experience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. A Teenager Named Túkaaga: Murder and Society&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Land to Live Free&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Footnotes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/00_Meta/Footnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/00_Meta/Footnotes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;13-how-much-grammar-do-people-need&#34;&gt;13 How Much Grammar Do People Need?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*The concept of esoteric communication comes from work by Carol Thurston and by George Grace and Alison Wray. Its relevance to the analysis of Pirahã was first suggested in research by Jeanette Sakel and Eugenie Stapert, of the University of Manchester, England. Esoteric communication is communication that is used within, and partially defines, a well-defined group. Esoteric communication facilitates understanding because hearers are likely to anticipate what speakers are going to say in different situations. The language is not limited to old or predictable information, but that is the default. In fact, in Pirahã there is a special channel, as we have seen, musical speech, that is used for new information. This might explain the relative richness of both prosody and phonemes in musical speech—new information might require a slower rate of information and greater perceptibility in an esoteric group in the sense intended here. The linguist Tom Givon refers to a concept similar to esoteric communication in his phrase &lt;em&gt;society of intimates.&lt;/em&gt; By this felicitous expression, Givon refers to small groups of people who speak together frequently and form a culture group together. Such groups share a greater amount of implicit information than other groups, even other groups who speak the same language.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Return to text.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preface</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/00_Meta/Preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/00_Meta/Preface/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Science is not just about research teams in lab coats working under the direction of an eminent scientist. It can be pursued by lone individuals slogging it out in hard times and hard places—feeling lost and over their heads, yet challenged to bring new knowledge out of their difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is about scientific work of the latter type and about intellectual growth in the crucible of an Amazonian culture, living among the Pirahã (pee-da-HAN) Indians of Brazil. It is about them and the lessons they taught me, both scientific and personal, and how these new ideas changed my life profoundly and led me to live differently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prologue</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/00_Meta/Prologue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/00_Meta/Prologue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Look! There he is, Xigagaí, the spirit.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Yes, I can see him. He is threatening us.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Everybody, come see Xigagaí. Quickly! He is on the beach!”&lt;/em&gt; +++(5)+++&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I roused from my deep sleep, not sure if I was dreaming or hearing this conversation. It was 6:30 on a Saturday morning in August, the dry season of 1980. The sun was shining, but not yet too hot. A breeze was blowing up from the Maici River in front of my modest hut in a clearing on the bank. I opened my eyes and saw the palm thatch above me, its original yellow graying from years of dust and soot. My dwelling was flanked by two smaller Pirahã huts of similar construction, where lived Xahoábisi, Kóhoibiíihíai, and their families.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Notes on the Pirahã Language as Used in This Book</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/00_Meta/Some_Notes_on_the_Pirah_Langu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/00_Meta/Some_Notes_on_the_Pirah_Langu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although Pirahã has one of the smallest set of speech sounds (phonemes) known, it can still be very difficult to pronounce without a little help. Here is a rudimentary guide to pronunciation, using the writing system that my missionary predecessors to the Pirahãs, Arlo Heinrichs and Steve Sheldon, and I developed for the language.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;b&lt;/em&gt; Pronounced at the beginning of a word like the &lt;em&gt;m&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;em&gt;mama&lt;/em&gt;. Between the vowels &lt;em&gt;i&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;o&lt;/em&gt; it is pronounced as a trill, with the lips vibrating (as in some American children’s imitation of a car motor running). Elsewhere it is pronounced like the &lt;em&gt;b&lt;/em&gt; of &lt;em&gt;baby.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
