<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/pashto/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/pashto/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overblown native defence</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/pashto/articles/overblown-native-defence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/pashto/articles/overblown-native-defence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Something interesting to consider with the “graveyard of empires” rhetoric re:Afghanistan is that for a massive swath of its medieval history, it was ruled by Turkic rulers. Turk-Shahis, Ghazni, Ghor, Khilji, even Babur.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abdali was significant as a first native Pashtun ruler. This is what makes Ahmed Shah Abdali so honored in modern Afghanistan, as “Baba”, father of the nation; a native king who was able to unite his people to throw off prolonged foreign occupation of centuries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suren: Taliban v2 2021</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/pashto/articles/suren-taliban-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/pashto/articles/suren-taliban-v2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, here is my take on what the Taliban will do next. Forward looking statements, so usual disclaimers apply.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Taliban are Deobandis, which means their political goals are local in nature. What they want is to establish a pure Islamic State, one untainted by secular decadence a la Pakistan. The goal of Pakistan was to establish a modern nation-state for subcontinent Muslims. The goal of Taliban is to establish a proper Islamic State in Afghanistan, recover the Pashtun territory across the Durand and prepare for Ghazwa e Hind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
