<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०१ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०१ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pyrotechnics in the gloom</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/01/2005-01-06_pyrotechnics-in-the-gloom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/01/2005-01-06_pyrotechnics-in-the-gloom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/01/06/pyrotechnics-in-the-gloom/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The day was enveloped in a forbidding gloom, and the air reeked with&#xA;monsoonal decay, even as the Hindu civilization in its downward slide.&#xA;The studious youth busied themselves with the most mundane of chemical&#xA;experiments. Some were vigorously blowing into a charcoal lump with the&#xA;hope of seeing a bead of lead. Yet others were soulfully bubbling a foul&#xA;smelling miasma of sulfuretted hydrogen through a tube and waiting for a&#xA;precipitate to form with bated breath. Still others were furiously&#xA;inscribing in the most pleasant scripts the notes scrawled on the&#xA;chalk-board by the sanguine lecturer. Lambashiras, Blackie and others&#xA;were humbly bowing to a lecturer to get his stamp approval on their&#xA;diligently copied notes. Our outer mind mindlessly imitated the deeds&#xA;done by the rest of this flotsam mass. In performing our karma we&#xA;reached the triple waisted Kipps flask to bubble the foul gas through&#xA;our tube. Even as we reached there comely Mis-creant (we called her&#xA;that, so we shall refer to her thus) from her sub-section of the closed&#xA;system also arrived at the fetid source of the gas. She joined the line&#xA;along with me as there was an orderly queue for the gas. We looked at&#xA;each other with a tired expression and seemed to almost hold a&#xA;conversation within our minds without any words. We almost&#xA;simultaneously seemed to turn to the large block of sodium that was&#xA;lying in the kerosene. Mis-creant cut out a decent cube of the block&#xA;when nobody watched. We smiled at each other; then I picked up the cube&#xA;of Na and threw it into a puddle out of the window. There was a&#xA;tremendous explosive flash, very like the last flash of Essen Taiji&#xA;lighting up the decadent Mongol horizon on the steppes. Our plebeian&#xA;bystanders were immensely shaken even as the ignorant Hindu is rudely&#xA;awakened from his joyous complacence by a violent Abrahmist. We felt a&#xA;great sense of satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The gaviShTi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/01/2005-01-04_the-gavishti/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/01/2005-01-04_the-gavishti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/01/04/the-gavishti/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;O indra and viShNu come bear us aid as you had done to the ikShvAku in the great gaviShTi for wealth and glory.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;None among men knows his own life’s duration: bear us in safety over these through these battles.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our foemen trimitvAnt, biDAla-smashru and vyuptakesha assembing their troops rushed towards us with their sword and upraised and spears pointed forward. We who had seen many grim battles, with arrows having lodged themselves in our armor, but having failed to slay us, marched forward for the final the showdown. trimitvAnt approached us from the side with his javelin aloft. We saw him through the corner of our eye and moved ahead as though we did not see him. He was certain that we were in his hand and hurled his javelin at us. We were just waiting for this. We ducked and it flew over us and even missed out flankers and hissed into the ground. We suddenly wheeled around and lassoed trimitvAnt with our pAsha. He was unhorsed and reeled to the ground. Our men struck him with their musalas and he was history. An arrow fired by biDAla-smashru hit our helmet and glanced away. We shot back hitting him on his chest and reeled under the impact though his armor saved him. vyuptakesha shot our horse but its armor absorbed the shot. By then biDAla-smashru had reached us with an upraised club. We dodged the heave and leveled a massive sword-blow at him. He narrowly escaped it and fled away with his co-conspirator, disappearing into the eastern forest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kuriltai and other affairs</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/01/2005-01-01_kuriltai-and-other-affairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/01/2005-01-01_kuriltai-and-other-affairs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/01/01/kuriltai-and-other-affairs/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ever querulous vAtavyAdi kept coming up with more of his ideas that were often of little value. We appointed him vidUShaka, and asked him to serve in that capacity without much further ado.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We were asked to hold a kuriltai with the circle of further clansmen and allies. They first grumbled that we had not made any progress on front #2 in the great war. We bluntly told them that if they needed my council they should serve me appropriately or just leave me alone. I made it clear to them that they should come to me, like jAnashruti going to raikva, and not the other way around. They grumbled as before, but then resorted to serve me with due respect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
