<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०६ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/06/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०६ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/06/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Saved from the mAraNa prayoga by the yakShiNi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/06/2006-06-27_saved-from-the-marana-prayoga-by-the-yakshini/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/06/2006-06-27_saved-from-the-marana-prayoga-by-the-yakshini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/06/27/saved-from-the-marana-prayoga-by-the-yakshini/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have seen the hits of a few mAraNa prayoga-s in the past but never&#xA;had we seen vaisvasvata’s agents more closely than now. Some how the&#xA;Northern journey is an opportunity for the mAraNa of the vairis. We were&#xA;weakened by the effects of the tapta prayoga but were still completely&#xA;functional. The night before we had performed the adhara-kulAnanda&#xA;rahas-tarpaNa of the beautiful but terrifying yakShiNi&#xA;nIlalohita-mekhalA. We fatefully ventured out to the AvarNa-patha and&#xA;were making our way for the midday oblations to savitA, when without&#xA;warning we were struck by the terrifying devastambhini. The blow was so&#xA;terrifying and so sudden that we simply could not protect ourselves all&#xA;our varman-s were demolished thoroughly. We were being literally drowned&#xA;in the waters and could see yama’s agents bearing us away. For several&#xA;minutes we were trashed by the waters of vaitaraNI, any moment sliding&#xA;towards our jalasamAdhi. We just then realized that the only one who&#xA;could physically bear us out of this deadly mAraNa prayoga was the great&#xA;yakShiNi, nIlalohita-mekhalA, hovering yonder. We piteously called for&#xA;her help. A fragment of the mahAstra hit her leg, but she ably dodged it&#xA;and still came to our aid. nIlalohita-mekhalA gave us her arm, and&#xA;holding to it like mArkaNdeya to shiva, we struggled out of vaitaraNi&#xA;with the yama dUtas lashing at us. But the great nIlalohita-mekhalA grew&#xA;immensely heavy and pulled us out from the frothing abyss with her&#xA;ivory-hued creeper-like arm endowed with the might of 800 elephants. We&#xA;were bruised, bleeding and covered with the mire of yama’s flow, but we&#xA;had been pulled out by the most beautiful nIlalohita-mekhalA from what&#xA;would have been certain death. While we are reeling from the effects of&#xA;this mAraNa that came closest to fruition, we are happy we are alive.&#xA;You never know when the trikoNoddhbhava mahA-yakShiNi can save you,&#xA;hence her sweet-bitter sAdhana is never in nought.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The great battle of the ghR^itagaNa cha dvyAmlaka</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/06/2006-06-21_the-great-battle-of-the-ghritagana-cha-dvyamlaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/06/2006-06-21_the-great-battle-of-the-ghritagana-cha-dvyamlaka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/06/21/the-great-battle-of-the-ghritagana-cha-dvyamlaka/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While we were still being relentless hammered by the shiva-yuvatI of&#xA;mahArudra, we decided to attend to the long-standing battle where the&#xA;young yoddha was faltering. It was the glorious quest of what was&#xA;code-named: “ghR^itagaNa cha dvyAmlaka”, a high prize that I had earned&#xA;for since my earliest days in the senAmukha, in the halcyon teens,&#xA;filled with youthful intemperance. Now as a veteran of many bloody wars&#xA;in which the devas had seen us through, I was still being rebuffed on&#xA;that front. But then I remembered that R had prophesized long back that&#xA;the path would not be easy. We called that most attractive jewel of the&#xA;strI-loka, Hayasthanika to aid us in the battle. While Hayasthanika in&#xA;all due fairness was not capable of wielding the heaviest of weapons in&#xA;the senAmukha, she definitely had a whole array of skills that like&#xA;those of susheNa of the vAnaras that could be useful in completion of&#xA;certain battles. We were hard-pressed by the rAkShasi that was&#xA;dispatched against us, and she was threatening us with a chakra. Our&#xA;young yoddha, however made a critical incision in the ranks with his&#xA;excellent fighting early in the day. We had only a few hours to settle&#xA;the battle and were simply not finding touch. Then we straightened our&#xA;arm and lifted the bow invoking the deva-s to guide our astra-s. We&#xA;fired a series of arrows into the enemy chinks, even as our young yoddha&#xA;strategically made use of Hayasthanika’s charms. I noticed however that&#xA;they were faltering late in the day under our shatru’s counter-attack&#xA;and felt they might not last long. Our yoddha was in disarray himself&#xA;seeing Hayasthanika on the retreat. It was at that point that we struck&#xA;with series of rapid thrusts into the enemy ranks. Suddenly, by&#xA;kArtikeya’s aid the shatru was exposed and we decapitated him. Our flag&#xA;flew over “ghR^itagaNa cha dvyAmlaka”. We beheld Hayasthanika in the&#xA;blaze of victory: her sight was verily like the nectar flowing from the&#xA;heavenly soma cup; her charms like the octet of mayura. The brief&#xA;respite it gave from the hammering of the adverse edge of the&#xA;downward-turning chakra of the kali age was like the single rain shower&#xA;in the Namibian desert.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The aspirants</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/06/2006-06-12_the-aspirants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/06/2006-06-12_the-aspirants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/06/12/the-aspirants/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;RM had a charismatic appearance and could present a himself as an&#xA;intellectual. He was not a svayaM prakAsha but picked up knowledge from&#xA;different generally reticent sources and presented to his circle of&#xA;largely ignorant friends. He widely lectured to youngsters about the&#xA;Hindu ways of mythology, philosophy, exercise and ritual performance.&#xA;Most of his crowd was bored and clueless, forced to attend RM’s earnest&#xA;lectures at their equally clueless parents behest. N ran a similar show&#xA;of teaching the veda, more as a socializing process, also participated&#xA;in the above sessions. But RM disapproved of his teaching the veda in&#xA;such a non-serious way but still enjoyed the social intercourse N&#xA;generated through his activities. I kept out of all of this despite&#xA;several requests because I dwelt in the middle of the rasArNava as the&#xA;sAkShi but not the kartA. The one linked to me gave me input to the&#xA;outer social world, these were sthUla, or mundane links. But R was the&#xA;link to the sUkShma or the tattvas that we sought to witness as the&#xA;sAkShi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bolt</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/06/2006-06-11_the-bolt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/06/2006-06-11_the-bolt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/06/11/the-bolt/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The news reached us that rakShohA agni had cleared 3 of the vR^itra and&#xA;nirR^iti had gone back her way. We thought the clouds were clearing. But&#xA;Fourier’s man, who was feared as shUravarman, got the news too. Never&#xA;had he been intimidated thus or his men faced such uchChATana-s. He&#xA;accordingly released the deadly “crane arrow”. Never was balance between&#xA;life and death so clear.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Past mid-night we faced the terror of the crane. Never had anything been&#xA;so directly threatening in our existence. As yudhiShThira said when yama&#xA;visit yonder man we think he is not for us, but when he comes your own&#xA;way we experience his real fear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
