<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;How I Became Hindu on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;How I Became Hindu on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00 FROM ARYA SAMAJ TO MAHATMA GANDHI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/00_ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/00_ch1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;from-arya-samaj-to-mahatma-gandhi&#34;&gt;FROM ARYA SAMAJ TO MAHATMA GANDHI&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(I promised this intellectual autobiography to Hashmat, some twenty&#xA;years ago. Hashmat wrote frequently in the Organiser under the general heading &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Pakistan X-Rayed&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. It is years since I lost track of him. But I never forgot my promise. I wonder what I would have written twenty years ago. I wonder also how this story will shape if I wait for another twenty years. And I do not know what its worth is today. But I am impelled to write it because in today&amp;rsquo;s India it is not sufficient to be a Hindu by birth. Hindu society and culture are under attack from several quarters. One has to be a convinced and conscious Hindu to meet and survive that attack. One has to find one&amp;rsquo;s roots in Sanatana Dharma).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 FROM GANDHISM TO COMMUNISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/01_ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/01_ch2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;from-gandhism-to-communism&#34;&gt;FROM GANDHISM TO COMMUNISM&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had a brief encounter with the Sthanakavasi Svetambara sect of Jainism also, at about the same time. The school in which I was a student was a Svetambara Jam school. The relative with whom I stayed was also a Jain. There was a daily period in our school for teaching the elements of Jain dharma. But the Jam community which I saw from close quarters was too decadent, self centred, and morose for my taste. The lectures of some Jain sadhus which I attended in the local sthanaka (Jain hermitage) were narrow and sectarian, and never made any sense to me. What scandalised me most was the Jain version of Sri Krishna. He was portrayed as a crook. I was told that Sri Krishna had descended into the fifth hell for the killings in which he had indulged and that he was still there. I had to wait for years before I came to understand Bhagvan Mahavira and Jainism via my understanding of the Buddha and Buddhism. Both of them, I found, had scaled the same Himalayan heights of the soul.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 SEEDS THAT WERE TO SPROUT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/02_ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/02_ch3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;seeds-that-were-to-sprout&#34;&gt;SEEDS THAT WERE TO SPROUT&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Four years after leaving college I was ready to join the Communist Party of India when it declared war on the newly born Republic of India in February 1948. I conveyed my decision to my friend Ram Swarup, whom I had met after leaving college and who was to exercise a decisive influence on my intellectual evolution. He wrote back immediately: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;You are too intelligent not to become a Communist. But you are also too intelligent to remain one for long.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 SOME INTERESTING ENCOUNTERS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/03_ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/03_ch4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;some-interesting-encounters&#34;&gt;SOME INTERESTING ENCOUNTERS&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My plight was pretty serious after I left college. I was now a married man and the father of a son. There was a family to support which included my parents in die village. But I had not a penny in my pocket. I gave up the only job I could get as a clerk in the Central Secretariat after exactly 65 days because I was ashamed to be a cog in the British imperialist machine. My supreme aspiration was to be a lecturer in some college. But every interview to which I was called ended with the employers pointing out that I had no previous experience of teaching!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 CLOSE TO THE COMMUNIST PARTY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/04_ch5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/04_ch5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;close-to-the-communist-party&#34;&gt;CLOSE TO THE COMMUNIST PARTY&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I saw quite a bit of the Great Calcutta Killing of August 16-17, 1946 with my own eyes. There were a large number of dead bodies lying on the streets. There were many more floating down the Hooghly. I saw an extensive destruction of private and public property by fire as well as by mob fury. The death and desolation all around moved me to despair about human nature itself. But I did not try to find the causes of this holocaust or to fix its responsibility on the political movement which had provoked it. Instead, I wrote a long article, The Devil Dance In Calcutta, in which I held both Hindus and Muslims equally responsible for this meaningless massacre. The article was circulated in a cyclostyled newsletter which a circle of friends was publishing from Delhi. Some of these friends appreciated the graphic picture I had drawn and the literary flourishes I had displayed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 RAM SWARUP TO THE RESCUE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/05_ch6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/05_ch6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ram-swarup-to-the-rescue&#34;&gt;RAM SWARUP TO THE RESCUE&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was present in the Second Party Conference of the Communist Party of India which was held in the Maidan at Calcutta in February, 1948. It was some time before this Conference that B. T. Ranadive had taken over from P.C. Joshi the General Secretaryship of the CPI. The Ranadive line, as it came to be known in India, was an adoption of the international Communist line laid down by Stalin through the mouth of his minion, Zhdanov, in September 1947.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 BACK TO SQUARE ONE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/06_ch7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/06_ch7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;back-to-square-one&#34;&gt;BACK TO SQUARE ONE&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was back to square one. My faith in Gandhism had lost the battle to Marxism. Now I was no longer a Marxist. I asked myself again and again: Where do I go from here?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The business of life can go on very well without an ideological frame of reference. One eats and mates and sleeps and makes a living. One reads books and papers and gossips and goes about passing conventional judgments on current events, One has a family, a profession, a circle of friends, and some hobby to keep one occupied in leisure time. One grows old, collects one&amp;rsquo;s own share of diseases, and looks back with anguish towards earlier days when one was young and active. For most of us ordinary mortals, this is the whole of human life. We take very seriously our successes and failures and our loves and hates, without spending a thought on what it is all about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 RETURN TO MY SPIRTUAL HOME</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/07_ch8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/07_ch8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;return-to-my-spirtual-home&#34;&gt;RETURN TO MY SPIRTUAL HOME&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had to leave Calcutta for good and return to Delhi on account of my health. I had spent twelve long years in that great and stormy centre of Bengali culture and politics. I had participated in Calcutta&amp;rsquo;s politics in a way. It was my misfortune that I did not drink equally deep at the fount of Bengali culture which had, in the recent past, become synonymous with India&amp;rsquo;s reawakening to her innermost soul. Bengal herself was turning away from that great heritage and towards an imported ideology which was leading her towards spiritual desolation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 NIGHTMARE OF NEHRUISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/08_ch9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/How_I_Became_Hindu/08_ch9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;nightmare-of-nehruism&#34;&gt;NIGHTMARE OF NEHRUISM&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am adding this postscript to the third reprint of what may be described as my intellectual autobiography in order to complete my story as a convinced and conscious Hindu. The story relates mainly to my encounter with Nehruism in its various expressions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, I view Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru as a bloated Brown Sahib, and Nehruism as the combined embodiment of all the imperialist ideologies Islam, Christianity, White Man&amp;rsquo;s Burden, and Communism that have flooded this country in the wake of foreign invasions. And I do not have the least doubt in my mind that if India is to live, Nehruism must die. Of course, it is already dying under the weight of its sins against the Indian people, their country, their society, their economy, their environment, and their culture. What I plead is that a conscious rejection of Nehruism in all its forms will hasten its demise, and save us from the mischief which it is bound to create further if it is allowed to linger.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
