<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;vembu-shrIdharaH on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;vembu-shrIdharaH on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Compartmentalization</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/compartmentalization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/compartmentalization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One problem that comes with modernity is ultra-specialization and the resulting compartmentalization of fields of knowledge and of life itself. Fields that became ultra specialized and compartmentalized go stale, similar to what happens to crop land. So does life itself. Efficiency dictates that we &amp;ldquo;outsource&amp;rdquo; our children to schools and our elderly to old age homes. Yet in that process we lose an organic life essence. Due to my being in a village, I am surrounded by kids and elderly and that brings me the joys of my childhood.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Credentials</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/credentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/credentials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1309657505077714945&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1309657505077714945&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From extensive experience, I have come to oppose credentials driven education and it&amp;rsquo;s counterpart, metrics driven management. I have opposed them on the ground that humans are not widgets. Here are two books, coming from unorthodox university professors that I recommend.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, the case against college (the title &amp;ldquo;The case against education&amp;rdquo; is a mistake in my opinion, it should be &amp;ldquo;The case against college&amp;rdquo;) - &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Case_Against_Education&#34;&gt;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Case_Against_Education&lt;/a&gt; . It argues that the college degree is now primarily a &amp;ldquo;signaling mechanism&amp;rdquo; and not about learning. I agree.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Degrees</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/degrees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/degrees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have been very running a skills training program in one of our rural centers for the past 2 months, with the goal of hiring people who do well in it. We have not required a college degree to enroll but most people who show up are people with degrees and no jobs. What is surprising is the number of fancy sounding degrees such as &amp;ldquo;MBA in HR&amp;rdquo; we see. One person with that degree dropped out of training after 3 days because he said &amp;ldquo;I want a job relevant to my degree&amp;rdquo;. He didn&amp;rsquo;t even want to try.+++(5)+++ His mother - having spent her savings on the MBA in HR degree for her son - approached us again because she wants him to get a job and she cannot understand why he dropped out. These degrees are doing active damage, not just waste time and money.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formalist trap</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/formalist-trap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/formalist-trap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1462199139366686722&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1462199139366686722&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Try to describe a bicycle in words (no pictures but mathematical formulas allowed!), with the intent to communicate what a bicycle is to an imaginary person who has never seen one. It is far better to simply show a bicycle. The thing is simpler than its description! Formal description of the concept of a bicycle is harder for the human mind to grasp than a real bicycle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All too often, the education system and by extension the business world place too great an emphasis on formal descriptions. I call it the &amp;ldquo;formalist trap&amp;rdquo;. Imagine evaluating cooks based on formal descriptions of recipes instead of on how the food tastes. Unfortunately that happens all too often in the business world. The formalist trap is seductive and we end up valuing the articulate and verbose over the competent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impracticality</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/impracticality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/impracticality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This essay caught my attention. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/EH6RVpMZPk&#34;&gt;https://t.co/EH6RVpMZPk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;most classicists &amp;hellip; can&amp;rsquo;t sight-read a complex Latin text all that well.&amp;rdquo; Most CS professors cannot code well. Most EE professors cannot design circuits or motors. And so on - these are open secrets in academia. In fact, engineering faculty in many prestigious universities in the US disdain practical engineering. The disconnect was already obvious when I was a PhD student in the early 1990s. It has only gotten worse. Why did this happen? Publish or perish reward system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language competence</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/language-competence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/language-competence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: https://threader. app/thread/1315090641802588160)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday our high school age students, our teachers and I agreed on a concrete goal: students should be able to write a short essay in Tamil without error by Jan 1 2021. &amp;ldquo;பிழையில்லாமல் தமிழில் எழுதுவோம்&amp;rdquo; as the goal reads in Tamil. I have a deeper reason for this goal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tamil is an ancient language where Spoken Tamil (ST) has diverged substantially from written formal Literary Tamil (LT) and in effect every Tamil student learns two languages side by side.  LT is very strict. This is known as [Diglossia](https://en. m. wikipedia. org/wiki/Diglossia) among linguists.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/math/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: https://threader. app/thread/1325600735145291776)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have set a second goal for students (writing flawless Tamil is the first goal) and that is நம்பர் என் நண்பர் in Tamil, which translates as &amp;ldquo;Number is my friend&amp;rdquo;. We stress the importance of zero - &amp;ldquo;how many zeros does it have&amp;rdquo;.  They have to carry these around mentally.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the distressing things I have noticed is how many otherwise highly literate adults are effectively innumerate. As an example, I may ask a person &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s the population of Chennai&amp;rdquo; and a random guess like &amp;ldquo;6 lakhs?&amp;rdquo; (600K) is made when the true figure is ~10 million.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mother tongue</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/mother-tongue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/mother-tongue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I studied in Tamil as the medium of instruction till my 10th standard. Vast majority of Indian children study in their mother tongue, which is the custom world-wide except in a few former colonies. Yet economic opportunity is almost exclusively for the English educated. This fact becomes more painfully obvious in rural India. Not knowing English is something the average Indian carries like a shame. There really is only one way to erase it: universal schooling in one&amp;rsquo;s own mother tongue throughout India with a strong second language program.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schooling goals</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/schooling-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/schooling-goals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I started to informally tutor some village children because all schools were closed. Within a few days, my social-distanced open air class swelled from 3 kids to 25 and kids got unruly and I was struggling 😂 and realized how hard it is to be a teacher 🙏🙏 I learned quickly that if there is just one kid who won&amp;rsquo;t co-operate, the whole class would descend into chaos 😂 Fortunately one of my colleagues who is very interested in education and his wife, an experienced school teacher, came to my rescue and we got things organized.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Test taking vs skill development</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/test-taking_vs_skill-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/test-taking_vs_skill-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1260378700207407105&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1260378700207407105&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a society where the education system is based on our musical ability. All jobs demand that &amp;ldquo;basic&amp;rdquo; qualification and credentials in music are much sought after and are required to train to be doctors, lawyers and engineers. After all who can be against music? Someone like me who is &amp;ldquo;musically challenged&amp;rdquo; and will struggle in that society. I will have trouble getting the basic qualifications needed to get to the higher credentials needed for most jobs. The musical meritocracy will deem people like me to be unfit for those jobs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work context</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/work-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/svembu/work-context/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1435810596725743618&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1435810596725743618&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have come to believe that much of higher education, particularly in fields like engineering or software, is best provided in the context of work. Contextual, experiential and relevant: that&amp;rsquo;s how we describe the @ZohoSchools educational philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abstract principles don&amp;rsquo;t take root in our minds unless we see those principles put into action. In that sense, theory should come after practice. We must first remove the fear about learning something new and that can only happen by getting our hands dirty and feet wet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
