<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;जातिः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;जातिः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>96-kulIna-marATha-s</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/96-kulIna-marAThas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/96-kulIna-marAThas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;self-identity&#34;&gt;Self identity&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;96 kuli Marathas is a group of 4 royal clans- 24 Suryavanshi, 24 Yaduvanshi, 24 Somvanshi and 24 Nagvanshi.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They self identify as kShatriya-s.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;samskara-s&#34;&gt;saMskAra-s&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;मराठाः परम्परागतरूपेण विवाहात् पूर्वं उपनयनसंस्कारं कुर्वन्ति । समग्रतया अद्यतनस्य मराठाः धार्मिकाः सन्ति, परन्तु द्विजसौभाग्यस्य महत्त्वं रूढिवादीनियमानाम् अनुसरणं च न अवगच्छन्ति।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;तेषां कृते शुद्धमलिप्तक्षत्रियकुलत्वं क्षत्रियत्वं पर्याप्तम्। अस्माकं संस्काराणां महत्त्वं शक्तिश्च न ज्ञायते।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;वैदिकशिक्षााधिकारः तेषां रक्ताधिकारः प्रतीयते। तदधारेण तन्त्रपुराणोक्तमार्गान् अपि +उपेक्षन्ते ।&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;अननम&#34;&gt;अन्नम्&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;मम वृद्धैः कथितासु मौखिकपरम्परासु मराठाः केवलं शाकाहारिण एव आसन् । बकमांसमात्रं मृगमांसमेव च मे पितरः । केवलं मृगयातः एव प्राप्तम् आसीत् । रूढिवादस्य शिथिलतायाः कारणात् अधुना एव मत्स्यस्य, कुक्कुटस्य च भोजनं आरब्धम् अस्ति ।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>koDungallUr nAyars</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/koDungallUr-nAyars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/koDungallUr-nAyars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(The Chera Perumal era (~8-9th centuries CE) warrior group of Nairs still survive today in Kodungallur, the former capital of Chera kingdom. They&amp;rsquo;re known as Onnu Kure Ayiram Yogam. They play significant role in managing Kodungallur Bhagavati temple.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some of the old customs and practices of the &amp;lsquo;Onnu Kure Ayiram&amp;rsquo; acquire significance in the light of this explanation. Its membership is hereditary and the head of the family represented the family house. Four important Nayar houses Valloppillil Tayyappallil, Kilikkotta, and Kattollil - have a prominent place in the organisation. The local Ksatriya chief, the rāja of Kodungallur, is informed about the proceedings of this assembly but he has no membership and no veto there. The meetings are held in the morning of the first of every month in the Malayalam calendar in the precincts of the Bhagavati temple. The sitting is called &amp;lsquo;Nilal irikkal&amp;rsquo;, i.e., Sitting as Nilal, a term the meaning of which remained obscure. Till recently the members were expected to attend the meeting with their traditional weapons.+++(5)+++ They used to sit in two rows facing each other. The member from Vallõppillil known as Valloppillil Patanäyar (military commander of Vallöppillil house) presided over the assembly. If anyone came late, he had to go round the gathering thrice holding the weapons upside down and then take the seat with the presiding officer&amp;rsquo;s permission. The members addressed each other as &amp;lsquo;cangati&amp;rsquo; meaning comrade. While announcing decisions the president put the question &amp;ldquo;Sammatam alle?&amp;rdquo; (Does everybody agree?) The persons, who disagreed, if any, could indicate their disapproval by turning around and facing outward. If attempts at an agreed solution failed, they consulted the temple oracle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Late nairs</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/late-nairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/late-nairs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They are all bred to the war, even from the seventh year of age, when they begin to anoint their limbs with certain ointments, to render the nerves pliable, which makes them very active and nimble, and the best wrestlers in the world. They are not only well acquainted with the use of bows and arrows, but also with mulkets and grea cannon; for I have seen them give a salvo with the same order and dexterity as our best-disciplined troops in Europe, and they are of late years arrived to that perfection, that they make their own gun-barrels, gunpowder, and matches. They commonly engage naked, having only a piece of stutt wrapp&amp;rsquo;d about the middle: being very nimble they often turn their backs, but soon return to the charge, when they find the least opportunity of having an advantage against their enemies. On the hilts of their swords they wear certain pieces of metal, which making a noise as they move, serves them for a certain musick : they are very dextrous in defending their bodies with their shields; and consequently are better at handy blows than at firing, for they commonly fire too high.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>nair-sanskrit</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/nair-sanskrit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/nair-sanskrit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thus in addition to regular lessons, there were other opportunities to learn Sanskrit. The late C. K. Ravi Varma (1917-2011). a former diplomat and head of the aristocratic family (Mal. karaṇavan) from the Chemprol Palace.36 when asked about the education of girls in his family. described the following picture: his older sister. Asvati Nal37 Srimati Tampu- ratti (Mal. aśvati nāl śrimatī tampuraṭṭi), called Kunjikutti (Mal. kuññikuṭṭi) (1915-1990), recites Panini&amp;rsquo;s grammar rules. and their teacher. helping in the kitchen, just grinds the coconut pulp and at the same time corrects the student. Asvati Nal Srimati, when she grew up, authored minor works in Sanskrit, unfortunately not preserved by the family, although there are anecdotes about the circumstances in which some of them were created. The old gen-&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>qAyamkhani</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/qayamkhani/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/qayamkhani/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1671217438141054979.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nyamat Khan or better known as Jan Kavi in his Qayamkhani Rasa, describing the exploits of his father Alif Khan mentions the battle of Kangra. As per Kavi, so fierce was the battle that ash-smeared bhagavan Shiva with his trident, skull bowl came to the battlefield and danced. Yoginis were seen drinking blood &amp;amp; eating the flesh of the slain warriors on the battlefield; a common Rajput war motif. The Khan, though styled as a ghazi, a mujahid, reaches Amarapura (land of Immortal) after his shahadat, before he goes to Vaikuntha (abode of bhagavan Vishnu).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vaNNiyAr</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/vaNNiyAr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/vaNNiyAr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;from the 1931 census, the Vanniyars in the 1980s constituted around 10 per cent of the population of Tamil Nadu, being particularly prevalent in the northernmost districts of Chingelput, North Arcot, South Arcot and Salem, where they formed around 25 per cent of the population.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;most Vanniyars are agricultural labourers but they are increasingly benefiting from political influence and organisation and they now own 50 per cent of the lands of the traditional landowners.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Pattali Makkal Katchi political party was formed from the Vanniyar Sangam, a caste association.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;kshatriya-rise&#34;&gt;kShatriya rise&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sources: Wiki and papers cited there.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hildebittel notes that &amp;ldquo;traditions of demotion from a once higher rank are a commonplace of South Indian caste mythologies&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lloyd I. Rudolph notes that as early as in 1833, the Vanniyar, who were then known as Pallis, had ceased to accept their &amp;ldquo;low caste&amp;rdquo; status.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Pallis tried to get an order in Pondicherry that by descent they were not a low agricultural caste. In preparation for the 1871 Indian census they petitioned to be recognised as being of the Kshatriya varna.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;They formed a number of caste organisations using their preferred name, with the Vanniyakula Kshatriya Maha Sangam appearing in Madras in 1888 and extending state-wide in 1952.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The community adopted such practices as vegetarianism and prohibiting the remarriage of widows. They claim descent from pallava-s.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;By 1931, due to their successful politicking (with sanskritisation), the term Palli was removed from the Madras census, with the term Vanniya Kula Kshatriya appearing instead.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;recent-backwardness-claims&#34;&gt;Recent backwardness claims&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot; The Vanniyars who previously were of the Backward Class category, were now designated as a Most Backward Caste after successful agitations by them in the 1980s. The reason for the agitation and subsequent re-classification was to avail more government benefits for the community&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vELirs and ixvAkus</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/vELirs_and_ixvAkus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/jAtiH/vELirs_and_ixvAkus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Author: GhorAngirasa&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The truly interesting part which many seem to have missed is the full relevance of the description of atiyamAn’s (the vELir king) lineage as that which gave the world sugarcane. This is known among students of the tamizh poems but it’s significance is not fully appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, as per paurANika tradition, it is the hoary ikSvAku who introduced sugarcane-planting. But the ikSvAkavas are based in ayodhya, no? So, how would this tie with atiyamAn’s ancestry from tuvArai (dvAraka)? There was a side-branch of the ikSvAkavas or a branch of the sUryavaMsha not descended from ikSvAku but one of his brothers, which settled at what will be later known as dvAraka &amp;amp; named the city kushasthali.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
