<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;hindu society under seige on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_society_under_seige/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;hindu society under seige on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_society_under_seige/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 1. Significance of Hindu Society</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_society_under_seige/01_ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_society_under_seige/01_ch1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Significance of Hindu Society&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hindu society is the only significant society in the world today which presents a continuity of cultural existence and functioning since times immemorial.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most other societies known to human history-East and West, North and South-have suffered a sudden interruption and undergone a traumatic transformation due to the invasion and victory of latter-day ideologies-Christianity, Islam, Communism. The pre-Christian, pre-Islamic and pre-Communist cultural creations of these societies are now to be met only in libraries and museums, thanks to the labours of antiquarian scholars.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 2. The Residue of Islamism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_society_under_seige/02_ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_society_under_seige/02_ch2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The Residue of Islamism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most malevolent of these residues is Islamism, the residue of the Muslim invasion of India spread over several centuries. Its basic tenets are ultimately derived from the teachings of Islam which has so far succeeded in sealing itself off from every shade of empiricism, rationalism, universalism, humanism and liberalism, the hallmarks of Hindu as well as modern Western culture. But in the context of India where Islam failed in its mission of lasting conquest and total conversion, these tenets have acquired a singularly sinister and subversive character.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 3. The Residue of Christianism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_society_under_seige/03_ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_society_under_seige/03_ch3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The Residue of Christianism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The British rule in India crystallised two residues-Christianism and Macaulayism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Certain strains of Macaulayism developed what is euphemistically described as a “revolutionary temper” in the later stages of the British rule and joined hands with Communism after the Bolshevik victory in Russia. The whole of Communism, which is also hostile to Hindu society and culture, is not Macaulayism. Yet, if Macaulayism had not prepared the ideological ground, Communism could not have made the strides it did in this country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 4. The Residue of Macaulayism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_society_under_seige/04_ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_society_under_seige/04_ch4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. The Residue of Macaulayism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now for the second residue of British rule, Macaulayism. The term derives from Thomas Babington Macaulay, a member of the Governor General’s Council in the 1830s. Earlier, the British Government of India had completed a survey of the indigenous system of education in the Presidencies of Bengal, Bombay and Madras. A debate was going on whether the indigenous system should be retained or a new system introduced. Macaulay was the chief advocate of a new system. This, he, expected, will produce a class of Indians brown of skin but English in taste and temperament. The expectation has been more than fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 5. The Communist Conspiracy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_society_under_seige/05_ch5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_society_under_seige/05_ch5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. The Communist Conspiracy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;This article was written in 1981. Now the Soviet Union has disappeared&#xA;from the scene and the Communist movement in India does not know whom to serve. But its hostility towards Hindu society and culture remains undiminished. It is quite on the cards that this mercenary outfit will be bought over, in due course, by some other power or powers hostile to positive Indian nationalism. A Communist cannot help being a traitor to his country and his people.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 6. The United Front of Hostile Forces</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_society_under_seige/06_ch6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_society_under_seige/06_ch6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. The United Front of Hostile Forces&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far we have discussed (1) the significance of Hindu Society as the last of the ancient societies to survive the invasion of latter-day ideologies, and (2) the methods and means employed by these ideologies to finish Hindu society as well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this concluding survey we shall take up the United Front which these ideologies, particularly Islamism and Communism, have forged to malign Hindu society and keep it on the defensive. This United Front functions mostly at a psychological level. But it presents itself as a political alliance also whenever specific issues affecting the welfare of Hindu society come up before the Parliament or are debated in public.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
