<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;अज्ञातगोत्राः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;अज्ञातगोत्राः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>karapAtrI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/karapAtrI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/karapAtrI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;the advaitin yatI, known as rudranArAyaNa before he left gRhasthAshrama at 19 after the birth of a girl child. He combated decadence in society by Dharma sangha and dharma Veer Dal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;He campaigned against reforms imposed by government - successfully against Hindu marriage and divorce bill drafted by Hindu law committee formed in 1941 and unsuccessfully against Nehru&amp;rsquo;s government (भारत अखंड हो,  गोवध बंद हो, अधार्मिक बिल रद्द हों, मंदिरों की मर्यादा सुरक्षित रहे, विधान शास्त्रीय हो) and Ambedkar&amp;rsquo;s later codes - he was arrested (among 5k others), leaders like GoswAmi LakshmanAchArya and Swami KrishnAnanda lost their lives.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Opposed partition, supported victims of &amp;ldquo;Direct Action Day&amp;rdquo; riots; established land for riot victims, helped those who were forcibly converted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;He started a satyAgraha demanding that the 14 slaughter houses in Mathura be shut down. Soon he was arrested and put in Agra jail for 6 months but the agitation continued and finally the Mathura municipality agree to shut down these slaughterhouses. In the next stage KarpAtri ji encouraged people to pressurise local boards and municipalities to shut down slaughter houses. As a result of public pressure, 32 districts passed proposals to shut down slaughter houses. In 1954, Dharma Sangha organised a VirAt Gau Raksha Sammelan and KarpAtri ji met the UP Chief Minister GV Pant to demand cow slaughter ban. Soon anti cow slaughter legislations were passed by UP and Bihar. KarpAtri ji was arrested next day and sent to Tihar jail where he was attacked by some inmates. It was a violent attack in which his he received head injuries and became unconscious. He also lost vision in one eye.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In November 1966, a million Gau Bhaktas led by him peacefully protested to demand ban on Gau HatyA. &amp;ldquo;The crowd was lathi charged and then bullets were fired on crowd. A curfew was imposed in Delhi. As per official estimates 11 people were killed. However other sources indicate that this figure was in hundreds.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;KarpAtri ji was involved with was the  &amp;ldquo;Hindi Raksha Andolan&amp;rdquo; in Punjab ( 1957)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;He repeatedly stressed the need for political consciousness among DhArmika people for survival of Dharma. When elections were declared in 1945, he appealed all Dharmika people to join politics. In September 1945, Akhil Bhartiya SanAtani dal was formed by him  to provide a platform to such people. Post independence, KarpAtri ji formed the Akhil BhAratiya RAm RAjya Parishad in 1948. &amp;hellip; This was 2% of the national vote. The party got 14.2% of votes in Madhya BhArat and 9.3% in Rajasthan. It won 3 Lok Sabha seats, all in Rajasthan and 32 assembly seats of which 24 came from Rajasthan&amp;hellip;. By 1962, the party&amp;rsquo;s organisational structure weakened considerably with most of its members switching to Jana Sangha or Swatantra.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;As per the rules of KAshi VishvAnAth temple, no one was allowed to touch the Shivalinga. Even the king of kAshi  used to pray from far. Everyone was allowed inside the temple but no one was allowed inside the Garbhagriha. However, in December 1957,  when a group of Harijans forcibly entered there with help of the city magistrate. He was so infuriated that he announced the construction of a new VishvAnAth temple. This temple was constructed in Meerpur, KAshi .&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;errors&#34;&gt;Errors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Claimed that earth did not rotate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PV kANe</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/kANE-pANDuranga-vAmanaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/kANE-pANDuranga-vAmanaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;chitpAvana, author of the stunning, expansive &amp;ldquo;History of the dharmashAstras&amp;rdquo;, whose &lt;a href=&#34;http://dadegaonkar.blogspot.com/2007/09/p-v-kane-notes-for-biography.html&#34;&gt;autobiography&lt;/a&gt; is in its epilogue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On his motivation via his son at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prekshaa.in/reminiscences-pandurang-vaman-kane-part3&#34;&gt;prexA&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;ldquo;It turns out that long before commencing the writing of the volumes, PVK had a keen interest in all subjects related to Indian culture. He also had a deep understanding of the dharma-shastras and matters related to Indian heritage. He was a master of the Sanskrit language and of his own interest, he had read the Vedas, Upaniṣads, the Epics, the Purāṇas, and other traditional works. But time and again, when PVK would come across the writing of some Western scholar or soi-disant Indologist on the subject of the dharma-śāstra that showed Indian culture in bad light, and his blood would boil. His anger would know no bounds when he came across writers who passed loose comments on the dharma-śāstras or concluded that the Indian mind was uncivilized and nascent. At the dining table, he would express his anguish, “What does this fellow know about India and its heritage to comment this way? Where on earth does he find all these things in our dharma-śāstras? What were people in Europe and the Americas doing when we already had a flourishing civilization in India?” Such constant episodes convinced him that he had to write something to shut the mouths of Western scholars who spewed absolute drivel about our ancient works. He made up his mind. “It is my duty to write this. I shall write about the dharma-śāstra in greater detail so that it will put all confusion to rest.” Doubtless he ended up becoming successful. A needle prick in the beginning sufficed to put the great mind on track to undertake the herculean task of compiling all the dharma-śāstras and its commentaries right from Parāśara, Manu, and Yājñavalkya all the way until the day on which he wrote the specific chapter. This included the judgments passed by Indian courts and the Privy Council.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;शरनवस-रमनज&#34;&gt;श्रीनिवास-रामानुजः&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;shrInivAsa rAmAnujan&#xA;great mathematician, with good grounding the shrIvaiShNava tradition, whose fecundity was inspired by the devI nAmakkAL, whose great memory was able to recite digits of numbers like pi as well as things like roots of Sanskrit words, (&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.stephenwolfram.com/2016/04/who-was-ramanujan/&#34;&gt;W&lt;/a&gt;), who has inspired the likes of Ono(&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scientificamerican.com/article/inspired-by-genius-how-a-mathematician-found-his-way/?WT.mc_id=SA_TW_MATH_NEWS&#34;&gt;SA&lt;/a&gt;), whose works have continued to impact mathematics and its diverse applications 100 years after his passing (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=207&amp;amp;v=uhNGCn_3hmc&#34;&gt;YT&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;- Period depictions), whose experimentation/ intuitive approach to mathematics marked him as a poet/ seer rather than a problem solver.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>raghunAthAchAri</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/raghunAthAchAri/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/raghunAthAchAri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(1828-1880 CE), a shrIvaiShNava-brAhmaNa, Hindu astronomer who was rooted in tradition yet learned, adopted and spread modern astronomy, [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2015/06/02/remembering-raghunathachari/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;coming from a traditional astronomer family he sought to do modern astronomy and was an autodidact in this regard;  reduced to supporting himself as a coolie for the Sāhibs but at age of 18 he was appointed to the British observatory of Madras,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;gave several public lectures in Chennai to attempt to increase the awareness of Hindus on modern astronomy and the importance of first hand and meticulous observations&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;discussed the importance of modern astronomy with the ācarya of the Sriperumbudur śrīvaiṣṇava maṭha and convinced him to adopt a modern astronomical almanac, &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;demonstrated to his Vedic ritualist friends, Venkateshvara Dikshita and Sundaresha Shrautin, that the astronomical tables of the traditional astronomers of Andhra and Dramiḍa were otiose and that they badly mis-predicted basic astronomical events which are central to Vaidika rituals&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;during the solar eclipse of August 18, 1868 RA was able to demonstrate his predictions: He got the eclipse time correct with an error of 12 seconds using calculations done by his hand while the traditional astronomers performed dismally with a whopping 24 minute error. This had a strong effect and many traditional Hindus now switched over to his side. He then demolished the most recalcitrant traditional astronomers in a sadas of brāhmaṇa-s of the Dramiḍa country. Seeing this the Śaṃkara maṭha sent out a circular stating that the Vedic ritualists Venkateshvara Dikshita and Sundaresha Shrautin were correct in adopting modern theory and techniques for their rituals. His efforts were paralleled by those of Ketkar in Maharashtra and Venkatakrishna Raya in Andhra to get the Hindus to use modern astronomical calculations.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;was the first modern Hindu to realize the importance of variable stars&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;RA and Pogson also discovered the May 1863 eruption of U Scorpii that led to the discovery of the recurrent nova which erupts as matter from a companion star falls on a white dwarf in a binary system. RA along with Muthusvami Pillai also captured the fading of R Coronae Borealis in 1863 CE.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;he and Muthusvami Pillai managed a local saving fund, “dravya-siddhi”, for Hindus&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RaghuvIra, Lokesh Chandra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/raghu-vIra_lokesha-chandra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/raghu-vIra_lokesha-chandra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;raghu-vira&#34;&gt;Raghu vIra&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;scholarship&#34;&gt;Scholarship&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Raghu vIra was a great wide-ranging scholar.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;His grandfather and father were in the British service - both taught English grammar, but were led to sanskrit grammar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Edited jaiminIya brAhmaNa, was an expert in gAndhAran statues, Indo European linguistics, Japanese, Tibetan.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Created a tibetan printing press. Later collaborated with Tibetan refugees regarding their education system.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;He admired perfection of European editions, systematic collation of variant readings, attention to details, comparitive study etc..&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ShrIdharAchAryaH shivaprasAdaH dvivedI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/shrIdharAchAryaH_shivaprasAdaH_dvivedI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/shrIdharAchAryaH_shivaprasAdaH_dvivedI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SrI SrIdharAchArya studied certain sAmAnya SAstra texts and SrI-BhAshya like VEdAnta granthas under SrI UtthamUr SwAmi, mainly when swAmi was staying at Pushkar,Rajasthan. Infact, it was SrI SrIdharAchArya who wanted SrI UtthamUr SwAmi to bless them with a commentary for SrI-BhAshyam {after listening swAmi&amp;rsquo;s kAlakshEpam, which had many insights not so far been recorded in previous texts}, which would be very useful for those scholars at North India as well {since they don&amp;rsquo;t have regular touch with swAmi Or any south-indian scholar as well}.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>subbarAyaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/subbarAyaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/subbarAyaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. T. S. Subbaraya was a brilliant student, teacher and an excellent individual. Born on 10.10.1905 (his parents were Pandit T N Subbaraya Shastry, a Kannada and Sanskrit scholar who taught Vidwat classes in Maharaja’s College, Mysore, and Kaveramma, a self-effacing and god-fearing housewife), he had an excellent academic record and became an erudite professor of physics in Central College, Bangalore. For some time he was also the Principal of the First Grade College at Tumkur. A synopsis of his bio-data is provided on the following page.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>निर्मलकण्ठः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/nirmalakaNThaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/nirmalakaNThaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;nirmalakaNTha (aka KanThabhaTTa), a daring paNDita, reconverted several muslims to sanAtana-dharma. The converts famously sat on Qurans to do their pUjA.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;rivalry-with-shams-iraqi&#34;&gt;Rivalry with shams iraqi&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sufi Shams Iraqi (in conflict with the khurasan sultAn) returned to kAshmIr after 12 years. Mir Syed Mohammed Isfahani alias Mir Shams-ud-din Muhammad Iraqi (1440–1515) spread Shia Sufi Islam in Kashmir. His Khanqah produced many of the future leaders of Kashmir (including Chak nobles).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>पन्तप्रतिनिधिः भावनरावः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/panta-pratinidhiH_shrInivAsarAvo-bhAvanarAvaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/panta-pratinidhiH_shrInivAsarAvo-bhAvanarAvaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Balasaheb Bhavan Rav Shrinivas Rav Pant Pratinidhi (1868-1951), Raja of Aundh, Satara region of Maharashtra. He was a passionate practitioner of Suryanamaskara, and authored a good book on it. Not only did he practice Suryanamaskar, his queen Ranisaheb of Aundh, mother of 11 children also practiced Suryanamaskar. His son Shrimant Appasaheb also practiced. He also implemented the practice of Suryanamaskar in schools in his region for both boys and girls. He was such a visionary Yogic Raja.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>भारतीकृष्णतीर्थः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/bhAratI-kRShNa-tIrthaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/bhAratI-kRShNa-tIrthaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Venkataramana Shastri  was born on 14 March 1884 to an orthodox Tamil Brahmin family. According to his own testimonials, Sanskrit and oratory were his favorite subjects. Due to his knowledge of the language, he was conferred the title &amp;ldquo;Saraswati&amp;rdquo; at the age of 16 by the Madras Sanskrit Association in July 1899. Venkataraman worked under Gopal Krishna Gokhale in 1905 for the National Education Movement and the South African Indian problems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>सीतारामशास्त्री</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/sItArAma-shAstrI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/sItArAma-shAstrI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;परवर&#34;&gt;परिवारः&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A fine mulukunADu brAhmaNa. He hailed from a traditional, erudite household. (Birth: 4th November 1893 in Nanjangud, Mysore. Death: 7th January 1971 in Bangalore). Though he was born ‘Sitarama Jois,’ he became ‘Sitarama Shastri’ owing to his maternal uncles, i.e. brothers of his mother Parvatamma. The three brothers (Yajneshwara Shastri, Srikantha Shastri, and Krishna Shastri) were all eminent personalities. Srikantha Shastri was the chief officer in the Śṛṅgeri Maṭha; Krishna Shastri was the dharmādhikarī during the reign of Krishnaraja Wodeyar IV.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
