<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post peshva on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post peshva on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapekar brothers</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/Chapekar_brothers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/Chapekar_brothers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Damodar Hari Chapekar (1870-1898), Balkrishna Hari Chapekar (1873-1899, also called Bapurao) and Vasudeo Hari Chapekar (1879-1899, also spelt Wasudeva or Wasudev), killers of W C Rand tyrant of puNyanagarI during the third plague pandemic and his escort Ayerst on the dayof diamond jubilee of barbarian Queen Victoria&amp;rsquo;s coronation (22 June 1897); very astute thinkers about the goal and means for independence, warned against Congress and foreign agents, who had a distaste for Cricket and the Engilsh, who cultivated bodily strength, tried (in vain) to get army experience (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=from%3Arjrasva%20chapekar&amp;amp;src=typd&#34;&gt;TW1&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dada Rane Sardesai</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/Dada_Rane_Sardesai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/Dada_Rane_Sardesai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;from the legendary Maratha clan of Ranes, initiated the Rane Revolt of 1895. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/maharattas/status/1266326534966648832&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Background: &amp;ldquo;On September 14, 1895 the Maratha soldiers of Goa were ordered to set sail to Mozambique where they would die out a slow death. As all dignified men do, they refused collectively. They rode out to Sattari and conquered the fort of Nanuz and requested Dada Rane Sardesai of Sattari, to take up their leadership. Dada Rane himself was infuriated that Portuguese encroachers were distributing land of his forefathers among the Narcornis. Thus the united parties under the leadership of Dada Rane unleashed their Revolt on October 14, 1895.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fights: &amp;ldquo;Dada Rane first mounted an assault against Bardez and looted the Tivim Church where all the hoarded treasures of Hindus accumulated by the Portuguese came into their hands and with this they swiftly struck next at Mapusa. The garrison surrendered as the Mayor was attacked and the entire Municipal Treasury fell into the hands of the rebels. Moving on, they invaded Colvale and broke open the Community Safe. The impact of Dada Rane&amp;rsquo;s ferocity was such that some of the local merchants, landlords and others fled to British India. &amp;hellip; To support them, a reinforcement fleet was deployed from Portugal itself led by their own Prince Alfonso Henriques. With their bolstered numbers and morale, the Portuguese Prince and the Governor-General attacked Dada Rane together. Despite this, the revolt was further intensified and the Portuguese had to end up inviting Dada’s spiritual guru, Shankaracharya of Sankeshwar, who requested Dada to conclude the mutiny peacefully!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;End: &amp;ldquo;They were sentenced guilty and in 1902, he was sentenced to exile in Timor in the Pacific ocean, where he and his son, Indroji, died in the course of time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>gangAbAyi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/gangAbAyi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/gangAbAyi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;aka tapasvinI mAtAjI, born in 1835 of Maharashtrian parents at Vellore, became well versed in Sanskrit religious literature as well as skilled in riding and sword-play at an early age, left her home,  came to Jhansi, and became an intimate companion of Rani Laxmi Bai, who was a distant maternal aunt, fought bravely in 1857, fled to nepal with nAnA saheb,  spent the life of a fugitive there for nearly 30 years practicing tapas, arrived in Calcutta around 1890 and founded her school Mahakali Pathashala in 1893. Over the next ten years the institution expanded to twenty-three branches with four hundred and fifty students, died in 1907. In May 1897 Swami Vivekananda paid a visit to the Mahakali Pathshala in Calcutta, and saw excellent sanskrit hindu education there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jhalkari Bai</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/Jhalkari_Bai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/Jhalkari_Bai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;of the kori SC jAti, trained in arms and horse-riding, inducted by laxmIbAi into her army, pretended to be the queen and distracted the enemy while laxmIbAi escaped with her son.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kEshav baLIrAm hEDagEvAr</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/kEshav_baLIrAm_hEDagEvAr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/kEshav_baLIrAm_hEDagEvAr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/K._B._Hedgewar&#34;&gt;kEshav baLIrAm hEDagEvAr&lt;/a&gt;, hindu svarAjya activist, social reformer, RSS founder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lokamAnya bAla-gangAdhara TiLak</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/lokamAnya_bAla-gangAdhara_TiLak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/lokamAnya_bAla-gangAdhara_TiLak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;chitpAvana (&lt;a href=&#34;../../../images/people/tilak-wears-cap-on-shikhA.gif&#34;&gt;shikhA_img&lt;/a&gt;), great patriot, a fine sanskrit poet (even a chitrakavi) in his boyhood [&lt;a href=&#34;../../images/snippets/tilak-chitra-kAvya.jpg&#34;&gt;IMG&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/991509282582560770&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;], good scholar of the veda-s (taking a philological angle), &amp;ldquo;endeavored to position Hindu thought as a capable player in the arena of modern philosophical discourse&amp;rdquo;, who said &amp;ldquo;svarAj is our right, and we shall have it&amp;rdquo;, and went to jail; who initiated the svadeshI movement, and boycott of English administration. [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hVjJ4UQZJcc&#34;&gt;nehru1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BpS2bF3KwmU&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&#34;&gt;vid_trailer1&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;लोकमान्यः शाण्डिल्य इति ज्ञायते।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mahAdva govinda rANaDe</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/mahAdva_govinda_rANaDe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/mahAdva_govinda_rANaDe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mahadev_Govind_Ranade&#34;&gt;w&lt;/a&gt;), a pacifist reformer who sought to recast the dharma to better respond to the British / Christian challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rANI laxmIbAi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/rANI_laxmIbAi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/rANI_laxmIbAi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;nee maNikarNikA of jhansi (1828-1858), born in vArANAsI to a marATha brAhmaNa family, raised upstream in the exiled peshva court at biThUr, trained in fighting, horseriding, mallakambha etc.. with her childhood friends nAnA-sAheb and tAtya Tope, married to scholarly rAjA Gangadhar Rao Newalkar (of karhaDe brAhmin descent) of Jhansi in bundelkhaND.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tough intrigues: Lost her 4 month old child at age 21, began raising another boy adapted by her husband the day before he died, resisted the Doctrine of Lapse, but acceeded in the end.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fighting: When the 1857 rebellion spread to jhAnsi, she ransomed out the rebels (who&amp;rsquo;d massacred the Eurpoeans), started governing. Then she fought off British assisted rAjaputra neighbor states (Orchcha and Datia); built up defences, cannon foundries. Supposedly recruited women into the army (even as gunners).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gen Rose attacked next after she her offer of autonomy (supported by subjects) was rejected. tAtyA Tope came to aid jhAnsi, but was defeated (jhAnsi forces rushing out of the fort might have helped?). Peer ali, supposedly caused a gunner duhaju to open the gate leading to ingress and heavy street fighting. Escaped with son on her back by jumping off with her horse bAdal (which supposedly died) to kalpi where she met tAtyA Tope and rAo sAheb (who might have disagreed on tactical matters with her leading to losses). Following her strategic advice, they took gwalior from the sindhia rulers aided by his revolting soldiers - here she made her final stand and died.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vIra sAvarkar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/sAvarkara/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/sAvarkara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;vIra &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Savarkar&#34;&gt;vinAyaka dAmodara sAvarkara&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;chitpAvana brAhmaNa of vasiShTha gotra and hiraNyakeshi-sUtra of KYV, hindu nationalist, the visionary who caused massive Hindu recruitment into the British Indian army - a factor which would prove critical during partition, social reformer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;pro-independence-contributions&#34;&gt;Pro independence contributions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The first political leader to daringly set Absolute Political Independence as India&amp;rsquo;s goal (1900). Daringly performed a bonfire of foreign (English) clothes (1905). Organized revolutionary movement for Bharat&amp;rsquo;s Independence on international level (1906).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The first law student who was not called to the English Bar despite having passed his examination and observed the necessary formalities, as he asked freedom.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The book on the 1857 War of Independence was proscribed by British Authorities even before its publication. The Governor General had asked the Postmaster General to confiscate copies of the book six months before the book was officially banned (1909). The same book was later published by Bhagat Singh.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Inspirer of madan lAl DhingrA, rAjaguru.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;first-war-of-indian-independence-book&#34;&gt;First war of Indian independence book&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1907, sAvarkar wrote a history book about the 1857; calling it the First War Of Indian Independence, as opposed to Sepoy Mutiny. He wrote it in Marathi at first, in London, using sources from the British library&amp;rsquo;s India Office. He even won over a racist librarian who then opened up secret documents to him, like proceeds of the parliament from 1857-58.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
