<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jAti-varNa practice on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in jAti-varNa practice on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#43;Dispute Resolution</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/dispute-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/dispute-resolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;disputes&#34;&gt;Disputes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sometimes the varNa affiliation of certain jAti-s were subject to disptues.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In marATha times, these disputes were called &amp;ldquo;grAmaNya&amp;rdquo;-s.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;decisions&#34;&gt;Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;basis-in-shastra&#34;&gt;Basis in shAstra&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;In reaching their conclusions based on these Purānic narratives, the pandits were essentially trying to open new spaces by reading between the lines of the narratives, and the final verdicts became authoritative not so much by the strength of the arguments, but by the perceived authority of the persons rendering these verdicts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;These instances demonstrate to us the dynamics of decision-making based on the Sanskritic tradition, that at once claimed to be timeless and universal, and yet at the same time was deeply entrenched in specific temporal, geographic, social and political environments, that continuously shifted and led to the emergence of a bewildering mass of conflicting opinions seen Sanskrit and vernacular documents.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The texts exist only in the forms in which they are produced and reproduced, and the production and reproduction of texts is at all times a highly motivated activity.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Example - Multiple versions of Kāyastha-dharma-dīpa with regards to the CKP question (See separate page).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The motivations, real or suspected, are often clearly referred to in the available Sanskrit and vernacular documents, including dveṣabuddhi &amp;ldquo;hatred&amp;rdquo; and dravyalobha &amp;ldquo;greed&amp;rdquo; among Brahmins and others, and ostracism and fear of various kinds of reprisals by the different parties.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Sanskrit-based knowledge was continuously created and negotiated within these complicated parameters.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;reference-to-authority&#34;&gt;Reference to authority&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The disputes would oft be sent to distant authorities (eg. dharmashAtra writers in kAshi or shankarAchArya-s) for resolution.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;There was an established pattern of either sending the locally unresolved Dharmaśāstric disputes to authoritative centers of Brahmanical learning like Paithan or Banaras for resolution, or inviting authoritative persons from such centers of learning to the region to resolve the local disputes. We have a number of such decision-documents relating to disputes in the Maharashtrian communities going back to the fifteenth and the sixteenth centuries, and this pattern continues into the subsequent periods until the coming of the British colonial rule.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;On matters of dharma, including varNa and jāti, non-specialist administrative and legal functionaries of regional courts, lacking in Sanskrit knowledge, deferred to specialist Brahmins living in places like Paithan and later Banaras. Dalmia describes Banaras as a “supraregionally recognized” locus of juridical authority (Dalmia 1996: 322–3). The brahmasabhā would issue a decision, recorded in a document called a vyavasthā-patra (‘document (patra) bearing the decision (vyavasthā)’) or vijaya-patra (‘document spelling out the victory (vijaya) (of the authoritative claim&amp;rdquo;(siddhānta)’).169 The disputants would carry out the injunctions of this document, and their local political authority would not object.&amp;quot; [&lt;a href=&#34;http://works.bepress.com/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1088&amp;amp;context=ananya_vajpeyi&#34;&gt;AV2011&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;local-opposition&#34;&gt;Local opposition&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Such verdicts, though accepted by the communities at a given time and place, were eventually subject to dispute and repudiation, if the perceived authority of the verdict-givers eroded by the emergence of new circumstances.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#43;Ethnic shifts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/ethnic-shifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/ethnic-shifts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ethnic shifts provide important context for development of later social organizations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-peopling&#34;&gt;Initial peopling&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First came early hominids such as H.heidelbergensis from around 250,000-300,000 years BP.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/notes/history/paganology/indian_hunter_gatherer&#34;&gt;Indian hunter gatherers&lt;/a&gt; came next.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Then the &lt;a href=&#34;https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/notes/history/paganology/iranian-farmer&#34;&gt;iranian-farmer-invasion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Then, &lt;a href=&#34;https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/&#34;&gt;Aryan migration/ invasion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Then, &lt;a href=&#34;https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/notes/history/paganology/austro-asiatic/orissa-invasion&#34;&gt;Austro-Asiatic incursion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/Arya-invasion&#34;&gt;dravidian-bloom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Great &lt;a href=&#34;https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/Arya-consolidation&#34;&gt;Indo Aryan consolidations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;islamic-invasions&#34;&gt;Islamic invasions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, during the Islamic invasions, we get some Turkik input.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;These seem to have left comparatively little genetic footprints even among muslims. Partly because they are genetically very similar to the earlier Aryan influx - albeit more admixed with Turkik markers. &amp;ldquo;Detectable ancestry - probably less than 10%, closer to 1%.&amp;rdquo; - RK&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;foreigner-absorption&#34;&gt;Foreigner absorption&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Originally foreigners seem to have been adopted into shudra varna. And in case of warriors, they were added to kshatriya (like Meitei, ahom etc). While magha priests from Iran were accepted into brahmana fold (an exception since v2 and v4 seem to be most common).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparison</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;persistent-elite-dominance&#34;&gt;Persistent elite dominance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Among the non-human great apes, power hierarchies (some hereditary) have been observed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;kazoku and samurai in Japan - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Rjrasva/status/555363885927366656&#34;&gt;TW1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Communist china - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Rjrasva/status/894288819335385088&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Son also rises&amp;rdquo; by Gregory Clark - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0c2Ugb4VKH8&#34;&gt;YT-TED&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IN_-2rILolk&#34;&gt;C2020&lt;/a&gt; documents the inheritability of social status.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In fact, prior to 1800-s in England, rich had higher fertility than the poor; reverse in Qubec.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oxbridge attendence in England - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Rjrasva/status/842466759143743488&#34;&gt;TW1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;occupational-impurity-and-separation&#34;&gt;Occupational impurity and separation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Burukumin in Japan, Cagots in France, &amp;ldquo;dishonorable people&amp;rdquo; (unehrliche Leute) in early modern Germany, similar groups in Arabia, Yemen and Korea, practicing muslims and christians in India [&lt;a href=&#34;http://kafila.org/2011/09/15/in-allahpur-a-moment-of-truth/&#34;&gt;A&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ritual-purity&#34;&gt;Ritual purity&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;najasat&amp;rdquo; in Islamic socieites (spiritual pollution, separate from &amp;ldquo;kesafat&amp;rdquo;, physical uncleanliness).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A 3rd-century CE account of the Egyptian Priesthood and the lives of its priests by Porphyry in his Abstinence, Book 4 illustrating:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;much admired, exclusive, mostly-isolated state [&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GhorAngirasa/status/888768695308238848&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;1, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GhorAngirasa/status/888768695308238848&#34;&gt;TW2&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;self-restriction in diet, attire, countenance, travel [&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GhorAngirasa/status/888768695308238848&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;regular engagement in rituals&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;engagement in geometry etc.. in leisure &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GhorAngirasa/status/888768695308238848&#34;&gt;TW3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early ossification</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/early-ossification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/early-ossification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;varNa classification was ancient and predated Arya entry into India. More notes in the &lt;a href=&#34;../../ethnic-shifts/Arya-invasion/&#34;&gt;Aryan entry page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;By the time Megasthenes visited, there were already rigid restrictions about intermarriage and avocations. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sdstate.edu/projectsouthasia/upload/Megasthene-Indika.pdf&#34;&gt;MI&lt;/a&gt;]&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot; Such, then, are about the parts into which the body politic in India is divided. No one is allowed to marry out of his own caste, or to exercise any calling or art except his own: for instance, a soldier cannot become a husbandman, or an artizan a philosopher. &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ancient Hindu legal texts, such as the Manu-smRRiti, favored the maintenance of the varNa system - for example, by enjoining the rulers not to let the shUdra-s become too powerful, by fixing higher standards of behavior and harsher punishments for people of higher varNa-s, by emphasizing the need for close cooperation between the brAhmaNa-s and the kShatriya-s. Many Hindu kings were proud of maintaining the varNa-Ashrama-dharma.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Xuan Zang [&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=oNhVAAAAYAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA82&amp;amp;lpg=PA82&amp;amp;dq=With+respect+to+the+division+of+families+there+are+four+classifications.+The+first+is+called+the+Brahman,+men+of+pure+conduct.&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=lp-gckTVmi&amp;amp;sig=BwGuD_a8UlvF7xrJGXnGpvFMVQw&amp;amp;hl=sa&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0CCAQ6AEwAWoVChMIgLyk4uD8xgIVlVyICh3Epgl9#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=With%20respect%20to%20the%20division%20of%20families%20there%20are%20four%20classifications.%20The%20first%20is%20called%20the%20Brahman%2C%20men%20of%20pure%20conduct.&amp;amp;f=false&#34;&gt;XZ_GB&lt;/a&gt;]&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;With respect to the division of families there are four classifications. The first is called the Brahman, men of pure conduct. They guard themselves in religion live purely, and observe the most correct principles.he second is called Kshattriya, the royal class: they apply themselves to virtue and kindness. The third is called Vaisyas, the merchant class:they engage in commercial exchange, and they follow profit at home and abroad. The fourth is called Sudra, the agricultural class: they labor in plowing and tillage. &amp;hellip; In these four classes purity or impurity of caste assigns to every one place. When they marry they rise or fall according to their new relationship.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Alberuni confirms [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.columbia.edu/cu/lweb/digital/collections/cul/texts/ldpd_5949073_001/pages/ldpd_5949073_001_00000155.html?toggle=text&amp;amp;menu=maximize&amp;amp;top=200px&amp;amp;left=70px&#34;&gt;ALB&lt;/a&gt;]:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The kings of antiquity, who were industriously devoted to the duties of their office, spent most of their care on the division of their subjects into different classes and orders, which they tried to preserve from intermixture and disorder. Therefore they forbade people of different classes to have intercourse with each other, and laid upon each class a particular kind of work or art and handicraft. They did not allow any body to transgress the limits of his class.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Final composition</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/varNa-composition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/varNa-composition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;kshatriya-s&#34;&gt;kShatriya-s&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The brAhmaNas (brahmins) and the kShatriyas are in essense the descendents of the aristocracy or elite families of the invading Aryans. Overtime the kShatriya fold adopted other Indo-Aryan tribes outside of the pa~nchajana-ikShvAku orthodoxy, and various “honorary” kShatriyas of diverse ethnic backgrounds. These newcomers displaced or supplemented the original kShatriyas to a significant degree.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/09/01/inter-caste-strife/&#34;&gt;MT1&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;brahmana-s&#34;&gt;brAhmaNa-s&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;However, in the case of the brahmin the displacement was less significant, though there was a noticeable ethnic diversification through the process of anuloma marriage and the 7 generation rule of ascent to brahmin-hood. Nevertheless the brahmins and kshatriyas do seem to maintain a significant component of their ancestral Indo-Aryan ethnicity as supported by recent genetic studies.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/09/01/inter-caste-strife/&#34;&gt;MT1&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;From genetic data we can now confidently say that while a major component of v1 male lines in several parts of India is from the old Arya settlers there have been Harappan and tribal male lineages who have been absorbed. So the gotra is not a perfect correlate of deep ancestry. &amp;hellip; The (shaiva tantra) system also served as a conduit for fast-tracking the cream from individuals with high HG ancestry into higher varNa-s. Their incorporation into V2s is relatively well-known but now we can say that probably up to 10-15% of V1s in south India emerged via this mechanism coeval with the flowering of the shaiva traditions in the south.&amp;rdquo; {&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1072321253535567873&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;}&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;vaishays&#34;&gt;vaishays&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The vaishyas- these were in chief the descendents of the Indo-Aryan laity. However, they eventually included a diverse group of individuals.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/09/01/inter-caste-strife/&#34;&gt;MT1&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;shudras&#34;&gt;shUdras&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;shUdras- these seem to represent a mixture of individuals, namely:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;those of Indo-Aryan ethnic and linguistic origins, but outside of the pale of the pa~nchajana-ikShvAku orthodoxy&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/09/01/inter-caste-strife/&#34;&gt;MT1&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Non-Indo-Aryan peoples of various origins.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/09/01/inter-caste-strife/&#34;&gt;MT1&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;See notes on early conflict with Arya-s leading to restrictions above.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fluidity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/fluidity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/fluidity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hindu legal/ behavioral/ social system is not at all static. [See &lt;a href=&#34;../../../dharma-fluid/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.] It has adjusted to the abolition of jAti-privileges relatively smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Factors in favor of rigidity: Self interest, Standards etc.. are considered in the Motivation section in the theory-page.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Social fluidity in the far ancient times is considered &lt;a href=&#34;../../ethnic-shifts/Arya-consolidation//&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Non examples&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;satyakAma jAbAla - &lt;a href=&#34;https://padmavajrablog.wordpress.com/2017/10/06/the-tale-of-satyakama-jabala-as-seen-by-traditionalists/&#34;&gt;G17&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Related notes&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;shatAvadhAnI gaNesh&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d5xMQNu3M0k&#34;&gt;perspective&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ascendency-to-brahmana-ship&#34;&gt;Ascendency to brAhmaNa-ship&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Influx of magha-brAhmaNa from the proto-Iranian haumavarga shAka-s. [&lt;a href=&#34;https://musingsofhh.wordpress.com/2011/05/10/musings-on-multan/&#34;&gt;HH&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Early inclusion into the brAhmaNa-varNa tends to be enmeshed in myth. (eg: &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chitpavan&#34;&gt;chitpAvana&lt;/a&gt;-s, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sakaldwipiya_history&#34;&gt;Śākadvīpīya&lt;/a&gt;-s).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Arya samAja, ISKCON etc.. conferring the saMskAra-s irrespective of family of birth.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;For example, the Koliyans, who are weavers, and the Valluvans, who are medicine men and priests and wear the sacred thread, will not intermarry or eat with the others, and are now practically distinct castes.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;http://archive.org/stream/castestribesofso06thuruoft/castestribesofso06thuruoft_djvu.txt&#34;&gt;CT06&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;As early as 1705 A.D. the Brahmans of Madura called in question the Patnulkarans&amp;rsquo; right to perform the annual upakarma (or renewal of the sacred thread) in the Brahman fashion. [Eighteen members of the community were arrested by the Governor of Madura for performing this ceremony.] The matter was taken to the notice of the Queen Mangammal, and she directed her State pandits to convene meetings of learned men, and to examine into it. On their advice, she issued a cadjan (palm leaf) sasanam (grant) which permitted them to follow the Brahmanical rites.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;descent-from-v1&#34;&gt;Descent from V1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kadambas descendended to V2 (mayUrasharman → mayUravarman), and thence to V4 in later days (&amp;ldquo;kadam&amp;rdquo; in MH).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kerala</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/kerala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/kerala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;breast-tax&#34;&gt;Breast tax&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=guuFX4066zY~~~~&#34;&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opindia.com/2018/01/the-recurring-myth-of-breast-tax-doesnt-seem-to-die-down-this-time-propagated-by-scroll/&#34;&gt;OP18&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern caste politics</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/modern-caste-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/modern-caste-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dalit politics is considered separately.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;british-and-academic-subversion&#34;&gt;British and academic subversion&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The British, at the pinnacle of their rule over the sub-continent succeeded in raising a wide section of Indic public opinion against brahmins. This resulted in several anti-brahmin movements that blamed the brahmins for the ills of various socio-ethnic sections of Indic society. They cited as proof for their grievance the dharma shAstras, chief amongst which was the mAnava dharma shAstra. These anti-brahminists claimed that these texts sanctioned the brahmins to ill-treat and oppress their people. These movements were orchestrated and their perceptions abetted by the British, and later by the collective Anglosphere, because they saw it as a potent tool to blunt the traditional Brahminical leadership of Hindu society against foreign invaders. This framework for the interpretation of the ancient Hindu texts was further built up by Anglospheric India-agents (“Indological scholars”) and their Marxist fellow travellers who had been planted in India just before freedom.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/09/01/inter-caste-strife/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This is concordant with the &amp;ldquo;divide and rule&amp;rdquo; policy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
