<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;svembu on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/wealth/articles/svembu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;svembu on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/wealth/articles/svembu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dollar debt</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/wealth/articles/svembu/dollar-debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/wealth/articles/svembu/dollar-debt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dollar strength is almost entirely due to the level of dollar-denominated debt in the global financial system, much of it not involving US entities nor under Fed regulation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The world is being strangled by designating so much of its debt in &amp;ldquo;dollars&amp;rdquo;, as Fed dollars get scarce.. That also explains why countries with massive trade surpluses are seeing their currencies plunge against the dollar. Dollar-denominated debt vastly exceeds trade flows because trade surpluses become dollar-reserves and the reserves then get multiplied into dollar liabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dollar reserve and bubbles</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/wealth/articles/svembu/dollar-reserve_and_bubbles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/wealth/articles/svembu/dollar-reserve_and_bubbles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1469463718874398723&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why do countries as different as the US, China and India have big asset bubbles at the same time? What is the common factor? The common factor is the dollar as the reserve currency and very undisciplined monetary policy by the US Fed. Lets explore.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a normal business, when your output fetches a higher value than the sum of your inputs, you make a profit. That profit is a claim on the broader world. A country that exports more than it imports is similar but with a crucial difference. Lets look at their surplus. The surplus of the net exporter is a claim on the broader world and those claims are mostly denominated in the reserve currency, US dollar. With persistent multi-decade trade deficits by the US, those claims have been piling up. What happens to those accumulated claims?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US poor</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/wealth/articles/svembu/us-poor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/wealth/articles/svembu/us-poor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-soil-depletion&#34;&gt;Top soil depletion&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rattibha.com/thread/1505765429863616512?lang=en&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a thread on America, based on my thirty years being a student and permanent resident before returning home in 2019. I have lived longer in America than India. I have a lot of friends and family in America. This thread is based on my close and personal observation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;America is the most open and friendly society to immigrants in the world, of every race, religion or creed. America is truly the land of immigrants. Yet America is also convulsed by race, with a substantial part of the population believing it to be a deeply racist society. This seeming contradiction between being the most open society in the world and the self image on the part of so many of its people of being a racist nation cries out for explanation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
