<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>analysis of history</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/MT/2015-06-15_sulapuruSha-chatvarakam-3-a-method-for-the-analysi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/MT/2015-06-15_sulapuruSha-chatvarakam-3-a-method-for-the-analysi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2015/06/15/sulapuru%e1%b9%a3a-catvarakam-3-a-method-for-the-analysis-of-history/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;śūlapuruṣa-catvārakam-3: A method for the analysis of history&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Somakhya, standing beside a pillar outside his university department, glanced at his watch with a tinge of irritation as he waited for Lootika to show up. She was to bring her sister Vrishchika from the medical school, which was some distance away, and meet him there. Beside him were several of his classmates. One clump was talking about how difficult the latest lessons on the chemical synthesis of peptides were and how it could slay them in their exams. Another group was less worried and talking about sexual pleasures, cricket and films. Yet another set had formed a little circle with Sharad, who was considered a seasoned politics buff, in the middle. He was giving his nuggets of political wisdom even as the other classmates were approvingly listening and adding their own tidbits. Just then a student from the history department walked by and delivered a brisk spray of tāṃbūla-rasa on the pillar with a click of his mouth. Somakhya anticipating his action moved away from the pillar even as he watched the red parabola terminate on the pillar and in turn bounce off as little droplets to the floor. He mentally remarked: “So much for Vātsyāyana’s effort to inculcate the use of a pot among our peoples.” As he did so he noticed that the said student wore a shirt with a mug shot of Che Guevara and a cap with an image of a dustbin printed on it. From this he realized that he belonged to the PB [Pratibhraṣṭācār] party founded by a rabble-rouser, Rajiv Jaisval, from the rājadhānī. Then he overheard Sharad say: “Pakistan is Duryodhan and Afghanistan is māmā Śakuni. Yāroṇ, this is just a repeat of the Mahābhārat. Duryodhan will take us to Kurukṣetr where all of us would be destroyed. Hence, I think the PM is right in keeping the peace channel open like bhagavān Kṛṣṇ did.” Another classmate said: “Then who are the cīna-s?” Sharad: “They are like bhagavān Balrām – they will support Duryodhan but we can deal with them diplomatically like bhagavān Kṛṣṇ did because they are rational players.” Thus, their conversation went on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hindu historical account</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/MT/hindu-historical-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/MT/hindu-historical-account/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1872174819057291593&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Certain historical events cannot be spoken about in their totality in the Occident. One such is the complex of WW1-interwar-WW2. At the end of these events many groups, the Russians, Germans, Jews, Poles, Japanese, suffered huge losses. However, each of their own stories of these events are often in deep conflict with those of the others and narrative of the Anglospheric victor. It is too interwoven into the mythology of the neo-Anglosphere, like the kurukShetra war for the H. This makes it imperative for H to study this history unbiased by the dominant Occidental narrative.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>khaldun tradition</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/MT/khaldun-tradition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/MT/khaldun-tradition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The way ibn Khaldun presents his understanding&amp;amp; theorizing is rather unique. Hence, 1 could say there was no equivalent anywhere else in the ancient/medieval world. However, if we take a more general view we can see that he might be part of a large tradition which has parallels in various H works.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1st looking at ibn Khaldun himself he says he comes from the best of the Arab clans; hence the criticism might have been for those Arabs/Bedouins he saw as being lower.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2nd. His encounter with the islamized Mongol Timur gave him a direct understanding of the steppe people, the like of which we don&amp;rsquo;t see elsewhere.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3rd However, his historical analysis can be seen as a culmination of the world history project initiated by the Mongols, especially successors of Hulegu, including synthesis by Rashid ad Din.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4th. I think he may also be seen as strand of historical tradition/theorizing continuing from Herodotus in the ancient Greek world, which was taken up by at least 1 lost author in the Iranic world&amp;amp; from them by Islamic writers like Gardizi.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;indian-parallels&#34;&gt;Indian parallels&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Coming to India, ideas on the climes &amp;amp; their peoples (also having Iranic parallels in the karshvares) are seen in purANa-s, varAhamihira&amp;amp; the classical H medical tradition. Political thought is parallels by kauTilya &amp;amp; viShNusharman. The ethnology is seen kavi rAjashekhara&amp;rsquo;s works; the social critique is seen in kShemendra. Together, viShNusharman &amp;amp; kShemendra offer considerable social critique of the self. That tradition continued in pockets closer to our times in the critique of nIlakaNTha dIkShita.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
