<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Economic growth on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/growth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Economic growth on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/growth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Economic value indicators</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/growth/01_Economic_value_indicators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/growth/01_Economic_value_indicators/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Certain numbers reveal the current evaluation of the economy. The health of the economy can be roughly viewed in terms of the financial health and confidence of 4 major components: consumers, banks, non-bank businesses, government.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eg: Prices of critical commodities (like oil), value of index funds, growth in real estate prices, government debt, public debt.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;gross-domestic-product&#34;&gt;Gross domestic product&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;as-a-summary&#34;&gt;As a summary&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a measure of the total gross income of the country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Booms and busts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/growth/02_Booms_and_busts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/growth/02_Booms_and_busts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Economies generally keep cycling through periods of booms and busts (described below). This is due to heuristic way in which demand and supply are balanced.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;boom&#34;&gt;Boom&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To meet demand, industry in certain sectors grow - often on borrowed money, counting on future profits. Industries indeed produce profit for some time, but production keeps increasing until production exceeds demand.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During this time, the industries’ economic value - or at least their evaluation by the securities market- grows. Their operating cost increases because they invest more and hire more workers. Banks are more willing to lend at low interest rates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Investment</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/growth/03_Investment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/growth/03_Investment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GDP growth usually requires investment in business enterprise. But, investments may have returns either in the short-term or in the long-term. Investment which responds to consumer demand yields immediate benefits, and is often favored.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Investments vary in quality: for example, a rich government investment firm can increase GDP by just building cities which will never be occupied in the desert.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;consumer-demand-and-public-debt&#34;&gt;Consumer demand and public debt&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Individuals borrow money, and they have to repay them. The purchasing power of people correspondingly decreases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Disadvantages of growth</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/growth/04_Disadvantages_of_growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/growth/04_Disadvantages_of_growth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-costs&#34;&gt;Social costs&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A society often pays an excessive price for economic growth in the form of environmental pollution, eroding social/ cultural values, compassion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;inflation&#34;&gt;Inflation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The injection of new money by governments to favor economic growth leads to inflation/ currency devaluation, which disproportionately affects the poor, for the following reason.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The poor spend a greater fraction of their income on food/ raw materials, whereas rich tend to spend a greater fraction of their wealth on services. During inflation, the price of commodities grows at a much greater rate than the price of services.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 Effect of local disasters</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/growth/05_Effect_of_local_disasters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/growth/05_Effect_of_local_disasters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Suppose that a natural disaster like a hurricane in the gulf coast of USA or a earthquake + tsunami + nuclear leak in a part of Japan (2011) occurs. Regardless of where such a disaster occurs, much wealth is destroyed, and the economy of the affected region is severely set back.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If the country where the disaster occurs is advanced - like Japan or USA, effect on the GDP may not even be noticeable both in the short and the long term. This is because, these countries have redundant economic units (roads/ industries) which compensate for the destruction; and they have savings or lines of credit which they can use to rebuild - such investment increases, rather than decrease the GDP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 Financial crises</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/growth/06_Financial_crises/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/growth/06_Financial_crises/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Growth in economic value slows down drastically sometimes. The immediate cause for this disruption is a drop in investment/ money-lending due to varied reasons.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1929-great-depression&#34;&gt;1929: great depression&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;importance&#34;&gt;Importance&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A transformative event in world (especially US) history: disagreement about the goodness of new deal set lasted throughout the following century as rivalry between Democrats and Republicans in politics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;boom--bubbles&#34;&gt;Boom + bubbles&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the 1920’s, there was over-investment and under-consumption - there was a boom and a bubble. The bubble burst.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
