<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;0 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/0/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;0 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>0 CONTENTS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/0/0_CONTENTS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/0/0_CONTENTS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Page.&#xA;I&#xA;Introduction List of Abbreviations &amp;hellip;&#xA;&amp;hellip; VIII&#xA;ABHINAVAGUPTA.&#xA;PART I. HISTORICAL&#xA;CHAPTER I.&#xA;LIFE OF ABHINAVAGUPTA. Preliminary Two Abhinavaguptas His ancestry His parents Abhinava as a Yoginībhū Probable time of his birth His childhood and education Abhinava as an incarnation of śeṣa His teachers His family and its atmosphere Some events in the family and their effect on his&#xA;young mind His ascetic period His miraculous powers &amp;hellip; Centres of his activity &amp;hellip; The last scene of his earthly existence A bird&amp;rsquo;s-eye view of his life&#xA;CHAPTER II.&#xA;HIS WORKS. List of his known works Explanation of the arrangement&#xA;(2&#xA;)&#xA;Page.&#xA;Chronological order of his works M. M. Mukundarāma Sāstrī on the Chronology of&#xA;Abhinava&amp;rsquo;s works &amp;hellip; Works known from references Division of his works into three periods&#xA;I Tantric Period &amp;hellip; II Ālankārika Period III Philosophical Period A General idea of his available works&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 INTRODUCTION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/0/1_INTRODUCTION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/0/1_INTRODUCTION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following pages present a short but comprehensive study of Abhinavagupta pāda, the Kashmir Saiva Philo sopher and Literary Critic. His name is familiar and his fame is still alive. His writings are voluminous and his philosophical and poetical theories hold their ground even to-day. To most Sanskrit Scholars, however, he is known only from references in the generally studied books on poetics, such as the Sahitya Darpana and the Kavya Prakāśa. Very few know that he was more a philosopher than a literary critic, and that his contribution to Saiva philosophy is much greater both in volume and importance than that which he made to poetics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 LIST OF ABBREVIATIONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/0/2_LIST_OF_ABBREVIATIONS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/0/2_LIST_OF_ABBREVIATIONS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A. Bh. Abhi. Ah. A. K. B. B. Bh. Bh. G. Bh. G. S. Bh. K.&#xA;Bh. S.&#xA;Bh. Su. B. P. V. B. V. C.C. D. C. D. M. S. D. S. Dh. L. E. H. I. Gh. Gh. V. H. S. P. I. Ph. I. P. V. I. P. V. V. K. K. V. K.S. K. S. K. Sa. M. Bh. M.&#xA;Abhinava Bhāratī. (Baroda) Abhinavagupta. Āhnika. Adhāra Kārikā. (Vāṇi Vilasa) Bāla Bodhini. (Nirnaya Sagar) Bhāskarī. MS. Bhagavad Gītā. Bhagavad Gītārtha Sangraha. MS. Bhoga Kārikā. (Vāṇi Vilāsa) Bhairava Stava. MS. Bharata Sūtra. (Nirnaya Sagar) Bimba Pratibimba Vāda MS. Bịhatī Vimarsini. MS. Catalogus Catalogorum. Daśāvatāra Carita. Dakṣiṇā Mūrti Stotra. (Nirnaya Sagar) Devi Sataka. Dhvanyāloka Locana. (Nirnaya Sagar) Early History of India. Ghata Karpara Kāvya. (Nirnaya Sagar) Ghaṭa Karpara Kulaka Vivrti. MS. History of Sanskrit Poetics. Indian Philosophy. Isvara Pratyabhijñā Vimarsinī. (Kashmir) Isvara Pratyabhijñā Vivrti Vimarsinī MS. Kāvya Kautuka Vivarana. Kashmir Saivaism. (Kashmir) Krama Stotra. MS. Kāvyālankāra Sārasangraha. Mahā Bhārata Mañjarī.&#xA;(ix&#xA;)&#xA;M. K. Moksa Kārikā. (Vāṇi Vilāsa) M. M. Mahārtha Mañjarī. (Trivandrum) M. V. V. Mālinī Vijaya Vārtika. (Kashmir) Mr. T. Mrgendra Tantra. (Devakottai) Mr. V. Mrgendra Vrtti.&#xA;N. K. Nāda Kārikā. (Vānī Vilāsa) P. H. Pratyabhijñā Hrdaya. (Kashmir) P, S.&#xA;Paramārtha Sāra. P. T. V. Parā Trimśikā Vivarana,,, R. T.&#xA;Rāja Taranginī. (Stein&amp;rsquo;s edition) R. Tr. Ratna Traya. (Vāṇi Vilāsa) S. Bh. Sānkara Bhāṣya. (Nirnaya Sagar) S.C. Sabdārtha Cintāmaṇi. (Udayapur) S. D.&#xA;Sankara Digvijaya. S. Dr. śiva Drsti. MS. S. S. V. śiva Sutra Vārtika. (Kashmir) S. S. Vi. śiva Sūtra Vimarsini. S.C. Stava Cintāmaṇi. S. D. S. Sarva Darśana Sangraha. (Abhyankar)&#xA;Spanda Nirnaya. (Kashmir) T. A. Tantrāloka.&#xA;Tanjore Catalogue. T.P. Tattva Prakāśikā. (Vāni Vilāsa) T. S. Tantra Sāra. (Kashmir) T. San. Tattva Sangraha. (Vāni Vilasa) Ta. San. T. D. Tarka Sangraha Tattva Dipikā. T. T. N. Tattva Traya Nirnaya. (Vāṇi Vilasa) T. V.&#xA;Traditional Verse. T. V. Dh. Tantra Vata Dhānikā. (Kashmir) V. S. S. Bh. Vedānta Sutra Sankara Bhāṣya. (Nirnaya&#xA;Sagar)&#xA;S. N.&#xA;T. C.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
