<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;bhakti-yoga on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;bhakti-yoga on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>106 PRAYER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/106_definition_of_bhakti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/106_definition_of_bhakti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;prayer&#34;&gt;PRAYER&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;स तन्मयो ह्यमृत ईशसंस्थो ज्ञः सर्वगो भुवनस्यास्य गोप्ता।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;य ईशेऽस्य जगतो नित्यमेव नान्यो हेतुर्विद्यत ईशनाय॥&lt;br&gt;&#xA;यो ब्रह्माणं विदधाति पूर्व यो वै वेदांश्च प्रहिणोति तस्मै।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;तं ह देवं आत्मबुध्दिप्रकाशं मुमुक्षुर्वै शरणमहं प्रपद्ये॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He is the Soul of the Universe; He is Immortal; His is the Rulership;&#xA;He is the All-knowing, the All-pervading, the Protector of the Universe,&#xA;the Eternal Ruler. None else is there efficient to govern the world&#xA;eternally. He who at the beginning of creation projected Brahmā (i.e.&#xA;the universal consciousness), and who delivered the Vedas unto him —&#xA;seeking liberation I go for refuge unto that effulgent One, whose light&#xA;turns the understanding towards the Âtman.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>107 THE PHILOSOPHY OF ISHVARA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/107_the_philosophy_of_ishwara/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/107_the_philosophy_of_ishwara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER II&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-philosophy-of-ishvara&#34;&gt;THE PHILOSOPHY OF ISHVARA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Who is Ishvara? Janmādyasya yatah — &amp;ldquo;From whom is the birth,&#xA;continuation, and dissolution of the universe,&amp;rdquo; — He is Ishvara — &amp;ldquo;the&#xA;Eternal, the Pure, the Ever-Free, the Almighty, the All-Knowing, the&#xA;All-Merciful, the Teacher of all teachers&amp;rdquo;; and above all, Sa Ishvarah&#xA;anirvachaniya-premasvarupah — &amp;ldquo;He the Lord is, of His own nature,&#xA;inexpressible Love.&amp;rdquo; These certainly are the definitions of a Personal&#xA;God. Are there then two Gods — the &amp;ldquo;Not this, not this,&amp;rdquo; the&#xA;Sat-chit-ānanda, the Existence-Knowledge-Bliss of the philosopher, and&#xA;this God of Love of the Bhakta? No, it is the same Sat-chit-ananda who&#xA;is also the God of Love, the impersonal and personal in one. It has&#xA;always to be understood that the Personal God worshipped by the Bhakta&#xA;is not separate or different from the Brahman. All is Brahman, the One&#xA;without a second; only the Brahman, as unity or absolute, is too much of&#xA;an abstraction to be loved and worshipped; so the Bhakta chooses the&#xA;relative aspect of Brahman, that is, Ishvara, the Supreme Ruler. To use&#xA;a simile: Brahman is as the clay or substance out of which an infinite&#xA;variety of articles are fashioned. As clay, they are all one; but form&#xA;or manifestation differentiates them. Before every one of them was made,&#xA;they all existed potentially in the clay, and, of course, they are&#xA;identical substantially; but when formed, and so long as the form&#xA;remains, they are separate and different; the clay-mouse can never&#xA;become a clay-elephant, because, as manifestations, form alone makes&#xA;them what they are, though as unformed clay they are all one. Ishvara is&#xA;the highest manifestation of the Absolute Reality, or in other words,&#xA;the highest possible reading of the Absolute by the human mind. Creation&#xA;is eternal, and so also is Ishvara.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>108 SPIRITUAL REALISATION, THE AIM OF BHAKTI-YOGA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/108_spiritual_realisation_the_aim_of_bhakti-yoga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/108_spiritual_realisation_the_aim_of_bhakti-yoga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER III&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;spiritual-realisation-the-aim-of-bhakti-yoga&#34;&gt;SPIRITUAL REALISATION, THE AIM OF BHAKTI-YOGA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To the Bhakta these dry details are necessary only to strengthen his&#xA;will; beyond that they are of no use to him. For he is treading on a&#xA;path which is fitted very soon to lead him beyond the hazy and turbulent&#xA;regions of reason, to lead him to the realm of realisation. He, soon,&#xA;through the mercy of the Lord, reaches a plane where pedantic and&#xA;powerless reason is left far behind, and the mere intellectual groping&#xA;through the dark gives place to the daylight of direct perception. He no&#xA;more reasons and believes, he almost perceives. He no more argues, he&#xA;senses. And is not this seeing God, and feeling God, and enjoying God&#xA;higher than everything else? Nay, Bhaktas have not been wanting who have&#xA;maintained that it is higher than even Moksha — liberation. And is it&#xA;not also the highest utility? There are people — and a good many of them&#xA;too — in the world who are convinced that only that is of use and&#xA;utility which brings to man creature-comforts. Even religion, God,&#xA;eternity, soul, none of these is of any use to them, as they do not&#xA;bring them money or physical comfort. To such, all those things which do&#xA;not go to gratify the senses and appease the appetites are of no&#xA;utility. In every mind, utility, however, is conditioned by its own&#xA;peculiar wants. To men, therefore, who never rise higher than eating,&#xA;drinking, begetting progeny, and dying, the only gain is in sense&#xA;enjoyments; and they must wait and go through many more births and&#xA;reincarnations to learn to feel even the faintest necessity for anything&#xA;higher. But those to whom the eternal interests of the soul are of much&#xA;higher value than the fleeting interests of this mundane life, to whom&#xA;the gratification of the senses is but like the thoughtless play of the&#xA;baby, to them God and the love of God form the highest and the only&#xA;utility of human existence. Thank God there are some such still living&#xA;in this world of too much worldliness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>109 THE NEED OF GURU</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/109_the_need_of_guru/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/109_the_need_of_guru/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER IV&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-need-of-guru&#34;&gt;THE NEED OF GURU&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every soul is destined to be perfect, and every being, in the end, will&#xA;attain the state of perfection. Whatever we are now is the result of our&#xA;acts and thoughts in the past; and whatever we shall be in the future&#xA;will be the result of what we think end do now. But this, the shaping of&#xA;our own destinies, does not preclude our receiving help from outside;&#xA;nay, in the vast majority of cases such help is absolutely necessary.&#xA;When it comes, the higher powers and possibilities of the soul are&#xA;quickened, spiritual life is awakened, growth is animated, and man&#xA;becomes holy and perfect in the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>110 QUALIFICATIONS OF THE ASPIRANT AND THE TEACHER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/110_qualifications_of_the_aspirant_and_teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/110_qualifications_of_the_aspirant_and_teacher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER V&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;qualifications-of-the-aspirant-and-the-teacher&#34;&gt;QUALIFICATIONS OF THE ASPIRANT AND THE TEACHER&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How are we to know a teacher, then? The sun requires no torch to make&#xA;him visible, we need not light a candle in order to see him. When the&#xA;sun rises, we instinctively become aware of the fact, and when a teacher&#xA;of men comes to help us, the soul will instinctively know that truth has&#xA;already begun to shine upon it. Truth stands on its own evidence, it&#xA;does not require any other testimony to prove it true, it is self&#xA;effulgent. It penetrates into the innermost corners of our nature, and&#xA;in its presence the whole universe stands up and says, &amp;ldquo;This is truth.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The teachers whose wisdom and truth shine like the light of the sun are&#xA;the very greatest the world has known, and they are worshipped as God by&#xA;the major portion of mankind. But we may get help from comparatively&#xA;lesser ones also; only we ourselves do not possess intuition enough to&#xA;judge properly of the man from whom we receive teaching and guidance; so&#xA;there ought to be certain tests, certain conditions, for the teacher to&#xA;satisfy, as there are also for the taught.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>111 INCARNATE TEACHERS AND INCARNATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/111_incarnate_teachers_and_incarnation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/111_incarnate_teachers_and_incarnation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER VI&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;incarnate-teachers-and-incarnation&#34;&gt;INCARNATE TEACHERS AND INCARNATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wherever His name is spoken, that very place is holy. How much more so&#xA;is the man who speaks His name, and with what veneration ought we to&#xA;approach that man out of whom comes to us spiritual truth! Such great&#xA;teachers of spiritual truth are indeed very few in number in this world,&#xA;but the world is never altogether without them. They are always the&#xA;fairest flowers of human life — अहेतुकदयासिन्धुः — &amp;ldquo;the ocean of mercy&#xA;without any motive&amp;rdquo;. आचार्यं मां विजानीयात् — &amp;ldquo;Know the Guru to be Me&amp;rdquo;,&#xA;says Shri Krishna in the &lt;em&gt;Bhagavata&lt;/em&gt;. The moment the world is absolutely&#xA;bereft of these, it becomes a hideous hell and hastens on to its&#xA;destruction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>112 THE MANTRA: OM: WORD AND WISDOM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/112_the_mantra_om_word_and_wisdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/112_the_mantra_om_word_and_wisdom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER VII&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-mantra-om-word-and-wisdom&#34;&gt;THE MANTRA: OM: WORD AND WISDOM&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But we are now considering not these Mahā-purushas, the great&#xA;Incarnations, but only the Siddha-Gurus (teachers who have attained the&#xA;goal); they, as a rule, have to convey the germs of spiritual wisdom to&#xA;the disciple by means of words (Mantras) to be meditated upon. What are&#xA;these Mantras? The whole of this universe has, according to Indian&#xA;philosophy, both name and form (Nāma-Rupa) as its conditions of&#xA;manifestation. In the human microcosm, there cannot be a single wave in&#xA;the mind-stuff (Chittavritti) unconditioned by name and form. If it be&#xA;true that nature is built throughout on the same plan, this kind of&#xA;conditioning by name and form must also be the plan of the building of&#xA;the whole of the cosmos. यथा एकेन मृत्पिण्डेन सर्वं मृन्मयं विज्ञातं&#xA;स्यात् — &amp;ldquo;As one lump of clay being known, all things of clay are&#xA;known&amp;rdquo;, so the knowledge of the microcosm must lead to the knowledge of&#xA;the macrocosm. Now form is the outer crust, of which the name or the&#xA;idea is the inner essence or kernel. The body is the form, and the mind&#xA;or the Antahkarana is the name, and sound-symbols are universally&#xA;associated with Nāma (name) in all beings having the power of speech. In&#xA;the individual man the thought-waves rising in the limited Mahat or&#xA;Chitta (mind-stuff), must manifest themselves, first as &lt;em&gt;words&lt;/em&gt;, and&#xA;then as the more concrete &lt;em&gt;forms&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>113 WORSHIP OF SUBSTITUTES AND IMAGES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/113_worship_of_substitutes_and_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/113_worship_of_substitutes_and_images/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER VIII&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;worship-of-substitutes-and-images&#34;&gt;WORSHIP OF SUBSTITUTES AND IMAGES&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next points to be considered are the worship of Pratikas or of&#xA;things more or less satisfactory as substitutes for God, and the worship&#xA;of Pratimās or images. What is the worship of God through a Pratika? It&#xA;is अब्रह्मणि ब्रह्मदृष्ट्याऽनुसन्धानम् — Joining the mind with devotion&#xA;to that which is not Brahman, taking it to be Brahman&amp;quot; — says Bhagavān&#xA;Rāmānuja. &amp;ldquo;Worship the mind as Brahman this is internal; and the Âkāsha&#xA;as Brahman, this is with regard to the Devas&amp;rdquo;, says Shankara. The mind&#xA;is an internal Pratika, the Akasha is an external one, and both have to&#xA;be worshipped as substitutes of God. He continues, &amp;ldquo;Similarly — &amp;rsquo;the Sun&#xA;is Brahman, this is the command&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;He who worships Name as Brahman&amp;rsquo; — in&#xA;all such passages the doubt arises as to the worship of Pratikas.&amp;rdquo; The&#xA;word Pratika means going towards; and worshipping a Pratika is&#xA;worshipping something as a substitute which is, in some one or more&#xA;respects, like Brahman more and more, but is not Brahman. Along with the&#xA;Pratikas mentioned in the Shrutis there are various others to be found&#xA;in the Purānas and the Tantras. In this kind of Pratika-worship may be&#xA;included all the various forms of Pitri-worship and Deva-worship.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>114 THE CHOSEN IDEAL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/114_the_chosen_ideal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/114_the_chosen_ideal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER IX&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-chosen-ideal&#34;&gt;THE CHOSEN IDEAL&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next thing to be considered is what we know as Ishta-Nishthā. One&#xA;who aspires to be a Bhakta must know that &amp;ldquo;so many opinions are so many&#xA;ways&amp;rdquo;. He must know that all the various sects of the various religions&#xA;are the various manifestations of the glory of the same Lord. &amp;ldquo;They call&#xA;You by so many names; they divide You, as it were, by different names,&#xA;yet in each one of these is to be found Your omnipotence&amp;hellip;.You reach&#xA;the worshipper through all of these, neither is there any special time&#xA;so long as the soul has intense love for You. You are so easy of&#xA;approach; it is my misfortune that I cannot love You.&amp;rdquo; Not only this,&#xA;the Bhakta must take care not to hate, nor even to criticise those&#xA;radiant sons of light who are the founders of various sects; he must not&#xA;even hear them spoken ill of. Very few indeed are those who are at once&#xA;the possessors of an extensive sympathy and power of appreciation, as&#xA;well as an intensity of love. We find, as a rule, that liberal and&#xA;sympathetic sects lose the intensity of religious feeling, and in their&#xA;hands, religion is apt to degenerate into a kind of politico-social club&#xA;life. On the other hand, intensely narrow sectaries, whilst displaying a&#xA;very commendable love of their own ideals, are seen to have acquired&#xA;every particle of that love by hating every one who is not of exactly&#xA;the same opinions as themselves. Would to God that this world was full&#xA;of men who were as intense in their love as worldwide in their&#xA;sympathies! But such are only few and far between. Yet we know that it&#xA;is practicable to educate large numbers of human beings into the ideal&#xA;of a wonderful blending of both the width and the intensity of love; and&#xA;the way to do that is by this path of the Istha-Nishtha or &amp;ldquo;steadfast&#xA;devotion to the chosen ideal&amp;rdquo;. Every sect of every religion presents&#xA;only one ideal of its own to mankind, but the eternal Vedantic religion&#xA;opens to mankind an infinite number of doors for ingress into the inner&#xA;shrine of divinity, and places before humanity an almost inexhaustible&#xA;array of ideals, there being in each of them a manifestation of the&#xA;Eternal One. With the kindest solicitude, the Vedanta points out to&#xA;aspiring men and women the numerous roads, hewn out of the solid rock of&#xA;the realities of human life, by the glorious sons, or human&#xA;manifestations, of God, in the past and in the present, and stands with&#xA;outstretched arms to welcome all — to welcome even those that are yet to&#xA;be — to that Home of Truth and that Ocean of Bliss, wherein the human&#xA;soul, liberated from the net of Māyā, may transport itself with perfect&#xA;freedom and with eternal joy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>115 THE METHOD AND THE MEANS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/115_the_method_and_the_means/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/bhakti-yoga/115_the_method_and_the_means/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER X&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-method-and-the-means&#34;&gt;THE METHOD AND THE MEANS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In regard to the method and the means of Bhakti-Yoga we read in the&#xA;commentary of Bhagavan Ramanuja on the &lt;em&gt;Vedanta-Sutras&lt;/em&gt;: &amp;ldquo;The attaining&#xA;of That comes through discrimination, controlling the passions,&#xA;practice, sacrificial work, purity, strength, and suppression of&#xA;excessive joy.&amp;rdquo; Viveka or discrimination is, according to Ramanuja,&#xA;discriminating, among other things, the pure food from the impure.&#xA;According to him, food becomes impure from three causes: (1) by the&#xA;nature of the food itself, as in the case of garlic etc.; (2) owing to&#xA;its coming from wicked and accursed persons; and (3) from physical&#xA;impurities, such as dirt, or hair, etc. The Shrutis say, When the food&#xA;is pure, the Sattva element gets purified, and the memory becomes&#xA;unwavering&amp;quot;, and Ramanuja quotes this from the Chhāndogya Upanishad.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
