<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;2 search for space on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;2 search for space on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>16 Ups and Downs with Malaysia</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/16_Ups_and/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/16_Ups_and/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 20 March 1966, eight months after separation, Tunku Abdul Rahman, the prime minister of Malaysia, visited Singapore. I called on him at Federation House near the Botanic Gardens. For three hours we talked, had a Chinese dinner, watched television and continued talking. The only other persons present that night were his wife and the Malaysian high commissioner, Jamal Abdul Latiff. It was the way the Tunku usually conducted business. He talked of many things besides the matters most on his mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Indonesia: From Foe to Friend</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/17_Indones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/17_Indones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Indonesia faced separatist rebellions in 1957, Western arms dealers arrived in Singapore to sell weapons to rebels in Sumatra and Sulawesi. The Indonesian consul-general, Lieutenant-General Jatikusomo, met me in 1958 when I was an opposition leader. I assured him that if we became the government, these arms dealers would be expelled. When the PAP won the 1959 general election I kept this promise, and Jatikusomo – a dapper, intelligent, courteous and active Javanese aristocrat – proposed that I consolidate our relationship with Jakarta with an official visit. I agreed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Building Ties with Thailand, the Philipphines and Brunei</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/18_Buildin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/18_Buildin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My early impressions of the Thais were gathered from stopovers in Bangkok on the way to and from London in the 1950s. Later, on visits accompanying the Tunku in 1962–63, I was impressed by the quality of the men in charge of their foreign policy. The Thai foreign ministry recruited their brightest and best, educated in British, European and Latin American universities. It was their glamour service, highly paid and much respected because of their foreign travels at a time when travel was rare. Their domestic administrators did not match the quality of their foreign service officers. They needed their best to fend off encroachments by the British from Burma and by the French from Indochina. Thailand is the only Southeast Asian country that has never been colonised.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Vietnam, Myanmar and Cambodia: Coming to Terms with the Modern World</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/19_Vietnam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/19_Vietnam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 29 October 1977 a Vietnamese DC3, an old Dakota, was hijacked while on an internal flight and made to fly to Singapore. We could not stop it from landing at Seletar Air Base. We allowed the Vietnamese to send a new crew to fly the plane back with the old crew and the other passengers, after we had refuelled and refurbished it. We prosecuted the hijackers who were convicted and sentenced to 14 years’ jail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Asean-Unpromising Start, Promising Future</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/20_Asean-U/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/20_Asean-U/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Asean was formed in August 1967 amid great uncertainty in the region. In a low-key ceremony, the foreign ministers of Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore and Thailand met in Bangkok to sign the declaration. The war in Vietnam was spreading into Cambodia and the region was caught up in communist insurgencies. I did not set great store by the lofty aims of the group: to accelerate economic growth, social progress and cultural development; to promote peace and stability; to collaborate in agriculture and industry and expand trade. The unspoken objective was to gain strength through solidarity ahead of the power vacuum that would come with an impending British and later a possible US withdrawal. Indonesia wanted to reassure Malaysia and Singapore that, with the end of the Sukarno era, its intentions were peaceful and it had abandoned Sukarno’s aggressive policies. Thailand wanted to associate itself with its non-communist neighbours who were members of the Non-Aligned Movement. The Philippines wanted a forum to push its claim to North Borneo. Singapore sought the understanding and support of its neighbours in enhancing stability and security in the region.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 East Asia in Crisis 1997–99</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/21_East_As/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/21_East_As/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The sudden devastation to the economies of Asean in 1997 has set back its standing and its capability to play an international role. Indonesia’s President Suharto, who had built up his country and gained stature and recognition, was deposed. Prime Minister Mahathir of Malaysia was diminished by the Western media headlining his denunciations against currency speculators and Jews like George Soros. Thailand’s Prime Minister Chuan Leekpai needed time to establish his international standing. What happened?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Inside the Commonwealth Club</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/22_Inside/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/22_Inside/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we became independent I assumed that Singapore would be a member of the Commonwealth. The British government was supportive, and the Tunku was keen to sponsor us. I did not know that Pakistan had initially opposed our admission; it had considered Malaysia too pro-India in the India-Pakistan conflict over Kashmir. Arnold Smith, the secretary-general of the Commonwealth, in his memoirs wrote that Pakistan’s antagonism against Malaysia was carried over to the Singapore government which had shown sympathy for India. But Smith persuaded Pakistan to abstain and not object to Singapore’s admission. In October 1965 Singapore was admitted as the 22nd member of the Commonwealth. This membership was valuable. For a newly independent country, it provided links to a network of governments whose institutions were similar and whose leaders and officials shared a common background. They were all English-speaking governments, with British civil administration practices and legal, judicial and educational systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 New Bonds with Britain</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/23_New_Bon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/23_New_Bon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 24 September 1975, the Gordon Highlanders’ drums and pipes struck up in final farewell as the HMS &lt;em&gt;Mermaid&lt;/em&gt; pulled out of Sembawang Naval Base. It was a mere 2,500-tonne frigate – a tiny component of the Royal Navy warships and aircraft carriers that once were based there. The last of the British troops left soon after. Their departure marked the end of 150 years of British political and military influence in the region.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Ties with Australia and New Zealand</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/24_Ties_wi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/24_Ties_wi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Japan’s sudden invasion in December 1941 dramatically changed Australia’s memories of Singapore. Some 18,000 of its troops with no combat experience, together with 70,000 British and Indians, had to fight without adequate air cover against a battle-hardened Japanese Imperial Army. By the time Singapore fell in February 1942 about 2,000 Australians had been killed, over 1,000 wounded and some 15,000 captured.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More than one-third of the prisoners of war died from malnutrition, disease and ill-treatment, especially along the infamous Burma Railway. Many gravestones stand at the Kranji Commonwealth War Cemetery in Singapore, mute testimony to their sacrifice for king and country. The capture of thousands of their soldiers by the Japanese Imperial Army in Singapore will forever be seared into Australia’s national memory, a disaster second only to Gallipoli. But Singapore is nearer home and strategically more relevant to Australia. Hence, after World War II, Australia continued its old links with Britain and its troops returned to Singapore to help put down communist insurgency in Malaya.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 South Asia’s Legends and Leaders</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/25_South_A/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/25_South_A/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a young student, I admired Nehru and his objective of a secular multiracial society. Like most nationalists from British colonies, I had read his books written during his long years in British jails, especially his letters to his daughter. They were elegantly written, and his views and sentiments struck a resonant chord in me. Together with other democratic socialists of the 1950s, I had wondered whether India or China would become the model for development. I wanted democratic India, not communist China, to win. But despite achievements such as the green revolution, population growth has kept down India’s standard of living and quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 Following Britain into Europe</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/26_Followi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/26_Followi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My views of the Europeans had been much influenced by British attitudes of the 1950s and ’60s. The Europeans seemed different and somewhat strange, not as cohesive as nations nor as constitutional-minded as the British: the French were prone to riots and revolutions and the overturning of constitutions; the Germans tended to use force to settle disputes. But once Harold Macmillan as prime minister made his bid in 1962 to join the European Economic Community (EEC, now the European Union) and was rebuffed, I believed it was only a matter of time before a second application or a third would succeed. After Britain announced its withdrawal from east of Suez in 1968, Prime Minister Harold Wilson made an overture to President Charles de Gaulle. Again it failed, but it underlined how important Europe had become for Britain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 The Soviet Union: An Empire Implodes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/27_The_Sov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/27_The_Sov/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was in Jesselton (now Kota Kinabalu) near the jungles of British North Borneo for a court case when news broke in October 1957 that the Russians had sent a sputnik into space. It was a spectacular demonstration of the superiority of Soviet technology. I took the challenge of the communist system seriously. The Soviets were aggressive everywhere in Asia, and together with communist China were fuelling guerrilla insurrections. They loomed even larger in my mind after they sent the first man into space in April 1961. It lent credence to their claim that history was on their side.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 America: The Anti-Communist Anchorman</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/28_America/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/28_America/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In late August 1965, within days of the trauma of separation from Malaysia, I was suddenly faced with a personal problem. Choo had a worrying medical condition that required surgery. Her gynaecologist, Dr Benjamin Sheares, recommended an American specialist who was the best man in this field. I tried to get him to come but could not persuade him to do so. He wanted Choo to go to Switzerland where he was going for some other engagement. I enlisted the help of the US consul-general and, through him, the US government. They were unhelpful; either they could not or would not help. I approached the British to get their top specialist named by Sheares. He agreed and immediately flew to Singapore, expressing understanding for my not wanting her to travel abroad when I could not leave Singapore. This incident reinforced my gut feeling that I would find it difficult to work with the Americans whom I did not know as well as the British.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Strategic: Accord with the United States</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/29_Strateg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/29_Strateg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When President Jimmy Carter took over from Gerald Ford, there was an abrupt change of emphasis in US foreign and defence policies. He was more interested in Africa than Asia. To the dismay of America’s friends and allies in Asia, he announced that there would be a rundown of US troops in Korea. Carter believed Americans were tired after the Vietnam War and wanted to forget Asia. He concentrated on the reconciliation of black and white Americans. He also saw his role as a builder of bridges across the great divide between the whites and the blacks in southern Africa. His emphasis was on human rights, not defence and security. Asean leaders braced themselves for four difficult years as they waited to see what he would actually do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 America’s New Agenda</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/30_America/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/30_America/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Singapore’s relationship with the United States falls neatly into two parts – during and after the Cold War. When the Soviet Union posed a threat to America and the world, we had good relations with both the Democrat and Republican administrations from Johnson in the 1960s to Bush in the 1990s. Our strategic interests coincided completely. The United States was against the Soviet Union and communist China. So were we. Furthermore, we were strongly in support of a US military presence in East Asia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 Japan: Asia’s First Miracle</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/31_Japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/31_Japan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My impressions of the Japanese have undergone several changes over the last 60 years. Before World War II, I knew them as polite and courteous salesmen and dentists. They were a clean, neat, disciplined and self-contained community. I was thus completely unprepared for the cruelties they inflicted from February 1942 as conquerors of Singapore. They were unbelievably cruel. There were exceptions but systematic brutalisation by their military government made them a callous lot. We suffered three and a half years of privation and horror. Millions died in Japanese-occupied territories in Southeast Asia. Prisoners of war, British, Dutch, Indian and Australian alike, rotted away or were worked to death.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32 Lessons from Japan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/32_Lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/32_Lessons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After World War II, a few men at the top of Japanese society were determined to rebuild Japan and its industrial sinews. This elite had not been disbanded by General MacArthur’s occupying forces. When communist China intervened in the Korean War, the Americans switched their policy to one of rebuilding Japan. Japanese leaders realised this was their chance and kept a low, humble posture while they caught up with Americans in textiles, steel, ships, motorcars and petrochemicals, then electrical and electronic goods and cameras, and finally computers. They had an elitist system. Like the French with their Grand Ecoles, their former imperial universities as well as the top private ones selected the best and honed their talent. That talent found its way to the top of the bureaucracy and their corporations. Their elite, both administrators and corporate leaders, are equal to any in the world. However, the Japanese miracle was not the work of just a few at the top. The Japanese people as a whole shared a determination to prove that they were able to make the grade. At every level they strove to excel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>33 Korea: At the Crossroads</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/33_Korea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/33_Korea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I did not have happy memories of the Koreans because the first ones I met were in Japanese uniform. They were one of two groups of auxiliaries the Japanese brought to Singapore, the other being Taiwanese. The Koreans were the toughs and as heavy-handed as the Japanese soldiers. The Taiwanese were used as interpreters, speaking Hokkien, Singapore’s major Chinese dialect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After the war, Korea’s economic dynamism overrode my past prejudices. I visited the country in October 1979 when President Park Chung Hee received me in his official residence, the Blue House. Park was an ascetic-looking man, small and wiry with a sharp face and a narrow nose. He had been chosen and trained as a military officer by the Japanese. He must have been among the best of his generation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 Hong Kong’s Transition</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/34_Hong_Ko/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/34_Hong_Ko/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I first visited Hong Kong in 1954 on an Italian liner, the &lt;em&gt;Asia&lt;/em&gt;. She stayed three nights in Hong Kong, allowing Choo and me to wander around the colony on foot. It was a charming city on the island fronting the harbour, with a growing township across the water on the Kowloon side. It was attractive because behind the town centre was the Peak, some 1,000 feet high with roads and houses dotting the hillside.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 Taiwan: The Other China</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/35_Taiwan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/35_Taiwan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Their isolation made the Taiwanese keen to develop ties with Singapore in the early years. On our part, we were anxious not to be completely dependent on the Israelis for military training. Initial discussions began in 1967. They sent a top-level representative who saw Keng Swee, then defence minister, and me. By December they had submitted a proposal for building up an air force. We were keen to train our pilots and naval officers in Taiwan; the Israelis could not offer such facilities. The Taiwanese defence ministry was helpful, but every now and again would hint that when their foreign ministry got wind of their defence assistance, they would require some form of diplomatic recognition in return. We made it clear that we could not give way on this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>36 China: The Dragon with a Long Tail</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/36_China/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/36_China/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No foreign country other than Britain has had a greater influence on Singapore’s political development than China, the ancestral homeland of three-quarters of our people. The Singapore-China relationship has been long, complex and unequal. From the founding of Singapore in 1819 until 1867, Qing dynasty China did not recognise the existence of the overseas Chinese. This changed in the 1870s when China set up consulates in Nanyang (the South Seas), then under the colonial control of the British, French and Dutch. These consulates, including one in Singapore, were intended not so much to protect the Chinese as to harness their loyalty to China by promoting Chinese culture and education, and to obtain their financial support.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>37 Deng Xiaoping’s China</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/37_Deng_Xi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/37_Deng_Xi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My meeting with Vice-Premier Deng Xiaoping was unforgettable. A dapper, stocky man of 74, not more than five feet tall, in a beige Mao suit came down from a Boeing 707 at Paya Lebar Airport in November 1978. Walking briskly, he inspected the guard of honour, then drove with me to the Istana Villa, our guesthouse in the Istana domain. We met that afternoon for formal discussions in the cabinet room.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>38 China Beyond Beijing</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/38_China_B/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/38_China_B/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the 1980s and ’90s, I visited China almost every year to better understand its leaders’ motivations and ambitions for China. Because we had started from antagonistic positions, we needed time and deeper interaction to develop a relationship of confidence with China. China had been exporting revolution to turn Singapore into a communist state. When they had a fight with Vietnam on their hands, they needed better relations with Asean. It was during this period, from 1978 to 1991, when we worked in our different ways against Vietnam’s occupation of Cambodia, that our perceptions of each other changed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>39 Tiananmen</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/39_Tiananm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/39_Tiananm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In May 1989 the world watched a bizarre drama unfold in Beijing. It was shown live on satellite television because the Western media were there in strength with their cameras in position to cover the Deng-Gorbachev summit. Students had gathered in large numbers in orderly fashion at Tiananmen Square in front of the Great Hall of the People. They carried banners and placards to protest against corruption, nepotism and inflation. The police were benign. The general secretary of the Chinese Communist Party (CCP) himself, Zhao Ziyang, made encouraging noises, that the students wanted the party and the government to reform, and had good intentions. As the crowds swelled, the banners and slogans became more critical, anti-government and strident. They started to denounce the government and Premier Li Peng by name. When nothing happened, they targeted Deng Xiaoping, ridiculing him in satirical doggerel. When I saw this on television, I felt that this demonstration would end in tears. No emperor in China can be lampooned and ridiculed and continue to reign.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>40 China: To Be Rich Is Glorious</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/40_China/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/2_search_for_space/40_China/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deng Xiaoping went on a well-publicised tour of south China in February 1992. At Shenzhen he said that Guangdong should catch up with Asia’s Four Dragons (Hong Kong, Singapore, South Korea and Taiwan) in 20 years, not only in economics but also in social order and social climate. China should do better than these countries in these matters. Only then would it have the distinguishing characteristics of Chinese socialism. Deng added, “There is good social order in Singapore. They govern the place with discipline. We should draw from their experience, and do even better than them.” In China, commendation from Deng was the ultimate word on what was good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
