<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;कृष्ण-कविता on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/kRShNa-kavitA/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;कृष्ण-कविता on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/kRShNa-kavitA/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flight from mArtANDamandira</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/kRShNa-kavitA/flight_from_mArtANDamandira/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/kRShNa-kavitA/flight_from_mArtANDamandira/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“namastae Sharadae Devi kaashmeera puravaasini&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;tvaamaham praarthayae nityam vidyaadaanam cha daehi mae…”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Aditi Chauhan, Author of “Saffron: the colour of Kashmir” recited these evocative lines at her unique book release function today, held befittingly in the vicinity of Sharda Peeth, amongst a select august audience of Kashmiri Pandits, who trekked along with her to this sacred spot, to raise awareness amongst youth, of the surviving cultural heritage of this region. While paying tribute to the Goddess of Knowledge, Sharada Devi, who has blessed the land to be the seat of learning for centuries, Dr. Chauhan spoke of the traditional university it once was, frequented by Hindus for aeons from all over the sub-continent in search of rare texts or a long lost commentary of an obscure work. After a short reading of a passage from her book, she concluded her talk by a clever wordplay on the title of her newly published work, saying that kesar was not alien to Kashmir, it had been in use for making kumkum, in preparing Ayurvedic medicines, in embellishing cuisines, as well as in being a much sought after export commodity, for a long time now, so this outcry against saffronisation of Kaashmeera Pradesha was a bid by the erstwhile power grabbers to relegate Kashmir’s economy back to dependency and loans. The average Kashmiri was so much more aware now, s/he could no longer be taken for a ride by a few families acting on their behalf to their detriment, as in the past.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flight from Modhera</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/kRShNa-kavitA/flight_from_modera/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/kRShNa-kavitA/flight_from_modera/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Professor Khorshed Mehr’s daily evening walks by the Zayandeh, listening to underground music by the courageous youth, who could be jailed simply for singing or dancing publicly, he would often think about what made Persia, and the powerful, wealthy, and sophisticated Sassanids fall to Islam, and what was it that helped India remain Hindu, to date. Despite 800 years of Islamic rule.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Khorshed old and frail struggled against his captors, his voice muffled. He heard himself chant silent prayers for help. They had not only gagged and blindfolded him with great dexterity but had also tied his hands at the back, a skill that was no doubt acquired by watching a few routine Bollywood films. The two young village men who had come to meet him for ‘consultation’ during his dinner at the roadside dhaba should have raised an alarm in him, he who was so used to being accosted by secret police should have sensed something was amiss, yet he had not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flight from mUlasthAna</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/kRShNa-kavitA/flight_from_mUlasthAna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/kRShNa-kavitA/flight_from_mUlasthAna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sri gurubhyo namaha!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nuruddin was hallucinating and he knew it. That image of gold and red kept coming back to him, his eyes were reeling under the excessive light inside his brain, sending shockwaves through his body. He shivered more out of a need to shrug off this preposterous reality than fear. How was it even possible?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The streets sang with the camaraderie of foreign tongues, the lotus filled ponds and lakes were lit up with oil lamps all along the perimeters, the two-storied guest houses were decorated with mango leaves and rangolis, roads lined with flowering trees, incense-filled the air, fragrant in the cool spring dusk, beautiful dancing women heady with exquisite gold jewellery, tinkling bells and silver anklets, gliding gaily towards the massive structure, skipping and hopping, climbing the steps like deer springing away from strange sights… all this easy laughter heralded certain doom..such freedom, such magnificence, such celebration and riches …..&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kondh in Konark</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/kRShNa-kavitA/kondh_in_konark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/kRShNa-kavitA/kondh_in_konark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Translated from the original Kui; “Memoirs of a Kondh in Konark”, by K. Kasturi. Culled from a series of conversations held over a period of six months with the famous tribal leader Rojalin Kondh, instrumental in the rebuilding of the Konark Temple, this is the first such written account of a Kui. Basic facts have not been tampered with, but some liberties have been taken in embellishing the account to make it more reader-friendly.&#xA;Surya Dev Mandir – Konark&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suryanar Kovil, Kumbakonam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/kRShNa-kavitA/kumbhakoNa-sUryanAr-kovil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/kRShNa-kavitA/kumbhakoNa-sUryanAr-kovil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“No”, with just one word Murugan anna dropped them off at Kumbakonam and proceeded to Thirubuvanam a few miles to the north east. Did they not just pass it on the way from Chennai? “Yes, …but that area is not safe for you women and young kids…I will drop off the collection at Tamizhan Catering and come back don’t worry..”, saying so he placated his worried wife Valli, who did not look too happy. Her husband was literally entering the lion’s den unarmed, the very area where his cousin Ramalingam had bled to death. Being a businessman with some local power his cousin had objected to Islamic preachers in the nearby Dalit colony, next thing his hands were chopped off for having the temerity to stand up to the radicals. Fearing more violence, or worse, of being termed Islamophobes none of the hospitals had agreed to treat Ramalingam on time, he would have been alive if he had been attended to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>अरसवल्लि-सूर्यनारायणार्चककथा</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/kRShNa-kavitA/arasavalli-sUryanArAyaNArchaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/kRShNa-kavitA/arasavalli-sUryanArAyaNArchaka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sri gurubhyo namaha!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“…Āditya Hṛudayam Puṇyam Sarva Śatru Vināśanam….”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although he did not have to, Seetaraama Sastry Chief Archaka of the oldest surviving Surya Devata temple in the land, decided to dress his lord for the last time. The one in charge of this duty was brusquely told to go and fetch the requisite garments and garlands and various other accessories that would adorn Suryanarayana today while the Chief Archaka himself made sure that he anointed the deity with the best of oils, fragrant with natural essences. His hands trembled while they massaged the stone as though he was afraid to hurt a frail man or a very important personage. Who can hurt the god of health himself! What a foolish thought! I must not let any negativity come my way today he told himself. He had not consulted his wife or children about this sudden life-changing decision of his which would cause furore not just in his household, but statewide, he was sure of that. Maybe even a nationwide stir, given how news carried far and wide these days so quickly. No, I will not let anything or anyone change my decision. For now, let me serve my lord with devotion one last time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
