<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/uralic/ugric/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/uralic/ugric/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aryan-ethnonyms</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/uralic/ugric/articles/Aryan-ethnonyms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/uralic/ugric/articles/Aryan-ethnonyms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://unrollthread.com/t/1603364562706702337/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aryan ethnonyms of Finno-Ugric peoples.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The former presence of an Aryan-speaking elite layer among the Finno-Ugric speaking peoples of the Oka–Volga–Kama region is clearly visible in the ethnonyms of these peoples.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The name Mari goes back to Proto-Aryan *márya- ‘man’, literally ‘mortal, one who has to die’. It is quite possible that this ethnic name is of Bronze Age origin, for marya- is used in Mitanni Aryan of Syria (c.1500–1300 BC) for the nobility with horse chariots. The name Mordvin seems to go back to early Proto-Aryan mórto- ‘mortal, man’. The same word was separately borrowed into Finnic after the change o &amp;gt; a had taken place in Proto-Aryan, so as to yield márta- ‘mortal, man’ preserved in Old Indo-Aryan: Finnish marras, stem marta- ‘dying, dead; manly, male’.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hungarians: mAgyAr ghost</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/uralic/ugric/articles/hungarians_mAgyAr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/uralic/ugric/articles/hungarians_mAgyAr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: rAzIb khAn &lt;a href=&#34;https://razib.substack.com/p/hungarians-as-the-ghost-of-the-magyar&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hungarians as the ghost of the Magyar confederacy&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The cultural legacy of the Magyars far outweighs their genetic impact&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Though right at the heart of Europe, Hungary is an ethnolinguistic oddity, with a distinct history and unique language. The Pannonian grasslands that cover most of its territory are the westernmost tendril of the Eurasian steppe. Though called the Nagy Alföld in Hungarian, or “Great Hungarian Plain,” in relation to the vast Pontic steppe to its east, it is quite small, only 10% the size. It has loomed large in European history because the Nagy Alföld is the furthest west that nomadic pastoralists could maintain vast herds of horses, from the Pontic Steppe’s Yamnaya herders 5,000 years ago, down to the Magyars in the early medieval period. It served as the base for Sarmatians who raided the Roman Empire in the 3rd century AD, the Avar Empire that menaced Byzantium in the 6th and 7th centuries, and it was here that in 453 AD Attila the Hun died in a drunken stupor, surrounded by riches plundered from half the continent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
