<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Diverse input</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/MT/diverse-input/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/MT/diverse-input/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A sentence in 3 Germanic languages:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Frisian: De sinne skynt moai oer it griene lân.&#xA;English: The sun shines beautifully over the green land.&#xA;German: Die Sonne scheint schön über das grüne Land.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is notable that the ortholog of the Frisian word for beautiful, &amp;lsquo;moai&amp;rsquo;, is entirely lost in English. It has been completely replaced by &amp;lsquo;beautiful&amp;rsquo; of Norman (French) origin. It has likely been lost in modern standard German too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>English aristocrat</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/MT/english-aristocrat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/MT/english-aristocrat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://unrollthread.com/t/1588373222873260033/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Had some reason to talk to a lady, who (genuinely), to use her words, &amp;ldquo;is from a line of minor english aristocrats.&amp;rdquo; A major tangential branch of that conversation was of considerable interest. While not all of it can be mentioned in public, she made some remarks that I found to be rather striking. Approximately:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A big concern of those [in the aristocracy] with Christian bent was that we not just turn atheists but return to paganism. That was their biggest fear when the first contact with India occurred – like what you said about William Jones’ work. In a way, Sunak has crystallized their deep fears… but Sunak has inherited a nation steeped in decline … I don’t see myself going back to live in my country anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five eyes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/MT/five-eyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/MT/five-eyes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;entities&#34;&gt;Entities&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1847160950735921502&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is an entente of entities that are distinct but aligned on some issues in the pa~nchanetra sphere:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the deep-state proper centered on the mahAmlechCha DoS and praNidhi-saMsthA-s;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Then there are sora, navyA~Nka &amp;amp; tAla-vR^ikShaka-s with their shaNDa-sainya.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;then there are the tech bros like duShTa mukhagiri, pachchaisundari and the like who merge into the previous class.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, there is the most dangerous X who cannot be mentioned in public.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;nAri~nga will likely run into them &amp;ndash; the signals have already been sent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientific endgame</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/MT/scientific-endgame/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/MT/scientific-endgame/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the early modern intellectual transitions, it looks as though the English often stole the thunder from a mass of their continental counterparts by coming in towards the end of a line of investigation &amp;amp; capping it with a conclusive piece. In physics we have Copernicus, Galileo, Montanari, Tycho&amp;amp; Kepler on the continent to be capped by a Newton on the island. In biology we have de Buffon, Cuvier, Lamarck, von Goethe on the continent to be capped by Darwin on the island. In electromagnetism we have Coulomb, Volta, Ampere, Oersted, Ohm, Lenz &amp;amp; Kirchhoff capped by a Maxwell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Subversion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/MT/subversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/MT/subversion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1869256707030835207&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a discussion with a friend, we wondered if: the Anglo-Abrahamistic (the Brits and CIA) intelligence agencies are best at sowing discord in the targeted nation&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by inciting malcontents into rebellion and then arming them.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The pretamata is often used as a wedge in the process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In contrast, the rUs were more effective in the art of raising agent provocateurs and effective assassinations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The mUlavAtUla-s appear to have inherited their tradition primarily from rUs side, where some of their cousins were active.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
