<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vikīrṇā viṣayāḥ India</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/MT/2022-06-12_vikirNaH-viShayaH-india-and-the-rus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/MT/2022-06-12_vikirNaH-viShayaH-india-and-the-rus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2022/06/12/vikir%e1%b9%87a%e1%b8%a5-vi%e1%b9%a3aya%e1%b8%a5-india-and-the-rus/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vikīrṇā viṣayāḥ: India and the Rus&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5CS&amp;#43;%5Cstar&amp;amp;bg=ffffff&amp;amp;fg=333333&amp;amp;s=0&amp;amp;c=20201002&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5CS&amp;#43;%5Cstar&amp;amp;bg=ffffff&amp;amp;fg=333333&amp;amp;s=0&amp;amp;c=20201002&#34; alt=&#34;\S \star&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA; Our sleep was disturbed by a dream with a circulating motif whose exact story line, if any, was lost upon awakening. It started with a tall elderly man of West African ancestry playing cricket (batting) with the swagger of a young star at the peak of his career. Striking the ball along the ground or smashing it high into the stands he scored on with ease reminding one of the great black emperors of yore from the Caribbean. Then the dream entered the motif phase with the same man, rather paradoxically, in a classroom repeatedly explaining a single-peaked statistical distribution he claimed to have discovered — we tried hard to capture the equation of that distribution but failed at every repetition of the motif. This kind of REM sleep can be rather troubling, and we tossed and turned around before settling into another scene that seemed to have no connection to the above (unless of course, we forgot that snatch upon awakening). In this scene was an elderly Russian Jewish woman — we would estimate her age as being around 85-90 years — who sat on a chair with a table in front of it. Soon another bearded man appeared beside her — he seemed to be in his 60s but in great health. He exuded a profound ambivalence that strongly impressed upon us — while a part of him presented features consistent with a good character, the rest of him was filled with rapacity, cunning and a taskara spirit. He told the old woman in an unusual accent that seemed either German or Russian that we spoke German. The woman responded in a feeble voice: “Die beiden Grenadiere.” We then saw ourselves in the dream reading out the famous poem of Heinrich Heine:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The weakness of Russia</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/MT/2004-09-07_the-weakness-of-russia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/MT/2004-09-07_the-weakness-of-russia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/09/07/the-weakness-of-russia/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The recent string of Islamic attacks and the spineless Russian response have shown that Russia has indeed lost its edge. In the case of India one can easily see how it is really a weak country and not really capable of standing up to the Americans. So when the Americans and the West ask India to show restrain even when punched by the Mohammedans, India obeys with nothing more than a mild protest. However, Russia has nuclear weapons that can indeed seriously threaten the US, and it is unlikely that the US can do much to Russia directly. Russia has the resources to carry itself and it has proven itself in battle against the superior and ruthless army of the Nazis. Despite this Russia has thus far shown hardly any signs of acting decisively. To the contrary Putin admitted that they were weak.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 eyes vs Rus</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/MT/5-eyes_vs_rus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/MT/5-eyes_vs_rus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Context&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ukraine invasion 2021&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is rather obvious that SM is almost entirely taken over by pysops &amp;amp; disinfo ops in this war between the Occident+Ukr &amp;amp; the Rus. Hence, any prognostication, even short term seems quite hazy for the lesser mortal. 1 thing is however crystal clear. There were no two ways about this for the Rus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a classic trap the AngloXtian core of the Occident has sprang on many nations over the past 350 years. On most occasions they have executed it by using their resource control&amp;amp; cannon fodder to fight on their behalf. Their 5 eyes distributed network spanning the 2 hemispheres has allowed them regenerate even if 1 of the centers was badly hit &amp;ndash; like when their shUlapuruSha cousins led by netA hakAra hammered their kR^ishapuruSha root. Thus, they destroyed &amp;amp; subjugated nation after nation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arabs and Rus 2022</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/MT/arabs_and_rus_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/MT/arabs_and_rus_2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I suspect that the Arabs might be reading the geopolitical wind correctly &amp;ndash; the A~NglamlechCha confederation is essentially a rival to their objectives  of modernization under the aegis of marUnmada because it &amp;rsquo;ll push the radioactive navyonmAda into their populations. While now marUnmAda &amp;amp; navyonmAda are allied, being sprouts of the same root, they will ultimately be on collision course. marUnmatta-s know that &amp;amp; so far are among the quite resistant populations. The Arabs seem to&amp;rsquo;ve realized that the power in the mlechCha world as transiently or perhaps even permanently shifted to the navyonmatta-s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indica history interview</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/MT/indica-history-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/MT/indica-history-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Early Rus khAganate was led by Viking royalty, albeit influenced by various Turkik khAganates (jewish kazar, pagan kipchak ) in structure.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Converted to byzantine christianity - heavily influenced by a queen. Initially the conversion was superficial - limited to the viking elite. Temple of perkunas was demolished, grand statue thrown to a river.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Broke into loose frederation of duchys. Muskovy acquired more power. Elites progressively slavicized.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Invaded and incorporated by Chinggiz&amp;rsquo;s mongol generals. (In a famous battle, Mongol horses did not have iron shoes - so could cross frozen rivers. Shot down the Rus. Smothered 4 princes to death under a plank [not spilling royal blood].)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thence reemerged Rus identity. Plus, updated steppe warfare and administration tactics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dmitry Donskoy Prince of Moscow defeated the then islamized Mongols under Mamai (Battle of Kulikovo). Rus misnomer - &amp;ldquo;Overthrowing the Tatar yoke&amp;rdquo;. Despte later back-and-forth, Rus got confidence - fielded a large force, used good tactics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Czar Peter - shift to western military tactics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Conquered Sibieria - gave them strategic depth (used in war against French and Germans later). Contact with China.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Expanded south - conquering various turkic domains. Great game against the British began.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Osmanli Turks allied with Western (Catholic + Protestant) Christian powers against the Eastern Orthodox Rus. The latter were alarmed by Rus gaining naval power in the black sea.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Catastrophic defeats at Crimea and later by Japan shook them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Then came the communist revolution (likely fostered by western powers, but which went out of hand).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Then, during the german invasion - defence of Stalingrad was a great moment of reckoning. At big human cost they reforged their national spirit.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After German defeat, Rus forces destroyed Japanese forces in Manchuria (great loss of life). Caught between the devil and the deep sea, Japanese surrendered to the western powers (not due to the atom bomb).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lomonosov</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/MT/lomonosov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/MT/lomonosov/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1539855805289226240.html#google_vignette&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the consequences of our closeness to the Rus in the days of my youth was that a good part of our education was from Rus works (translated to Eng). There we learnt of 1 of the greatest intellectuals the gigantic Lomonosov. He seems to be largely ignored in the occident &amp;amp; even sometimes claimed to be a product of Rus boosterism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;m no scholar of the topic to formally rebut that claim but we find it shaky as we have his exchanges with Euler that are a clear testimony of his remarkable achievements. The Rus imported a lot of Germans &amp;amp; high IQ Jews to build their intellectual tradition&lt;br&gt;&#xA;but Lomonosov was a local man of v.humble roots &amp;ndash; a literal matsyendra in their midst.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-economic interests vs oil</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/MT/non-economic-interests_vs_oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/MT/non-economic-interests_vs_oil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1533564683998855170.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Those who fail to account for the interests of conspiring elites (yes people will smear you as &amp;ldquo;conspiracy theorists&amp;rdquo;), religion (overt &amp;amp; covert), ethnicity and energy needs, but look at things purely in economic terms tend to get things wrong. Don&amp;rsquo;t be fooled by the fact they might be widely published &amp;amp; advertised in MSM.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is sometimes surprising to see rich left-liberals, who live in large houses with multiple motor vehicles, overlook the fact that as of today there is no comfortable modern life without the exothermic consumption of fossil fuels. What to say of the uses of coal tar or petroleum derivatives. Hence, it is rather notable that the Occidental confederation has made several moves that have dropped the axe on its own foot while fighting the Rus in a thinly proxied war.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
