<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Priya on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/priyA/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Priya on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/priyA/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>‘Nysa in India’ &amp; the</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/priyA/2021-12-17_nysa-in-india-the-related-narratives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/priyA/2021-12-17_nysa-in-india-the-related-narratives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://cestlaviepriya.wordpress.com/2021/12/17/nysa-in-india-the-related-narratives/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘Nysa in India’ &amp;amp; the Related Narratives&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alexander III of Macedon in his campaign of world conquest reached India&#xA;in 327 BCE after attaining victory over the Persian Achaemenid Empire.&#xA;It is reported by western classical sources that in India, the invaders&#xA;stumbled on a city named Nysa and the inhabitants of the city told him&#xA;that it was founded by none other than Dionysus. Alexander, we are told,&#xA;was elated; he had found descendants of Greeks, in a far away land,&#xA;conquered by the divine. As fascinating this tale is, a history&#xA;enthusiast is intrigued to know more about the historicity of this&#xA;tradition. Though, as Arrian had rightly said, even if there is doubt&#xA;about credibility of such events, they do not seem to be incredible&#xA;altogether, if one takes divine agency into account.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; But as this&#xA;tradition is related to Indian civilization and is intricately weaved&#xA;with historical personalities; it becomes pertinent to understand the&#xA;curious case of ‘Nysa in India’ in detail. This post is a humble attempt&#xA;to do precisely that – to understand exactly what this city was, who&#xA;were its people and were they really descendants of the Greeks? Or did&#xA;such city actually exist? What are the views of various scholars&#xA;regarding this issue?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Stolen King: Alexander III of Macedon</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/priyA/2020-12-23_a-stolen-king-alexander-iii-of-macedon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/priyA/2020-12-23_a-stolen-king-alexander-iii-of-macedon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://cestlaviepriya.wordpress.com/2020/12/23/a-stolen-king-alexander-iii-of-macedon/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s June 323 BCE in Babylonia. In the grand palace of one of the most&#xA;powerful Neo-Babylonian emperor of the past, Nebuchadnezzar II lies the&#xA;lifeless body of another powerful monarch, Alexander III of Macedon. But&#xA;the scorching heat of the Mesopotamian summer apparently does not take&#xA;its toll on the body of the king. You see, in Alexander, the lines of&#xA;history and myth tends to blur to the point of looking the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
