<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/crime/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/crime/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The rise of the</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/crime/articles/MT/2023-05-15_the-rise-of-the-psychopath-oligarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/crime/articles/MT/2023-05-15_the-rise-of-the-psychopath-oligarchy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2023/05/15/the-rise-of-the-psychopath-oligarchy/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rise of the psychopath oligarchy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are certain things in (geo)politics that are largely unsurprising to us because we had seen their seeds over a decade or two ago. In part, we were able to infer several things correctly in advance due to a few simple reasons. First, we have spent most of our life as an alien — outside of our small inner circle, we have mostly lived in the midst of and transacted with people who were very unlike us. The type of difference included, singly or together, ethnicity, religion, food preferences, linguistic attitudes, knowledge of the sciences, and philosophy. Second, when people speak to us in real life, for at least the beginning of the conversation, we say little and let them say what they want and how they feel about things. Most people honestly convey their thoughts when they are confronted by someone who does not engage in social reputation games. The remainder who are dishonest are an interesting class (see below) and can be made out through close examination. Third, irrespective of the group in which we find ourselves, we never lose sight of the fact that we are biological entities, the product of a chain of natural selection (at to a degree drift) events. Finally, we accept the fact that history tends to rhyme and a comparison with past cycles is typically illuminating. If we saw several things correctly, then there is really no need to waste words by repeating what has been said before. So why this exercise in svastuti? It is hard to stop the urge that arises every now and then to remark about this or that facet of political unfolding. The above is merely a prolog to one such excursus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
