<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some ramblings on Indo-European</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/2005-08-10_some-ramblings-on-indo-european/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/2005-08-10_some-ramblings-on-indo-european/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/08/10/some-ramblings-on-indo-european/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Due to a late night encounter back from work we got rambling about one of our favorite topics the evolution of IE languages from PIE. Despite the difficulties, that we are familiar with from other areas of science, we have some idea of the phylogeny of IE. Below is the picture as we see it today:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasa.google.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/pbp.gif&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/pbp.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Posted by Picasa&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://photos1.blogger.com/img/133/1300/640/indoeur.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/img/133/1300/400/indoeur.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/img/133/1300/400/indoeur.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This made me drift back in time toward my ancestors who composed the glorious mantras of the veda in the nascent days of Indo-Aryans. The earliest of their compositions in the R^igveda appear to have happened in the distant Uralic steppes and the allusions to the high latitudes and dark winters still linger on though largely unrecognized by the modern Hindu mind. Beyond lies the RUKI-SATEM clade which unifies I-Ir with Balto-Slavic. This made me think more about the polycephalous deities like Svantovit, Porevit and Rugevit and their iconography. What does this mean for Indic iconography?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple abalIka</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/apple_abalIka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/apple_abalIka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;sevam is clearly from an Iranian loan in NW Indo-Aryan tongues. While Early Indo-Aryan probably had a name for apple it was lost.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a NW IA language Pashayi which has a word wAlI for apple that cannot be etymologized in any Iranian pathway. Some have propose that it is a descendant of the now lost Indo-Aryan abalikA, the original word for apple. Of course, some I-Ir linguists could get hot as a coil hearing this proposal.  Iranic probably had a comparable abarnA based on some East Iranic forms and a loan into Uralic. So by reconstruction from the possible form in Corded Wear IE it would be better to form abalikA rather than sevam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beaver-veneration</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/beaver-veneration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/beaver-veneration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1624899292954599424&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wonder where the Iranian counter-religion acquired its appreciation for beavers: killing a beaver is equated with killing a dastur or worshiping daeva-s. Was it from a sense of realization of their importance in wet land ecology: below a recent case of dramatic beaver engineering.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At any rate beavers are also associated with river goddesses in Baltic folk songs. So their exalted character seems to go as far back as the Common IE period.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>chariot-petroglyphs</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/chariot-petroglyphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/chariot-petroglyphs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1619221438761934850.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The late Littauer had remarked in her landmark review of chariot petroglyphs:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;One cannot help wondering if, no matter what other ends it may eventually have served, this type of rendering of a vehicle was not first suggested to the artist by looking down into a tomb&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The petroglyphs she was talking about are from the Poltavka-Sintashta-Andronovo horizons &amp;amp; zones influenced by them. The tombs she was referring to re the chariot burials that appear in the Sintashta horizon &amp;amp; continue to the steppe-I-Ir influenced Shang age of what became China.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Horse-names</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/horse-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/horse-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/Lxhh2P0u33&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the jaiminIya brAhmaNa, we encounter an A&lt;del&gt;ngirasa vipra of the priyamedha line named sAkamashva: horse-together. It seems like the opposite name of the Iranian hero vIshtAspa which seems to mean horse-apart or horse-loosened. The Iranian name in turn closely parallels the name of the ancient A&lt;/del&gt;Ngirasa mentioned several times in the RV: vi+ashva=vyashva. He said to have composed the incantations to the 1000 eyed soma.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some other names:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interdigitation - Greek</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/interdigitation_greek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/interdigitation_greek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1781517494789734622.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A 🧵on interdigitation in IE branches.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;One of the offshoots of the recent archaeogenetic work&lt;br&gt;&#xA;is the developing view that&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Greek- (Greco-Armenian) sprang directly out of Yamnaya,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;with Greeks sojourning in the upper Balkans&lt;br&gt;&#xA;before reaching the peninsula&amp;amp; islands.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is consistent with certain linguistic (word) trees&lt;br&gt;&#xA;that favor an early branching of Greek (Greco-Armenian)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;after the basal most branches Anatolian &amp;amp; Tocharian.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;But until not long ago there was an alternative&lt;br&gt;&#xA;or partly overlapping linguistic hypothesis of Greco-Armeno-Aryan.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Was that signal entirely illusory&lt;br&gt;&#xA;or was there something to it that is still relevant.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It has 3 dimensions:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kernosovskiy images</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/kernosovskiy-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/kernosovskiy-images/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rattibha.com/thread/1511958224848797696?lang=en&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;kernosovskiy&#34;&gt;Kernosovskiy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A thread on the Kernosovskiy &amp;amp; related icons. This image found in what&amp;rsquo;s today Ukraine is from the Yamnaya horizon. If indeed it dates closer to then it is of considerable significance as it is a rare image from the early IE period.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;thumbnail&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;../../../images/balbal/Kernosovskiy-front-back.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;../../../images/balbal/Kernosovskiy-front-back.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;thumbnail&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;../../../images/balbal/Kernosovskiy-side.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;../../../images/balbal/Kernosovskiy-side.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve so far seen reasonably clear images of 3 sides. Above are front &amp;amp; back &amp;amp; here is the 3rd side with clear imagery on it. It depicts an ithyphallic male figure in a general iconographic convention seen in the later &amp;ldquo;balbal&amp;rdquo; stones of shaka, mongolic &amp;amp; turkic peoples &amp;amp; the more mysterious Hakkari stones. However, there is one indicator of an early age &amp;ndash; the similarity of the axe on the image to the Abashevo axe that is closer culturally &amp;amp; temporally to Yamnaya. A similar axe is seen in the Federovsky idol from the Poltava region of Ukraine likely again from the Yamnaya age.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Koryos Nonsense</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/koryos_nonsense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/koryos_nonsense/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Kóryos nonsense that is endlessly boosted in the Occidental IEist cycles with an almost lupine/canine frenzy is one of the most foundationless bits of speculation that is largely untethered from IE philology. It really has no place in sane understanding of the IE past. It is something that happens when you only have the language but not the living tradition to conduct a good philological exploration of the past.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kurgan tumulus meaning</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/kurgan_tumulus_meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/kurgan_tumulus_meaning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The early Arya-s imagined the tumulus (kurgan) as a shelter with the &amp;ldquo;mother&amp;rdquo; - i.e. earth. This is clarified in the tR^icha deployed for the funerary rite of the piling of the kurgan, i.e. shmashAna+++(5)+++:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;js_include&#34; url=&#34;https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/vedAH_Rk/shAkalam/saMhitA/vishvAsa-prastutiH/10/018/11_uchChvanchasva_pRthivi.md&#34;  newLevelForH1=&#34;5&#34; includeTitle=&#34;false&#34;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;  &#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;js_include&#34; url=&#34;https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/vedAH_Rk/shAkalam/saMhitA/vishvAsa-prastutiH/10/018/12_uchChvanchamAnA_pRthivI.md&#34;  newLevelForH1=&#34;5&#34; includeTitle=&#34;false&#34;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;  &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May the earth stand piled high above him; verily upheld by a 1000 props. May it be&#xA;the house dripping with ghee; Through eternity may he be sheltered here!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Truly that shelter on the steppe has been a great mechanism to understand our pitaraH.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/language/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the RV athA and the paralogous adhA both occur 66 times. The former shares cognates with Iranian &amp;amp; Italo-Celtic. The latter with Hittite. A notable survival of an archaism that did not persist in later Skt showing the effect of the postulated &amp;ldquo;laryngeal&amp;rdquo; in the ancestor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>okunevo</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/okunevo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/okunevo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1622856208389398528.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Okunevo had a rather complex ancestry for their time with the IE Afanasievo from Yamnaya, the Baikal Early neolithic type, another Altai contribution with ANE &amp;amp; Paleosiberian. This makes us think that their unprecedented iconography indeed had connection with that of some &amp;ldquo;First Americans&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Okunevo are so strange &amp;amp; alluring that we often wonder what it might have been in their midst. What language did they speak? Did they retain an early branching IE tongue of their Yamnaya ancestors or had they shifted to a Paleo-Siberia or Altaic one? We suspect it was IE but with major cultural influences of these more eastern groups.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Southern Arc - Anatolian split review</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/southern-arc_anatolian-split_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/southern-arc_anatolian-split_review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1562956497293758464.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finally the much talked about &amp;ldquo;Southern Arc&amp;rdquo; paper of LAZARIDIS etal has been published. Below are just some preliminary comments based on the authors&amp;rsquo; statements &amp;amp; results in the main text (nothing deep). First some background:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We have good evidence that the likely phylogenetic model for the languages including Indo-European &amp;amp; Anatolian is Indo-Hittite (Indo-Anatolian), i.e., Anatolian branched first, then the rest of IE split up from PIE.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Balto-Slavic was a likely sister group of I-Ir in a ``satem&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; clade lodged deep in IE.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Greco-Armenian &amp;amp; Italo-Celtic were likely solid clades as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;All these non-Anatolian branches can be clearly traced to the steppe on philological/archaeogenetic grounds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;So far the Anatolia archaeogenetics has not revealed a strong steppe signal.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The authors have assembled hundreds of genomes from west Asia, including Anatolia &amp;amp; covering the period when Anatolian languages were spoken. Despite this expanded dataset, they found no clear evidence for steppe presence in the period when Anatolian languages were dominant.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hence, they posit a variant of the Caucasian Hunter Gatherer (CHG) hypothesis that had made its rounds in the early days of the archaeogenetic foray into IE origins.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;thumbnail&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;../../../images/southern-arc_anatolian-split.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;../../../images/southern-arc_anatolian-split.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;As per their current version, there were two pulses of CHG ancestry into the steppe. An old one which was pretty deep in time &amp;amp; a more recent one which they believe also took some Anatolian Farmer/Levantine ancestry along with it into the steppe. This second pulse is postulated as pre-Yamnaya and critical for its founding.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They also see a rise in CHG ancestry starting from an Eastern Anatolian locus &amp;amp; moving west.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They take this movement of CHG into Anatolia &amp;amp; the second pulse into the steppe as the signal of original Indo-Anatolian spread &amp;ndash; Anatolian obviously the movement into Anatolia &amp;amp; the movement into the steppe as PIE. They present this as the below map &amp;ndash; something that brings memories of the Soviet workers, Gamkrelidze and Ivanov.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;However, in the text, the authors are more circumspect &amp;amp; mention that it could Maykop, Eastern Anatolia in addition to Armenia as possible sources from which this CHG pulse that founded PIE might have originated.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They also admit that a much wider sampling in Iran, North Mesopotamia, and Azerbaijan would be needed for more precise mapping. Note that the Mesolithic individual from Hotu Cave from Iran is a classic CHG.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To summarize the Indo-Anatolian cladogenesis as per the authors&amp;rsquo; conception:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>इधर</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/idhar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/articles/MT/idhar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Interestingly Middle &amp;amp; New Indo-Aryan &amp;ndash; Pkt: idha; Hindi: idhara; Avestan: idhA(?); Old Iranic: Ida; Greek: ithA conform to the PIE state rather than Skt iha. This points to multiple waves of Arya-s (also seen in Vedic/Para-Vedic religions) &amp;amp; the retention of IE archaism in MIA.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One can also, despite all the orthographic challenges, say that the West Asian Indo-Aryan dialect seen in the Mitanni and Hittite lands was distinct from the core RV dialect. It was rhotacizing like some early Aryan dialects in India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
