<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;स्वरक्षणम् (Defence) on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;स्वरक्षणम् (Defence) on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Division of power, scale-free feudalism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/Division_of_power_scale-free_feudalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/Division_of_power_scale-free_feudalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Consider the list of individual heroes involved in politics and war. Thence we learn the following. Where ever kShatriyas tasked with protecting their land (as if it were their wife) and subjects (as if they were their children) fell, others rose to take their place (eg: harihara and bukka, chandragupta maurya, shivAji, reDDi chieftains). They were guided and inspired by learned men and sages (eg: tukArAm, vidyAraNya, chANakya). Further, their efforts were financed often by taxation, but also sometimes by donations from merchants. This division of power (in the form of occupation specific jAti-s) lent to the civilization the character of a multi-headed snake - chop one head off, another takes its place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lack of ruthlessness</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/lack_of_ruthlessness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/lack_of_ruthlessness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;not-rolling-back-inimical-religions&#34;&gt;Not rolling back inimical religions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unlike spanish reconquista or the jApanese expulsion of christianity, various hindu empires did not mostly expel Islam from their conquered lands. This was a huge cumulative loss for Hinduism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;marathas&#34;&gt;Marathas&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Marathas never planned to get rid of Christianity and Islam - they just wanted to merely capture political power from them. Examples below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do not abandon the righteous path or ethical conduct. If Marathas or Muslims behave as per the traditions of their caste or community, do not discriminate against them. The Kingdom should not discriminate on the basis of the person&amp;rsquo;s faith or his deity -&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maratha loss</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/marATha-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/marATha-loss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Discussions -&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2011/10/09/yuddha-vyuha-s-mlechcha-s-and-vanija-niti-in-the-last-hindu-empire/&#34;&gt;MT11&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/05/13/end-of-the-maharattas-i/&#34;&gt;MT04&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://agnimaan.wordpress.com/2015/08/15/reasons-for-maratha-hindu-loss-to-the-british-v0/&#34;&gt;WP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;reasons&#34;&gt;Reasons&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Our understanding of the enemy was inferior.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;grand-strategy&#34;&gt;Grand strategy&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;British grand strategy and understanding of the enemy was much superior to ours.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The British had been planning on how to colonize India as far back as early 1700&amp;rsquo;s while the Marathas were in their life and death struggle with the Mughals.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Besides, the British Plan already had the solid backing of a very thorough study of India by now and evaluation of its people. Consider this: Captain James Tod had already surveyed the history and geography of the entire rAjapUta country with every single one of its clan – even though they were politically still independent – and had already produced in the first two decade his celebrated ‘Annals and Antiquities of rAjapUtAnA’, not to mention that the European Indology as a discipline was already flourishing with its second generation with the likes of Colebrooke and Schlegel now in chairs, William Jones dead just a couple of years back. In contrast, we seriously doubt if there was even one Hindu at the time who properly knew the basic history and geography of Britain!&amp;rdquo;  [&lt;a href=&#34;http://bharatendu.com/2009/10/13/mana-simha-the-rashtrakuta-ii/&#34;&gt;BE&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Misplaced mercy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/misplaced-mercy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/misplaced-mercy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One drawback hindus had was misplaced generosity - a paucity of ruthlessness. The source is nothing but moral weakness and fragility. These people want approval and admiration of others. This is the disease that motivated moronic actions right from dharmarAja to  PrithvirAja Chauhan (atleast in myth) to Nehru and Gandhi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When yudhiShThira gave duryodhana his choice of weapon and combatant when he emerged from the lake hiding spot, and kRShNa scolded him - &amp;ldquo;Again, even now you are gambling! A deceitful person should be destroyed with deceit without this kind of show.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resistance to alien invasions and resurgence</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/Resistance_to_alien_invasions_and_resurgence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/Resistance_to_alien_invasions_and_resurgence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Constant low level pesant revolt against muslim rulers was noted by Peter Mundy, Manucci, Abul Fazl, Bernier, Jahangir, Kopf. (sItA-rAm-goel&amp;rsquo;s assessment &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.voiceofdharma.org/books/siii/ch9.htm&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;disunity&#34;&gt;(Dis)Unity&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;effective-disunited-resistance&#34;&gt;Effective disunited resistance&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Very strong resistance to foreign invasion has been repeatedly observed. With regard to the Muslim invasions, it must be noted that for over a 1000 years, there was on average 1 battle every month between local resistors and Islamic armies. Even as proud civilizations from Iran to Indonesia fell, the native Hindu culture survived. Earlier invaders, such as the shAkas, huNas, yavanas were similarly checked. Empires such as the paramAras, the vijayanagara empire, the marATha empire repeatedly checked for many centuries, and were beginning to reverse Islamic invasion. Like the European crusades launched to conquer Palestine, similar efforts began to be observed late in the 18th century with the marATha and sikh confrederacies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temple blackmail</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/temple-blackmail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/temple-blackmail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the unbelievers march against mUltAn, and the faithful do not feel themselves strong enough to oppose them, they threaten to break their idol, and their enemies immediately withdraw”. Another writer (this one from persia), al-ishtakhri also mentions the same state of affairs regarding the defense of the city against hindu invaders. The self proclaimed butshikan-s were forced to take refuge behind the famous ‘but’ of their capital to retain their kingdom. - al-masUdI&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
