<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Government on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Government on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>01 Services</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/01_Services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/01_Services/</guid>
      <description>Government agencies or companies hired by them are responsible for providing basic infrastructure - public health-care, roads, water, security, regulation, environment protection, foreign policy, arbitration - to the public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Design</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/02_Design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/02_Design/</guid>
      <description>Branches Government has 3 main arms: Legislative (to make laws and oversee policies), Executive (to provide services as designed at a high level by the legislature) and Judiciary (to take care of grievances, punish wrong-doing).
Importance Government design determines the type and the quality of the services provided by the government. Bad governments are often a result of bad design.
Legislature Legislatures have great power because they determine the laws/ policies; the executive and judiciary merely execute them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 Formation</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/03_Formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/03_Formation/</guid>
      <description>Monarchy In the past monarchy, based on armed or religous support, was common. Succession was based on very narrow nepotism - this often led to fragile states whose fortunes varied wildly over the generations: See nepotism section of business succession for details.
Democracy In democracies, legislatures are constituted by election. [Incomplete]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 Income</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/04_Income/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/04_Income/</guid>
      <description>Taxation In exchange for government services, people and businesses pay taxes on their incomes/ gains (any increase in wealth). So, the government collects taxes on behalf of its citizenry.
Taxation rate and service level Some highly ’socialist’ countries (Eg: Scandinavian countries, France etc..) tend to have high taxation rates, and provide excellent services to their citizens in return. Other countries, like USA, have low taxation rates and in return provide low-quality public services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 Budget deficits</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/05_Budget_deficits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/05_Budget_deficits/</guid>
      <description>Many cities, states and countries outside have greater expenditure than revenue, a gap which is often projected to widen as time passes.
Quantification Government deficit is often measured as a percentage of the GDP, which is much larger than the actual income of the government alone. Anything over 10% is considered too high.
Expectations without willingness to spend Often people expect unrealistically good public services from the government, without the willingness to spend a proportionate fraction of their income.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 Corruption, inefficiency</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/06_Corruption_inefficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/06_Corruption_inefficiency/</guid>
      <description>Public servants and those who otherwise depend on public funding fall into unethical practices like accepting bribes, lying, delay and coercion because their seniors compel them to do so - either explicitly or unwittingly as a result of the unrealistic or wrong expectations, or because of a desire for personal profit, or for job security.
Bad expectations For example, during the Chinese famine, officials presented Mao with fake fields and yields during his inspections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 Law enforcement</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/07_Law_enforcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/07_Law_enforcement/</guid>
      <description>Considered in the society survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08 Health care</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/08_Health_care/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/08_Health_care/</guid>
      <description>Quality of health care varies widely amongst nations, and within nations.
Universal health care Universal Health Care in many countries is free or low cost.
Quality The quality in many countries is good - In France there are even house-calls. In other countries beset with inefficient executive branches, like India, public health care is often low quality - though even there, there are islands of high quality.
Delays, overuse Free health care is often overused, leading to resource scarcity given that a limited amount of money is alloted for health care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 Education</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/09_Education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/09_Education/</guid>
      <description>Schools Most countries provide free universal compulsory primary education for children. Quality varies.
Tuition Access to prestigious universities/ schools may be limited, so there is often a competitive exam; for which there often exists special tuition/ cram schools.
Higher education In some countries (like Scandinavia, France), government heavily subsidizes higher education; while in others students must mostly rely on other sources, and accrue huge debts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Business attraction</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/10_Business_attraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/10_Business_attraction/</guid>
      <description>Luring away businesses More businesses mean more tax money, and prosperity of the nation. So, territories (cities, states or countries) try to lure businesses from each other - they usually have special agencies called ’Economic development agencies’ which do this.
They sometimes offer tax-breaks in the initial years to attract businesses. They also try to achieve concentration of talent by offering pre-setup infrastructure and by setting up special economic zones where companies will get tax benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11 Business regulation</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/11_Business_regulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/11_Business_regulation/</guid>
      <description>Businesses, left to themselves, often operate to increase their own profit at the expense of the environment and the general economy.
Regulation about working conditions are described in another chapter.
Competition promotion Governments then try to ensure that no company gets a monopoly on any market, as monopoly reduces progress and keeps the prices up.
Illegal activities Disadvantaging competition Microsoft, in the 1990’s, bundling the internet explorer browser with its operating system, disadvantaged rival browsers and gained monopoly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Critical goods</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/12_Critical_goods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/economics/state-level/government/12_Critical_goods/</guid>
      <description>The availability of items determine the value of others. A reduction in their supply leads to various crises.
Foreign currency If an entity in country B wants to buy something from an entity in country A, it needs to pay in some currency used by country A: it could still have a choice among a set of currencies like $, yuan etc.
Shortage Sometimes there is a shortage in country A of currency accepted by country B’s entities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>