<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Government on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Government on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Services</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/01_Services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/01_Services/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Government agencies or companies hired by them are responsible for providing basic infrastructure - public health-care, roads, water, security, regulation, environment protection, foreign policy, arbitration - to the public.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Design</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/02_Design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/02_Design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;branches&#34;&gt;Branches&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Government has 3 main arms: Legislative (to make laws and oversee policies), Executive (to provide services as designed at a high level by the legislature) and Judiciary (to take care of grievances, punish wrong-doing).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;importance&#34;&gt;Importance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Government design determines the type and the quality of the services provided by the government. Bad governments are often a result of bad design.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;legislature&#34;&gt;Legislature&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Legislatures have great power because they determine the laws/ policies; the executive and judiciary merely execute them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Formation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/03_Formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/03_Formation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;monarchy&#34;&gt;Monarchy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the past monarchy, based on armed or religous support, was common. Succession was based on very narrow nepotism - this often led to fragile states whose fortunes varied wildly over the generations: See nepotism section of business succession for details.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;democracy&#34;&gt;Democracy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In democracies, legislatures are constituted by election. [&lt;strong&gt;Incomplete&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Income</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/04_Income/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/04_Income/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;taxation&#34;&gt;Taxation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In exchange for government services, people and businesses pay taxes on their incomes/ gains (any increase in wealth). So, the government collects taxes on behalf of its citizenry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;taxation-rate-and-service-level&#34;&gt;Taxation rate and service level&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some highly ’socialist’ countries (Eg: Scandinavian countries, France etc..) tend to have high taxation rates, and provide excellent services to their citizens in return. Other countries, like USA, have low taxation rates and in return provide low-quality public services.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 Budget deficits</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/05_Budget_deficits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/05_Budget_deficits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many cities, states and countries outside have greater expenditure than revenue, a gap which is often projected to widen as time passes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;quantification&#34;&gt;Quantification&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Government deficit is often measured as a percentage of the GDP, which is much larger than the actual income of the government alone. Anything over 10% is considered too high.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;expectations-without-willingness-to-spend&#34;&gt;Expectations without willingness to spend&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Often people expect unrealistically good public services from the government, without the willingness to spend a proportionate fraction of their income. So, politicians in many countries are elected based on promise to increase or maintain public services while reducing (rather than increasing) taxation - this results in the perpetuation of a budget crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 Corruption, inefficiency</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/06_Corruption_inefficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/06_Corruption_inefficiency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Public servants and those who otherwise depend on public funding fall into unethical practices like accepting bribes, lying, delay and coercion because their seniors compel them to do so - either explicitly or unwittingly as a result of the unrealistic or wrong expectations, or because of a desire for personal profit, or for job security.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;bad-expectations&#34;&gt;Bad expectations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, during the Chinese famine, officials presented Mao with fake fields and yields during his inspections. NYPD cops, whose anti-crime activity was being tracked using statistics, registered fewer cases, and were coerced into unnecessary pat-downs, tickets and arrests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 Law enforcement</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/07_Law_enforcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/07_Law_enforcement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Considered in the society survey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 Health care</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/08_Health_care/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/08_Health_care/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quality of health care varies widely amongst nations, and within nations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;universal-health-care&#34;&gt;Universal health care&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Universal Health Care in many countries is free or low cost.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;quality&#34;&gt;Quality&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The quality in many countries is good - In France there are even house-calls. In other countries beset with inefficient executive branches, like India, public health care is often low quality - though even there, there are islands of high quality.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;delays-overuse&#34;&gt;Delays, overuse&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Free health care is often overused, leading to resource scarcity given that a limited amount of money is alloted for health care. This can lead to long delays in access to health care procedures or specialists (dentists, MRI scans) - in 2010, this was a problem for UK’s NHS and Canada’s health service.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 Education</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/09_Education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/09_Education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;schools&#34;&gt;Schools&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most countries provide free universal compulsory primary education for children. Quality varies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tuition&#34;&gt;Tuition&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Access to prestigious universities/ schools may be limited, so there is often a competitive exam; for which there often exists special tuition/ cram schools.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;higher-education&#34;&gt;Higher education&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In some countries (like Scandinavia, France), government heavily subsidizes higher education; while in others students must mostly rely on other sources, and accrue huge debts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Business attraction</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/10_Business_attraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/10_Business_attraction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luring-away-businesses&#34;&gt;Luring away businesses&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More businesses mean more tax money, and prosperity of the nation. So, territories (cities, states or countries) try to lure businesses from each other - they usually have special agencies called ’Economic development agencies’ which do this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They sometimes offer tax-breaks in the initial years to attract businesses. They also try to achieve concentration of talent by offering pre-setup infrastructure and by setting up special economic zones where companies will get tax benefits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Business regulation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/11_Business_regulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/11_Business_regulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Businesses, left to themselves, often operate to increase their own profit at the expense of the environment and the general economy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Regulation about working conditions are described in another chapter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;competition-promotion&#34;&gt;Competition promotion&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Governments then try to ensure that no company gets a monopoly on any market, as monopoly reduces progress and keeps the prices up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;illegal-activities&#34;&gt;Illegal activities&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;disadvantaging-competition&#34;&gt;Disadvantaging competition&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft, in the 1990’s, bundling the internet explorer browser with its operating system, disadvantaged rival browsers and gained monopoly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Critical goods</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/12_Critical_goods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/12_Critical_goods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The availability of items determine the value of others. A reduction in their supply leads to various crises.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;foreign-currency&#34;&gt;Foreign currency&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If an entity in country B wants to buy something from an entity in country A, it needs to pay in some currency used by country A: it could still have a choice among a set of currencies like $, yuan etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;shortage&#34;&gt;Shortage&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes there is a shortage in country A of currency accepted by country B’s entities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dumbocracy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/dumbocracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/dumbocracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here we examine problems of democracy and briefly consider alternative systems of government&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;problems&#34;&gt;Problems&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &amp;ldquo;one person one vote&amp;rdquo; paradigm prominent in democracies rests on an unnatural, false assumption: That all men are equal in their abilities and judgement.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Politicians compete for attention and approval of masses (who in heterogeneous countries like India tend to be bottom heavy - ie dominated by incompetents). So, their legislative goals and administration becomes flawed.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;As ordinary citizens are encouraged to take part in the political life of the country, they have the power to directly influence the outcome of government policies through the democratic procedures of voting, campaigning and the use of press. The result is that government policies may be more influenced by non-specialist opinions and thereby the effectiveness compromised.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Politicians spend far more time gathering money for reelection (not to mention their own retirement) than on sincere government. &lt;a href=&#34;https://bulletin.represent.us/much-time-congress-members-spend-fundraising/&#34;&gt;US2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Political instability&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;this hinders general progress and business (which prefer stable guidelines)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This is exploited by our national and civilizational enemies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Short-termism&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Susceptibility to intolerant demographically growing communities (eg. fanatical Muslims and Christians). This leads to the destruction of national ethos over generations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Susceptibility to propaganda by manipulation of public opinion and opposition (see &lt;a href=&#34;../subversion/&#34;&gt;subversion&lt;/a&gt; page)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Corruption&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Relatively more inefficient and harder to pivot.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Almost no truly effective organization is a democracy (esp. in our society). No company (let alone successful ones) is a democracy. No military is run democratically. Same with ISRO or police or administrative cadres.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-assessments&#34;&gt;General assessments&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;DV Gundappa in his &amp;ldquo;maisUru divAnaru&amp;rdquo; part of &amp;ldquo;jNApaka-chitra-shAle&amp;rdquo;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/dvg-jnapaka-chitra-shaale-maisUrina-dIvAnaru-1.5x/24_Upasamhara_p1.mp3&#34;&gt;audio-1.5x p1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/dvg-jnapaka-chitra-shaale-maisUrina-dIvAnaru-1.5x/25_Rashtra_Samasthithiya_Mulasuthra_p1.mp3&#34;&gt;p2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Machiavelli put the idea that democracies will tend to cater to the whims of the people,  who follow false ideas to entertain themselves, squander their reserves, and do not deal with potential threats to their rule until it is far too late.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;monarcy--aristocracy&#34;&gt;Monarcy + aristocracy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;ideals&#34;&gt;Ideals&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Plato argues that only Kallipolis, an aristocracy led by the unwilling philosopher-kings (the wisest men), is a just form of government.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;risks&#34;&gt;Risks&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Top down enforcement of monotheism on pagan socieities&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Example&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Akhenaten&amp;rsquo;s Atenism (Egyptians returned to polytheism.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Constantine and successors in Rome. (Julian repaganized - but christians returned after his death.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vladimir of the Kievan rUs, became Orthodox Christian for alliance with Basil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rinchan of Kashmir.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jogaila of Lithuania, who became Catholic for alliance with Poles.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Haakon and Sigurd Haakonsson, Jarls in norway. (His son Haakon Sigurdarson rebelled briefly.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;consensus&#34;&gt;Consensus&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Consensus-based (rather than election-based) appointments, successions and leadership choices lead to more harmonious outcomes and organizations which whole-heartedly pivot when necessary. Eg. Japanese companies &lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/1971/03/what-we-can-learn-from-japanese-management&#34;&gt;hbr article&lt;/a&gt;, japanology pages.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;realizations&#34;&gt;Realizations&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mysore kingdom under the Wodeyars and their chief ministers (divAns) was one of the best administered states in the world. The chief minister was chosen based on merit from the administrative and engineering services, for a limited term. They tended to be highly effective, sincere, and incorruptible rulers. They were supported by an elected &amp;ldquo;prajA-pratinidhi-sabhA&amp;rdquo;, who could only make suggestions to the chief minister who could dispense with the recommendations as he thought fit. The state of Karnataka which succeeded it pales in comparison.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;See varNavatI &lt;a href=&#34;../../../../social-cultivation/clan/theory/fiction/varnavatii/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;rigged-democracies&#34;&gt;Rigged democracies&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Singapore has a strong de-ghettoisation policy: every electoral constituency is chinese majority; so less voice for malay islamists. The legacy of Lee Kuan Yew stays strong.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Share-based system: Every citizen living as of today (for example) gets a share in the nation. The total number of shares remains constant over time (just as in a company). Every time he has a child, he/ she forfeits a portion of his share to the child. Once he dies, his shares are divided among his children. So, if the muslim community grows from 10% to 50% in a hundred years, the problem is not as severe: they will continue to have only 10% share in the national political power.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;vote-buying&#34;&gt;Vote buying&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;George Washington was getting voters drunk to vote for him all the way back in 1758&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sick-rhetoric&#34;&gt;Sick rhetoric&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adams frequently called Hamilton a “bastard brat” &amp;amp; made fun of him for being poor.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Hamilton called Adams fat and small.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Pro Jefferson papers called Adams “hermaphrodital”.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The Adams campaign responded that Jefferson was born of a “half-breed Indian squaw” &amp;amp; labeled Jefferson the pro-incest candidate.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Charles Lee publicly accused Washington of trying to assassinate him.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Newspapers called Andrew Jackson’s mom a prostitute.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Jackson openly regretted not having shot Henry Clay or hanged John Calhoun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
