<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/colonization/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/colonization/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Latin america japanese culture drift</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/colonization/articles/latin-america-japanese-culture-drift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/colonization/articles/latin-america-japanese-culture-drift/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;paraguay-2024&#34;&gt;Paraguay 2024&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5,441 Japanese nationals&lt;br&gt;&#xA;10,000 Paraguayans of Japanese descent&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Eastern and Cultural Religions&amp;rdquo; (excl Islam)*** 2566&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First-generation Japanese Paraguayans were generally followers of Shinto and Buddhism. The first Japanese settlers at La Colmena brought a piece of stone from the Ise Shrine which was gazetted as a monument mark the settlement&amp;rsquo;s founding. Japanese religious festivals were celebrated within the first few decades among the first and second-generation Japanese settlers and in the late 1960s, a majority identified themselves with the Buddhist and Shinto faiths. Conversion to Roman Catholic Christianity increased from the late 1970s onwards.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Questions of survival</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/colonization/articles/questions_of_survival/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/colonization/articles/questions_of_survival/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.vn/1Imtt&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Questions of Survival&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pushing aside competition and even hostility, Jewish leaders sat together last weekend for the first time and discussed what they agree is the unclear future of their people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WASHINGTON - The following disparity tells us more about human nature than about the future of the Jewish world: The executive branch - the heads of the large Jewish organizations, on the whole - are optimistic and believe Judaism has a glowing future, while the intellectuals and thinkers are much more pessimistic and insist on mentioning the pitfalls and obstacles the coming years hold in store. Those who are entrusted with carrying out affairs must be convinced there is a point to what they do - and what is the point if there is no future?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sikh transplants</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/colonization/articles/sikh-transplants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/colonization/articles/sikh-transplants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Carl&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sikhs who buy land in N. America and build farm communities depend on getting a lot of pendu cousins to immigrate. Entire pinds get transplanted from Punjab to Kanedda. Like soldiers, farmers also depend on social capital and know-how. Not easy to learn.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;deployment&#34;&gt;Deployment&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sikhs see pendu farmer/soldier connection as prestigious. Urbanized as contemptible and patted on the back only so long as they use their connections and education to further the goals of the community. Average N. American Gurdwara has truck drivers and surgeons serving langar together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US jews</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/colonization/articles/us-jews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/colonization/articles/us-jews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;carls-comments&#34;&gt;Carl&amp;rsquo;s comments&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maryland Jews are sorted out. I&amp;rsquo;m surrounded by them. They have a large ranch, their own rifle range, their own boy scouts and survivalist training courses, krav maga, and of course business guilds, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lots of Hindu temples around but none even so much as offer childcare. Desis in my neighborhood all send their toddlers to a Pakistani lady.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
