<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;jihAd on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;jihAd on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Foreword</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/01_for/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/01_for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foreword&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There was a time, not so long ago, when the exponents of jihãd minced no&#xA;words and pulled no punches. They were brutally frank in spelling out&#xA;what &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; really meant.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But times have changed, particularly after the collapse of Christianity&#xA;in the West and the rise of modern rationalism and humanism. Standards&#xA;of moral judgment have increasingly tended to become universal, and no&#xA;statement of faith can escape scrutiny simply because it is made in a&#xA;book hailed as holy by some people. Defenders of &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; have been&#xA;forced to develop an apologetics. They are now trying to protect by&#xA;means of scholarship a doctrine which has so far been sustained by means&#xA;of the sword.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Preface</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/02_pre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/02_pre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preface&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a slightly enlarged version of a small monograph I wrote in&#xA;Bengali on the important Islamic subject of &lt;em&gt;Jihãd fi Sabilillah&lt;/em&gt; (war&#xA;in the way of Allah). &lt;em&gt;Jihãd&lt;/em&gt; has five clear components, and a complete&#xA;understanding of the subject requires a discussion of each one of them.&#xA;Thus &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; stands for (1) Forcible expansion of Islam; (2) Destruction&#xA;of infidels; (3) Establishment of &lt;em&gt;jizyah&lt;/em&gt; on the subdued infidel&#xA;population; (4) Plunder in the form of properties wrested from infidels;&#xA;and (5) Plunder in the form of enslaved female and child population&#xA;acquired from the vanquished infidels. In the Bengali monograph I&#xA;discussed at length only the subject of plunder, which in Arabic is&#xA;known as &lt;em&gt;ghanîmah&lt;/em&gt;. I discussed and explained the other divisions from&#xA;the text of the Koran alone, without illustrating them from the career&#xA;of the Prophet. In this enlarged version I have devoted separate&#xA;chapters to these divisions, highlighting the Prophet’s activities in&#xA;connection with each of them, and added some new appendices. It is my&#xA;hope that, though increasing the size but slightly, I have left out&#xA;nothing of real importance, and the theoretical aspects of this&#xA;important Islamic doctrine have been treated here in full. I have not&#xA;indeed described the numerous historical &lt;em&gt;jihãds&lt;/em&gt; undertaken by Islamic&#xA;zealots over the centuries; but I have discussed two of the &lt;em&gt;ghazwahs&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;(=jihadic campaigns) of the Prophet - his conquest of Mecca and his&#xA;destruction of the Jewish clan of Kuraizah; these two form part and&#xA;parcel of the theoretical apparatus of &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt;. The Prophet’s life and&#xA;works form the bedrock of Islamic theology and are known as Sunnah.&#xA;This, with Koranic sayings attributed to Allah and known by the Arabic&#xA;title &lt;em&gt;‘wahy’&lt;/em&gt; (=revelation), are the final sources of Islam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 REFERENCES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/03_ref/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/03_ref/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REFERENCES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;em&gt;The Meaning of the Glorious Koran&lt;/em&gt;, by Mohammed Marmaduke&#xA;Pickthall.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;em&gt;Sahih Muslim&lt;/em&gt;, 4 volumes, translated by Abdul Hamid Siddiqi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3. &lt;em&gt;Mishkãt Sharîf&lt;/em&gt; (in Bengali), Vol. 7, translated by M. Aflatoon&#xA;Kaisar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4. &lt;em&gt;The Life of Mahomet&lt;/em&gt;, by Sir William Muir.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5. &lt;em&gt;Mohammed and the Rise of Islam&lt;/em&gt;, by D.S. Margoliouth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6. &lt;em&gt;Hidãyah&lt;/em&gt; (the standard digest of Islamic tenets according to the&#xA;School of Imam Hanifa), by Shaikh Burhanuddin Ali, translated by Charles&#xA;Hamilton.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Introduction</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/04_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/04_intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jihãd&lt;/em&gt; is one of the basic doctrines of Islam, but the average Indian’s&#xA;knowledge of it is both superficial and unsatisfactory. Hindus usually&#xA;render the term as &lt;em&gt;dharmayuddha&lt;/em&gt;, but this rendering is totally&#xA;misleading. &lt;em&gt;Dharmayuddha&lt;/em&gt; means ‘war fought according to rules laid&#xA;down in the &lt;em&gt;Dharmashãstras’&lt;/em&gt; such as not attacking a person who does&#xA;not have a weapon or has dropped it, not molesting an adversary who has&#xA;surrendered, not pursuing a defeated enemy who has run away, not&#xA;attacking the non-combatants in the enemy camp, not harming the women&#xA;and holy people and places in the enemy’s territory, etc. Hindus have&#xA;never known the concept of a religious or holy war, a concept which is&#xA;characteristic of the monotheistic creeds. Therefore, to the common&#xA;Hindu, in particular to those who are ignorant of the history of the&#xA;many religious wars waged by monotheistic creeds of Asia and Europe,&#xA;&lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; is a lofty conception. It is nothing less than war aimed at&#xA;establishing what they consider righteousness in the world. Very few&#xA;Hindus care to remember that the boy-emperor Akbar had become a &lt;em&gt;ghãzî&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;by slaughtering his helpless and fatally wounded prisoner Himu at the&#xA;bidding of Bairam Khan in 1556 AD. Actually, even those Hindus who&#xA;remember the story do not know that the title &lt;em&gt;ghãzî&lt;/em&gt; is conferred only&#xA;on victorious, &lt;em&gt;kãfir&lt;/em&gt; - slaughtering &lt;em&gt;mujãhids&lt;/em&gt;.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) In truth,&#xA;&lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; is war for the destruction of infidels (&lt;em&gt;kãfirs&lt;/em&gt;) and infidelity&#xA;(&lt;em&gt;kufr&lt;/em&gt;). To obviate prevailing misconception, it is important to&#xA;explain the meaning of &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; from the Koran, the Hadis and the corpus&#xA;of theological works collectively going by the name of Shariat. As&#xA;&lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; is a basic doctrine of Islam and as its focus is on the infidel,&#xA;it is not fit that Hindus should go on cherishing their deep-seated&#xA;delusion regarding its meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 1 Jihãd in the Koran</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/05_ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/05_ch1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Jihãd in the Koran&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Koran does not discuss a single Islamic tenet systematically and in&#xA;conformity with the arrangement of its chapters. The combined body of&#xA;Revelations from Allah which constitute the Holy Book of Islam appeared&#xA;to the Prophet without any logical sequence during the 23 years of his&#xA;prophetic career (609 to 632 AD), and this fact accounts for its&#xA;haphazard arrangement. The Koran has 114 chapters and some six thousand&#xA;verses. The verses of &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt;, like those explaining any other doctrine,&#xA;remain spread over a great many chapters. This is the reason why, to an&#xA;ordinary reader, the knowledge of any and every Islamic doctrine appears&#xA;difficult, the doctrine of &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; being no exception.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 2 Jihãd in the Hadis</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/06_ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/06_ch2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jihãd&lt;/em&gt; in the Hadis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before I discuss the contents of the Hadis literature, in so far as&#xA;those pertain to &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt;, I must tell the reader that only Sunni works&#xA;of Hadis have been published in translation and even those translations&#xA;are partial. The Koran is canonical scripture par excellence, and is&#xA;common to all sections of Muslims. But the Hadis of the Sunnis is not&#xA;the same as the Hadis of the Shias. Western scholars have studied most&#xA;of the religions of the world, but even they have not cared to render&#xA;the Hadis literature in English. The translations I have met are mostly&#xA;due to the ulema of Pakistan and Bangladesh. It seems there is hesitancy&#xA;even amongst the ulema in making the Hadis literature easily available&#xA;to infidels. At any rate, their enthusiasm for making the Koran&#xA;accessible to one and all is not matched by a similar effort towards&#xA;popularising the Hadis literature. This is perfectly understandable if&#xA;we consider the fact that the language used in the Hadis literature at&#xA;times borders on extreme coarseness and obscenity. It stands to reason&#xA;that the ulema would not want to display this portion of their religious&#xA;merchandise before the eyes of unsympathetic infidels.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) But&#xA;this very fact has rendered the work of scholarship difficult. One has&#xA;to be not only a competent Arabist but has also to run the gauntlet of&#xA;ulemaic apposition to secure authentic works of Hadis. The scholarly&#xA;searcher has to beware of the bowdlerised and severely edited works of&#xA;Hadis which would meet him at every step in his research. With this&#xA;warning, I would lead the reader to a brief discussion of the Hadis&#xA;literature of the Sunnis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 3 Ghanîmah or Plunder in the Koran</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/07_ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/07_ch3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ghanîmah&lt;/em&gt; or Plunder in the Koran&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To round off the theoretical discussion of &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; I must pass on to the&#xA;doctrine of &lt;em&gt;ghanîmah&lt;/em&gt; as explained in the Koran and the Hadis. We have&#xA;seen that the reward of a &lt;em&gt;mujãhid&lt;/em&gt; in the hereafter is the highest&#xA;heaven. What is his reward on earth? It is ‘plunder’, or ‘spoils of&#xA;war’, or ‘war booty’, as the Arabic expression &lt;em&gt;ghanîmah&lt;/em&gt; is variously&#xA;translated. Not many are prepared to believe that plunder can be&#xA;considered a meritorious or even desirable outcome of the highest duty&#xA;enjoined upon the followers of a religion. To remove their incredulity a&#xA;somewhat detailed discussion of the matter is necessary. It has to be&#xA;admitted that both the Koran and the Hadis declare this outcome of&#xA;&lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; as much inferior to the propagation of Islam as also to the&#xA;pleasures of Paradise to be earned by fighting with the infidels. But at&#xA;the same time these works have given detailed instructions on the mode&#xA;of distribution of plunder as also the laws regulating the distribution.&#xA;The legislation relating to this is first mentioned in the Koran itself.&#xA;The Hadis elaborates it and narrates the Prophet’s own plundering&#xA;activities. Last but not the least, the various schools of Islamic&#xA;jurisprudence codify the regulations in a systematic manner. I shall&#xA;come to the schools of jurisprudence in their proper place. Here I refer&#xA;to the relevant Koranic verses which will be supported by the relevant&#xA;&lt;em&gt;ahãdîs&lt;/em&gt; in the next chapter. But first of all I must explain the word&#xA;&lt;em&gt;ghanîmah&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 4 Plunder (Ghanîmah) in the Hadis</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/08_ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/08_ch4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Plunder (&lt;em&gt;Ghanîmah&lt;/em&gt;) in the Hadis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1) Is plunder compatible with religion and piety? We have seen that&#xA;the Koran itself says ‘yes’. But it appears that some objection was&#xA;raised against this view as early as the Prophet’s own life-time. The&#xA;Prophet himself met this objection in a somewhat longish &lt;em&gt;hadîs&lt;/em&gt;. We&#xA;find him declaring in favour of the Koranic view by contrasting Allah’s&#xA;dispensation regarding plunder in the epoch of former prophets with that&#xA;in his own. The same issue had been raised when the followers of a&#xA;former prophet had amassed a goodly amount of loot which Allah&#xA;apparently disapproved. So “a fire approached the spoils to devour&#xA;them”, but stopped just short of touching it. The prophet of aforetime&#xA;was clever enough to guess the reason for such strange behaviour on the&#xA;part of the divine fire. And he told his followers, “One of you must be&#xA;guilty of concealing a part of the spoil. So come forward and touch my&#xA;hand by way swearing fealty to me.” One or two hands stuck the prophet’s&#xA;hand and, true enough, on questioning they disgorged “gold equal in&#xA;volume to the head of a cow”. So the whole plunder was put together and&#xA;Allah’s fire promptly lapped it up. To the prophet of Islam, the meaning&#xA;of this parable was unmistakable. As he reasoned:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 5 Islamic Expansion through Jihãd:xa0 The Evidence of the Sunnah</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/09_ch5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/09_ch5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;**Islamic Expansion through &lt;em&gt;Jihãd&lt;/em&gt;: **&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;The Evidence of the Sunnah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the foregoing chapters I have attempted to give a brief but complete&#xA;outline of the Islamic theory of &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt;, that is, the injunctions of&#xA;Allah and his Prophet regarding the subject. However, no part of Islamic&#xA;theory is supposed to be complete without a description of the Prophet’s&#xA;own actions in terms to those injunctions. In fact, these actions in&#xA;their totality are the Sunnah properly so called, the mere injunctions&#xA;even from the Prophet’s mouth being only a part of it. To a devout&#xA;Muslim, the Prophet’s actions and sayings rather than revelations from&#xA;Allah supply the model of excellence which he is expected to emulate&#xA;throughout his life-span. The Prophet is the best ruler, the best&#xA;parent, the best husband, and, by the same token, the best &lt;em&gt;mujãhid&lt;/em&gt;. To&#xA;round off the theory of &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt;, a discussion of his own jihãds is,&#xA;therefore, essential.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 6 Destruction of Idols and Idol-Temples inxa0 Jihãd: The Evidence of the Sunnah</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/10_ch6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/10_ch6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;**Destruction of Idols and Idol-Temples in **&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jihãd&lt;/em&gt;: The Evidence of the Sunnah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A natural and in fact inevitable consequence of spreading Islam by&#xA;&lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; is the destruction of non-believers’ places of worship and their&#xA;idols. It is somewhat remarkable that this duty has not been enjoined in&#xA;any Koranic verse as a part of &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt;. The destruction of idols is&#xA;often mentioned in the Koran, but nowhere in connection with &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt;.&#xA;Such an ordinance derives from the Sunnah and the Sunnah alone. In the&#xA;Koran there are descriptions of such destruction in heaven at the hands&#xA;of angels (&lt;em&gt;firishtas&lt;/em&gt;) and on earth at the hands of Prophet Ibrãhîm&#xA;(Abraham), who is proclaimed the first Mussalman in the world. But these&#xA;descriptions are not connected with any &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 7 Slaughter of Infidels in Jihãd: The Evidence of the Sunnah</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/11_ch7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/11_ch7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Slaughter of Infidels in &lt;em&gt;Jihãd&lt;/em&gt;: The Evidence of the Sunnah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The generosity shown by the Prophet to his kinsmen at Mecca was not&#xA;matched by anything in relation to the Jews of Medina, nor, for the&#xA;matter of that, to any Jewish tribe of Arabia. Actually, the Prophet’s&#xA;uniformly stringent measures adopted against the Jews contrasted most&#xA;signally with his leniency towards the Arabs. To account for the&#xA;contrast, D.S. Margoliouth credits the Prophet with being a “champion of&#xA;the national idea” of the Arabs, and this supposition does give a&#xA;national explanation of his uniform hostility to the Jews. As&#xA;Margoliouth puts it, “With this attitude [namely the Prophet’s supposed&#xA;nationalism] agreed his ordinary tenderness for the lives of Arabs when&#xA;he massacred Jews without mercy.” Whatever the explanation, the&#xA;Prophet’s treatment of the Jews brings out a most important body of&#xA;Sunnah connected with one aspect of &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt;, namely, “making slaughter&#xA;in the land” (K 8/67). To illustrate this aspect, a short account of the&#xA;massacre of the Jewish clan of Kuraizah is in order.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 8 Plunder (Ghanîmah) in Jihãd:xa0 The Evidence of the Sunnah</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/12_ch8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/12_ch8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;**Plunder (&lt;em&gt;Ghanîmah&lt;/em&gt;) in &lt;em&gt;Jihãd&lt;/em&gt;: **&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;The Evidence of the Sunnah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Did the Prophet appropriate plunder (&lt;em&gt;ghanîmah&lt;/em&gt;) for his own use? The&#xA;relevant Revelations and &lt;em&gt;ahãdîs&lt;/em&gt; have already been discussed in detail,&#xA;and the part of &lt;em&gt;Khums&lt;/em&gt;, the holy one-fifth of the plunder in the&#xA;Islamic scheme of things, analysed threadbare. But here again the&#xA;Prophet’s own practice (&lt;em&gt;Sunnah&lt;/em&gt;) has to be mentioned if only to round&#xA;off the discussion. A proper analysis of this single topic would require&#xA;a whole book; here I shall content myself with a bare outline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 9 Jihãd in the Shariat</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/13_ch9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/13_ch9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jihãd&lt;/em&gt; in the Shariat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Islam, the term ‘Shariat’ is often used to mean the system of&#xA;ordinances as given in the Koran and the Hadis. But I shall use it in a&#xA;more restrictive sense - for those ordinances which were formulated in&#xA;the schools of jurisprudence (&lt;em&gt;Fiqh&lt;/em&gt;) of the famous Imams Hanîfah,&#xA;Hanbal, Mãlik and Shãfi’î. The school of Hanîfah being the most popular&#xA;in the Islamic world, I shall confine my attention to that school alone&#xA;and use Shykh Burhanuddin Ali’s (d. 1198 AD) &lt;em&gt;Hidãyah&lt;/em&gt; in order to set&#xA;forth the opinions of the Shariat on the subject of &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 10 Jihãd and Religious Riot</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/14_ch10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/14_ch10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jihãd&lt;/em&gt; and Religious Riot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An important question relating to the subject of &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; is this: in&#xA;mixed populations consisting of Muslims and non-Muslims alike, should&#xA;this sanguinary creed not inevitably lead to religious riots? Certainly,&#xA;the Koran furnishes us with verses which have the appearance of&#xA;extremely provocative utterances aimed at rousing the Mussalmans to a&#xA;state of murderous mob-fury. “Go forth light armed and heavy armed and&#xA;strive with your wealth and your lives in the way of Allah,” says the&#xA;Koran (9/41). A verse of this kind does look like being more in the&#xA;nature of a rabble-rousing ejaculation than a proclamation of preplanned&#xA;and premeditated warfare. “Slay the idolaters wherever you find them”&#xA;(9/5) is again, to all appearances, a call to lawless violence rather&#xA;than a general’s directive to draw the battle lines with discipline and&#xA;forethought. Indeed, the whole group of the so-called Immunity Verses&#xA;(9/1-12) of the Koran seems for all practical purposes to indicate a&#xA;sort of abdication of the Islamic state’s responsibility for law and&#xA;order by asking the Muslim masses to destroy the infidel population by&#xA;whatever means available to them. A close examination of the context and&#xA;consequences of the verses is, therefore, necessary to investigate the&#xA;question of the relation of the doctrine of &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; to religious riot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 11 Recapitulation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/15_ch11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/15_ch11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Recapitulation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In summing up the contents of this book one must remember that its aim&#xA;is the exposition of the theoretical aspects of &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt;, and as such its&#xA;subject is Islamic tenets rather than Islamic history. This remark&#xA;applies with equal force to the brief historical accounts of the&#xA;Prophet’s own &lt;em&gt;jihãds&lt;/em&gt; which this book mentions. These are intended as&#xA;accounts of the Prophet’s Sunnah or practice which is part and parcel of&#xA;theoretical Islam as distinct from the Islam of history. The distinction&#xA;is fundamental if only because not everything in the Prophet’s own&#xA;history is considered his Sunnah. His bloodless conquest of Mecca, for&#xA;example, does not constitute a body of Sunnah, whereas his destruction&#xA;of the Jewish clan of Kuraizah very much does so. This is because the&#xA;latter act conforms to the Koranic injunction of “making slaughter in&#xA;the land” while the former has no such scriptural backing. To put the&#xA;whole matter in a nutshell: the Koran as the word of Allah supplies the&#xA;injunction; the Hadis in the language of the Prophet confirms it; and&#xA;the Sunnah gives a practical demonstration of the same and thereby acts&#xA;as an exemplar to future performers of the hallowed exercise called&#xA;&lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 12 Conclusion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/16_ch12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/16_ch12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In concluding this small treatise on the important Islamic doctrine of&#xA;&lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt;, the reader must be reminded that it does not purport to be a&#xA;critique of Islam as such. Even in the restricted field of its survey,&#xA;its aim has been descriptive rather than critical. But before one leaves&#xA;the subject it is only fair to address to the reader certain reflections&#xA;which the foregoing discussion inevitably raises.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Appendix I Jihãd and Expulsion of Non-Muslimsxa0 from Islamic Countries</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/17_app1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/17_app1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appendix I&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;**&lt;em&gt;Jihãd&lt;/em&gt; and Expulsion of Non-Muslims **&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;from Islamic Countries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is expulsion of non-Muslims from countries conquered by Islam a tenet of&#xA;&lt;em&gt;jihad&lt;/em&gt;? The question is important, for a whole chapter of the Koran is&#xA;concerned with this very topic. &lt;em&gt;Sûrah&lt;/em&gt; 59 of the Koran is entitled&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Hashr&lt;/em&gt; which in plain English means ‘banishment’. The &lt;em&gt;sûrah&lt;/em&gt; refers to&#xA;the expulsion of the Jewish tribe of Banu Nazir from Medina in early 625&#xA;AD. As mentioned earlier, the Jewish tribes of Medina were the first&#xA;victims of early Islam’s plundering expeditions. Banu Kainuka was&#xA;despoiled and banished in 624 AD. The next year (625 AD) saw the&#xA;banishment of Banu Nazir. Banu Kuraizah was exterminated in 627 AD.&#xA;These acts of spoliation and mass-slaughter are celebrated in the Hadis&#xA;literature with unbounded pride and exultation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Appendix II Jizyah and the Zimmî</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/18_app2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/18_app2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appendix II&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jizyah and the Zimmî&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The imposition of &lt;em&gt;jizyah&lt;/em&gt; on a vanquished infidel population being one&#xA;of the five fundamentals of &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt;, besides forcible conversions, mass&#xA;slaughter and the two kinds of &lt;em&gt;ghanîmah&lt;/em&gt; (=plunder), a short discussion&#xA;of this tax on religion is essential for a full understanding of the&#xA;doctrine of &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt;. Needless to say, every single aspect of &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; is&#xA;aimed at the ultimate Islamic objective of conquering the whole world&#xA;for Islam, but &lt;em&gt;jizyah&lt;/em&gt; has a very special role to play in attaining&#xA;that objective. It is the only activity connected with &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; which may&#xA;be called ‘bloodless’. As such this topic merits the closest attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Appendix III Development of the Doctrine of Jihãd in the Koran</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/19_app3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/19_app3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appendix III&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Development of the Doctrine of &lt;em&gt;Jihãd&lt;/em&gt; in the Koran&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study of any Islamic doctrine as it developed step by step in the&#xA;Koran is important on many counts. Not least among these is the&#xA;consideration as to how far the doctrine was moulded by pressure of&#xA;immediate circumstance, and how far it stood for any perennial religious&#xA;concern. As regards &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; this question can be answered with some&#xA;assurance. For &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; was never contemplated in Mecca where the Koranic&#xA;verses started being revealed from 609-10 AD onwards and continued upto&#xA;622. It was in the Medinese &lt;em&gt;sûrahs&lt;/em&gt; alone that &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; was enjoined&#xA;right from the beginning, and by the time the 9th &lt;em&gt;sûrah&lt;/em&gt; was revealed&#xA;towards the end of the Prophet’s career it became the chief concern of&#xA;Islam overshadowing every other concern. Chronologically these &lt;em&gt;sûrahs&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;mark a clear change of tone and temper. What begins as a hesitant call&#xA;to arms for the defence of ‘Mosques, Churches and Synagogues’ ends by&#xA;being transformed into a violent call for all round destruction of&#xA;non-Muslims, working murder and rapine all along the line.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Appendix IV Akbarx92s Attitude to Jihãd</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/20_app4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/20_app4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appendix IV&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Akbar’s Attitude to &lt;em&gt;Jihãd&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The story of how Akbar, the Mughal emperor, earned the title of ghãzî by&#xA;beheading the defenceless Himu on November 5, 1556, and its repudiation&#xA;by his court historians (Abul Fazl etc.) is a silent commentary on the&#xA;doctrine of &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; by the one and the only Muslim potentate of medieval&#xA;times who had a wiser head on his shoulders. I give below the two&#xA;versions of the story - one from the pen of the Afghan historian Ahmad&#xA;Yadgar and the other from that of Badauni (who drew his material from&#xA;Nizamuddin’s &lt;em&gt;Tabaqãt-i-Akbarî&lt;/em&gt;). I need only add that Nizamuddin, Abul&#xA;Fazl, and Faizi - all give the same fabricated version of the story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Appendix V Doctrine of Jihãd as Defensive War</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/21_app5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/jihAd/21_app5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appendix V&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctrine of &lt;em&gt;Jihãd&lt;/em&gt; as Defensive War&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book has attempted to show by means of adequate citations from the&#xA;Koran that &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; is aggressive war par excellence, with one or two&#xA;verses thrown in, in between, to indicate that counsels of moderation&#xA;and non-aggression are not wholly absent from the Islamic scheme of&#xA;things. But as Islamic apologists the world over have of late started&#xA;protesting rather loudly that Koranic^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;em&gt;jihãd&lt;/em&gt; is war in&#xA;self-defence and nothing else, it is important that we discuss&#xA;threadbare the worth of the Koranic verse which is most often referred&#xA;to in this connection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
