<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;The life of Tilak on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;The life of Tilak on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>02 MR BLUNT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/02_MR_BLUNT/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/02_MR_BLUNT/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oh hush thee&amp;rsquo; my baby, the time soon will come&lt;br&gt;&#xA;When thy sleep shall be broken by trumpet and drum;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Then hush thee, my darling, take rest while you may.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For strife comes with manhood and waking with day.+++(5)+++&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scott&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The highest praise that has yet been accorded to&#xA;Lokamanya Tilak has come, curiously enough, from the&#xA;Hon. Mr. Gokhale who is reported to have said to an&#xA;Enghsh friend that, bom a hundred and twenty years&#xA;before, Mr. Tilak would have carved out a kingdom for&#xA;himself.+++(5)+++ This pithiest and most appropriate compliment pictures for us Mr. Tilak as he really was, not a&#xA;product of the Western Civilisation and of the English&#xA;Government but a solitary surviver of the race which&#xA;four generations back had well-nigh conquered the whole&#xA;of India. It was impossible for him to be assimilated,&#xA;like most of his countrymen by and in the mighty&#xA;Enghsh Government ; nor could that Government crush&#xA;his spirit and make him a helpless spectator of our&#xA;downfall. He was every inch a soldier a soldier&#xA;in a civilians&amp;rsquo; garb. The Press and the Plaftorm were&#xA;his field of action; and from this battlefield he waged&#xA;a relentless war on the Indian Bureaucracy for nearly&#xA;forty years. He alone of all others dared strike the&#xA;shield of the Government with the &amp;quot; sharp end of the&#xA;steel.&amp;quot; The silent suffering country wanted a man&#xA;who could speak out without mincing matters, one who&#xA;could boldly stand up for cur birth-right held in pawn&#xA;by the rulers of the land. Where could such an one be&#xA;found except in the great Mahratta race ?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 THE FIRST ORDEAL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/03_THE_FIRST_ORDEAL/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/03_THE_FIRST_ORDEAL/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ruby wine is drunk by knaves.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sugar spends to fatten slaves,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The Hero is not fed on sweets.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Daily his own heart he eats ;+++(5)+++&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Chambers of the great are jails.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And head-winds right for royal sails.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Emerson&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IT has been said of Buddha that the sight, in quick&#xA;succession, of disease, old age and death took away&#xA;forever the smile from his lips and joy from his mind&#xA;and thenceforth the Lord of Compassion devoted all his&#xA;energies to the solution of the problem of misery.&#xA;Mr. Tilak&amp;rsquo;s youthful thoughts, too, were clouded by&#xA;three great events, which produced an indelible impression on his sensitive spirit and here we must seek&#xA;for the motive which led him to dedicate his life to&#xA;the service of the Mother-land. The lirst of these&#xA;events was the deposition (1875) of the late H. H.&#xA;Malharrao Gaekwar and his subsequent trial, by a&#xA;special commission, on the charge of having attempted&#xA;to poison his Resident Col. Phayre.+++(5)+++ People in the&#xA;Baroda State and outside, strongly believed in the innocence of the Maharaja who was not restored to his&#xA;throne though the Commission differed in its findings.&#xA;The fate of a hapless Indian Prince, who ought to&#xA;have got at least the benefit of doubt created a deep&#xA;wound in Mr. Tilak&amp;rsquo;s mind ; for its patriotism was&#xA;not outlandish, based merely on the perusal of the&#xA;works of Mill and Bright. It was essentially Indian,&#xA;and was directly derived from a contemplation of&#xA;the great and heroic deeds of Shivaji and his descend###ants. The Maratha History of the 17th and 18th Centu###ries formed the Bible of his patriotism and his blood&#xA;was aflame when he reflected on the utter impotence&#xA;to which the representatives of the Empire-builders&#xA;of the 1 8th century were reduced.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 THE SCHOOL AND THE COLLEGE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/04_THE_SCHOOL_AND_THE_COLLEGE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/04_THE_SCHOOL_AND_THE_COLLEGE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have undertaken this work of popular education with the&#xA;firmest conviction and belief that, of all agents of human civili###sation, education is the only one that brings about material,&#xA;moral and religious regeneration of fallen countries and raises&#xA;them up to the level of most advanced Nations by slow and&#xA;peaceful revolutions : and in order that this should be so, it&#xA;must be ultimately in the hands of the people themselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 TILAK AND SOCIAL REFORM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/05_TILAK_AND_SOCIAL_REFORM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/05_TILAK_AND_SOCIAL_REFORM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do not believe in reform ; I believe in growth.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Swami Vivekananda.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have yet to see a nation, whose faith is determined, by the&#xA;number of husbands its widows get.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Swami Vivekananda.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Instead of increasing the elements of friction — the besetting&#xA;weakness of reformers and dissidents of all kinds — he took&#xA;infinite trouble to reduce those elements to the lowest possible&#xA;points. Hence he was careful not to take up too many subjects&#xA;at once, because, the antagonism generated by each, would have&#xA;been made worse, by the antagonism to each other ; and he&#xA;would have called up a host of enemies together, instead of&#xA;leaving himself free to deal with one at a time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 TILAK AND THE CONGRESS— I</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/06_TILAK_AND_THE_CONGRESS_I/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/06_TILAK_AND_THE_CONGRESS_I/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the Poona Congress of 1895, when Gokhale was a secretary&#xA;of the Reception Committee, the ridiculous controversy started&#xA;by Mr. Tilak, about letting the Social Conference have the use&#xA;of the Congress Mandap assumed disproportionate dimensions&#xA;and Mr. Tilak triumphed momentarily. I do not know what&#xA;he now (1915) thinks in his heart of hearts of the part, that he&#xA;played in the matter, though he can, like the skilful advocate&#xA;that he is, still put a fair complexion on it is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 THE HONOURABLE AND</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/07_THE_HONOURABLE_AND/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/07_THE_HONOURABLE_AND/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An Additional Membership is, as I view it, no sop or gag intended to stop honest and fair criticism. But if it is, I should&#xA;certainly give it up rather than consent to draw the curtain over&#xA;the gross negligence or the palpable errors of officials, however&#xA;high they may be.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B. G. Tilak&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On August 7th, 1895, Mr. Tilak, elected by an overwhelming majority by the District Local Boards&#xA;of the Central Division, took, in the Legislative&#xA;Council, the customary oath of allegiance to Her Ma###jesty, the Queen-Empress. Two years later he was&#xA;standing as an under-trial prisoner in the High Court&#xA;of Judicature, to be punished of disaffection, in spite&#xA;of his protests and in anticipation of a new interpre###tation of the term ! The first event did not ensnare&#xA;him, nor was his Hfe-work paralysed by the second.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 THE LOKAMANYA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/08_THE_LOKAMANYA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/08_THE_LOKAMANYA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My position among the people entirely depends upon my&#xA;character ; and if I am cowed down by the prosecution,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;living in Maharashtra is as good as living in the Andamans.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;We are incapable of nourishing any sinster feeling against the&#xA;British Rule and it is thus impossible for any of us to be convicted of such a heinous charge as sedition. Such risks however,&#xA;we must take * * They are the risks of our profession * * Their&#xA;(the Government&amp;rsquo;s) object is to humiliate the Poona leaders,&#xA;and I think in me they will not find a &amp;quot; kutchha reed &amp;ldquo;. . .&#xA;Then you must remember that beyond a certain stage we are&#xA;all servants of the people. You will be betraying and disap###pointing them, if you show a lamentable want of courage at a&#xA;critical time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 THE SCHOOL OF MODERATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/09_THE_SCHOOL_OF_MODERATION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/09_THE_SCHOOL_OF_MODERATION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let us swear an oath and keep it with an equal mind&lt;br&gt;&#xA;In the hollow lotus-land to live and lie reclined.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Surely surely slumber is more sweet than toil, the shore&#xA;Than labour in the deep mid ocean, wind and wave and oar ;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Oh, rest ye, brother mariners, we will not wonder more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tennyson.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While the Social Reformers were remarrying widows&#xA;and breaking castes with the ultimate object of&#xA;making the people fit for political rights, Mr. Tilak was&#xA;labouriouly striving to infuse vigour into the public mind&#xA;by his passionate appeals to the great traditions of our&#xA;History, Religion and Society. He inaugurated the&#xA;Ganapati and the Shivaji festivals, which in spite of the&#xA;bitter attacks of Moderates and the hostile attitude of&#xA;the Government have now come to form a permanent&#xA;feature of the social life of Maharashtra. These festivals&#xA;deserve to be recorded as Mr. Tilak &amp;rsquo;s memorable contri###butions to our public life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 THE FIERY CROSS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/10_THE_FIERY_CROSS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/10_THE_FIERY_CROSS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rejoice and fear not for the waves that swell.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The storms that thunder, winds that sweep.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Always our Captain holds the rudder well.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;He does not sleep.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Arabindo Ghose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That, for nearly eighteen years of his life, Mr. Tilak&#xA;was involved in a private litigation, arising out of&#xA;an unnatural alliance between an inexperienced young&#xA;widow, a number of unscrupulous persons inimical&#xA;to him and the mighty Bureaucracy hopelessly preju###diced against him, is known to all. The Tai Maharaj&#xA;Case was really a flank movement on the public career&#xA;of Mr. Tilak and was intended to drive him out&#xA;of public life by judicially proving his dishonesty.&#xA;Fortunately Mr. Tilak did ultimately triumph.&#xA;But before the final victory came, he suffered two&#xA;reverses which were fully exploited by his political&#xA;enemies. The judgment of Mr. Justice Chandavarkar&#xA;(1910) with its unwarranted aspersions on Mr. Tilak&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;character, was of invaluable aid to Sir Valentine&#xA;Chirol in villifying him. Apart from the capital made&#xA;out of it by the allies of the Bureaucracy, the&#xA;Tai Maharaj case, in its winding courses, threatened&#xA;to ruin Mr. Tilak in every possible way. It put him&#xA;to an expenditure of thousands of rupees and pro###mised to crush him financially. It took huge slices&#xA;from his leisure ; in fact, during some of the stages of&#xA;this never-ending case, the task of vindicating his cha###racter was his principle business and politics or&#xA;literature was the work of leisure. A careful calcula###tion of the actual time spent by him in fighting out the&#xA;case from its commencement to the conclusion shows&#xA;that it took away six precious years of his time. Nor&#xA;was the loss of time and money his only misfortune.&#xA;The dread uncertainty of it all threw a shadow on his&#xA;cheerfulness. Mr. Tilak&amp;rsquo;s life during the better part of&#xA;this period can be compared to the course of a ship&#xA;which every minute stands in danger of being blown&#xA;over by a stray mine or a torpedo. In the end, truth&#xA;triumphed over falsehood, justice over m justice, and&#xA;Mr. Tilak&amp;rsquo;s character was completely vindicated, first&#xA;by the judgment of the Bombay High Court (1904) and&#xA;then by that of the Privy Council in 1915.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 THE NEW PARTY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/11_THE_NEW_PARTY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/11_THE_NEW_PARTY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bal Gangadhar Tilak is a Maratha Brahmin, thinker and&#xA;fighter in one. His is the brain that conceived, his is the pen&#xA;that expressed, his is the force that has directed the extra-ordi###nary movement against which the bureaucracy is now calling&#xA;up all its resources.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Morning Leader in 1908.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The year 1905 forms a land-mark in Indian History.&#xA;In that year was carried out the fatal Partition of&#xA;Bengal. The whole Province was thrown into a ferment. The Bengalis heartily disliked the odius measure.&#xA;Appeals were made, monster petitions were sent to the&#xA;Parliament. Then came the Bycott. It encouraged&#xA;Swadeshism. The Swadeshi movement quickly out###grew its economic or political nature and became a&#xA;movement for National Regeneration. The Nation&#xA;called for Swadeshism in dress, in diet, in habits, in life,&#xA;in arts, in literature, in science, in religion and philoso###phy. Swadeshism thus became an all-pervading spiri###ritual movement directed against the Western Civilisa###tion which the British Government represented and&#xA;symbolized. The Boycott bade fair to develop into a&#xA;movement of Passive Resistance. Young men enrolled&#xA;themselves as National Volunteers for peaceful partici###pation in public Hfe. The Government retaliated with&#xA;the Risley Circular and the Carlyle Circular. The-&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 TILAK AND THE CONGRESS— II</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/12_TILAK_AND_THE_CONGRESS_II/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/12_TILAK_AND_THE_CONGRESS_II/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The days of absolute leadership are gone, never to return&#xA;back.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;N. G. Chandavarkar&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Elsewhere we have traced Mr. Tilak&amp;rsquo;s connection&#xA;with the Congress from 1889 down to the early&#xA;years of the present century. We have seen, how,&#xA;in the period of poUtical re-action, beginning &amp;lsquo;with&#xA;1897, the Congress leaders showed their ** states###manship,&amp;quot; by scrupulously following a policy of&#xA;Moderation, which, very often meant inaction, timi###dity or indifference to the National good.&#xA;Ever since his return (1899) ^^ public life after&#xA;one year&amp;rsquo;s incarceration,Mr. Tilak had been fighting with&#xA;these tendencies in and out of the National Congress.&#xA;but what with his pre-occupations in the Tai Maharaj&#xA;Case, and what with the small following he had in the&#xA;Congress, he could not effectually raise his voice against&#xA;the policy of inertia and negation, which Sir Pheroze###shah later came to glory in. From 1905, however all&#xA;this was changed. The wave of awakening in the coun###try strengthened the nascent New Party and Mr. Tilak&#xA;could get that amount of following in the Congress&#xA;which was required to put up a fair fight. This tended&#xA;to enUven the proceedings of the Congress and increase -&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 TOWARDS REPRESSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/13_TOWARDS_REPRESSION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/13_TOWARDS_REPRESSION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The stars are blotted out.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The clouds are covering clouds,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The sea has joined the fray&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And swirls up mountain waves&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The flash of lurid light&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Reveals on every side&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A thousand thousand shades.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kali by Swami Vivekananda,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Who broke the Congress at Surat ?&amp;rdquo; In reply ^&#xA;we ask, &amp;quot; Who wanted to go back on the&#xA;Calcutta resolutions ?&amp;quot; &amp;ldquo;Who hailed the Surat split&#xA;with rapture ?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Who wanted to rally round the&#xA;banner of Lord Morley?&amp;rdquo; Not the least important&#xA;question is &amp;quot; whose conduct was unconstitutional and&#xA;un-Parliamentary ?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 THE COUNTRY&#39;S MISFORTUNE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/14_THE_COUNTRYS_MISFORTUNE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/14_THE_COUNTRYS_MISFORTUNE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Lion when struck to the heart gives out his mightest roar ;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;When smitten on the head, the cobra lifts its hood ;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And the majesty of the soul comes forth only when a man is wounded unto his depths.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Swami Vivekananda.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The arrest of Mr. Tilak, though it caused widespread&#xA;grief and resentment did not surprise anybody. What&#xA;however extremely surprised all was that such a mild and&#xA;innocent article as that of May 12th, 1908 had been&#xA;selected for prosecuting Mr. Tilak under Sections 124 A&#xA;and 153 A of the Indian Penal Code. The Government&#xA;of Bombay seem to have realised the risk of getting&#xA;conviction on the article of May 12th and so, another&#xA;sanction to prosecute Mr. Tilak for publishing the lead###ing article in the Kesari of June 9th entitled &amp;quot; These&#xA;remedies are not lasting &amp;quot; was given, a fresh warrant&#xA;was issued and executed on Mr. Tilak in jail ; and by&#xA;two separate orders was Mr. Tilak committed to the&#xA;Criminal Sessions of the Bombay High Court on June&#xA;29th, 1908.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 RIP VAN WINKLE !</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/15_RIP_VAN_WINKLE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/15_RIP_VAN_WINKLE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, thou great sea !&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I am more mighty and out-billow thee.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;On thy tops I rise —&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;lsquo;Tis an excuse to dally with the skies.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I sink below&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The bottom of the clamourous world to know.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I come, oh free Ocean, to measure my huge soul with thee.+++(5)+++&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arahindo Ghose&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IVTR. TILAK&amp;rsquo;S transportation to Mandalay was&#xA;followed by a long period of political re-action.&#xA;Boycott, political or economic, ceased to count as a&#xA;iactor in practical politics. Only lord Minto&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;&amp;quot; Honest Swadeshi &amp;quot; lived. National schools and&#xA;colleges were deserted. The Samitts were sup###pressed. Arbitration courts collapsed. Whole###sale repression drove the movement underground,&#xA;bringing Terrorism in its train. The Terrorist was&#xA;vigorously hunted. Popular leaders found their way&#xA;either to goal or to self-imposed exile. The National&#xA;Congress with its ever-dwindling enthusiasm and&#xA;attendance, met only to register the grosving depres###sion of the Moderate leaders. The &amp;quot; Reformed &amp;quot;&#xA;Councils had disillusioned the people. Even Mr.&#xA;Gokhale&amp;rsquo;s optimism was shattered. The Octopeaa&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 THE GREAT HOME-RULER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/16_THE_GREAT_HOME-RULER/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/16_THE_GREAT_HOME-RULER/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sons of India ! Let your sadness &lt;br&gt;&#xA;Turn to gladness ; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;For the long night of your sorrow &lt;br&gt;&#xA;Now has passed ; a glorious morrow&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Dawns upon you. Day is shining&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Cease repining.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C, F, Andrews,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IN the darkest hour of Mr. Tilak&amp;rsquo;s life, when neither&#xA;friend nor foe expected him to survive six long years&#xA;^f transportation, the Hon. Mr. Gokhale could not forget&#xA;his old grievances against him. But Mr. Tilak was&#xA;nothing if not chivalrous, and on hearing the unexpect###ed news of Mr. Gokhale&amp;rsquo;s death, (19th February 19 15)&#xA;he motored down to Poona from Sinhgad to do honour&#xA;to the great Moderate. The funeral oration delivered&#xA;by him on this occassion is intensely passionate. Mr;&#xA;Tilak said : —&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 RESPONSIBLE GOVERNMENT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/17_RESPONSIBLE_GOVERNMENT/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/17_RESPONSIBLE_GOVERNMENT/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For us there is but one choice. We have made it. Woe be&#xA;to the man or groups of men that seek to stand in our way in&#xA;this day of our high resolution when every principle we hold&#xA;dearest is to be Vindicated and made secure for our salvation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;President Wilson&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After nine long years of separation, Mr. Tilak&#xA;joined his old comrades at the Congress of Lucknow (1916). What a change ! In 1907, the nation was&#xA;on the eve of a relentless campaign of repression. Now&#xA;in 1916, the country was throbbing with the expectation of a vast political transformation, which Mr. Tilak&#xA;had worked so laboriously to bring about. No wonder&#xA;therefore, that when he stood to address the 2350 ex###pectant delegates and thrice as many spectators he was&#xA;accorded an enthusiastic ovation. He said : —&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 THE MISSION TO ENGLAND</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/18_THE_MISSION_TO_ENGLAND/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/18_THE_MISSION_TO_ENGLAND/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have had many opportunities of exchanging views with Mr.&#xA;Tilak during his stay in England, and every time that I have&#xA;spoken with him, I have felt that he was truly a statesman and&#xA;not a mere politician. The way in which he was able to take a&#xA;sane view of the Indian situation in Britain, within a few days&#xA;of his arrival in this country (England) made me marvel at his&#xA;perspicuity&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 TILAK—V— CHIROL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/19_TILAKV_CHIROL/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/19_TILAKV_CHIROL/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the Deccan his (Mr. Tilak&amp;rsquo;s) influence projected far and wide. His prestige as a Brahmin of Brahmins, and as pillar of Orthodoxy, his reputation for pro###found learning in the philosophies of the West and the East,&#xA;his trenchant style, his indefatigable activity, the glamour of&#xA;his philanthrophy, his accessibility to high and low, his many&#xA;acts of genuine kindliness, (his) personal magnetism combined to equip him more fully than any other Indian Politician for the leadership of a revolutionary movement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 RESPONSIVE CO-OPERATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/20_RESPONSIVE_CO-OPERATION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/20_RESPONSIVE_CO-OPERATION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not what thou and I have promised to each other but what&#xA;the balance of our forces can make us perform to each other :&#xA;that, in so sinful a world as ours, is the thing to be counted&#xA;upon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thomas Carlyle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Mr. Montague asked Mr. Tilak what he would&#xA;do in case the reforms fell short of his expect###ations, Mr. Tilak readily replied &amp;ldquo;I would accept what is&#xA;given and fight for more.&amp;quot;+++(5)+++ Being a strategist and not&#xA;a mere idealist, Mr. Tilak knew full well how to make&#xA;use of the smallest concessions. That is why, when&#xA;the Montague-Chelmsford report was out,he did not run&#xA;into hysterics over it. He never called for its unquali###fied rejection. From the very beginning his criticism&#xA;was strong but constructive and he refused to lend the&#xA;weight of his support to that small party in the Congress&#xA;which in July and August, 19 18, talked of a summary&#xA;refusal of the &amp;rsquo;little&amp;rsquo; Mont-ford gift. It was not, there###fore, likely, that Mr. Tilak would, in November 1919&#xA;reject those Reforms which nearly two years back he&#xA;had decided to accept for a time. When he returned&#xA;to India in November 1919 after advocating the Congress&#xA;demands before the British Democracy, he had already&#xA;matured in his mind a plan of operations, which he&#xA;thought, would be the shortest cut to Home Rule.&#xA;When in England, Mr. Tilak had been deeply impres&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 THE END</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/21_THE_END/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/21_THE_END/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Tilak is dead ! Long live Mr. Tilak !&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Tribune.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The situation which Mr. Tilak occupied towards the&#xA;middle of 1920 was the most enviable any public&#xA;man has occupied in India. He was the most success###ful and the most longlived of the band of self-sacrificing&#xA;workers who started the New English School (1880),&#xA;the Kesari and the Mahratta (1881). His opponents —&#xA;Ranade, Telang, Mehta and Gokhale — were gathered&#xA;to their fathers before the substantial achievement of&#xA;their labours. He alone represented, not merely the&#xA;youngest but the oldest generation living. Starting&#xA;his life as an &amp;rsquo; opponent of Social Reform &amp;rsquo; he lived to&#xA;count the staunchest reformers among his lieutenants.&#xA;The branded &amp;rsquo; enemy of the Mahomedans &amp;rsquo; was the&#xA;ambassador of Hindu-Moslem unity at Lucknow and&#xA;his active co-operation was sought by and promised to&#xA;the leaders of the Khilafat movement. The slogan of&#xA;Swaraj, issuing from his pen in 1895 was echoed by the&#xA;National Congress of 1906 and the Government of India&#xA;Act of 1919. His no-rent campaign of 1896 forms one&#xA;of the planks of the Non-co-operation programme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 THE MAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/22_THE_MAN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/22_THE_MAN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The pages of thy book I read.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And as I closed each one,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;My heart responding, ever said,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;quot; Servant of God! Well done!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Longfellow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;T IKE his literary career, Mr. Tilak&amp;rsquo;s private life was&#xA;almost absorbed into his political existence and it&#xA;serves but to enhance the charm of his magnetic per###sonality and romantic career ; and yet, considered even&#xA;separately, that private life, lived in the full blaze of&#xA;publicity, will serve as a model for all those who consider&#xA;self-introspection and self-elevation as the principle&#xA;duty of life. Charles Stuart Parnell is reported to have&#xA;said in one of his moments of infatuation that his pub###lic life belonged to his country and that his private life&#xA;was his own. Mr. Tilak made no such distinction and his&#xA;public career was only the logical outcome of those qua###lities of the heart, which have been over and over test###ed in his private life. Excepting what have been sent&#xA;bv the cold hand of Death, no cloud has marred the&#xA;sunshine of his domestic felicity. His wife, calm, active&#xA;and devoted, without the least touch of the modern wo###man in her, made his private life perfectly happy to&#xA;him. She bore him six children,~three sons and three&#xA;daughters, the latter all married — and died on 6th June&#xA;1912, while Mr. Tilak was at Mandalay. His eldest son&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 IN THE EDITORIAL CHAIR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/23_IN_THE_EDITORIAL_CHAIR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/23_IN_THE_EDITORIAL_CHAIR/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Great is Journalism. Is not every Able Editor a Ruler of&#xA;the World, being a persuader of it ; though self-elected yet&#xA;sanctioned by the sale of his Numbers ?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thomas Carlyle&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mr. TILAK became the declared editor of the&#xA;Kesari on 22nd October 1887, and of the Mahratta&#xA;on 3rd Spetember 1891. Since then, he conducted these&#xA;journals as proprietor till the last, and though, the&#xA;editorship was occasionally transferred to others, still&#xA;he supplied the necessary inspiration, except during the&#xA;intervals when he was a guest of His Majesty&amp;rsquo;s gaols.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 TILAK THE SCHOLAR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/24_TILAK_THE_SCHOLAR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/24_TILAK_THE_SCHOLAR/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To me it (i e. The Arctic Home in the Vedas) is significant&#xA;because it appeared in the midst of the author&amp;rsquo;s direst persecution when money reputation, influence and everything were at stake, and few men would have had the courage to spare&#xA;a thought either for sacred books or Arctic Circles.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;H. W. Nevinson.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The scholar in politics is either a remarkable failure or an extraordinary success. In the scholar&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;temperament, hesitency, lack of strong will-power, im###patience and petulance usually form the chief mgrcdi###ents. His knowledge of men is limited ; his grasp of&#xA;actualities is imperfect. He has no resourcefulness,&#xA;very little courage or presence of mind. His personality is weak and he is very rarely a ruler of men. The&#xA;failure as an administrator of M. Guizot, the celebrated&#xA;philosopher-historian is a striking illustration of the&#xA;danger of appointing men of letters at the helm of&#xA;affairs. Mr. Tilak however was primarily a man of&#xA;action. His wonderful and luminous scholarship and&#xA;his versatile and comprehensive genius formed merely&#xA;the back-ground of a strong-willed, fiery, masterful,&#xA;soldierly personality. His scholarship illuminated his&#xA;political leadership with a lustre as rare as it was dazzling ; his political leadership gave his scholarly work&#xA;a prestige and a significance totally absent in the efforts&#xA;of mere scholars. If a scholar in politics is a rarity, a&#xA;scholar-politician finding his way to gaol is still more so;&#xA;and that, such a man should have lifted his thoughts&#xA;from the chilling atmosphere of gaol-life and the excru###ciating pain which inevitably attends it, up to the re###gions of ethics and philosophy is, verily a wonder of&#xA;wonders !&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 LOKAMANYA TILAK AND MAHATMA GANDHI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/25_LOKAMANYA_TILAK_AND_MAHATMA_GANDHI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/25_LOKAMANYA_TILAK_AND_MAHATMA_GANDHI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yet this is not the whole man. You cannot say this is he,&#xA;that is he. All that you can say with certainty is that he is&#xA;here, he is there. Everywhere his influence reigns, his .autho###rity rules, his elusive personality pervades ; and this must be&#xA;so, for it is true of all great men that they are incalculable,&#xA;beyond definition. They partake of the nature of the Illimi###table and the Eternal from which they have sprung and to&#xA;which they are bound. With their feet firm-set on earth and&#xA;their hands among the stars, they are pointers of the way to&#xA;those who search, encouragers of the faint and weary, inspirers&#xA;of those breathing in deep draughts of hope.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 GENERAL REFLECTIONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/26_GENERAL_REFLECTIONS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/26_GENERAL_REFLECTIONS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We can sacrcely express the admiration which we feel for&#xA;a mind so great and at the same time so healthy and well-proportioned, so willingly contracting itself to the humblest&#xA;duties, so easily expanding itself to the highest, so contended in&#xA;repose, so powerful in action. Every part of this virtuous and&#xA;blameless life is not hidden from us in modest privacy is a&#xA;splendid-portion of our national history.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Macaulay on John Hampden&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 THE ORION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/27_THE_ORION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/27_THE_ORION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;( Appendix A and B will give the reader an idea of&#xA;the principal arguments advanced by Mr. Tilak&#xA;in the Orion and the Arctic Home in the Vedas to&#xA;establish his theories. The Gita-Rahasya being com###paratively a recent production is too well-known&#xA;to require any summary. )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oriental scholars have advanced vague and uncertain conjectures about the age and character of the Vedas. Prof. Max Muller has divided the Vedic literature into four arbitrary periods, the Chhandas, Mantra, Brahmana and Sutra and by assigning two hundred&#xA;years for each period he arrives at about 1200 B.C.&#xA;as the latest date at which the Vedic hymns have been&#xA;composed. As opposed to this linguistic method of&#xA;ascertaining the age of the Vedas, there is the astronomical method which though condemned by European scholars as inaccurate and conjectural, can, if properly&#xA;applied, lead us to good results. The Vedas, the Brahmanas and the Sutras contain numerous allusions and&#xA;references to astronomical facts. There are several&#xA;sacrificial hymns in the Rig-veda. Now, no sacrificial&#xA;system could be developed without the knowledge of&#xA;months, seasons and the year. It appears that&#xA;the Vedic Rishis kept up their calender by performing the corresponding round of sacrifices on the sacred fire that constantly burnt in their houses ; and&#xA;as they were not only the sacrificers of the community&#xA;but were also its time-keepers, these two functions&#xA;appear to have blended into one by assigning the commencement of the several sacrifices to the leading days&#xA;of the year on the natural ground that if the sacrifices&#xA;were to be performed, they must be performed on the&#xA;principal days of the year. Samvatsara and Yajna&#xA;therefore came to be regarded as convertible terms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 Arctic Home</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/28_Arctic_Home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/life_of_lokamAnya_tilak_athalye/28_Arctic_Home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APPENDIX B [[389]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Up to the middle of the 19th century, myths and traditions were the only materials available for the study of pre-historic man. So various attempts were made to systematise these myths and explain them rationally. But the mythologists carried on their researches at a time when man was believed to be postglacial and when the physical and geographical surroundings of the ancient man were assumed not to have been materially different from those of the present day. But about the middle of the igth century, from hundreds of stone and bronze implements found buried in various places in Europe, the archaeologists established the chronological sequence of the Iron, the Bronze and the Stone age in times preceding the historic period and discovered evidence to prove the existence of the Glacial period at the close of the Quarternary era and the high antiquity of man who was shown to have lived not only throughout the Quarternary but also in the Tertiary era when the climatic conditions of the globe were quite different from those in the present or Post-Glacial period. It, therefore, became evident that the results previously arrived at by philologists and mythologists must be revised in the hght of new scientific discoveries. It also became necessary to study the ancient sacred books of the Aryans in the light of modern archaeological and geological discoveries ; for if man existed before the last Glacial period and witnessed the gigantic change which brought on the Ice age, it is not unnatural to expect that a reference, howso ever concealed and distant, to these events would be found in the oldest traditionary beliefs and memories of mankind. If we read some of the passages in the Vedas, which have hitherto been considered incomprehensible, in the light of the new scientific discoveries, we arc forced to the conclusion that the home of the ancestors of the Vedic people was somewhere near the North Pole before the last Glacial epoch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
