<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Evil Greed on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/evil-greed/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Evil Greed on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/evil-greed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Amazon suicide kits</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/evil-greed/amazon-suicide-kits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/evil-greed/amazon-suicide-kits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1578121292502409216.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last Friday, CBS cancelled a segment about our clients suing Amazon for selling suicide kits to their now deceased kids. CBS’ cowardice gave me renewed clarity about how urgent this litigation is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As background, on Feb 3, 2022 we filed a lawsuit in WA State against Amazon on behalf of the Estate of Mikael Scott. In Dec. 2020 Mikael purchased a chemical from Amazon, 98% pure Sodium Nitrite, for $19.99. It was prime delivered two days later. He died three days after that. There is no household use for pure SN, a chemical that when mixed with water and swigged causes a very painful death within 20 min. (NOTE: the product we’re suing about should not be mistaken for curing salt which is only 6% pure SN and used to cure meats.). Starting in April 2021, we began urging Amazon to stop selling suicide kits to households. Unlike other products that could be used for suicide (i.e. knives, ropes), there is no other use for Sodium Nitrite at this level of purity outside the laboratory. And Amazon was bundling SN with other products to basically create create a suicide kit &amp;ndash; Amazon recommends that purchasers also buy Tagamet to avoid vomiting up the poison, a personal use scale to measure the proper quantity, and the Amazon Edition of the Peaceful Pill Handbook, a suicide manual with an entire chapter on how to die by SN.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
