<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Math on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/programming/programmingLanguages/math/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Math on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/programming/programmingLanguages/math/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CVX</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/programming/programmingLanguages/math/cvx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/programming/programmingLanguages/math/cvx/</guid>
      <description>Distinctive features Disciplined convex programming framework Makes specification easy. Abstracts away the mathematical and methodological details (like what underlying solver to call?).
Tries to mimic the way people formulate convex programs: drawing from a library of convex functions, combining them in various valid ways to preserve convexity. Similarly, it has a rich, expandable library of functions with known properties, plus it specifies valid ways of composing and combining them.
Good way to check convexity of the problem!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Spreadsheet</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/programming/programmingLanguages/math/google_spreadsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/programming/programmingLanguages/math/google_spreadsheet/</guid>
      <description>Google docs Cell referencing Columns are numbered with letters and rows with numbers. A cell can be specified using a latter and a number.
When cell references are copied (perhaps as part of formulae), the references may be automatically changed in a certain way - this is called relative reference: Eg: The reference A20 used in cell A2, when copied to B2 will automatically be changed to B20.
When such change does not happen, we have absolute reference to a cell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matlab/ Octave</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/programming/programmingLanguages/math/matlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/programming/programmingLanguages/math/matlab/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Distinctive features of the language Excellent plotting facilities; many libraries; interactive sessions good for exploring features of data; easy I/O: don&amp;rsquo;t need to spend as much time in getting I/O right as in actual computation; excellent debugging facilities.
Octave is an open source clone of matlab.
Purpose of design Matrix computations. This is meant to be a rapid prototyping language : It is not meant for fast implementations.
Versions Certain OOP methods, properties don&amp;rsquo;t work with 2007 version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/programming/programmingLanguages/math/R/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/programming/programmingLanguages/math/R/</guid>
      <description>Introduction and use When to use Statistics is the emphasis, not matrix manipulation. It is an expression language.
When not to use Text processing and general purpose programming are painful.
Writing, Building and executing code Script execution source(&amp;quot;/path/file.R&amp;rdquo;).
Reloading changed code library(&amp;ldquo;R.utils&amp;rdquo;);
sourceDirectory(&amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo;, modifiedOnly=TRUE, \pattern=&amp;rdquo;[A-Z]*[.]R$&amp;rdquo;, recursive=FALSE);
Important environment variables \verb R_LIBS : the place where R libraries are installed.
Working environment getwd(), setwd(dir)
options(): Example options(digits=3)
Command history history(), savehistory, loadhistory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapidminer</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/programming/programmingLanguages/math/rapidminer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/programming/programmingLanguages/math/rapidminer/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Purpose Rapidminer provides convenient tools for data loading, exploration, modelling, visualization.
UI and API It comes with a nice GUI. It provides Java API. It also has a scripting interface.
Data types (Bi or Poly) Nominal, Integer, Double, Varchar.
Processes One can visualize the data mining process as a tree of operators. The leaf nodes correspond to the result nodes. Processes can be edited in the design view : here it looks like an electronic circuit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>