<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;islamic imperialism india on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;islamic imperialism india on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 CHAPTER I IN THE NAME OF NATIONAL INTEGRATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/01_ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/01_ch1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER I&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-the-name-of-national-integration&#34;&gt;IN THE NAME OF NATIONAL INTEGRATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Comrade Radek, whom Stalin liquidated in the late ‘thirties, was a Communist intellectual endowed with acid humour. He coined many jokes at the cost of the Communist Party and the Soviet State. One of these jokes which did the rounds in Moscow was as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One day Comrade Radek stood stark naked in the Red Square in broad daylight. A courageous citizen approached and asked him, “Aren’t you afraid of the police, Comrade Commissar?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 CHAPTER II THE CHARACTER OF MUSLIM RULE IN INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/02_ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/02_ch2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER II&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-character-of-muslim-rule-in-india&#34;&gt;THE CHARACTER OF MUSLIM RULE IN INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some of the guidelines seem to be good. It is eminently desirable that “the ancient period of Indian history cannot be referred to as the Hindu period and the medieval period as the Muslim period”. It follows, though it is not mentioned in the guidelines reported by the &lt;em&gt;Indian Express&lt;/em&gt;, that the modern period of Indian history also will not be named as the British period. This scheme of periodization, however, was given up by most historians quite some time ago. One only wonders what the votaries of Islamic imperialism will do without a Muslim period of Indian history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 CHAPTER III PLEA FOR A PERSPECTIVE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/03_ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/03_ch3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER III&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;plea-for-a-perspective&#34;&gt;PLEA FOR A PERSPECTIVE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let us now consider the next guideline from the NCERT, namely, that “characterisation of the medieval period as a time of conflict between Hindus and Muslims is forbidden”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The underlying assumption is that Muslims invaders of India in the medieval period were as good natives and patriots as the Hindus who resisted them, and that the numerous wars which the Hindus were forced to fight with the Muslim marauders were nothing more than domestic discords.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 CHAPTER IV THE NATURE OF CONFLICT IN MEDIEVAL INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/04_ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/04_ch4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER IV&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-nature-of-conflict-in-medieval-india&#34;&gt;THE NATURE OF CONFLICT IN MEDIEVAL INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another guideline laid down by the NCERT for school-level textbooks of history exhorts that “no exaggeration of the role of religion in political conflicts is permitted”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let us for the time being forget the fiat of the State as to what is permitted and what is forbidden while writing the new textbooks of history. Let us first find out the facts as recorded by medieval historians, and review the various interpretations of those facts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 CHAPTER V ISLAM WAS THE CULPRIT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/05_ch5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/05_ch5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER V&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;islam-was-the-culprit&#34;&gt;ISLAM WAS THE CULPRIT&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Aligarh apologists accuse the medieval Muslim historians of exaggerating the barbarities committed by the Muslim invaders and rulers. Next, they blame on the inherent barbarism of the Turks whatever irreducible minimum of atrocities cannot be hushed out of recorded history. And they end by absolving Islam of every crime committed in its name.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My first question is: How is it that what the Prophet of Islam did in Arabia and the Arab armies in Syria, Iraq, Iran, North Africa, Sicily, Spain and Sindh, bears such close resemblance to what the Turks did in India?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 CHAPTER VI THE MAGNITUDE OF MUSLIM ATROCITIES - I</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/06_ch6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/06_ch6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER VI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-magnitude-of-muslim-atrocities---i&#34;&gt;THE MAGNITUDE OF MUSLIM ATROCITIES - I&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The world famous historian, Will Durant has written in his &lt;em&gt;Story of Civilisation&lt;/em&gt; that “the Mohammedan conquest of India was probably the bloodiest story in history”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;India before the advent of Islamic imperialism was not exactly a zone of peace. There were plenty of wars fought by Hindu princes. But in all their wars, the Hindus had observed some time-honoured conventions sanctioned by the Śāstras. The Brahmins and the Bhikshus were never molested. The cows were never killed. The temples were never touched. The chastity of women was never violated. The non-combatants were never killed or captured. A human habitation was never attacked unless it was a fort. The civil population was never plundered. War booty was an unknown item in the calculations of conquerors. The martial classes who clashed, mostly in open spaces, had a code of honour. Sacrifice of honour for victory or material gain was deemed as worse than death.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 CHAPTER VII </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/07_ch7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/07_ch7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER VII&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-magnitude-of-muslim-atrocities---ii&#34;&gt;THE MAGNITUDE OF MUSLIM ATROCITIES - II&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The NCERT is not the only villain in the game of propping up palpable falsehoods in the field of medieval Indian history. For quite some time, the All India Radio has been presenting a programme in Hindi - &lt;em&gt;Itihāsa Ke Jharokhe Se&lt;/em&gt; (Window on History). The refrain is that medieval India under Muslim rule was a period of peace and amity between Hindus and Muslims, and that Muslim rulers, particularly Aurangzeb, went out of their way to be kind and considerate to the Hindus. The insinuation is that the Hindu-Muslim strife was a creation of the British imperialists whose “nefarious game” is now being continued by “Hindu communalists”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 CHAPTER VIII THE MYTH OF MUSLIM EMPIRE IN INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/08_ch8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/08_ch8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER VIII&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-myth-of-muslim-empire-in-india&#34;&gt;THE MYTH OF MUSLIM EMPIRE IN INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The apologists of Islam and their secularist lick-spittles argue that if the Muslim conquerors had practised such systematic, extensive, and continued terror against Hindus and Hinduism as has been recorded by the Muslim historians of medieval India, Hindus could not have survived as an overwhelming majority at the end of the long spell of Muslim rule.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The logic here is purely deductive (formal). Suppose a person is subjected to a murderous assault, but he survives because he fights back. Deductively it can be concluded that the person never suffered a murderous assault because otherwise he could not have been alive! But this conclusion has little relevance to the facts of the case.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 CHAPTER IX THE DETERMINANTS OF HINDU DEFEATS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/09_ch9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/09_ch9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;**CHAPTER IX **&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-determinants-of-hindu-defeats&#34;&gt;THE DETERMINANTS OF HINDU DEFEATS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is true that Hindus resisted Islamic imperialism for a long time, and overcame it in the long run. But it would be foolish to forget that their failure for a long time in the face of an enemy with whom they had become familiar pretty soon, was of frightening proportions. It is this failure of the Hindus and not the defeat of the Muslim marauders which invites a serious review and reflection. I will, therefore, do my own loud thinking on this subject. For I feel very strongly that the lessons we may learn from these failures are still valid for us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 CHAPTER X THE STATUS OF HINDUS IN AN ISLAMIC STATE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/10_ch10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/10_ch10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER X&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-status-of-hindus-in-an-islamic-state&#34;&gt;THE STATUS OF HINDUS IN AN ISLAMIC STATE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now I can take up the next NCERT guideline, namely, that historians cannot identify Muslims as rulers and Hindus as subjects, and that the state in medieval India under Muslim rule cannot be described as a theocracy without examining the role of religion in political conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I will take up the second half of this guideline first.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The modern apologists of Islam have been trying to rescue this “religion” from its macabre record as presented by the medieval Muslim historians.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Firstly, they accuse the medieval historians of gross exaggeration.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Secondly, they blame the Turks for barbarities committed in the name of Islam.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The third pillar of this apologetics is to present as politically motivated the dismal deeds which the medieval historians regarded as religiously inspired.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 CHAPTER XI OF ASSIMILATION AND SYNTHESIS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/11_ch11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/11_ch11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER XI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;of-assimilation-and-synthesis&#34;&gt;OF ASSIMILATION AND SYNTHESIS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another major NCERT guideline regarding writing of medieval Indian history is that “neglect and omission of trends and processes of assimilation and synthesis, and growth of a composite culture” is “prejudicial to national integration”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The right hand does not know what the left hand has done. First, we are told not to treat the Islamic invaders as foreigners. Next, we are asked not to neglect trends and processes of assimilation and synthesis. One may very well ask: If the Islamic invaders were not foreigners, who was getting assimilated by whom? If the culture which these invaders brought with them was not alien, what was getting synthesised with what? And where is the need for inventing and sponsoring a composite culture, unless the Islamic culture is found to be working at cross purposes with the indigenous Hindu culture?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 CHAPTER XII ISLAM VERSUS INSÃNIYAT (HUMANISM)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/12_ch12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/12_ch12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER XII&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;islam-versus-insāniyat-humanism&#34;&gt;ISLAM VERSUS INSĀNIYAT (HUMANISM)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few friends had expressed misgivings about my starting upon this series on the basis of a report in the Indian Express. They were apprehensive that in the process I may have been unfair to the NCERT.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A journalist friend has now kindly given me an authentic copy of&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Guidelines And Tools For Evaluating School Text-books From the&#xA;Standpoint of National Integration&lt;/em&gt;. I have studied the mimeographed document and compared it carefully with the report in the &lt;em&gt;Indian Express&lt;/em&gt;. I find that Mrs. Coomi Kapoor’s reporting of the official position was fully faithful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 APPENDIX</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/13_app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/islamic_imperialism_india/13_app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;APPENDIX&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(These articles appeared in the weekly &lt;em&gt;Organiser&lt;/em&gt; and invited some&#xA;comments from the readers, particularly Dr. K.K. Mittal with whom I developed almost a debate spread over several issues of the weekly. I discovered that Dr. Mittal had equated Islam with Urdu poetry with which he happened to be in love. The following questions from Sindhu, the pseudonym used by the editor, Shri K.R. Malkani, and the answers I gave are relevant to this book.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
