<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;4 South India 1981–2011 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/4_South_India_19812011/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;4 South India 1981–2011 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/4_South_India_19812011/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1994; August 15: Hubli (Karnataka)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/4_South_India_19812011/1994_August_15_Hubli_Karnataka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/4_South_India_19812011/1994_August_15_Hubli_Karnataka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;69% Hindus, 26% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Karnataka: M. Veerappa Moily, Congress Party, November 1992–December 1994&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Violence erupted on Independence Day in Hubli (Karnataka). The town had suffered from communal tensions for quite some time over the Idgah Maidan, a piece of open land held by the Anjuman-e-Islam (AEI), a Muslim organization. The Hubli municipality had leased out the area to the AEI in 1921 so that Muslims could have a place to hold prayers twice a year. Troubles cropped up in the 1960s when the AEI built a commercial complex on the land. In 1992, echoing the hoisting of the national flag by BJP President &lt;a href=&#34;murli-manohar-joshi.html&#34;&gt;Murli Manohar Joshi&lt;/a&gt; in Srinagar (Kashmir), the Hubli&amp;rsquo;s BJP unit attempted to hoist the national flag on the Idgah Maidan, thereby provoking the indignation of the AEI. BJP attempts were successfully countered by the state administration till 1994. On August 15, 1994, two BJP leaders, &lt;a href=&#34;sikander-bakht.html&#34;&gt;Sikander Bakht&lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href=&#34;uma-bharti.html&#34;&gt;Uma Bharti&lt;/a&gt;, joined the flag-hoisting campaign in Hubli on the Idgah Maidan. They were arrested by police, angering a crowd of BJP activists. The police resisted and opened fire, killing six people. This riot remains a symbol of the communalization of the South of India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1994; October 6–8: Bangalore (Karnataka)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/4_South_India_19812011/1994_October_68_Bangalore_Karnataka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/4_South_India_19812011/1994_October_68_Bangalore_Karnataka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;76% Hindus, 16% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Karnataka: M. Veerappa Moily, Congress Party, November 1992–December 1994&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Violence erupted in the city of Bangalore (Karnataka) after the broadcasting in Urdu of a Doordarshan (television) program on October 2, from 7:45 to 7:55 p.m., just after the Kannada newscast (Karnataka&amp;rsquo;s dominant language). On October 3, a three-hundred-strong mob of pro-Kannada organizations gathered to protest in front of Bangalore&amp;rsquo;s Doordarshan office. Over the following two days, many protest marches were held in the city and inflammatory speeches were delivered. On October 6, the linguistic agitation took a communal turn with the involvement of Hindu communal organizations-such as the ABVP-which damaged buses and official vehicles. On October 7, a Friday, a protest procession passed through a predominantly Muslim area shouting anti-Muslim slogans near a mosque where prayers were being said. Violence spread to the city. Sixty-three Muslim houses were destroyed. People died in the mob violence, shooting by police, and in stabbing incidents. The riot claimed 25 lives according to official sources, while unofficial estimates put the death toll at 40, and, on occasion, as high as 100. On October 8, the Urdu news bulletin was suspended, but the violence continued, leading to the stabbing deaths of seven persons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1997; November 29–December 1; 1998; February 14: Coimbatore (Tamil Nadu)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/4_South_India_19812011/1997_November_29December_1_1998_February_14_Coimbatore_Tamil_Nadu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/4_South_India_19812011/1997_November_29December_1_1998_February_14_Coimbatore_Tamil_Nadu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;84% Hindus, 8% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Tamil Nadu: K. M. Karunanidhi, Dravida Munnetra Kazhagam (DMK), May 1996–May 2001&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Communal violence flared up in the city of Coimbatore (Tamil Nadu). Tensions had increased between the Hindu and Muslim communities over the recent successes of Muslim businessmen in the town. The Hindu Munnani (an organization formed to defend the Hindu religion) leader, Rama Gopalan, had come to Coimbatore several times, asking Hindus to purchase only from Hindu shops. Moreover, relations between the police and the Muslim community had seriously deteriorated after the bombing of the RSS office in Madras in 1993: looking for members of the Al-Umma, an organization formed by S. A. Basha after the demolition of the Babri Masjid and which was suspected of being behind the blasts, the police raided Muslim localities, and they had arrested many Muslim youths in recent years. Several check posts were set up around the Muslim-dominated area of Kottaimedu, angering local residents. Muslim traders were also irritated by the daily collection by the police of a mamool (illegal levy) from each shop. Muslims had become organized through various organizations (Al-Umma; AIUTC–All India Trade Union Congress –, and TMMK - Tamil Nadu Muslim Munnetra Kazhagam), which were involved in a permanent conflict with the police.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
