<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3 CHANGE AND ASSIMILATION on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3 CHANGE AND ASSIMILATION on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>21 THE WAY OF ALL FEASTS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/21_THE_WAY_OF_ALL_FEASTS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/21_THE_WAY_OF_ALL_FEASTS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Il serait bien difficile de faire cesser les anciennes coutumes; il faut laisser au peuple quelque sorte de divertissements qui contribuent beaucoup à leur faire oublier leurs peines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-LIEUTENANT DU ROI EN LANGUEDOC&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mais quelqu&amp;rsquo;un troubla la fête&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LA FONTAINE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WE HAVE SURVEYED the agencies of change at work. Now it is time to look at some direct effects of their conjunction. Since we have just left the realm of religion, as good a place as any to start is with a related one-that of feasts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 CHARIVARIS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/22_CHARIVARIS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/22_CHARIVARIS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ainsi donc le charivari, qui primitivement était un châtiment infligé spontanément par le peuple à ceux dont le mariage blessait les usages reçus et constituait un défi à la morale publique, est devenu un amusement pour les villages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-HENRI LALOU&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MANY MAY MOURN the passing of traditional celebrations like Carnival. But few today, and possibly few people of the time, would want to shed a tear for a more somber aspect of Carnival that we have only hinted at so far: the ridicule and punishment of those who had contravened the rules of village society. Social censorship of this order was another thing that modern society could and would dispense with. The state had laws, police, gendarmes, magistrates. There was no need for, and eventually no room for, unofficial justiciaries to visit society&amp;rsquo;s wrath on those who &amp;ldquo;sinned&amp;rdquo; against it. Yet this form of rough justice endured into the twentieth century.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 MARKETS AND FAIRS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/23_MARKETS_AND_FAIRS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/23_MARKETS_AND_FAIRS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Grace is given of God, but knowledge is bought in the market.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ARTHUR HUGH CLOUGH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE EVOLUTION OF Sociability in the countryside can be studied—and it should be studied, for here we can afford only passing attention-in two other domains: that of the public marketplace, and that of the semiprivate but highly communal veillée.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Markets and fairs were major cogs in the wheels of the old economy, turntables of essential exchanges, mostly within a limited local context. Markets were frequent, at least weekly, and there one sold and bought items of everyday necessity for the most part food. Fairs were periodic and offered a wider choice of goods-apparel, cattle, tools, and household utensils—as well as entertainment. All rural societies included fairly large numbers of landless peasants and varying numbers of artisans or forest folk, or both, who had to buy some or all of their food, albeit from their neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 VEILLEES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/24_VEILLEES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/24_VEILLEES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Après le souper, on veille encore une heure ou deux en teillant du chanvre, chacun dit sa chanson à son tour.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-JEAN-JACQUES ROUSSEAU&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Veillée, n.f. Time from supper to bedtime, evening (in company); sitting up to work, etc. in company.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-CASSELL&amp;rsquo;S FRENCH-ENGLISH DICTIONARY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THROUGHOUT MOST OF rural France the winter evenings were long and cold and lonely. Fires had to be husbanded; candles and rushlights too. Everything cost too much. Adequate heat and light were almost unthinkable. During the frigid winter months in Mâconnais women, when they had finished their housework, went into the stables for the veillées du jour. The men would join them there, and the midday meal was often taken in the stable because the house was too cold. The evening meal necessitated a fire, but where fuel was short, people made the briefest possible use of the fire. So after the soupe they hastened to curl up in a pallet, in the dark, sharing the animal heat of one or several neighbors, presumably asleep; or took refuge in the stable; or repaired to any other place where they could find a little warmth. In places like Treigny in Yonne, where pottery was the main industry, most of the local people warmed themselves in winter by the heat of the kilns and &amp;ldquo;thus dispensed with making fires at home.&amp;rdquo; The justice of the peace in 1852 reported considerable crowds “à la veillée&amp;quot; every evening. In parts of Marne veillées were held in wine cellars, which being of chalk kept in the warmth. Artisans who worked late into the night, perhaps because of different tasks during the daytime, needed a light, as carpenters and shoemakers did. Around them there might form a chatting circle, which sometimes turned into a chambrée. But most evening gatherings were to be found in barns or sheepfolds or stables, where the warmth of animals was more important than the sharp odors of manure.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 THE ORAL WISDOM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/25_THE_ORAL_WISDOM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/25_THE_ORAL_WISDOM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the beginning was the Word.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-JOHN I:I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WITH THE PASSING of the veillées there died one of the great institutions for the transmission of knowledge acquired by word of mouth. In the veillées there had been much talk, the voicing of personal memories, the recitation of tales, saws, and witty sayings. The degree to which this went on seems to have varied from region to region. Peasants in general do not appear to have been very articulate. But whether they tended to be taciturn and sober, as in the Landes or Beauce, or expansive and ebullient, as in Languedoc, peasants everywhere relied heavily in their everyday speech on an established fund of locutions that could take the place of general ideas. Like old Père Martin in Ernest Lavisse&amp;rsquo;s widely used elementary school text, L&amp;rsquo;Année préparatoire d&amp;rsquo;instruction morale, the peasants talked largely in proverbs, dictons, common sayings-ready-made expressions of wisdom or comment. Proverbs, wrote Père Gorse, &amp;ldquo;there&amp;rsquo;s the peasant&amp;rsquo;s creed, the learning he has ripened and assimilated to the innermost recesses of his soul&amp;hellip;. All his thought is in them, and beyond that he thinks no more.&amp;rdquo; We should do well to heed this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 FLED IS THAT MUSIC</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/26_FLED_IS_THAT_MUSIC/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/26_FLED_IS_THAT_MUSIC/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Adieu! Adieu! thy plaintive anthem fades Past the near meadows, over the still stream, Up the hill-side; and now &amp;rsquo;tis buried deep In the next valley-glades:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was it a vision, or a waking dream? Fled is that music:-Do I wake or sleep?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-KEATS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AT A TIME WHEN light was bad, occasions for entertainment few, public performances outside church or fair strictly limited, music-homemade-and dance played a crucial role in the peasant&amp;rsquo;s life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 LE PAPIER QUI PARLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/27_LE_PAPIER_QUI_PARLE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/27_LE_PAPIER_QUI_PARLE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love a ballad in print, a-life, for then we are sure they are true.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-SHAKESPEARE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WE COME NOW to an obvious question affecting popular culture, and one of the most difficult, despite the attention it has received: when and how reading matter affected the common man. The printing press stands at the entrance of the modern world as dragons guard the gateway of a temple. But who, in nineteenth-century France, had access to the temple of the printing press? The answer is, surprisingly many people, for one need not read to enjoy its products. Yet printing was an urban art par excellence; it disseminated texts, images, ideas, that had been formulated by urban minds. Like printed songs, these often became popular in terms of their acceptance. They were not necessarily so by birth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 WRING OUT THE OLD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/28_WRING_OUT_THE_OLD/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/28_WRING_OUT_THE_OLD/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ring out the old, ring in the new, Ring happy bells, across the snow!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The year is going, let him go;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ring out the false, ring in the true.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TENNYSON&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You are old, Father William,&amp;rdquo; the young man said,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And your hair has become very white;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And yet you incessantly stand on your head- Do you think, at your age, it is right?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-LEWIS CARROLL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;CONTINUITY HAS broken down,&amp;rdquo; wrote Jules Méline about the changing world around him. &amp;ldquo;No longer an evolution, it is a true revolution that is taking place and that pursues its way.&amp;rdquo; Looking back at those years, the folklorist André Varagnac claimed that France in the last quarter of the nineteenth century underwent a veritable crise de civilisation.1 Traditional attitudes and traditional practices crumbled, but they had done so before. What mattered after 1880 was that they were not replaced by new ones spun out of the experience of local community. The decay and abandonment of words, ceremonies, and patterns of behavior were scarcely new. What was new and startling, said Varagnac, was the absence of homemade replacements: the death of tradition itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 CULTURES AND CIVILIZATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/29_CULTURES_AND_CIVILIZATION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/3_CHANGE_ASSIMILATION/29_CULTURES_AND_CIVILIZATION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every countryman who has learned to read renounces the countryside in his heart.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JOSEPH ROUX&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The colonist only ends his work of breaking in the native when. the latter admits loud and clear the supremacy of the white man&amp;rsquo;s values.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-FRANTZ FANON&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE FAMOUS hexagon can itself be seen as a colonial empire shaped over the centuries: a complex of territories conquered, annexed, and integrated in a political and administrative whole, many of them with strongly developed national or regional personalities, some of them with traditions that were specifically unor anti-French. A partial roll call serves as a reminder: in the thirteenth century, Languedoc and parts of the center; in the fifteenth, Aquitaine and Provence; in the sixteenth, Brittany; in the seventeenth, Navarre, Béarn, Pays Basque, Roussillon and Cerdagne, parts of Alsace and French Flanders, Franche-Comté; in the eighteenth, the Duchy of Lorraine, Corsica, the papal Comtat-Venaissin; in the nineteenth, Savoy and Nice.1 By 1870 this had produced a political entity called France-kingdom or empire or republic—an entity formed by conquest and by political or administrative decisions formulated in (or near) Paris. The modern view of the nation as a body of people united according to their own will and having certain attributes in common (not least history) was at best dubiously applicable to the France of 1870.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
