<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;1 HISTORICAL on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/1_HISTORICAL/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;1 HISTORICAL on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/1_HISTORICAL/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 LIFE OF ABHINAVAGUPTA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/1_HISTORICAL/1_LIFE_OF_ABHINAVAGUPTA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/1_HISTORICAL/1_LIFE_OF_ABHINAVAGUPTA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PRELIMINARY.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abhinava, it appears, knew the importance of biographical information about a writer in understanding his works. He has, therefore, not remained silent about himself, like Kālidāsa, about whose date scholars differ by centuries, or like Bhāsa, whose very authorship of his own dramas is now a matter of keen controversy. He has given a sketch, though very brief, of his person, descent and the then social conditions in the concluding portions of his two works, the Tantraloka and the Parātrimśikā Vivarana.+++(5)+++ This sketch, when coupled with the information gathered from the stray references to his life in the vast literature that he, his pupils, his commentators and the followers of his theories have produced, gives us a more or less connected and a little detailed, though still incomplete, account of his life. It can be fairly completed but only with the help of an oral tradition which is current down to this day in a few learned Brāhmana families as well as in a few muslim homes in Kashmir. But an oral tradition, though old and persistent, is after all an oral tradition, and as such cannot have the same value in the eyes of a historian as the evidence of inscriptions or literary works. However, in the case of Abhinava, it is possible for us to know exactly the forces and influences which produced such a mind, even if we confine ourselves to well-authenticated facts. For the purpose of understanding his writings we need no more,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 HIS WORKS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/1_HISTORICAL/2_HIS_WORKS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/1_HISTORICAL/2_HIS_WORKS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER II.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HIS WORKS.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LIST OF HIS KNOWN WORKS. 1. Bodha Pancadasikā. 2. Mālini Vijaya Vārtika. V 3. Parātrimśikā Vivrti. 4. Tantraloka. 5. Tantrasāra. 6. Tantravagadhānikā. 7. Dhvanyāloka Locana. 8. Abhinava Bhārati.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;9&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bhagavadgitārtha Sangraha. 10. Paramārtha Sāra. 11. Isvara Pratyabhijñā Vimarsini. 12. Isvara Pratyabhijñā Vivrti Vimarsini. - 13. Krama Stotra, tule available combi lobortis 14. Dehastha Devata Cakra Stotra. 15. Bhairava Stotra. V gone of the lies 16. Paramārtha Dvādasikā. 17. Paramārtha Carcā. 18. Mahopadeśa Vimsatik a. 19. Anuttarāṣtikā. 20. Anubhavanivedana. 21. Tant roccaya. 22. Ghatakarparakulaka Vivrti. 23. Karmakeli. 24. śivadrstyālocana. 25. Purva Pañcikā. 26. Padārthapraveśa Nirnaya ṭikā. 27. Prakīrṇaka Vivarana. 28. Prakarana Vivarana. 29. Kāvyakautuka Vivarana.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ont of the two coulbution to to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 HISTORICAL BACKGROUND OF HIS THOUGHT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/1_HISTORICAL/3_HISTORICAL_BACKGROUND_OF_HIS_THOUGHT/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/1_HISTORICAL/3_HISTORICAL_BACKGROUND_OF_HIS_THOUGHT/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;3 HISTORICAL BACKGROUND OF HIS THOUGHT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the last chapter we have divided the literary activity of Abhinava into three periods and have placed the Tantric period first of all. In this chapter we propose to trace the historical background of his Tantric, philosophic and alankārika thoughts. We may state at the very outset that our subject being &amp;ldquo;A Study of Abhinavagupta&amp;rdquo;, we do not mean to follow the traditional method of tracing the origin of the three subjects, on which he worked, to some ideas found in the Vedas and their development through the later literature till they got the respective names by which they are now known. We shall strictly confine ourselves to stating what idea of their history we get from the writings of Abhinava himself, and of his immediate predecessors, to whom he often refers, to enable the reader to picture to himself the stages in the development of these ideas at which Abhinava took them up and the modifications which he introduced into them. We may further add that certain statements in the following pages will appear more mythical than historical, particularly in the part, dealing with the history of the Tantric literature. But they have been given a place here, partly to let the reader know the orthodox belief in its high antiquity and partly for a grain of historical truth that we find therein.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 HIS IMPORTANCE AND INFLUENCE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/1_HISTORICAL/4_HIS_IMPORTANCE_AND_INFLUENCE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/agastyaH/articles/Abhinavagupta-An-Historical-and-Philosophical-Study-K-C-Pandey/1_HISTORICAL/4_HIS_IMPORTANCE_AND_INFLUENCE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;4 HIS IMPORTANCE AND INFLUENCE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the preceding chapter we have tried to trace the historical background of Abhinava&amp;rsquo;s tantric, poetic and philosophic thoughts to give a clear idea of the material on which he worked and of the advance that his thoughts present on those of his predecessors. In this chapter we propose to deal with some of the important writers, who succeeded him, to show his importance in the eyes of the later generations and to indicate how far he influenced the ideas of the future writers and how his work was carried on by his immediate successors. We, therefore, for the sake of convenience, divide the writers on whom we have to speak here into two classes :&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
