<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;18 Roman LawI 146 B C - A D 192 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/18_Roman_LawI_146_B_C_-_A_D_192/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;18 Roman LawI 146 B C - A D 192 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/18_Roman_LawI_146_B_C_-_A_D_192/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 THE GREAT JURISTS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/18_Roman_LawI_146_B_C_-_A_D_192/01_THE_GREAT_JURISTS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/18_Roman_LawI_146_B_C_-_A_D_192/01_THE_GREAT_JURISTS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LAW was the most characteristic and lasting expression of the Roman spirit. As Greece stands in history for freedom, so Rome stands for order; and as Greece bequeathed democracy and philosophy as the foundations of individual liberty, so Rome has left us its laws, and its traditions of administration, as the bases of social order. To unite these diverse legacies, to attune their stimulating opposition into harmony, is the elemental task of statesmanship.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 THE SOURCES OF THE LAW</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/18_Roman_LawI_146_B_C_-_A_D_192/02_THE_SOURCES_OF_THE_LAW/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/18_Roman_LawI_146_B_C_-_A_D_192/02_THE_SOURCES_OF_THE_LAW/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the terminology of science and philosophy comes mostly from the Greek, betraying their source, so the language of the law comes mostly from the Latin. Law in general was &lt;em&gt;ius,&lt;/em&gt; justice or right; &lt;em&gt;lex&lt;/em&gt; meant a specific law.II Jurisprudence—wisdom in the law—was defined in the &lt;em&gt;Digest&lt;/em&gt; of Justinian (A.D. 533) as both a science and an art: the “science of the just and the unjust,” and the “art [i.e., administration] of the good and the equitable.”2 &lt;em&gt;lus&lt;/em&gt; included unwritten law, or custom, as well as written law. The latter was composed of &lt;em&gt;ius civile&lt;/em&gt;—the “law of [Roman] citizens”—and &lt;em&gt;ius gentium—“the&lt;/em&gt; law of the nations.” Civil law was “public law” when it related to the state or the official worship, and “private law” when it dealt with the legal interrelations of the citizens.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 THE LAW OF PERSONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/18_Roman_LawI_146_B_C_-_A_D_192/03_THE_LAW_OF_PERSONS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/18_Roman_LawI_146_B_C_-_A_D_192/03_THE_LAW_OF_PERSONS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“All law,” says the precise Gaius, “pertains to persons, to property, or to procedure.”3 The word &lt;em&gt;persona&lt;/em&gt; had signified an actor’s mask; later it was applied to the part played by a man in life; finally it came to mean the man himself—as if to say that we can never know a man, but only the parts he plays, the mask or masks that he wears.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first person in Roman law was the citizen. He was defined as anyone who had been accepted into a Roman tribe by birth, adoption, emancipation, or governmental grant. Within this franchise were three grades: (1) full citizens, who enjoyed the fourfold right of voting &lt;em&gt;(ius suffragii),&lt;/em&gt; of holding office &lt;em&gt;(ius honorum),&lt;/em&gt; of marriage with a freeborn person &lt;em&gt;(ius connubii),&lt;/em&gt; and of engaging in commercial contracts protected by Roman law &lt;em&gt;(ius commercii);&lt;/em&gt; (2) “citizens without suffrage,” who had the rights of marriage and contract, but not of voting or office; and (3) freedmen, who had the rights of voting and contract, but not of marriage or office. The full citizen had, furthermore, certain exclusive rights in private law: the power of the father over his children &lt;em&gt;(patria potestas),&lt;/em&gt; of the husband over his wife &lt;em&gt;(manus),&lt;/em&gt; of an owner over his property, including his slaves &lt;em&gt;(dominium),&lt;/em&gt; and of a freeman over another by contract &lt;em&gt;(mancipium).&lt;/em&gt; A kind of potential citizenship, called &lt;em&gt;Latinitas&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;ius Latii,&lt;/em&gt; was conferred by Rome upon the free inhabitants of favored towns and colonies, whereby they acquired the right of contract, but not of intermarriage, with Romans, and their magistrates received full Roman citizenship upon completing their terms of office. Each city of the Empire had its own citizens and conditions of citizenship; and by a unique tolerance a man might be a citizen—and enjoy the civic rights—of several cities at once. The most precious privilege of a Roman citizen was the safeguarding of his person, property, and rights by the law, and his immunity from torture or violence in the trying of his case. It was the glory of Roman law that it protected the individual against the state.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 THE LAW OF PROPERTY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/18_Roman_LawI_146_B_C_-_A_D_192/04_THE_LAW_OF_PROPERTY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/18_Roman_LawI_146_B_C_-_A_D_192/04_THE_LAW_OF_PROPERTY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Problems of ownership, obligation, exchange, contract, and debt took up by far the largest part of Roman law. Material possession was the very life of Rome, and the increase of wealth and the expansion of trade demanded a body of law immeasurably more complex than the simple code of the Decemvirs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ownership &lt;em&gt;(dominium)&lt;/em&gt; came by inheritance or acquisition. Since the father owned as agent and trustee of the family, the children and grandchildren were potential owners—&lt;em&gt;sui heredes&lt;/em&gt; in the law’s queer phrase—“their own heirs.”23 If the father died intestate they succeeded automatically to the family property, and the oldest father among the sons inherited the &lt;em&gt;dominium.&lt;/em&gt; The making of valid wills was hedged about with hundreds of legal restrictions, and their composition required, as now, a gorgeous and sonorous tautology. Every testator was compelled to leave a specified portion of his estate to his children, another part to a wife who had borne him three children, and (in some cases) parts to his brothers, sisters, and ascendants. No heir might take any part of an estate without assuming all the debts and other legal obligations of the deceased; not infrequently a Roman found himself saddled with a &lt;em&gt;damnosa hereditas—a&lt;/em&gt; legacy, so to speak, in the red. Where an owner died without children and without a will, his property and his debts passed automatically to the nearest “agnate,” or relative descended from a common ancestor exclusively through males. In the later Empire this male conceit abated, and by the time of Justinian agnates and cognates (relatives through male or female lines of ascent) inherited with equal right. An old law passed on the urging of Cato (169 B.C.) had forbidden any Roman who owned 100,000 sesterces ($15,000) or more to bequeath any part of his estate to a woman. This &lt;em&gt;lex Voconia&lt;/em&gt; was still on the statute books in Gaius’ time, but love had found a way. The testator left property on trust &lt;em&gt;(fideicommissum)&lt;/em&gt; to a qualified heir, and bound him by a solemn request to transfer the property before a stated date to the woman named. By this and other channels much of the wealth of Rome passed into the hands of women. Gifts offered another escape from testamentary law; but gifts made in prospect of death were subject to legal scrutiny, and under Justinian they were liable to the same laws as those that harassed legacies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 THE LAW OF PROCEDURE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/18_Roman_LawI_146_B_C_-_A_D_192/05_THE_LAW_OF_PROCEDURE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/18_Roman_LawI_146_B_C_-_A_D_192/05_THE_LAW_OF_PROCEDURE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Of all ancient peoples the Romans were the most prone to litigation, despite the discouraging complexity, technicality, and confusing fictions of their procedural law. Doubtless our own legal actions would have seemed to them equally devious and prolonged. The older the civilization, the longer the lawsuits. Any man, as noted above, could make himself a prosecutor in a Roman court. In the patrician Republic the accuser, the defendant, and the magistrate were required to follow a form called &lt;em&gt;legis actio,&lt;/em&gt; or process of law, and the slightest deviation invalidated the action. “Thus,” says Gaius, “a man who sued another for cutting his vines, and in his action called them Vines,’ lost his case because he should have called them ‘trees,’ since the Twelve Tables speak generally of ‘trees’, and not particularly of vines.”27 Each party deposited with the magistrate a sum of money &lt;em&gt;(sacra-mentum),&lt;/em&gt; which was forfeited by the losing party to the state religion. The defendant also had to give bail &lt;em&gt;(vadimonium)&lt;/em&gt; as security for his subsequent appearances. The magistrate then turned over the dispute to a person on the list of those qualified to act as judges. In some cases the judge issued an interim &lt;em&gt;inter-dictum,&lt;/em&gt; requiring one or more of the parties in the case to perform or refrain from certain actions. If the defendant lost, his property—sometimes his person—could be seized by the plaintiff until the judgment was satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 THE LAW OF THE NATIONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/18_Roman_LawI_146_B_C_-_A_D_192/06_THE_LAW_OF_THE_NATIONS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/18_Roman_LawI_146_B_C_-_A_D_192/06_THE_LAW_OF_THE_NATIONS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most difficult problem of Roman law was to adjust itself as an intelligent master to the varied codes and customs of the lands that Roman arms or diplomacy had won. Many of these states were older than Rome; what they had lost in military courage they made up in proud traditions and a jealous fondness for their peculiar ways. Rome met the situation ably. A &lt;em&gt;praetor peregrinus&lt;/em&gt; was appointed at first for the foreigners in Rome, then for Italy, then for the provinces; and power was given him to make some viable union between Roman and local law. The annual edicts of this praetor and the provincial governors and aediles gradually created the &lt;em&gt;ius gentium&lt;/em&gt; by which the Empire was ruled.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
