<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Learning on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Learning on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lectures</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/learning/lectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/learning/lectures/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty An acquired skill: Learning to get information out of research seminars is an acquired skill, usually acquired much later than the skill of reading mathematics.
Approximation of private tuition The purpose of attending a lecture is to learn from the lecturer’s insights, opinions and ways of solving problems. Private tuition is far better than a lecture. But lecture exists due to lack of sufficient number of tutors. If you cannot follow what is going on, and if it is not too disruptive, ask.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/learning/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/learning/news/</guid>
      <description>Content type This could be research news, news from friends through social media, newspapers etc..
They often tend to be short messages leading to other links. Sometimes, they are followed by discussions.
Research news Besides internet journals and pre-print collections, twitter feeds and blogs of researchers tend to be a very good source of research news.
Lectures and course-notes are considered separately.
Curation of articles and comments News can be chosen, curated, arranged and presented either by a small group of professional editors (Eg: BBC, Time, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/learning/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/learning/notes/</guid>
      <description>Desiderata  Easy to navigate to topic of interests (on a variety of devices) Highlights a summary (सूत्रमन्त्रादिरूपेण) decision for execution, separate from exploratory notes. Highlights evocatively core ideas and wonders. Tight focus on essence - Learning involves repeated summarization.  In math - Record important patterns of ideas and solution strategies, with examples/ counter-examples and important results.   Builds complex ideas based on clear simple ideas. Easy to update, refactor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/learning/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/learning/reading/</guid>
      <description>Purpose  Enjoyment Learn ideas and skills.  Choosing what to read Whatever the purpose, some works are more suitable than others. Recommendations of connoiseurs are paramount.
General knowledge News is described elsewhere.
Course-notes posted on the websites of university instructors and encyclopedias like the wikipedia are very useful in getting some good knowledge.
Research papers Theses are often more detailed and friendly than journal papers. Journal papers are often better written than conference papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/learning/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/learning/testing/</guid>
      <description>Signs of understanding Ability to reduce everything to elementary school mathematics signifies true understanding.
Ability to solve textbook problems is another important sign.
Reconstruction ability One must be able to reconstruct important knowledge acquired so far, relevant to the subject being studied, from scratch. This must be done with minimal external reference, and with the power of one’s memory and abilities. This is helpful in preparing the mind for studies and in solidifying knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>