<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Car on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/motion/vehicle/car/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Car on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/motion/vehicle/car/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Buying</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/motion/vehicle/car/buying/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/motion/vehicle/car/buying/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;identifying-target&#34;&gt;Identifying target&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;target-identification&#34;&gt;Target identification&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;about-usage&#34;&gt;About usage&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;used-vs-new&#34;&gt;Used vs new&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Used cars, even those that are only one year old, are 20 to 30 percent cheaper than new cars. You&amp;rsquo;ll save money on insurance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most new cars are sold with a three-year/36,000-mile warranty. Therefore, if you buy a car that is from one to three years old, with less than 36,000 miles on the odometer, it will still be under the factory warranty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insurance</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/motion/vehicle/car/insurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/motion/vehicle/car/insurance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Can add or remove comprehensive coverage depending on evaluation of risk during journey.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Non-commuter / pleasure cars merit lower insurance rates - especially because they travel fewer miles. Negotiation should be tried.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;insurance-coverage&#34;&gt;Insurance coverage&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;permissive-use&#34;&gt;Permissive use&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Insurance coverage travels with an automobile and not the driver. Therefore, it is irrelevant who was driving an automobile. Anyone you permit to use your car is covered.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It won&amp;rsquo;t apply if you loan it for work/ commercial use. It won&amp;rsquo;t apply to drivers living with you who are explicitly removed from car usage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/motion/vehicle/car/maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/motion/vehicle/car/maintenance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;oil-change&#34;&gt;Oil change&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;oil-change-intervals&#34;&gt;Oil change intervals&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 3000 mile oil change interval had a scientific basis when engines used non-multi-weight, non-detergent oil. There are still vehicles that need 3K oil changes, but it&amp;rsquo;s not because the oil goes bad after 3K miles Eg: Saturn SK.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dark oil does not indicate the need for an oil change. The way modern detergent motor oil works is that minute particles of soot are suspended in the oil. These minute particles pose no danger to your engine, but they cause the oil to darken. A non-detergent oil would stay clearer. If you never changed your oil, eventually the oil would no longer be able to suspend any more particles in the oil and sludge would form. Fortunately, by following the manufacturer&amp;rsquo;s recommended oil change interval, you are changing your oil long before the oil has become saturated. The only real way to determine whether oil is truly in need of changing is to have an oil analysis performed. it&amp;rsquo;s acceptable to err heavily on the safe side and simply follow the manufacturer&amp;rsquo;s recommended change interval for severe service. [Ref]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
