<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/polynesian/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/polynesian/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>America contact</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/polynesian/articles/america-contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/polynesian/articles/america-contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1450149337741283337&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1450149337741283337&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Polynesia and America - a thread.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of all the daring deeds in the history of Man, few can rival the great voyages of the Polynesians. From their origins in the west, they spread north, south, and east, ever east. Yet what of the furthest east? Were the Americas a sea too far?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The origin of the Polynesians is a mystery that has long perplexed anthropologists. From vagrant Indo-Aryans to castaway Amerindians, it is the latter idea, through the exploits of Thor Heyerdahl, that has captivated the world. Genetics, however, are less kind than the public. Today, we know beyond doubt that the Polynesians came, not from the Americas, but from Asia - almost certainly what is now Taiwan, and before that, the south Chinese coast.Yet just because the Polynesians did not come &lt;em&gt;from&lt;/em&gt; America, does not mean they did not go &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Easter island deforestation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/polynesian/articles/easter-island-deforestation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/polynesian/articles/easter-island-deforestation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Consequences of Deforestation on Easter Island&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Historical Consequences of Deforestation: Easter Island (Diamond 1995)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The history of Easter Island, its statues and its peoples, has long been shrouded in mystery. Some have suggested that aliens marooned on earth planted the statues as signals to their fellow aliens to rescue them. Others have said that the statues were constructed by a great race of guilders that were stranded on the island and built them before being rescued. Still others are convinced that an ancient society with the capability of flight constructed them along with the Nazca lines in Peru. However new evidence based on pollen analysis supports a much simpler theory, that the Easter Island inhabitants destroyed their own society through deforestation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maori Pa forts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/polynesian/articles/maori-pa-forts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/austronesian/polynesian/articles/maori-pa-forts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source-  &lt;a href=&#34;https://threads-web.vercel.app/threads/1451912957860909058&#34;&gt;https://threads-web.vercel.app/threads/1451912957860909058&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thread concerning the development of Maori fortifications and engineering works spanning the years 1840-1869 with special attention paid to the role of projectile defense adaptations and earthen work formations to repel Her Majesty&amp;rsquo;s Armed Forces. From Ian Knight&amp;rsquo;s book, listed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Crucial from the outset was the radically different role the &amp;lsquo;pa&amp;rsquo;, the fortified village, served after the Musket Wars and now against the British. The aim was to control and hold land, frustrate settler expansion and execute specific military objectives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
