<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Moslem rebellion in France</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-11-06_the-moslem-rebellion-in-france/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-11-06_the-moslem-rebellion-in-france/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/11/06/the-moslem-rebellion-in-france/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The West often preaches solemnly to India about Moslem rioting. It is almost a given that when Moslem fraction of a population under consideration reaches 15-20% incidents of crime and abuse against Dhimmis and Kaffrs begin to surface. As the Islamists near 25-30% of the population we start to see violence emerging– there may be low intensity riots or clashes triggered by religious activities of the Non-Moslems. Of course the Western media like to give an impression that this is nothing to do with Moslems, but everything about poverty, racial discrimination and un-employment. Every non-White in the Leukosphere knows that there are incidents of racial discrimination and racial preference in social discourse. But the degree vastly varies. In the US it exists, but is not so high as to exclude non-Whites so completely that they cannot ascend the social ladder. This seems to be the case in England too, while perhaps Germany and France may be more xenophobic. In fact many types of non-Whites e.g. Hindus or pseudo-Whites, such as Chinas and Jews (in the past) have shown average to excellent performance in most of these relatively benign White states, despite sporadic instances of discrimination and violence against them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Islamism and the West</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-07-02_islamism-and-the-west/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-07-02_islamism-and-the-west/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/07/02/islamism-and-the-west/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One point to notice is that Islam, in part derives its modern strength from the West. The western commentators gleefully point out that Islam was defeated as a military force before the advent of the “modern era” by the western armies. The failure of the Turks before Vienna is oft cited as the turning point for this event. What we are not often told is that Islam was being rolled back by the Hindus too in the subcontinent. When Bajirao reached Delhi the Mogul power had ceased to be. There were of course two major Islamic incursions from central Asia- Nadir Shah and his successor Ahmed Shah, and terorrists like Tipu Sultan. But it was clear that the Hindus would have eventually cleared these Islamic pestilences had they gone ahead they way they were going.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe geopolitics</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/MT_lekhAH/europe_geopolitics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/MT_lekhAH/europe_geopolitics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nato&#34;&gt;NATO&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One key take home is that rotten-soy&amp;rsquo;s+++(=NATO&amp;rsquo;s)+++ primary function is to prevent a shUlapuruSha-rotsya alliance. We know how the rUs aided the shUlapuruSha unification as part of the revenge for the Crimean war rout they faced earlier in the century. hAdipuruSha &amp;amp; Stalin bungled that. If shUlapuruSha-s wanted to keep a spine their only hope was to form an alliance with the rotsya, pin the belligerent daNDapuruSha-s in the middle &amp;amp; constantly threaten the phira&lt;del&gt;Nga-s &amp;amp;A&lt;/del&gt;ngalika-s with their combined power. rotten-soy was put in place to prevent that from happening&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
