<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Raghunathachari</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/MT/2015-06-02_remembering-raghunathachari/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/MT/2015-06-02_remembering-raghunathachari/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2015/06/02/remembering-raghunathachari/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We do not intend to recount the biography of Chintamani Raghunathachari as it is publicly available to anyone interested in the matter. But our intention is simply to talk a little about his life and times. He lived at a time when the country was going through great tumult – 1828-1880 CE – a time when the humiliating conquest and subjugation of Bhārata by the English was completed. Raghunathachari represents an important figure in our eyes though few Indians know of him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The great chera magicians</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/MT/2005-05-29_the-great-chera-magicians/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/MT/2005-05-29_the-great-chera-magicians/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/05/29/the-great-chera-magicians/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;nambuthiris&#34;&gt;nambUthiris&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The nambUthiri brahmins of the chera country are representatives of the earliest great wave of brahminical settlers of the deep Dravida lands. In the modern Tamil country their cousins, the choliars and the dIkShitas of Chidambaram represent small pockets of this wave of the early Aryans of South India. They are all members of the pUrvashikha class of brahmins, who wear their shikha in the front, and separated from the mainstream Aryan core anywhere around 500-300 BC and proceeded southwards. In the Tamil country these brahmins have been largely overrun by the two notable later brahminical migrations: the bR^ihatcharaNa or the great sect that established itself under the pallava patronage and subsequently the various lines of vaDamas or Northerners who came in starting in the choLa period and through the Reddi and Vijayanagaran regimes. Both of whom are also seen in the Andhra and karNATa countries and are aparashikha brahmins wearing their shikha at the back of the head. Amongst the nambUthiris there were great exponents of three vedic saMhitas, shrauta sacrifices and the tantra.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pANiniH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/MT/pANiniH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/MT/pANiniH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.indica.today/long-reads/panini-xuanzang-and-tolkappiyan-some-legends-and-history/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pāṇini, Xuanzang, And Tolkāppiyaṉ: Some Legends And History&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Manasatarangini T November 10, 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pāṇini stands at the pinnacle of Hindu intellectual achievement. His sūtra-pāṭha may be considered a monument in the same league as the invention of the śūṇya-based numeral system for which the Hindus are renowned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, like several other Hindu figures of note, his life and times are the subject of divergent or contradictory narratives. To write about Pāṇini’s times would be in large part merely a rehash of Vasudeva Sharana Agrawala’s excellent monograph on the topic. Yet, we present some of the material on this matter (indeed partly just retelling what VS Agrawala has covered) for it might be of some interest to those not too well-acquainted with this topic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
