<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Kelly Kevin on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/kelly-kevin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Kelly Kevin on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/kelly-kevin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Forever book</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/kelly-kevin/forever-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/kelly-kevin/forever-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://kk.org/thetechnium/the-forever-boo/?ref=longnow.org&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Forever Book&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A key moment in cybernetics was&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Von Neumann’s attempt to figure out what the smallest possible self-reproducing machine could be (even though he never published this work).&lt;br&gt;&#xA;There were plenty of examples of large self-reproducing machines – all living creatures –&lt;br&gt;&#xA;but what was the tiniest thing that could reproduce itself?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Out of that line of inquiry came his seminal ideas of automatons,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and eventually a lot of artificial life work.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Recently biologists have begun to ask the same question:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;what is the smallest living thing we can imagine;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;how small can life get?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Out of this line of thinking exobiologists and origin of life&lt;br&gt;&#xA;researchers have experimented with the smallest possible bits of self-reproducing RNA –&lt;br&gt;&#xA;which are much smaller than what we find in the wild on earth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Library of utility</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/kelly-kevin/library_of_utility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/kelly-kevin/library_of_utility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://longnow.org/ideas/the-library-of-utility/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Library of Utility&lt;br&gt;&#xA;There is no need to wait for the Library to be built at the top of the mountain. It could be started now, in any garage. What books would you bring to it if you could?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By Kevin Kelly&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apr 25, 02011&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I imagine a library atop a remote mountain&lt;br&gt;&#xA;that collects the essential information needed to re-learn practical knowledge essential to civilization.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This depot, open to anyone who journeys there,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;is the cultural equivalent of the Svalbard seed bank,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;a vault on the Arctic Circle that holds frozen seeds of crop plants from around the world.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The utilitarian documents in this vault would be the seeds of culture,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;able to sprout again if needed.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It would be the Library of Utility, and it would serve as civilization’s backup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
