<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृत् on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृत् on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Human retroviruses,</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/2022-03-23_human-retroviruses-sociology-of-science-and-biogra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/2022-03-23_human-retroviruses-sociology-of-science-and-biogra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2022/03/23/human-retroviruses-sociology-of-science-and-biographical-ruminations/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Human retroviruses, sociology of science, and biographical ruminations&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We learnt via a recent obituary that the French researcher Luc Montagnier died a month or so ago after living for nearly 90 years. He along with his compatriot and erstwhile colleagues, Françoise Barré-Sinoussi and Jean-Claude Chermann discovered HIV-1. Subsequently, his lab also discovered HIV-2, the second virus that causes AIDS. It was around the time of the discovery of HIV-2 and the naming of the original AIDS virus as HIV-1 that we made our own first foray into studying evolution and biochemistry in the language of the genes. Soon thereafter, we realized that the study of the biochemistry of the endless war between viruses and their hosts offered some of the deepest insights into the evolutionary process after Darwin’s work. Thus, the path for our primary investigations in the coming years “crystallized” out of these early meditations. Not being an entirely autistic type of scientific enthusiast, we also started observing the sociology of science, if anything for the selfish reason of understanding better the social systems that we would become a part of due to our chosen course. We cannot say that we saw or understood things clearly in those early days, but the germs of the realization that the heroic hagiographies of science are far from the truth dawned on us then. One early introduction to this was the drawn-out conflict between the Frenchman Montagnier and his American rival Robert Gallo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Subjective and objective</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/2022-01-16_subjective-and-objective-insight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/2022-01-16_subjective-and-objective-insight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2022/01/16/subjective-and-objective-insight/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Subjective and objective insight&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The black American scientist Sylvester Gates mentioned a curious&#xA;personal anecdote in a talk. To paraphrase him, when he was in college,&#xA;he had to take a calculus course. He mentioned how he could cut through&#xA;differentiation as it was a largely mechanical process. Then came&#xA;integration, where he said he was stuck with the problems involving&#xA;multiple substitutions to arrive at the final integral. The inability to&#xA;crack difficult problems of that genre gave him a headache, and he fell&#xA;asleep. Something happened to him in his sleep that when he awoke, he&#xA;suddenly emerged with a new understanding to solve those problems, and&#xA;they no longer seemed difficult.+++(5)+++ We can completely identify with that&#xA;experience of his. However, it was not a night’s sleep that flipped the&#xA;switch in our case. We had to wait for that testosterone burst, that&#xA;elixir of masculinity, which allows males to perform great acts.+++(4)+++ We&#xA;clearly remember how, a few months before it, we struggled to derive the&#xA;equations of certain loci for which we had figured out mechanical&#xA;constructions. But, upon the passage to manhood, suddenly we found&#xA;ourselves possessed of svāyambhuva insights that allowed us to penetrate&#xA;such problems with ease — it was as if the doors to a deeper realm of&#xA;understanding had been opened. Other people have told us of similar&#xA;experiences — we recently heard from a friend how he had a phase&#xA;transition at some point in his life (overlapping with puberty), which&#xA;made him suddenly grasp a mathematical entity that had previously defied&#xA;him and led him to pursuing a degree in physics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some words on mleccha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/2021-12-26_some-words-on-mleccha-cartels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/2021-12-26_some-words-on-mleccha-cartels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2021/12/26/some-words-on-mleccha-cartels/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some words on mleccha cartels&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;context-of-the-note&#34;&gt;Context of the note&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An embedded anthropological study of social substructures is vital to&#xA;grasp some of their features that seem baffling to the outsider or the&#xA;“uninitiated” insider. Much of what we will be talking about here has&#xA;been said in some form on these pages before, and some of it will&#xA;necessarily be vague for the mleccha and his agents are still in control&#xA;of the world. Yet, we felt it is worth recording this as there is no&#xA;guarantee that the whole story can be said in plain language. If the&#xA;time does come when it can be told in such a way, then the tendency will&#xA;be to focus on the distracting specifics rather than the general&#xA;significance, and the focus will be through the lens of inter-personal&#xA;feelings rather than objectivity. Another point to note is that in the&#xA;past decade navyonmāda, whose long fuse was smoldering for decades,&#xA;finally exploded on the world scene along the lines its founders wanted.&#xA;This means that the old lenses used to view the mleccha are no longer a&#xA;perfect fit — cognizance should be taken of the deep divergences within&#xA;the mleccha world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data importance</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/data-importance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/data-importance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Who go on to be truly great scientists:IQ is one thing but the ability for detailed observational work which goes hand in hand with stepping back to see a synthetic picture that omits no detail is at the heart of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In short able to play as an true allrounder:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;that is what you see shining through in Newton&amp;rsquo;s notebooks:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;his eye for things like history, chemistry, biology things that you don&amp;rsquo;t normally associate with him&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iq tests</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/iq-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/iq-tests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1283618361465868288.html#google_vignette&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There has been some talk among American academics to do away with a gatekeeping exam called the GRE for admission to American grad-school.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;In our days that exam was in part IQ test, i&#xA;.e. the verbal+quantitative sections and partly claptrap (a 3rd part I forget).&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The 1st 2 parts was indeed reasonably correlated with people IQ&lt;br&gt;&#xA;but not the best measure of g&lt;br&gt;&#xA;as it could be gamed by those of above average&lt;br&gt;&#xA;but not spectacular IQ.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivies</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/ivies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/ivies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1736087726984659227.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Given that the American Ivies are in the news these days, many think that they have recently declined. It is true that there was a big downward plummet following the kR^iShNamukha riots organized by piNDaka’s backers to overthrow the nAri~NgapuruSha.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, those who are discerning and have interacted with Ivies for long know that even in the late 1990s-early 2000s. All of them had great science and math faculties; however, these were not in a position to fight the storm being brewed up in the fake knowledge disciplines. The said sci/math faculty could be categorized into 3 large groups in this regard:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jargon</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/jargon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/jargon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1873486900691865900&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Notation/shorthand is unavoidable because while working at the edge of knowledge one is often playing with representations that are highly intricate and often abstract. However, part of this the problem of prestige journals which do not give enough space for a well-presented explanation which would take many more words. A layman often needs that background provided by those additional words for understanding technical stuff. Finally, while English is the dominant language of scientific communication today, many of the authors, including those from English-speaking nations are not very fluid in it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physicists in biology</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/physicists_in_biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/physicists_in_biology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One general factor that partially explains our ineffective approach to Wuflu is that too many people in key jobs affecting our response – the press, the medical research establishment, politicians, advisors – aren’t all that smart.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We could  draft all the particle physicists ( for the duration) .  True, most would not have a lot of specialized domain knowledge:  it might take two or three weeks before they were better at their new jobs than typical CDC or WHO employees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prize</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/prize/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/prize/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1975436283586449517&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;m deeply skeptical about the institution of the Nobel Prize, sometimes one is pushed to make a comment or two.  The kind of lay justifications or causes they append to their pronouncement are sometimes amusing/irritating. Like, this year, they could have simply said that they are giving the prize for the discovery of regulatory T cells (Tregs). Of course, a layman would not understand what that means, but would be equally or even more confused by their citation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Receeding edge</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/receeding-edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/receeding-edge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1473845527083110405.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is India producing enough out-of-the-chart brilliant people ? Given our population and size (nearly 1/5th of humanity), we should be producing a few intellects of the level of Euler, Gauss, Newton, Ramanujan every generation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;receeding-edge&#34;&gt;Receeding edge&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If we are talking of level of Euler etc that doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen even in the US/Germany with apparently higher mean IQ &amp;amp; resources than India. A part of it is the expanding frontier of science. The edge of science today is at a large radius &amp;amp; it may not be easy to recognize anything at that edge without a lot of effort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/theoretical_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/theoretical_study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I have a -ve view of Mill, I do think Max Mueller&amp;rsquo;s achievement cannot be understated. Contrary to many H internet activists contemporary H leaders took a positive view of him. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/04/12/max-mueller-good-bad-or-a-malhotran-u-turner/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. More generally, I do hold that there is something I term tattvAveSha&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To illustrate this imagine an applied mathematician who not ever having seen a planet can predict its existence or a theoretical biologist who without having seen an organism can predict intimate aspects of its biology from its genome sequence that were unknown to a naturalist who has spent a lifetime studying it. Likewise, for a textual culture, if the texts are extensive enough and the knowledge in them presented systematically enough, a good philologist can penetrate the producing culture without ever being embedded in it. As in the above linked note - Jan Gonda from Holland is a good example. Of course there will be lacunae from the lack of being an insider or firsthand observer; however, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t imply that know insights can be provided by observer from his armchair.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wealthy gent</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/wealthy-gent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/wealthy-gent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1837689337862820167&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps a life like that of the Swiss nobleman mathematician and sometime Princeton Professor Ernst Carl Stueckelberg von Breidenbach might not have been a bad one. Independently wealthy, he could devote himself to doing science for science&amp;rsquo;s sake rather than going through the trouble of publishing in high-profile places.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But his work in physics was of the highest standing &amp;ndash; one of his great discoveries, which a relatively moderate student can understand, is that an antiparticle, e.g., positron, is the particle moving backward in time!+++(5)+++ He also developed Lorentz-covariant perturbation theory, proposing the vector boson exchange model for the strong nuclear force, the baryon number conservation principle, and co-discovering the renormalization group.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Western role models and hindus</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/western-role-models_and_hindus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/articles/MT/western-role-models_and_hindus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(In response to an article by rAghavendra gadagkar &lt;a href=&#34;https://science.thewire.in/the-sciences/james-watson-konrad-lorentz-contributions-biology-social-justice-raghavendra-gadagkar/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is the issue of idolizing the actors &amp;amp; then being disillusioned by their ways for one other reason. In this regard I must say that I read Watson&amp;rsquo;s biography (not autobiography) from a volume of Greek and Western European scientists. It did not make a big impression on me &amp;amp; hardly was the cause to inspire me towards biology/biochemistry. The ones that made the biggest impression were: 1) Archimedes; 2) Theophrastus; 3) da Vinci; 4) Regiomontanus; 5) Descartes; 6) Leibniz; 7) Scheele; 8) Laplace; 9) Euler; 10) Lagrange; 11) Lavoisier; 12) von Goethe; 13) Gauss; 14) Ohm; 15) Faraday; 16) Darwin; 17) Wallace; 18) Riemann; 19) Cauchy; 20) Kirchhoff; 21) Planck 22) Ameghino&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
