<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;1 The Reign of Terror on the Steppe: on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/1_The_Reign_of_Terror_on_the_Steppe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;1 The Reign of Terror on the Steppe: on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/1_The_Reign_of_Terror_on_the_Steppe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 The Blood Clot</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/1_The_Reign_of_Terror_on_the_Steppe/1_The_Blood_Clot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/1_The_Reign_of_Terror_on_the_Steppe/1_The_Blood_Clot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There is fire in his eyes and light in his face.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;THE SECRET HISTORY OF THE MONGOLS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OF THE THOUSANDS OF cities conquered by the Mongols, history only mentions one that Genghis Khan deigned to enter. Usually, when victory became assured, he withdrew with his court to a distant and more pleasant camp while his warriors completed their tasks. On a March day in 1220, the Year of the Dragon, the Mongol conqueror broke with his peculiar tradition by leading his cavalry into the center of the newly conquered city of Bukhara, one of the most important cities belonging to the sultan of Khwarizm in what is now Uzbekistan. Although neither the capital nor the major commercial city, Bukhara occupied an exalted emotional position throughout the Muslim world as Noble Bukhara, the center of religious piety known by the epithet “the ornament and delight to all Islam.” Knowing fully the propaganda value of his actions by conquering and entering the city, Genghis Khan rode triumphantly through the city gates, past the warren of wooden houses and vendors’ stalls, to the large cluster of stone and brick buildings at the center of the city.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Tale of Three Rivers</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/1_The_Reign_of_Terror_on_the_Steppe/2_Tale_of_Three_Rivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/1_The_Reign_of_Terror_on_the_Steppe/2_Tale_of_Three_Rivers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The banner of Chingiz-Khan’s fortune&lt;br&gt;&#xA;was raised and they issued forth.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ATA-MALIK JUVAINI,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Genghis Khan: The History of the&lt;br&gt;&#xA;World Conqueror&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;EARLY ONE MORNING AS the family slept in their &lt;em&gt;ger,&lt;/em&gt; which stood alone on an isolated steppe in the upper reaches of the Kherlen River, a raiding party of Merkids raced toward them. The old woman the family had taken in lay with her head on the ground, but as old women often do, she passed much of the predawn hours drifting in and out of a fitful sleep. As the horses drew nearer, she sensed the vibrations of their hooves on the ground. Suddenly snapping out of her sleep, she shouted with alarm to rouse the others. The seven boys sprang up, scrambled frantically to put on their boots, and raced out to their horses, hobbled nearby. Temujin fled with his six companions and his mother and sister, leaving behind his new bride, his stepmother, Sochigel, and the old woman who had saved them all. In the desperate tribal world where daily life skirted so close to potential tragedy and annihilation, no one had the luxury of artificially chivalrous codes of behavior. In the quick decision of their utilitarian calculus, leaving these three women as booty would at least slow the raiders enough so that the others might have time to escape. For Temujin’s fleeing band, the open steppe offered no refuge; they would have to ride hard to reach safety in the mountains to the north.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 War of the Khans</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/1_The_Reign_of_Terror_on_the_Steppe/3_War_of_the_Khans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/making_modern_world/1_The_Reign_of_Terror_on_the_Steppe/3_War_of_the_Khans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All the tribes were of one color and&lt;br&gt;&#xA;obedient to his command.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ATA-MALIK JUVAINI,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Genghis Khan: The History of the&lt;br&gt;&#xA;World Conqueror&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;EVERYONE REALIZED THAT ONG Khan was nearing the end of his career, but no one knew who would take over for him. After more than twenty years of struggle, Temujin controlled most of the Mongols, but he had not yet conquered his rival Jamuka. Ong Khan, while generally siding with Temujin, had continued to play the two subordinate khans off against one another. In 1203, the Year of the Pig and one year after the Tatar victory, Temujin decided to bring the issue out into the open and resolve it by requesting a marriage between Ong Khan’s daughter and Temujin’s eldest son, Jochi. If Ong Khan accepted the proposed marriage, it would be acknowledgment of Temujin as the favorite over Jamuka.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
