<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०४ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/04/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०४ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/04/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The battle of the train and bus towns</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/04/2006-04-29_the-battle-of-the-train-and-bus-towns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/04/2006-04-29_the-battle-of-the-train-and-bus-towns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/04/29/the-battle-of-the-train-and-bus-towns/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As many issues remain still murky and we are still behind the haze we&#xA;cannot narrate much. It was wild ride is all we can say. We knew that&#xA;one of our greatest sapatna-s stood straight in our path. It was going&#xA;to be a fight like the one between karNa and arjuna. Just as only one&#xA;sword can reside in a scabbard, just as there can only be indra or&#xA;vR^itra or just as there can be only one rAja in rAShTra it had to be&#xA;one of us. The sapatna arranged things such that we had to attack from a&#xA;very unfavorable position. We had no choice but to charge. We could not&#xA;deploy anything at first. But we planned everything pretty well in terms&#xA;of timing of the attack, and then found a moment to invoke the secret&#xA;aid of the breaker of vala’s stronghold: ma~njughoSha, combined plainly&#xA;with that great forgotten weapon: “the strike of shUlini”. The speed of&#xA;the maruts took us through the first attack scattering the&#xA;kR^iShNa-varNa-s and ekAntika-vAdin-s. Then we drove away ajadhADika,&#xA;viTshiras, biDAlashmashru and shuchiroman. Then our great shatru&#xA;repeatedly attacked trying to tie us with astras. We, however, invoked&#xA;the mahA-vajra to pierce him. That thunder which had burnt the the&#xA;enemies of trasadasyu, that might of indrAvaruNa bore us aid against&#xA;him. This round of the gaviShTi was ours. Then we were moving away after&#xA;having controlled the vile Damarushiras, when our old bhrAtR^ivya&#xA;attacked us violent with the rakta-ghAtaka. He could not bear the fall&#xA;of biDAlashmashru and mahA-shatru in the open field. (“mlechChas&#xA;horsemen are all around you.”). Four fierce weapons pursue us- the&#xA;raktaghAtaka, the bhaya nirR^iti (we remembered the old nairR^ita&#xA;attacks), rAkShasi and jvAlAmukha. We needed to obtain the yakShini-s&#xA;bAlachandrikA and suratama~njari to save ourselves now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From parIkShit’s window</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/04/2006-04-22_from-parikshits-window/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/04/2006-04-22_from-parikshits-window/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/04/22/from-parikshits-window/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the top of the fort, from the window we watched the desolate&#xA;landscape cloaked in the moist haze of indra sprinklings. The last cry&#xA;of the bird had been heard for the day. The amAtya and the shachiva were&#xA;caught in their own troubles due the passing of the vR^iddha. On the&#xA;shore Jx sat still unable to come to terms with the fact that he was&#xA;free. His mantri-s were also caught in the same troubles as our&#xA;mantri-s. The muni had retreated into his cave. We reminisced of our&#xA;brief conversation with him on the eve of the tragedy. The muni shared&#xA;my concerns at that point and our minds went back to the fateful clear&#xA;night when the PM was rattling under a ghorAbhichAra. He saw how that&#xA;very day we had taken the worst turn with respect to the issue of&#xA;khANDava. Having sized the situation we knew it was alright for us to&#xA;die, but the muni had to escape to continue the fight. We spoke then of&#xA;that step into the kAlaChidra. We did not know what was happening to our&#xA;arrows in the great raNa; we knew then knew what had befallen the brave&#xA;ikShvAku of ayodhya, when he stood before the fierce bharadvAja warrior&#xA;who was raging on that fateful day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>yarning on Anandavardhana</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/04/2006-04-13_yarning-on-anandavardhana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/04/2006-04-13_yarning-on-anandavardhana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/04/13/yarning-on-anandavardhana/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anandavardhana was a remarkable figure. In my Sanskrit learning I gave&#xA;him the skip because the theory and practice of alaMkAra never struck a&#xA;chord in me in my youth (I also had a great excuse). My mother spoke of&#xA;a lot of theory and practice of alaMkAra literature but I realized soon&#xA;that her way of conveying it was not at all for me. In any case my then&#xA;AchArya found my excuse convincing and maintained that we could continue&#xA;with analysis of the yajur vedic prose when I returned. But I had some&#xA;vague knowledge of Anandavardhana from the other learned brAhmaNas who&#xA;were disciples of my original aged AchArya. My teacher only said I&#xA;should return to devIshataka when I got the chance. Mis-creant who had&#xA;taken Sanskrit formally in the college mentioned some terrifying text&#xA;called dhvanyAloka and said she had a copy of the devIshataka. But&#xA;shortly there after I had to observe a major niyamas of for acquisitions&#xA;of the rahasyas, and was totally cut off from all oral and even written&#xA;communitication with her and never got the examining the text.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After the pAShaNDa hill</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/04/2006-04-12_after-the-pashanda-hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/04/2006-04-12_after-the-pashanda-hill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/04/12/after-the-pashanda-hill/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We were trying to trace back the footsteps of besieger. We realized some&#xA;of the details of what happened immediately after the pAShaNDa hill. We&#xA;got out of pAShaNDa hill and were confronted by the second “born of&#xA;soma”. We brushed aside “born of soma-2” pretty easily. Shortly there&#xA;after an incantation followed. We believed that out pitA had taken care&#xA;of that, but it was only partly so. Shaken by the recent turn of events&#xA;for the first time he told us that there might have been a mistake at&#xA;that point and that he might acted on a mistaken track for a whole year.&#xA;Now realizing that it had gone way beyond his level, he dumped the whole&#xA;thing on us to take care of it our own. But somewhat ironically we are&#xA;like two incomplete men each having only one key half- he all those&#xA;brilliant strategies and us the theoretical knowledge of mantras.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The southward passage</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/04/2006-04-09_the-southward-passage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/04/2006-04-09_the-southward-passage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/04/09/the-southward-passage/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;sUryaM cakShur gachChatu vAtaM AtmA dyAM ca gachCha pR^ithivIM ca&#xA;dharmaNA |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;apo vA gachCha yadi tatra te hitam oShadhIShu pratitiShThA sharIraiH&#xA;||&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(kaliyuga 5107, month: chaitra, shukla ekAdashi, magha)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Having reached the end of his span alloted by the son of vivasvAn he has&#xA;joined the line of the long past ones under the star of the manes. He&#xA;has gone the way of the great and first of the atharvaN-s, bhR^igu. He&#xA;has joined the line of chyavAna, dadhIchi, bR^ihaddiva, apnavAna, vatsa,&#xA;the fiery aurva, R^ichIka, jamadagni, rAma, kabandha, somAhUtI,&#xA;vAjaratna, somashuShma, vidarbha, sumantu, mANDukya and other great&#xA;atharvaN-s. But afterall he has met his gati in the upward journey of&#xA;the sun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 victims</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/04/2006-04-08_3-victims/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/04/2006-04-08_3-victims/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/04/08/3-victims/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The shachIva and and the amAtya gave us the signals that three kR^ityA’s&#xA;were dispatched. The strong PM, main victim of Fourier, seemed to be&#xA;under what might be his final decline. The dUtas of mahiShavAhana were&#xA;apparently approaching him. The muni confirmed this possibility. He had&#xA;lived his life of yoga and his mahAjapa of the shatarudriya, and&#xA;devotion to the vedas had given him the first 2 year respite when he was&#xA;first struck by the vairiprayogas. But his mantra bala had run out and&#xA;now he lay flattened. Mn, after his divergence from me was living a very&#xA;similar life. Mn was the smartest amongst us, and was a remarkable&#xA;schemer. His secretive shachIva performed several prayogas for him. So&#xA;while faced with issues similar to us, he acted far more smartly.&#xA;However, he was targetted by strike two. His shachIva did some rites to&#xA;save his life, but his ratha was badly damaged. The third strike&#xA;targetted us, we were intensely tormented by the piercing arrows of it.&#xA;It was made clear that this was a strike from which there was no escape.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The countryside expeditions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/04/2006-04-08_the-countryside-expeditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/04/2006-04-08_the-countryside-expeditions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/04/08/the-countryside-expeditions/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best remembered of our expeditions were those to the city of&#xA;bhairava, the fort of tridents and the long-winded peregrinations&#xA;through the Maharatta countryside.In the halcyon days Mis-creant,&#xA;muscleman S, his shUdra sycophant (shUdra shreShTha=SS) and me were&#xA;seated on our parked vehicles and yarning in the vicinity of a little&#xA;shrine of a medieaval devotional vaiShNava cult descending from the&#xA;mahAnabhav cult. There were some devotional singers doling out the tune&#xA;of a medieaval saint of the Maharatta country, whose song roughly&#xA;translated thus: “Our pANDuraNGa is not like the goddess jAkhAI, jokhAI,&#xA;mAyArANI or mhaisAbAI. Worship IThobhA, do not worship gods like&#xA;gaNapati and skanda or these AIs.” I was struck by this parochial tune&#xA;and asked SS who are these AIs and whether he happened to worship them.&#xA;He replied, the AIs were most important in his peoples and they surely&#xA;worshipped them. He told us of some cultic centers of his goddesses and&#xA;gods. I had heard these from other local shUdras and the Maharatta chief&#xA;who had given us the land to live (due to his high regard for&#xA;brAhmaNas). So I was filled with an urge to explore these regions and&#xA;know more and echoed them to Mis-creant, who as ever was always game for&#xA;such adventures. She also came up with the bright idea that we might be&#xA;able to couple it with our project to investigate the diversity of&#xA;predaceous hemipterans of India, which was for long being contemplated.&#xA;She also suggested that we take along S and SS as our bodyguard and&#xA;guide- I knew they would come if they knew she was going to come along.&#xA;Sure enough they agreed, if not for anything else just being around in&#xA;the company of Mis-creant, and we found S a good listener and sounding&#xA;board, whom we could bore endlessly with our newest theories on&#xA;hemipteran evolution, geology of the Deccan plateau or history of local&#xA;deities…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An year later</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/04/2006-04-02_an-year-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/04/2006-04-02_an-year-later/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/04/02/an-year-later/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The kR^ityA had hit precisely an year back. We knew that the anniversary&#xA;strike was in the making. Around 2.30 PM the kR^ityA was seen again; as&#xA;before, it rapidly breached all the kavachas and burnt its way through.&#xA;It was like the classical pratya~Ngirasa kR^ityA described in the&#xA;literature. The “Ajya tarpaNaM” held it off temporarily. We were&#xA;reviewing the indra jAla 2 front with our general when she struck again.&#xA;This time we deployed “kalAyasUpa” against it but that did not work and&#xA;it seized us violently. We had to finally use the “Asandi” to drive her&#xA;away. We thought we had her under check, when she suddenly returned and&#xA;could not be quelled by by “nimbUka” or “mAsha”. She raged for five&#xA;hours and the dhanAkarshaNa bhairava spell was repulsed. Then finally&#xA;with the gaNanAtha a temporary control was effected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
