<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/proto-onge/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/proto-onge/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>haryANa factory</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/proto-onge/articles/haryANa-factory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/proto-onge/articles/haryANa-factory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;original-article&#34;&gt;Original article&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SHUBHANGI MISRA 26 July, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mangar, Haryana: Prehistoric cave paintings belonging to the Paleolithic era, and rock shelters as well as tools and tool-making equipment, presumably dating back to the lower or early Paleolithic era have been found hiding in plain sight in the Aravallis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paleolithic era, or the Old Stone Age, dates back to 10,000 BC when humans still lived as hunters and gatherers. Tools belonging to the Stone Age have been found in rock shelters as well as in open-air sites, spread across nearly 5,000 hectares, Banani Bhattacharya, Deputy Director, Haryana Department of Archaeology and Museums, told ThePrint.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wallacea population</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/proto-onge/articles/wallacea-population/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/proto-onge/articles/wallacea-population/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wallacea = group of mainly Indonesian islands separated by deep-water straits from the Asian and Australian continental shelves. Wallacea includes Sulawesi, the largest island in the group, as well as Lombok, Sumbawa, Flores, Sumba, Timor, Halmahera, Buru, Seram, and many smaller islands. The islands of Wallacea lie between the Sunda Shelf (the Malay Peninsula, Sumatra, Borneo, Java, and Bali) to the west, and the Sahul Shelf including Australia and New Guinea to the south and east.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
