<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;1 Youth on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;1 Youth on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/I/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/I/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Libanius to Priscus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Antioch, March [A.D.] 380&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday morning as I was about to enter the lecture hall, I was stopped by a Christian student who asked me in a voice eager with malice, &amp;ldquo;Have you heard about the Emperor Theodosius?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I cleared my throat ready to investigate the nature of this question, but he was too quick for me. &amp;ldquo;He has been baptized a Christian.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was non-committal. Nowadays, one never knows who is a secret agent. Also, I was not particularly surprised at the news. When Theodosius fell ill last winter and the bishops arrived like vultures to pray over him, I knew that should he recover they would take full credit for having saved him. He survived.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>II</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/II/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/II/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Memoir of Julian Augustus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the example of my uncle the Emperor Constantine, called the Great, who died when I was six years old, I learned that it is dangerous to side with any party of the Gallleans, for they mean to overthrow and veil those things that are truly holy. I can hardly remember Constantine, though I was once presented to him at the Sacred Palace. I dimly recall a giant, heavily scented, wearing a stiff jewelled robe. My older brother Gallus always said that I tried to pull his wig off. But Gallus had a cruel humour, and I doubt that this story was true. If I had tugged at the Emperor&amp;rsquo;s wig, I would surely not have endeared myself to him, for he was as vain as a woman about his appearance; even his Galilean admirers admit to that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>III</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/III/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/III/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was eleven years old, my life again changed abruptly. One morning in May I was doing lessons with Mardonius. I was reciting Hesiod and making a good many mistakes, when Gallus came into the room.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He&amp;rsquo;s dead. The Bishop&amp;rsquo;s dead. In the church. He died. Just like that!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mardonius drew a cross on his chest; so did I. A moment later we were joined by clergy, officials, servants. Everyone was stunned, and alarmed, for it is a great event when the bishop of Constantinople dies, and who succeeds him is a matter of national importance. The emperor—if he is Galilean—always has a hand in the choosing of a successor. But Constantius was a thousand miles away, on the borders of Persia. So for several weeks no bishop was appointed, and no. one knew what to do with Gallus and me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IV</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/IV/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/IV/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Five years passed. Little news of the outside world came to us. Sapor, the Great King of Persia, threatened our Eastern border, while the Germans infiltrated Gaul. That was all we knew. Politics was a forbidden subject. I studied Homer and Hesiod; read Plotinus and Porphyry; made love to the Antiochene; fought with Gallus, until one day I out-wrestled him and he never challenged me again. He was a coward except when he was in a rage; then he would do anything.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IX</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/IX/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/IX/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Julian Augustus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was mid-October when I arrived in Milan. The weather was dry and the air so clear that one could see with perfect clarity those blue alps which separate civilization from barbarism, our world of sun from that melancholy green forest where dwells Rome&amp;rsquo;s nemesis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just before the city&amp;rsquo;s gate we were met by one of Constantius&amp;rsquo;s eunuchs, a gorgeous fellow with many chins and an effortless sneer. He did not salute me as is proper, a bad omen. He gave the commander of my guard a letter from the Emperor. When I saw this, I began to recite the first of the passwords I should need when I arrived in the kingdom of the dead. But I was not to be dispatched just yet. Instead I was taken to a house in one of the suburbs. Here I was imprisoned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>V</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/V/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/V/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And you like the poetry of Bacchylides, as well? Ah, we have extraordinary taste! No doubt of that.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was so overcome by Ecebolius&amp;rsquo;s flattery that had he asked me then and there to leap off the top of my uncle Julian&amp;rsquo;s house as a literary exercise, I would have done so gladly, with an appropriate quotation from Hesiod as I fell. I chattered like a monkey as he examined me closely in Hesiod, Homer, Herodotus, Thucydides, and Theognis. For seven hours he listened as I recited from memory the many thousands of lines I had memorized at Macellum. He affected to be amazed. &amp;ldquo;I knew Bishop George was a splendid scholar—that enviable library! But I had no idea he was a teacher of such genius!&amp;rdquo; I beamed idiotically and kept on talking. I had at last found my tongue, and there are those who think I have not stopped talking since.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/VI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/VI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Naturally the Caesar is concerned.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But without cause.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Without cause? You are a pupil of Maximus.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am also a pupil of Ecebolius.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But he has not been with you for a year. Your brother feels that you are in need of a spiritual guide, especially now.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But Maximus is responsible.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maximus is not a Christian. *Are you? *&amp;rdquo; The question came at me like a stone from a sling. I stared a long moment at the blackrobed Deacon Aetius of Antioch. He stared serenely back. I was close to panic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/VII/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/VII/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I arrived at Piraeus, the port of Athens, shortly after sunrise 5 August 355. I remember every one of the forty-seven days I spent in Athens. They were the happiest of my life, so far.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was a windy dawn. In the east, light tore at the dark. Stars faded. The sea was rough. It was like the morning of the world. The ship creaked and shuddered as it struck against the pilings of the quay. I had half expected to see a detachment of troops waiting on the shore, ready to arrest me on some new charge. But there were no troops in sight, only foreign merchant ships and the usual bustle of a busy port. Slaves unloaded cargoes. Officials of the port moved solemnly from ship to ship. Men with carts and donkeys shouted to those just arrived, promising to get them to Athens faster than that youth who ran from Marathon to the city in four hours (and fell dead, one would like to retort, but irony is lost on drivers, even Greek drivers who know their Homer).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VIII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/VIII/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/1_Youth/VIII/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Julian Augustus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A week after I arrived in Athens I met the Hierophant of Greece. Since I did not want the proconsul to know of this meeting, it was arranged to take place in the Library of Hadrian, a not much frequented building midway between the Roman and the Athenian agoras.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At noon I arrived at the library and went straight to the north reading room, enjoying as I always do the musty dry odour of papyrus and ink which comes from the tall niches where the scrolls and codices are kept. The high room with its coffered ceiling (for which we must thank Antinofis&amp;rsquo;s protector) was empty. Here I waited for the Hierophant. I was extremely nervous, for he is the holiest of all men. I am forbidden by law to write his name but I can say that he belongs to the family of the Eumolpidae, one of the two families from which Hierophants are traditionally drawn.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
