<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;3 Wolf Mother 1470–1509 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/3_Wolf_Mother_14701509/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;3 Wolf Mother 1470–1509 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/3_Wolf_Mother_14701509/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>10 The White Road of the Warrior Widow</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/3_Wolf_Mother_14701509/10_The_White_Road_of_the_Warrior_Widow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/3_Wolf_Mother_14701509/10_The_White_Road_of_the_Warrior_Widow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MANDUHAI WISHED TO RULE, BUT NOT ONLY DID SHE have no experience, she had no army. All the soldiers were loyal either to their respected general Une-Bolod or to Ismayil Taishi, the highest ranking official in the government.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yet Manduhai had one thing they did not have—a baby boy. This was not her own child; he was the abandoned infant of the Golden Prince. He was the only living male descendant of the bone of Genghis Khan, the son of the &lt;em&gt;jinong&lt;/em&gt; and the heir of the Great Khan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Winning the War and Raising a Husband</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/3_Wolf_Mother_14701509/11_Winning_the_War_and_Raising_a_Husband/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/3_Wolf_Mother_14701509/11_Winning_the_War_and_Raising_a_Husband/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;VOWS, PRAYERS, AND RITUALS BEFORE A SHRINE ADDED much needed sacred legitimacy to Dayan Khan’s rule, but without force of arms, they amounted to empty gestures and wasted breath. Only after demonstrating that she had the skill to win, as well as the supernatural blessing to do so, could Manduhai hope to rule the Mongols. She had enemies on every side, and she needed to choose her first battle carefully. She had to confront each enemy, but she had to confront each in its own due time. Manduhai needed to manage the flow of conflicts by deciding when and where to fight and not allowing others to force her into a war for which she was not prepared or stood little chance of winning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Facing the Wall</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/3_Wolf_Mother_14701509/12_Facing_the_Wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/3_Wolf_Mother_14701509/12_Facing_the_Wall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MANDUHAI MAY HAVE BEEN THE &lt;em&gt;KHATUN&lt;/em&gt; AND BATU Mongke the khan, but by claiming the office of &lt;em&gt;taishi&lt;/em&gt;, foreigners such as Ismayil and Beg-Arslan still had a stranglehold on Mongolia by controlling the Gobi and thereby all the trade with China. Not yet strong enough to confront them directly, Manduhai consolidated her authority north of the Gobi. Although she steadily increased her power, ever since Genghis Khan’s conquests more Mongols actually lived south of the Gobi than north. A majority of the Mongols remained loyal to Beg-Arslan and Ismayil rather than to Dayan Khan and Manduhai.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Her Jade Realm Restored</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/3_Wolf_Mother_14701509/13_Her_Jade_Realm_Restored/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/3_Wolf_Mother_14701509/13_Her_Jade_Realm_Restored/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MOST OF THE MEN CHOSEN FOR THE RAID AGAINST Ismayil came from Manduhai’s Choros clan. She trusted them, and they best knew the area that had once been ruled by her father. Because of the difficulty of fielding and supplying an army over vast stretches of desert, Manduhai sent out a small, but highly skilled, detachment that probably consisted of between 200 and 250 men. A man named Togochi Sigusi commanded the raiding party and had 22 experienced officers with him; each of them probably led a squad of about 10 men.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
