<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Geopolitical</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/2023-10-29_a-geopolitical-meandering-october-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/2023-10-29_a-geopolitical-meandering-october-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2023/10/29/a-geopolitical-meandering-october-2023/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Geopolitical meandering, October 2023&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sir Francis Drake, buccaneer bold and bloody,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sailed the seas in a gold-grabbing spree,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;With the Golden Hind, he circled the Earth wide –&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A murdering marauder on the swelling tide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Slaving in West Africa, slaughtering civilian and combatant alike in Ireland, sacking and burning cities and towns along the South American coast, and pillaging treasure-laden ships, slaying friend and foe for ascendancy, the famed pirate Francis Drake rose to be the hero of the English. As the intrepid marauder lay dying, emptying out his bowels while retreating from a failed assault on Panama, he marked a historical moment with decisive geopolitical consequences down to our current age. On one side, he was taking to sea the long Western European predatory tradition going back to the phiraṅga-s like +++(crusaders)+++ Raymond, Baldwin, Godfrey, and Warner and the king of his own people, the wicked Richard Yes-and-No +++(←nickname from terse speech)+++. On the other side, Drake set into motion a process that was to bloom into a maritime predatory tradition that continues to dominate the geopolitics of our times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transcripts of</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/2022-03-15_transcripts-of-conversations-the-addiction-princip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/2022-03-15_transcripts-of-conversations-the-addiction-princip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2022/03/15/transcripts-of-conversations-the-addiction-principle/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Transcripts of conversations: the addiction principle:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A friend recorded some of our verbalizations and made transcripts of them. He sent them to us to and we decide to edit them and post them as and when we get the chance — not out of a narcissistic impulse but simply to record some of these thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: You keep mentioning the “addiction principle” as yet another feature shared by biological conflicts at the microscopic level and human geopolitical conflicts. Could you explain that?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deterrence</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/deterrence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/deterrence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1966902200723972298&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Someone was recently telling me that before nuclear weapons, there was no concept of a deterrent that could maintain peace. It is believed that nuclear weapons were the primary cause for the Cold War being cold rather than hot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I question the idea that there was no concept of a deterrent before that. There were deterrents before nukes. The Germans had the best gas warfare capability in terms of the agents they synthesized. The British gas weapons were nowhere in the league of the German ones. The American versions were also inferior, but in sheer quantity, they were apparently way more than those of the Germans.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energetics</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/energetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/energetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1868882385455964456&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;industrial-revolution&#34;&gt;Industrial revolution&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Industrial Revolution was like a Permian extinction level event for many peoples around the world. Many parts of the world have still not entirely come to terms with it: it either created new faultlines or exacerbated old ones and continues to do so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;artisans&#34;&gt;Artisans&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was particularly brutal on the artisanal groups. Only these Japanese, to a degree, were able to balance this assault on their artisanal guilds. In India, it destroyed the service castes: leaders like the faux mahAtman never understood its real significance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High iq network</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/high-iq-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/high-iq-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1574937417559130112&#34;&gt;MT - TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The plain truth is hard to accept: the number of high IQ nodes (individuals) in a nation &amp;amp; the degree of connectivity between them (density of the graph edges) decide the line between its victory and defeat. &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Power differential between the pa~nchanetra &amp;amp; rest is quite a bit in terms of most of the basics: energy, nukes, militech, high IQ individuals working towards a common goal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Huntington</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/huntington/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/huntington/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intra-abrahamistic-synergy&#34;&gt;Intra-Abrahamistic synergy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In his theory of the clash of civilizations Samuel Huntington had predicted that the chIna-s and the marUnmatta-s will ally against the Occidental Judaeo-Christian civilization. He was not entirely right in this regard: what he missed was the extent to which intra-Abrahamistic synergy fosters marUnmAda.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While there might be synergy between the jihad and the chIna-s in specific limited cases, this is not a general thing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rather everything points in the direction of our theory: sarvonmAdasamAyoga-ekarAkShasa-jAla-shambara. The problem for the H is being at the receiving end of both axes &amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran vs NATO - Rus invasion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/iran_vs_nato_rus-invasion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/iran_vs_nato_rus-invasion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://unrollthread.com/t/1582574421369229314/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In interesting offshoot of the rUs-rotten soybean war is the window it offers into the arms race between the Islamic Republic on one hand &amp;amp; the Jewish intelligence + American pelf+++(=अधार्मिक-सम्पत्)+++ on the other. The latter clearly has a huge heft &amp;amp; the IR realized that it cannot have any kind of parity in terms of strategic defense measures against them. The Americans had shown how they could throw them around when they took out their key general +++(soleimani)+++. Israel&amp;rsquo;s iron dome had also shown it could work against the rockets of its Islamic rivals. This meant that the IR was essentially rendered toothless in the event of greater escalation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joining occident</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/joining-occident/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/joining-occident/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/i/lists/934873690050740224&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we have remarked at length before, Russia has always had the aspiration to be a full member of what is colloquially termed the Occident &amp;ndash; the currently ascendant confederation led by the Anglo-abrahamospheric core. However, its advances to them has been repeatedly spurned even as they see the rUs as an existential threat.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We believe the Russian desire is sincere but most of the Occident sees it totally unworthy of consideration barring players like duShTa jarilaputra. For the leadership of the Occident they are just too much of a competing and ideologically divergent world view to accommodate within their tent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MlechCha-marUnmattAbhisandhiH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/mlechCha-marUnmattAbhisandhiH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/mlechCha-marUnmattAbhisandhiH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1922840056672276656&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The American rehabilitation of the Al Qaeda chap +++(=2025 syria dictator)+++ is a textbook example of the mlechChamarUnmattAbhisaMdhi: outsiders shouldn&amp;rsquo;t take arguments between brothers seriously.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Will the mlecChamarUnmattAbhisaMdhi ever get directed against the chIna-s?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Huntington did not think so. He felt marUnmatta-s will play both sides. Further, I&amp;rsquo;ve posited that Galtonism is a strong force and might prevent that from happening.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sarvonmatta-samayoga-ekarakshasa-jala&#34;&gt;sarvonmatta-samAyoga-ekarAkShasa-jAla&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The pa~nchanetraka emasculates you, and the marUnmatta moves into your house to claim it as his: sarvonmatta-samAyoga-ekarAkShasa-jAla in a nutshell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sorAdi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/sorAdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/sorAdi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/i/lists/934873690050740224&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The election of the duShTa-s pauraputra by the himakarnATa-s and mahAshman by the A~Nglaka-s are striking examples of how the tides of democracy can be used to conquer a nation by the sorAdi. The chIna system is resistant to this type of infection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spengler</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/spengler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/geopolitics/articles/MT/spengler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spengler did not understand Darwin&amp;rsquo;s evolutionary theory correctly, but he correctly apprehended the evolutionary dynamics of civilization as a whole. While at one level, energetics might explain aspects of it (e.g., Tainter), Spengler had his finger on something more subtle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1423532226885607427&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oswald Spengler was a fertile thinker of the type that even if wrong in the details there is much of fertile value in the kind of thinking they initiated. That can be said of the geometric though of Plato &amp;amp; the natural history of Aristotle. Though many of our times tend&#xA;to put much faith in contra-Spenglerian thought I have not seen they have much to offer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
