<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;3 Augustus on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;3 Augustus on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>XIX</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/XIX/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/XIX/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Priscus&lt;/em&gt;: I arrived not long after the fire. My season of teaching ended with the old year, and I travelled from Constantinople to Antioch in eight days, which is excellent time. Julian so completely reformed the state transportation system that travel was a pleasure. Not a bishop in sight, though there were several newly appointed high priests in the carriages and I confess I began to wonder if they were any improvement over the Christians. I suspect that had Julian lived, matters would have been just as they were under Constantius, only instead of being bored by quarrels about the nature of the trinity we would have had to listen to disputes about the nature of Zeus&amp;rsquo;s sex life… rather an improvement, come to think of it, but essentially the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XVI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/XVI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/XVI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Priscus&lt;/em&gt;: That is the way it happened. At least that is the way Julian says it happened. As you must gather, he omits a number of details. To read his account one would think that there had been no resistance at all to him, other than from the wicked Constantius. This was hardly true. I should say that a majority of the &amp;ldquo;responsible&amp;rdquo; men in the empire preferred Constantius to Julian, nor was this on religious grounds, since Julian&amp;rsquo;s passion for Hellenism was not generally known as of November 361. I am sure you will want to state matters as they actually were. Your famous balance would be seriously deranged if you were to record that Julian&amp;rsquo;s success was the result of a popular uprising against Constantius. It was not-despite the impression you gave in your justly celebrated oration at the time of Julian&amp;rsquo;s death. But then the great wings of a memorial, like those of a panegyric, are not expected to be clipped by tedious fact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XVII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/XVII/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/XVII/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Julian Augustus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Constantius seldom addressed the senate for the excellent reason that he could not speak for any length of time without stammering or making some error in logic or grammar. As a result, he almost never set foot in the senate house. He preferred to summon the senate to the throneroom in the Daphne Palace where he could address them informally, on those rare occasions when he dealt with them at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XVIII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/XVIII/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/XVIII/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Julian Augustus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On Io May I left Constantinople for Antioch. All omens were favourable. The weather was good, though far too dry for that time of year. Instead of going straight south to Syria, I swung to the east, passing through Phrygia and Galatia.! pretended that I wanted to see for myself what these territories were like so that [ might have some firsthand knowledge of their problems when it came time for the tax reforms the new Count of the Sacred Largesse, Felix, insisted that I make. But my actual motive was to visit the temple of Cybele at Pessinus and there make solemn offering to my patroness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XX</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/XX/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/XX/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Journal of Julian Augustus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Callinicum on the Euphrates, *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;27 March 363&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Waiting for the fleet. They should have been here when we arrived. Callinicum is a rich city, strongly fortified. Morale is good. Dictating this while riding in a carriage to the river. Today is the festival of the Mother of the Gods. There is a great ceremony at Rome. I hold a small one here. The sun is hot. People crowd about the carriage. I dictate to the secretary. I wave to the crowd. I am in ceremonial vestments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XXI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/XXI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/XXI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Julian Augustus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;11 May&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have had excellent luck. Maiozamalcha fell with few casualties for us. I have just received Nabdates, the Persian commander. He hailed me as Lord of the World and I have spared his life. This should make a good impression. If the Persian lords believe that I am merciful, they will be more apt to surrender when overwhelmed. I hope so, since there is nothing so demoralizing for an army as to fight long sieges for unimportant cities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XXII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/XXII/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/XXII/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Julian Augustus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;31 May&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Midnight. * The deaf-mute sits cross-legged at my feet, playing a Persian instrument much like a lute.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The melody is unfamiliar but pleasing. Callistus is arranging my armour on the stand beside the bed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ormisda has just left. He is pleased at my decision, but I am somewhat uneasy. For the first time I find myself in complete disagreement with my officers. What is worse, I cannot tell them why I know that the course I have embarked upon is the right one. At this evening&amp;rsquo;s staff meeting, Victor challenged me openly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XXIII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/XXIII/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/XXIII/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Priscus&lt;/em&gt;: The next morning Julian gave the order to march west to the Tigris. We were in a dry desolate country of sand and stone. Our slow passage made clouds of white choking dust as we rode towards a series of low hills where waiting Persians watched us, like so many scorpions among the rocks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was with Julian in the vanguard. He wore no armour. His servant had not yet repaired the leather straps. &amp;ldquo;Just as well,&amp;rdquo; he said. Like all of us, he was soaked with sweat, even at dawn. Flies clung to our lips and eyes. Most of us suffered from dysentery. Yet despite the heat and the discomfort, Julian was in excellent spirits. For one thing, he had finally interpreted the dream to his own liking. &amp;ldquo;The Genius of Rome deserted me. There&amp;rsquo;s no denying that. But he left by the tent door, which was to the west. That means this campaign is finished, and we must return home to the west.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XXIV</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/XXIV/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/julian_by_vidal/3_Augustus/XXIV/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Libanius, Quaestor of Antioch, to the&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Antioch, May 381&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lord Theodosius, Augustus of the East&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May it please Your Eternity, I have it in mind to compose a biography of your famous predecessor the Augustus Julian, employing certain of his private papers which have only recently come into my possession.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since Your Eternity expressed pleasure in my ode, &amp;ldquo;On Avenging the Emperor Julian&amp;rdquo;, I need hardly mention that I intend to pursue my labour of vindication in precisely the same discreet style as the ode which you so graciously admired. Realizing as I do the religious and political implications of this work, I am impelled not only to remind the Augustus of my perfect (and obvious!) loyalty to his sacred person and sagacious policies but to assure him that I intend to relate this marvellous tale with the conscious delicacy which the subject inspires and the times require.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
