<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;2 Critical Theory from the South on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/2_Critical_Theory_from_the_South/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;2 Critical Theory from the South on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/2_Critical_Theory_from_the_South/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/2_Critical_Theory_from_the_South/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/2_Critical_Theory_from_the_South/6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Souths of Antonio Gramsci and the Concept of Hegemony&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Nadia Urbinati *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;preliminary-remarks&#34;&gt;Preliminary Remarks&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Southern Question was born along with the unity of Italy, out of an awareness of the limits of unity itself and a disillusionment with the leading class that had made it possible. These sentiments were shared by all the &lt;em&gt;meridionalisti&lt;/em&gt;, conservative, liberal, and democratic alike (P. Villari 1868; Franchetti 1911; Caizzi 1950; Salvadori 1976). Already in 1861, in &amp;ldquo;letters&amp;rdquo; to the Milanese magazine &lt;em&gt;La perseveranza&lt;/em&gt; on brigandage, the mafia, and the poverty of the southern peasants, Pasquale Villari employed the notion of the &lt;em&gt;questione meridionale&lt;/em&gt; to denote the &amp;ldquo;social&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;political&amp;rdquo; problems of the South. Villari denounced the selfishness of the largerly northern &amp;ldquo;bourgeoisie,&amp;rdquo; which, because of its inability to govern, had become brutal and repressive, like a colonizing force, &lt;em&gt;vis-à-vis&lt;/em&gt; the South. For him, the southern problem was unquestionably related to the way in which the political unification of the country was implemented, as an &amp;ldquo;occupation&amp;rdquo; of both the local and the central government by the moderate liberals of the North (P. Villari 1878: 147).1 A few years later another &amp;ldquo;conservative&amp;rdquo;, Sidney Sonnino, declared that for southerners Italy meant nothing but repression, high taxes, and arrogant public officials (Sonnino 1972: 155—61). Subsequently to Unification, in the 1880s and 1890s, the Italian government legislated a tariff policy protecting northern industries (primarily steel and textiles) and southern wheat from foreign competition. Both northern industrialists and southern landowners supported this policy, their alliance around it constituting what is sometimes called a &amp;ldquo;historic bloc&amp;rdquo;. Because the first generation of conservative &lt;em&gt;meridionalisti&lt;/em&gt; distrusted the free market and liberal international exchange, they had no critique of this policy, and did not attribute the South&amp;rsquo;s misery to it (Urbinati 1990: 109-47). At the turn of the century, Antonio De Viti De Marco and Francesco Saverio Nitti identified the tariff policy as the tool the North had used to industrialize at the expense of the South (Caizzi 1950: 225-34; Nitti 1987: 13-15).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/2_Critical_Theory_from_the_South/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/2_Critical_Theory_from_the_South/7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How Critical Was De Martino&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Critical Ethnocentrism&amp;rdquo; in Southern Italy?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Annalisa Di Nola *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ernesto de Martino&amp;rsquo;s engagement with Marxism, evident in his works on the South of Italy, by no means exhausted his main interests. Recent critical essays on this important Neapolitan anthropologist have highlighted his concern with the concept of the loss and maintenance of &amp;ldquo;presence,&amp;rdquo; that is with the possibility of constituting or preserving the &amp;ldquo;self&amp;rdquo; in the face of threatening crises (see Cherchi 1981; Cherchi and Cherchi 1987; Pasquinelli 1984). His adherence to this theme reflects his greater fascination with the existential philosophy of Heidegger, and with Kant&amp;rsquo;s and Hegel&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;critical&amp;rdquo; perspective, than with a Marxist approach to social research. Nevertheless, de Martino&amp;rsquo;s years of scholarship on Southern Italy influenced Italian cultural anthropology to approach the Southern Question with political commitment. During the period between 1949 and 1962, when French Marxist anthropology was not yet born and the American researchers in the South of Italy were following the path indicated by Robert Redfield (1941, 1955a, b; see, for example, Banfield 1958; Friedmann 1952), de Martino showed a genuine interest in the economic and social emancipation of the people he studied.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/2_Critical_Theory_from_the_South/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/2_Critical_Theory_from_the_South/8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Magic of the South: Popular Religion and Elite Catholicism in Italian Ethnology&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*George R. Saunders *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Northern Europeans have long come south to Italy for spiritual and aesthetic refreshment. Goethe, Freud, and Max Weber all discovered some sort of &amp;ldquo;spirit&amp;rdquo; in Italy that contrasted sharply with the overly rationalized, passionless instrumentality of their northern lands. Goethe, for example, spent nearly two years in Italy, from 1786 to 1788, recovering from a &amp;ldquo;terrible disease&amp;rdquo; brought on, apparently, by his service in the government of Weimar, but perhaps in part by a kind of mid-life crisis deriving from his literary work. In Italy he felt a spiritual and intellectual rebirth, a burst of new energy and excitement. His letters and journal entries from Italy express wonder and enthusiasm, generated in part by the sensual aesthetics and in part by the puzzling otherness of it all. At times, they also describe his dismay and a fair measure of disgust.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
