<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;notes from lectures and discourses on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;notes from lectures and discourses on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>370 ON KARMA-YOGA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/370_on_karma-yoga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/370_on_karma-yoga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-karma-yoga&#34;&gt;ON KARMA-YOGA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Isolation of the soul from all objects, mental and physical, is the&#xA;goal; when that is attained, the soul will find that it was alone all&#xA;the time, and it required no one to make it happy. As long as we require&#xA;someone else to make us happy, we are slaves. When the Purusha finds&#xA;that It is free, and does not require anything to complete Itself, that&#xA;this nature is quite unnecessary, then freedom (Kaivalya) is attained.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>371 ON FANATICISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/371_on_fanaticism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/371_on_fanaticism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-fanaticism&#34;&gt;ON FANATICISM&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are fanatics of various kinds. Some people are wine fanatics and&#xA;cigar fanatics. Some think that if men gave up smoking cigars, the world&#xA;would arrive at the millennium. Women are generally amongst these&#xA;fanatics. There was a young lady here one day, in this class. She was&#xA;one of a number of ladies in Chicago who have built a house where they&#xA;take in the working people and give them music and gymnastics. One day&#xA;this young lady was talking about the evils of the world and said she&#xA;knew the remedy. I asked, &amp;ldquo;How do you know?&amp;rdquo; and she answered, &amp;ldquo;Have you&#xA;seen Hull House?&amp;rdquo; In her opinion, this Hull House is the one panacea for&#xA;all the evils that flesh is heir to. This will grow upon her. I am sorry&#xA;for her. There are some fanatics in India who think that if a woman&#xA;could marry again when her husband died, it would cure all evil. This is&#xA;fanaticism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>372 WORK IS WORSHIP</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/372_work_is_worship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/372_work_is_worship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-is-worship&#34;&gt;WORK IS WORSHIP&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The highest man &lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; work, for there is no binding element, no&#xA;attachment, no ignorance in him. A ship is said to have passed over a&#xA;mountain of magnet ore, and all the bolts and bars were drawn out, and&#xA;it went to pieces. It is in ignorance that struggle remains, because we&#xA;are all really atheists. Real theists cannot work. We are atheists more&#xA;or less. We do not see God or believe in Him. He is G-O-D to us, and&#xA;nothing more. There are moments when we think He is near, but then we&#xA;fall down again. When you see Him, who struggles for whom? Help the&#xA;Lord! There is a proverb in our language, &amp;ldquo;Shall we teach the Architect&#xA;of the universe how to build?&amp;rdquo; So those are the highest of mankind who&#xA;do not work. The next time you see these silly phrases about the world&#xA;and how we must all help God and do this or that for Him, remember this.&#xA;Do not think such thoughts; they are too selfish. All the work you do is&#xA;subjective, is done for your own benefit. God has not fallen into a&#xA;ditch for you and me to help Him out by building a hospital or something&#xA;of that sort. He allows you to work. He &lt;em&gt;allows&lt;/em&gt; you to exercise your&#xA;muscles in this great gymnasium, not in order to help Him but that you&#xA;may help yourself. Do you think even an ant will die for want of your&#xA;help? Most arrant blasphemy! The world does not need you at all. The&#xA;world goes on you are like a drop in the ocean. A leaf does not move,&#xA;the wind does not blow without Him. Blessed are we that we are given the&#xA;privilege of working for Him, not of helping Him. Cut out this word&#xA;&amp;ldquo;help&amp;rdquo; from your mind. You cannot help; it is blaspheming. You are here&#xA;yourself at His pleasure. Do you mean to say, you help Him? You worship.&#xA;When you give a morsel of food to the dog, you worship the dog as God.&#xA;God is in that dog. He is the dog. He is all and in all. We are allowed&#xA;to worship Him. Stand in that reverent attitude to the whole universe,&#xA;and then will come perfect non-attachment. This should be your duty.&#xA;This is the proper attitude of work. This is the secret taught by&#xA;Karma-Yoga.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>373 WORK WITHOUT MOTIVE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/373_work_without_motive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/373_work_without_motive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-without-motive&#34;&gt;WORK WITHOUT MOTIVE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the forty-second meeting of the Ramakrishna Mission held at the&#xA;premises No. 57 Rāmkānta Bose Street, Baghbazar, Calcutta, on the 20th&#xA;March, 1898, Swami Vivekananda gave an address on &amp;ldquo;Work without Motive&amp;rdquo;,&#xA;and spoke to the following effect:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the Gita was first preached, there was then going on a great&#xA;controversy between two sects. One party considered the Vedic Yajnas and&#xA;animal sacrifices and such like Karmas to constitute the whole of&#xA;religion. The other preached that the killing of numberless horses and&#xA;cattle cannot be called religion. The people belonging to the latter&#xA;party were mostly Sannyāsins and followers of Jnāna. They believed that&#xA;the giving up of all work and the gaining of the knowledge of the Self&#xA;was the only path to Moksha By the preaching of His great doctrine of&#xA;work without motive, the Author of the Gita set at rest the disputes of&#xA;these two antagonistic sects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>374 SADHANAS OR PREPARATIONS FOR HIGHER LIFE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/374_sadhanas_or_preparations_for_higher_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/374_sadhanas_or_preparations_for_higher_life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;sadhanas-or-preparations-for-higher-life&#34;&gt;SADHANAS OR PREPARATIONS FOR HIGHER LIFE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If atavism gains, you go down; if evolution gains, you go on. Therefore,&#xA;we must not allow atavism to take place. Here, in my own body, is the&#xA;first work of the study. We are too busy trying to mend the ways of our&#xA;neighbours, that is the difficulty. We must begin with our own bodies.&#xA;The heart, the liver, etc., are all atavistic; bring them back into&#xA;consciousness, control them, so that they will obey your commands and&#xA;act up to your wishes. There was a time when we had control of the&#xA;liver; we could shake the whole skin, as can the cow. I have seen many&#xA;people bring the control back by sheer hard practice. Once an impress is&#xA;made, it is there. Bring back all the submerged activities — the vast&#xA;ocean of action. This is the first part of the great study, and it is&#xA;absolutely necessary for our social well-being. On the other hand, only&#xA;the consciousness need not be studied all the time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>375 THE COSMOS AND THE SELF</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/375_the_cosmos_and_the_self/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/375_the_cosmos_and_the_self/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-cosmos-and-the-self&#34;&gt;THE COSMOS AND THE SELF&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everything in nature rises from some fine seed-forms, becomes grosser&#xA;and grosser, exists for a certain time, and again goes back to the&#xA;original fine form. Our earth, for instance, has come out of a nebulous&#xA;form which, becoming colder and colder, turned into this crystallised&#xA;planet upon which we live, and in the future it will again go to pieces&#xA;and return to its rudimentary nebulous form. This is happening in the&#xA;universe, and has been through time immemorial. This is the whole&#xA;history of man, the whole history of nature, the whole history of life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>376 WHO IS A REAL GURU?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/376_who_is_a_real_guru/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/376_who_is_a_real_guru/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-a-real-guru&#34;&gt;WHO IS A REAL GURU?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A real Guru is one who is born from time to time as a repository of&#xA;spiritual force which he transmits to future generations through&#xA;successive links of Guru and Shishya (disciple). The current of this&#xA;spirit-force changes its course from time to time, just as a mighty&#xA;stream of water opens up a new channel and leaves the old one for good.&#xA;Thus it is seen that old sects of religion grow lifeless in the course&#xA;of time, and new sects arise with the fire of life in them. Men who are&#xA;truly wise commit themselves to the mercy of that particular sect&#xA;through which the current of life flows. Old forms of religion are like&#xA;the skeletons of once mighty animals, preserved in museums. They should&#xA;be regarded with the due honour. They cannot satisfy the true cravings&#xA;of the soul for the Highest, just as a dead mango-tree cannot satisfy&#xA;the cravings of a man for luscious mangoes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>377 ON ART</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/377_on_art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/377_on_art/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-art&#34;&gt;ON ART&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The secret of Greek Art is its imitation of nature even to the minutest&#xA;details; whereas the secret of Indian Art is to represent the ideal. The&#xA;energy of the Greek painter is spent in perhaps painting a piece of&#xA;flesh, and he is so successful that a dog is deluded into taking it to&#xA;be a real bit of meat and so goes to bite it. Now, what glory is there&#xA;in merely imitating nature? Why not place an actual bit of flesh before&#xA;the dog?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>378 ON LANGUAGE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/378_on_language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/378_on_language/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-language&#34;&gt;ON LANGUAGE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simplicity is the secret. My ideal of language is my Master&amp;rsquo;s language,&#xA;most colloquial and yet most expressive. It must express the thought&#xA;which is intended to be conveyed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The attempt to make the Bengali language perfect in so short a time will&#xA;make it cut and dried. Properly speaking, it has no verbs. Michael&#xA;Madhusudan Dutt attempted to remedy this in poetry. The greatest poet in&#xA;Bengal was Kavikankana. The best prose in Sanskrit is Patanjali&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Mahābhāshya&lt;/em&gt;. There the language is vigorous. The language of&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Hitopadesha&lt;/em&gt; is not bad, but the language of &lt;em&gt;Kādambari&lt;/em&gt; is an example&#xA;of degradation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>379 THE SANNYASIN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/379_the_sannyasin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/379_the_sannyasin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-sannyasin&#34;&gt;THE SANNYASIN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In explanation of the term Sannyāsin, the Swami in the course of one of&#xA;his lectures in Boston said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When a man has fulfilled the duties and obligations of that stage of&#xA;life in which he is born, and his aspirations lead him to seek a&#xA;spiritual life and to abandon altogether the worldly pursuits of&#xA;possession, fame, or power, when, by the growth of insight into the&#xA;nature of the world, he sees its impermanence, its strife, its misery,&#xA;and the paltry nature of its prizes, and turns away from all these —&#xA;then he seeks the True, the Eternal Love, the Refuge. He makes complete&#xA;renunciation (Sannyāsa) of all worldly position, property, and name, and&#xA;wanders forth into the world to live a life of self-sacrifice and to&#xA;persistently seek spiritual knowledge, striving to excel in love and&#xA;compassion and to acquire lasting insight. Gaining these pearls of&#xA;wisdom by years of meditation, discipline, and inquiry, he in his turn&#xA;becomes a teacher and hands on to disciples, lay or professed, who may&#xA;seek them from him, all that he can of wisdom and beneficence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>380 THE SANNYASIN AND THE HOUSEHOLDER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/380_the_sannyasin_and_the_householder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/380_the_sannyasin_and_the_householder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-sannyasin-and-the-householder&#34;&gt;THE SANNYASIN AND THE HOUSEHOLDER&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The men of the world should have no voice in the affairs of the&#xA;Sannyāsins. The Sannyasin should have nothing to do with the rich, his&#xA;duty is with the poor. He should treat the poor with loving care and&#xA;serve them joyfully with all his might. To pay respects to the rich and&#xA;hang on them for support has been the bane of all the Sannyasin&#xA;communities of our country. A true Sannyasin should scrupulously avoid&#xA;that. Such conduct becomes a public woman rather than one who professes&#xA;to have renounced the world. How should a man immersed in Kāma-Kānchana&#xA;(lust and greed) become a devotee of one whose central ideal is the&#xA;renunciation of Kama-Kanchana? Shri Ramakrishna wept and prayed to the&#xA;Divine Mother to send him such a one to talk with as would not have in&#xA;him the slightest tinge of Kama-Kanchana; for he would say, &amp;ldquo;My lips&#xA;burn when I talk with the worldly-minded.&amp;rdquo; He also used to say that he&#xA;could not even bear the touch of the worldly-minded and the impure. That&#xA;King of Sannyasins (Shri Ramakrishna) can never be preached by men of&#xA;the world. The latter can never be perfectly sincere; for he cannot but&#xA;have some selfish motives to serve. If Bhagavān (God) incarnates Himself&#xA;as a householder, I can never believe Him to be sincere. When a&#xA;householder takes the position of the leader of a religious sect, he&#xA;begins to serve his own interests in the name of principle, hiding the&#xA;former in the garb of the latter, and the result is the sect becomes&#xA;rotten to the core. All religious movements headed by householders have&#xA;shared the same fate. Without renunciation religion can never stand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>381 THE EVILS OF ADHIKARIVADA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/381_the_evils_of_adhikarivada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/381_the_evils_of_adhikarivada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-evils-of-adhikarivada&#34;&gt;THE EVILS OF ADHIKARIVADA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In one of his question classes the talk drifted on to the Adhikārivāda,&#xA;or the doctrine of special rights and privileges, and Swamiji in&#xA;pointing out vehemently the evils that have resulted from it spoke to&#xA;the following effect:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With all my respects for the Rishis of yore, I cannot but denounce their&#xA;method in instructing the people. They always enjoined upon them to do&#xA;certain things but took care never to explain to them the reason for it.&#xA;This method was pernicious to the very core; and instead of enabling men&#xA;to attain the end, it laid upon their shoulders a mass of meaningless&#xA;nonsense. Their excuse for keeping the end hidden from view was that the&#xA;people could not have understood their real meaning even if they had&#xA;presented it to them, not being worthy recipients. The Adhikarivada is&#xA;the outcome of pure selfishness. They knew that by this enlightenment on&#xA;their special subject they would lose their superior position of&#xA;instructors to the people. Hence their endeavour to support this theory.&#xA;If you consider a man too weak to receive these lessons, you should try&#xA;the more to teach and educate him; you should give him the advantage of&#xA;more teaching, instead of less, to train up his intellect, so as to&#xA;enable him to comprehend the more subtle problems. These advocates of&#xA;Adhikarivada ignored the tremendous fact of the infinite possibilities&#xA;of the human soul. Every man is capable of receiving knowledge if it is&#xA;imparted in his own language. A teacher who cannot convince others&#xA;should weep on account of his own inability to teach the people in their&#xA;own language, instead of cursing them and dooming them to live in&#xA;ignorance and superstition, setting up the plea that the higher&#xA;knowledge is not for them. Speak out the truth boldly, without any fear&#xA;that it will puzzle the weak. Men are selfish; they do not want others&#xA;to come up to the same level of their knowledge, for fear of losing&#xA;their own privilege and prestige over others. Their contention is that&#xA;the knowledge of the highest spiritual truths will bring about confusion&#xA;in the understanding of the weak-minded men, and so the Shloka goes:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>382 ON BHAKTI-YOGA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/382_on_bhakti-yoga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/382_on_bhakti-yoga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-bhakti-yoga&#34;&gt;ON BHAKTI-YOGA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The dualist thinks you cannot be moral unless you have a God with a rod&#xA;in His hand, ready to punish you. How is that? Suppose a horse had to&#xA;give us a lecture on morality, one of those very wretched cab-horses who&#xA;move only with the whip, to which he has become accustomed. He begins to&#xA;speak about human beings and says that they must be very immoral. Why?&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Because I know they are not whipped regularly.&amp;rdquo; The fear of the whip&#xA;only makes one more immoral.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>383 ISHVARA AND BRAHMAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/383_ishvara_and_brahman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/383_ishvara_and_brahman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ishvara-and-brahman&#34;&gt;ISHVARA AND BRAHMAN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In reply to a question as to the exact position of Ishvara in Vedantic&#xA;Philosophy, the Swami Vivekananda, while in Europe, gave the following&#xA;definition:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ishvara is the sum total of individuals, yet He is an Individual, as&#xA;the human body is a unit, of which each cell is an individual. Samashti&#xA;or collected equals God; Vyashti or analysed equals the Jiva. The&#xA;existence of Ishvara, therefore, depends on that of Jiva, as the body on&#xA;the cell, and vice versa. Thus, Jiva and Ishvara are coexistent beings;&#xA;when one exists, the other must. Also, because, except on our earth, in&#xA;all the higher spheres, the amount of good being vastly in excess of the&#xA;amount of evil, the sum total (Ishvara) may be said to be all-good.&#xA;Omnipotence and omniscience are obvious qualities and need no argument&#xA;to prove from the very fact of totality. Brahman is beyond both these&#xA;and is not a conditioned state; it is the only Unit not composed of many&#xA;units, the principle which runs through all from a cell to God, without&#xA;which nothing can exist; and whatever is real is that principle, or&#xA;Brahman. When I think I am Brahman, I alone exist; so with others.&#xA;Therefore, each one is the whole of that principle.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>384 ON JNANA-YOGA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/384_on_jnana-yoga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/384_on_jnana-yoga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-jnana-yoga&#34;&gt;ON JNANA-YOGA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All souls are playing, some consciously, some unconsciously. Religion is&#xA;learning to play consciously.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The same law which holds good in our worldly life also holds good in our&#xA;religious life and in the life of the cosmos. It is one, it is&#xA;universal. It is not that religion is guided by one law and the world by&#xA;another. The flesh and the devil are but degrees of difference from God&#xA;Himself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>385 THE CAUSE OF ILLUSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/385_the_cause_of_illusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/385_the_cause_of_illusion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-cause-of-illusion&#34;&gt;THE CAUSE OF ILLUSION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The question — what is the cause of Māyā (illusion)? — has been asked&#xA;for the last three thousand years; and the only answer is: when the&#xA;world is able to formulate a logical question, we shall answer it. The&#xA;question is contradictory. Our position is that the Absolute has become&#xA;this relative only apparently, that the Unconditioned has become the&#xA;conditioned only in Maya. By the very admission of the Unconditioned, we&#xA;admit that the Absolute cannot be acted upon by anything else. It is&#xA;uncaused, which means that nothing outside Itself can act upon It. First&#xA;of all, if It is unconditioned, It cannot have been acted upon by&#xA;anything else. In the Unconditioned there cannot be time, space, or&#xA;causation. That granted your question will be: &amp;ldquo;What caused that which&#xA;cannot be caused by anything to be changed into this?&amp;rdquo; Your question is&#xA;only possible in the conditioned. But you take it out of the&#xA;conditioned, and want to ask it in the Unconditioned. Only when the&#xA;Unconditioned becomes conditioned, and space, time, and causation come&#xA;in, can the question be asked. We can only say ignorance makes the&#xA;illusion. The question is impossible. Nothing can have worked on the&#xA;Absolute. There was no cause. Not that we do not know, or that we are&#xA;ignorant; but It is above knowledge, and cannot be brought down to the&#xA;plane of knowledge. We can use the words, &amp;ldquo;I do not know&amp;rdquo; in two senses.&#xA;In one way, they mean that we are lower than knowledge, and in the other&#xA;way, that the thing is above knowledge. The X-rays have become known&#xA;now. The very causes of these are disputed, but we are sure that we&#xA;shall know them. Here we can say we do not know about the X-rays. But&#xA;about the Absolute we cannot know. In the case of the X-rays we do not&#xA;know, although they are within the range of knowledge; only we do not&#xA;know them yet. But, in the other case, It is so much beyond know ledge&#xA;that It ceases to be a matter of knowing. &amp;ldquo;By what means can the Knower&#xA;be known?&amp;rdquo; You are always yourself and cannot objectify yourself. This&#xA;was one of the arguments used by our philosophers to prove immortality.&#xA;If I try to think I am lying dead, what have I to imagine? That I am&#xA;standing and looking down at myself, at some dead body. So that I cannot&#xA;objectify myself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>386 EVOLUTION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/386_evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/386_evolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;evolution&#34;&gt;EVOLUTION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Some of the topics which precede and follow are taken from the answers&#xA;given by the Swami to questions&lt;br&gt;&#xA;at afternoon talks with Harvard students on March 22 and 24, 1896.&#xA;There have also been added notes and selections from unpublished&#xA;lectures and discourses.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the matter of the projection of Akāsha and Prāna into manifested form&#xA;and the return to fine state, there is a good deal of similarity between&#xA;Indian thought and modern science. The moderns have their evolution, and&#xA;so have the Yogis. But I think that the Yogis&amp;rsquo; explanation of evolution&#xA;is the better one. &amp;ldquo;The change of one species into another is attained&#xA;by the infilling of nature.&amp;rdquo; The basic idea is that we are changing from&#xA;one species to another, and that man is the highest species. Patanjali&#xA;explains this &amp;ldquo;infilling of nature&amp;rdquo; by the simile of peasants irrigating&#xA;fields. Our education and progression simply mean taking away the&#xA;obstacles, and by its own nature the divinity will manifest itself. This&#xA;does away with all the struggle for existence. The miserable experiences&#xA;of life are simply in the way, and can be eliminated entirely. They are&#xA;not necessary for evolution. Even if they did not exist, we should&#xA;progress. It is in the very nature of things to manifest themselves. The&#xA;momentum is not from outside, but comes from inside. Each soul is the&#xA;sum total of the universal experiences already coiled up there; and of&#xA;all these experiences, only those will come out which find suitable&#xA;circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>387 BUDDHISM AND VEDANTA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/387_buddhism_and_vedanta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/387_buddhism_and_vedanta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;buddhism-and-vedanta&#34;&gt;BUDDHISM AND VEDANTA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Vedanta philosophy is the foundation of Buddhism and everything else&#xA;in India; but what we call the Advaita philosophy of the modern school&#xA;has a great many conclusions of the Buddhists. Of course, the Hindus&#xA;will not admit that — that is the orthodox Hindus, because to them the&#xA;Buddhists are heretics. But there is a conscious attempt to stretch out&#xA;the whole doctrine to include the heretics also.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>388 ON THE VEDANTA PHILOSOPHY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/388_on_the_vedanta_philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/388_on_the_vedanta_philosophy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-the-vedanta-philosophy&#34;&gt;ON THE VEDANTA PHILOSOPHY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Vedantist says that a man is neither born nor dies nor goes to&#xA;heaven, and that reincarnation is really a myth with regard to the soul.&#xA;The example is given of a book being turned over. It is the book that&#xA;evolves, not the man. Every soul is omnipresent, so where can it come or&#xA;go? These births and deaths are changes in nature which we are mistaking&#xA;for changes in us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>389 LAW AND FREEDOM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/389_law_and_freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/389_law_and_freedom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;law-and-freedom&#34;&gt;LAW AND FREEDOM&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The struggle never had meaning for the man who is free. But for us it&#xA;has a meaning, because it is name-and-form that creates the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have a place for struggle in the Vedanta, but not for fear. All fears&#xA;will vanish when you begin to assert your own nature. If you think that&#xA;you are bound, bound you will remain. If you think you are free, free&#xA;you will be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>390 THE GOAL AND METHODS OF REALISATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/390_the_goal_and_the_methods_of_realisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/390_the_goal_and_the_methods_of_realisation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-goal-and-methods-of-realisation&#34;&gt;THE GOAL AND METHODS OF REALISATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The greatest misfortune to befall the world would be if all mankind were&#xA;to recognise and accept but one religion, one universal form of worship,&#xA;one standard of morality. This would be the death-blow to all religious&#xA;and spiritual progress. Instead of trying to hasten this disastrous&#xA;event by inducing persons, through good or evil methods, to conform to&#xA;our own highest ideal of truth, we ought rather to endeavour to remove&#xA;all obstacles which prevent men from developing in accordance with their&#xA;own highest ideals, and thus make their attempt vain to establish one&#xA;universal religion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>391 WORLD-WIDE UNITY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/391_world-wide_unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/391_world-wide_unity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;world-wide-unity&#34;&gt;WORLD-WIDE UNITY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the world-wide unity, before the Oak Beach Christian Unity,&#xA;Swami Vivekananda said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All religions are, at the bottom, alike. This is so, although the&#xA;Christian Church, like the Pharisee in the parable, thanks God that it&#xA;alone is right and thinks that all other religions are wrong and in need&#xA;of Christian light. Christianity must become tolerant before the world&#xA;will be willing to unite with the Christian Church in a common charity.&#xA;God has not left Himself without a witness in any heart, and men,&#xA;especially men who follow Jesus Christ, should be willing to admit this.&#xA;In fact, Jesus Christ was willing to admit every good man to the family&#xA;of God. It is not the man who believes a certain something, but the man&#xA;who does the will of the Father in heaven, who is right. On this basis —&#xA;being right and doing right — the whole world can unite.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>392 THE AIM OF RAJA-YOGA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/392_the_aim_of_raja-yoga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_5/notes_from_lectures_and_discourses/392_the_aim_of_raja-yoga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-aim-of-raja-yoga&#34;&gt;THE AIM OF RAJA-YOGA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yoga has essentially to do with the meditative side of religion, rather&#xA;than the ethical side, though, of necessity, a little of the latter has&#xA;to be considered. Men and women are growing to desire more than mere&#xA;revelation, so called. They want facts in their own consciousness. Only&#xA;through experience can there be any reality in religion. Spiritual facts&#xA;are to be gathered mostly from the superconscious state of mind. Let us&#xA;put ourselves into the same condition as did those who claim to have had&#xA;special experiences; then if we have similar experiences, they become&#xA;facts for us. We can see all that another has seen; a thing that&#xA;happened once can happen again, nay, &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt;, under the same&#xA;circumstances. Raja-Yoga teaches us how to reach the superconscious&#xA;state. All the great religions recognise this state in some form; but in&#xA;India, special attention is paid to this side of religion. In the&#xA;beginning, some mechanical means may help us to acquire this state; but&#xA;mechanical means alone can never accomplish much. Certain positions,&#xA;certain modes of breathing, help to harmonise and concentrate the mind,&#xA;but with these must go purity and strong desire for God, or realisation.&#xA;The attempt to sit down and fix the mind on one idea and hold it there&#xA;will prove to most people that there is some need for help to enable&#xA;them to do this successfully. The mind has to be gradually and&#xA;systematically brought under control. The will has to be strengthened by&#xA;slow, continuous, and persevering drill. This is no child&amp;rsquo;s play, no fad&#xA;to be tried one day and discarded the next. It is a life&amp;rsquo;s work; and the&#xA;end to be attained is well worth all that it can cost us to reach it;&#xA;being nothing less than the realisation of our absolute oneness with the&#xA;Divine. Surely, with this end in view, and with the knowledge that we&#xA;can certainly succeed, no price can be too great to pay.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
