<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The battle of Haldighat</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/MT/2006-09-13_the-battle-of-haldighat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/MT/2006-09-13_the-battle-of-haldighat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/09/13/the-battle-of-haldighat/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;inspiration&#34;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the tragic battles that represents the epitome of the valiant struggle of Hindu rulers against the numerically superior Moslem armies buttressed by the quintessential Hindu traitors was the battle of Haldighat. It stands for that great freedom strugglecloser to the imperial capital of the country (relative to those in the south) occupied by the Moslem tyrants since Ghori’s invasions. Many years ago, when I was still a kid I received from my father a gift of a stone from Rajastancoming from theHaldighat geological horizon. Its yellow powdery consistency and the history behind the place left a profound impression on me and not a day was spent without enacting scenes from the great Hindu struggle in our evening games. I felt an urge to retell (I am sure it has been retold a hundred other times by hundred other people) some of this story on June 18th but have only reached thus far:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Akbar’s self-glorification</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/MT/2004-07-03_akbars-self-glorification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/MT/2004-07-03_akbars-self-glorification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/07/03/akbars-self-glorification/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No Hindu should forget the deaths of the valiant Rai Jaimal Rathore and Pratap Sisodia (Patta). A comparison of the Hindu chronicles of the Rathores of Badnor and Akbar’s Fathnamah reveals a discrepancy that I believe is a creation of Akbar. Of course the secularists who have penned the modern Indian history texts have whole-heartedly accepted Akbar’s narrative as they fall in the line of providing an Islamic narrative for Indian history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The conquest of Nagor</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/MT/2004-06-23_the-conquest-of-nagor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/MT/2004-06-23_the-conquest-of-nagor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/06/23/the-conquest-of-nagor/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nagor had been occupied by the Mohammedans after Khalji’s dreaded acts and it passed into the hands of the Khans of Gujarat related to the Turkic Qara U’nas tribe [To which the great Amirs of the Southern alliance like Qazaghan and Mir Hussain belonged]. The Khan of Nagor was the fierce Firoz Khan, a terror of Hindus, who died in 1454. On the death of Firoz, his son Shams Khan ascended the gaddi. But he was shortly thereafter thrown out by his brother Mujahid, who tried to assasinate him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bappa rAval</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/MT/bappa-rAval/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/MT/bappa-rAval/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1885928611921703228&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The guhila-s or the descendants of king guhadatta are probably one of the most remarkable dynasties of post-gupta India. While neither expansive in imperial terms nor widely remembered for their architectural splendors, they are perhaps foremost in representing the Hindu spirit of survival in face of the Islamic Jihads. Their heroic defense of the dharma inspired the later marAThA ruler shivAjI and the peshva bAjIrAv. How they came into being is somewhat shrouded in mystery, but they have consistently held themselves as a brahma-kShatra clan, i.e., brAhmaNa lineage with shaiva affiliations that took to the way of kShatriya-s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>choDa-siMha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/MT/choDa-siMha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/MT/choDa-siMha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1885950695750115805&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The arbuda, Ranpur and Kumbhalgarh inscriptions mention a guhila king choDa/choDasiMha who ruled ~1127-1138 CE. Me and a friend had a discussion about the origin of his name. It depends on whether you take it to be tatpuruSha or bahuvrIhi (sic).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One possibility is that he was lion to the chora-s (thieves).&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The other possibility is that he was a lion of the choDa-s i.e., the choLa-s. In favor of this in the mount arbuda inscription his name is just choDa. This would then be a case of the fame of the choLa-s reaching the north to become a personal name. From 980-1070 was the 90 year acme of the choLa empire. It is conceivable that the memory of their great kings like rAjarAja, rAjendra and rAjAdhirAja was behind the epithet, the lion of the choDa-s. Much later a marAThA ghorpaDa bahAdur was also named choLarAja. They were distant relatives of mahArAja shivAjI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zn mining</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/MT/zn-mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/rAjaputra/sisodiya/articles/MT/zn-mining/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1885941416263602307&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sAmoli inscription from ~646CE mentions the guhila king shIlAditya and a band of rich V3s led by jentaka shreShThin had settled in his kingdom. They started a mine at araNayakUpagiri. It is not clear what they were mining, but based on the geology they were probably mining Zn (/&amp;amp;Pb). The said V3 is mentioned as having built a temple to vanadurgA in the region, a deity who continued to be worshiped in Mewar&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
