<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apostacy technique summary</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/apostacy-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/apostacy-summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1443493771149135880&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1443493771149135880&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Japanese tortured catholic missionaries with a technique called anatsurushi (穴吊るし) or &amp;ldquo;hole hanging&amp;rdquo; in which christian priests were hung upside down in a pit of faeces. This was done to prolong suffering &amp;amp; make the priest give up Christianity. This had a lot of success. This method of prolong suffering was so successful that Father Cristovão Ferreira, the highest ranking priest of the Society of Jesuits gave up faith. He was then made to marry a Japanese, given a Japanese name &amp;amp; made to cooperate with interrogation of Japanese Kirishitans.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christian inconoclasm</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/christian-inconoclasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/christian-inconoclasm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://brill.com/view/journals/jemh/25/3/article-p163_1.xml?language=en&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Many Meanings of Iconoclasm: Warrior and Christian Temple-Shrine Destruction in Late Sixteenth Century Japan&lt;br&gt;&#xA;In: Journal of Early Modern History&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Author: Alan Strathern&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The conversion of certain warlords in Kyushu, Japan, (1560–1580 CE) represents one of the most important breakthroughs for Christianity in the early modern world, and it was accompanied by striking acts of destruction of the local sacred sites and objects. Yet shrine and temple destruction had already become a relatively commonplace feature of warfare in this period of internecine struggle, exemplified by the activities of Oda Nobunaga. How was the iconoclasm of Christian converts interpreted in this context? This article is particularly concerned with the implications of iconoclasm for a raging struggle of “empirical religiosity” – in which Christians and their opponents argued about the immanent power of the gods and their capacity to take revenge on iconoclasts. It also suggests that prevailing Buddhist and Confucian discourses presented important limits to how damaging such empirical arguments were to local religion. These issues are also explored in relation to the case of the Christianizing Ōtomo house, and their relations with the important Usa Hachiman shrine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>christian-wanted-notice</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/christian-wanted-notice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/christian-wanted-notice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A WANTED NOTICE FOR CHRISTIANS - JAPAN, 1711.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a Kirishitan Kosatsu, an official public notice offering a substantial cash reward for the identification and capture of Christians converts in early 18th century Japan, a time of brutal state-persecution of the faith.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sign reads&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Regulation. If anyone knows of Christian disciples, already banned, please report to the Government.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Rewards are as below:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Missionary: 500 silver coins.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Priests: 300 silver coins.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Christian disciples: 300 silver coins.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Anyone knowingly living with a Christian: 100 silver coins.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;If a family member identifies a Christian within his family, the reward is 500 silver coins.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Anyone identified as having hidden a Christian will bear responsibility along with his landlord. May 1711.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Costa oliveira iyasu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/costa-oliveira_iyasu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/costa-oliveira_iyasu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redalyc.org/pdf/361/36100703.pdf&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bulletin of Portuguese - Japanese Studies&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Universidade Nova de Lisboa&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Portugal&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Costa Oliveira e, João Paulo&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Tokugawa Ieyasu and the Christian Daimyó during the Crisis Of 1600&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The process of the political reunification of the Japanese Empire &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; underwent its last great crisis in the period between the death of Toyotomi Hideyoshi 豊臣秀吉 (1536-1598),&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in September 1598, and the Battle of Sekigahara, in October 1600. The entire process was at risk of being aborted, which could have resulted in the country lapsing back into the state of civil war and anarchy in which it had lived for more than a century.4 However, an individual by the name of Tokugawa Ieyasu 徳川家康 (1543-1616) 5 shrewdly took advantage of the hesitation shown by many of his rivals and the military weakness or lack of strategic vision on the part of others to take control of the Japanese Empire, which would remain in the hands of his family for more than 250 years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>hideyoshi to coelho</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/hideyoshi_to_coelho/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/hideyoshi_to_coelho/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He sent messengers this time to Padre Coelho demanding his immediate reply to the following for questions:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Why do you missionaries so anxiously, even forcefully, try to make converts?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Why do you destroy Shinto shrines and Buddhist temples and persecute monks instead of being conciliatory to them?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Why do you do such unreasonable things as eat useful animals like horses and cows that serve people?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Why do the Portuguese buy many Japanese and take them to their country as slaves?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Source: Japan&amp;rsquo;s Encounter With Christianity: The Catholic Mission in Pre- Modern Japan by Neil S. Fujita, p. 112&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iconoclasm meanings</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/iconoclasm-meanings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/iconoclasm-meanings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Many Meanings of Iconoclasm: Warrior and Christian Temple-Shrine Destruction in Late Sixteenth Century Japan&lt;br&gt;&#xA;In: Journal of Early Modern History&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Author: Alan Strathern&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://brill.com/view/journals/jemh/25/3/article-p163_1.xml&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The conversion of certain warlords in Kyushu, Japan, (1560–1580 CE) represents one of the most important breakthroughs for Christianity in the early modern world, and it was accompanied by striking acts of destruction of the local sacred sites and objects. Yet shrine and temple destruction had already become a relatively commonplace feature of warfare in this period of internecine struggle, exemplified by the activities of Oda Nobunaga. How was the iconoclasm of Christian converts interpreted in this context? This article is particularly concerned with the implications of iconoclasm for a raging struggle of “empirical religiosity” – in which Christians and their opponents argued about the immanent power of the gods and their capacity to take revenge on iconoclasts. It also suggests that prevailing Buddhist and Confucian discourses presented important limits to how damaging such empirical arguments were to local religion. These issues are also explored in relation to the case of the Christianizing Ōtomo house, and their relations with the important Usa Hachiman shrine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ieyesu_to_novaspania 1612</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/ieyesu_to_novaspania_contra-proselytization_1612/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/ieyesu_to_novaspania_contra-proselytization_1612/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To His Excellency the Ruler of Novispania.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your fragrant epistle is before me, and I have perused it without delay. The presents also I have received safely according to the invoice. During the past year the merchants of your honored country have been shipwrecked here from time to time owing to the severe gales on our shores. I have sent them back to you again, and rejoice to hear that they arrived safely. Your honored country and mine are thus strengthening the bonds of friendship, and if ships come every year and exchange the valuable commodities of our two territories even the best government cannot equal the benefit that will ensue to the land and its people. But this land is a Divine country. Since the beginning it has reverenced the Gods and respected the Buddhas. For these Gods and Buddhas are in reality one and the same, being but original form and extraneous manifestation. In the way of loyalty between lord and retainer, and in making firm and trustworthy agreements between the rulers of provinces the Deities are adjured to be witnesses of their faith. And those who do right they reward and those who do evil they punish. Their wondrous efficacy is as plain as an outstretched palm. Is not this the way of Benevolence, Duty, Etiquette, Knowledge, and Sincerity. But the religion that your honored country uses has tendencies of quite a different kind. There seems to be no affinity with anything in this land. In our texts it is written: &amp;ldquo;People of no affinity are difficult to estimate,&amp;rdquo; so that as regards propaganda on reflection it seems better to cease from it and employ it no more. But the mutually profitable trade that will follow the arrival of merchant vessels is in the highest degree desirable. Therefore we have no objection to your ships calling at any port in any of our provinces. I have given strict orders to this effect to my officers, so set your mind at rest and banish all suspicion and doubt. I send you some products of this country in the accompanying package, which I trust you will accept. Pray take care of yourself in the increasing heat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jesuit slave trade</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/jesuit-slave-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/jesuit-slave-trade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A short description of the Jesuit compound at Morisaki in Nagasaki in the 1580s, during the time of the year that the Portuguese carrack was at anchor, also illustrates how central the role of the Jesuits was to the whole trade:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the carrack arrives in Nagasaki, they (the padres) transfer its whole cargo, not just their own but also the merchandise belonging to others, and bring it to their convent, so that the Jesuit compound of Nagasaki is like the Customs House of Sevilla, where all the merchandise that comes from the Indies is registered. There are so many different things, and such a variety of contracts and agreements is entered into here, not only for the merchandise of the carrack but also for the slaves who are shipped in the same vessel, the one as well as the other passing through their hands, that I do not know if there would be more in the Vendution House of Sevilla.12&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temple-certificate</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/temple-certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/temple-certificate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tera Uke Jo no Koto&lt;br&gt;&#xA;1812&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Travelers also had to carry a Temple Certificate issued by a local temple &amp;amp; present it at checkpoints. It certified the bearer was not a Christian.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The above person has, for generations, been a Zen Buddhist and maintained a family temple.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tetsujiro on christianity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/tetsujiro_on_christianity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/tetsujiro_on_christianity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Early in the year a very severe attack was made upon Christianity by Professor Inoue Tetsujiro of the Imperial University. He wrote an article that appeared simultaneously in six Buddhist and one Unitarian magazine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a while it became the subject of controversy in all religious periodicals and to some extent in the secular papers. It was hailed with the greatest joy by Buddhists, and the ablest Christian writers busied themselves in replying to its charges. The following extracts from a synopsis given in the Japan Mail will show the spirit of the article:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
