<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Yew Lee kuan on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Yew Lee kuan on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Japanophilia</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/japanophilia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/japanophilia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw an unforgettable example of how they took pride in their work during a visit in the late 1970s to Takamatsu, a city on the island of Shikoku. The Japanese ambassador gave me dinner at their best but three-star hotel. The food was excellent. For fruit and dessert, a chef in his 30s appeared in immaculate white to demonstrate his skill with a sharp knife, peeling persimmons and crunchy pears. It was a virtuoso performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>singapore-days</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/singapore-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/singapore-days/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; in eradicating corruption. It is said that his brother, a police officer, was corrupt and forced him to resign. During his rule, Singapore created a Housing Board which developed huge colonies of flats built for the poorer and middle classes. It was ensured that the colonies were multi-racial in composition. These colonies are enviable models for third world and developing countries. The Singapore Port and Harbour are equally enviable models for even the most developed countries, with its highly advanced computerisation, containerisation and unbelievably rapid turnround of ships. All this could not have been accomplished without Lee Kuan Yew&amp;rsquo;s autocratic style of functioning, which included a pliable judiciary and a virtual one-party rule. For cosmetic purposes, a couple of anaemic opposition parties were tolerated. However, no one was fooled about the absolute supremacy of the ruling party, the People&amp;rsquo;s Action Party or PAP. In Singapore, free lunches at government expense were anathema. You worked, you earned and you contributed for healthcare, pensions and housing. Some Chinese joked, provided Big Brother was out of earshot and they were not telephoning, that PAP stood for pay and pay and pay and minuscule size of the island Republic was undoubtedly a pass away peacefully! The great help to the PM in establishing an iron grip on his people. With all his genius and sternness, Lee Kuan Yew could not have estabilished his type of rule over even the city of Calcutta or Delhi, in India, due to the enormity of the population, the size and the problems of governance. But this observation does not take away an iota of credit or praise for what Lee Kuan Yew has achieved in Singapore and done for its people. Gradually, the PM did also relax his iron grip, however, imperceptible this was. This is illustrated in another joke that was being quietly told in private. A visiting British Foreign Secretary expressed pleasant surprise to see Lee Kuan Yew&amp;rsquo;s name plate bearing the old British titles &amp;ldquo;CMG, KCMG, GCMG.&amp;rdquo; The PM explained, &amp;ldquo;English titles, like hell. When 1 assumed power I ordered the people to &amp;lsquo;Call Me God&amp;rsquo;. After a decade of strict rule, I could afford to be polite and said, &amp;lsquo;Kindly Call Me God&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo; He was then asked what GCMG stood for. He smiled and said, &amp;ldquo;Now that Singapore has stabilised, God Calls Me God&amp;rdquo;. Lee Kuan Yew had made Goh Chok Tong, a Deputy Prime Minister along with his son Brigadier Lee Hsien Loong. Singaporeans talked about the father&amp;rsquo;s plans to make his son the Prime Minister in due course. The Brigadier was considered intelligent, arrogant and hot headed. He is rumoured to have manhandled Dhanapalan at a Cabinet meeting, shortly after which incident, Dhanapalan resigned from the Government. I, however, doubt the bit about manhandling - tongue lashing may be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>spiegel 2005</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/spiegel_2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/spiegel_2005/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SPIEGEL Interview with Singapore&amp;rsquo;s Lee Kuan Yew&amp;quot;It&amp;rsquo;s Stupid to be Afraid&amp;quot;&#xA;Singapore&amp;rsquo;s first-ever prime minister, long-time government head and current political mentor Lee Kuan Yew talks about Asia&amp;rsquo;s rise to economic power, China&amp;rsquo;s ambitions and the West&amp;rsquo;s chances of staying competitive.&#xA;08.08.2005, 00.00 Uhr&#xA;The elder statesman Lee: &amp;ldquo;We run a meritocracy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The elder statesman Lee: &amp;ldquo;We run a meritocracy.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Foto: DPA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;dl&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;SPIEGEL&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The political and economic center of gravity is moving from the West towards the East. Is Asia becoming the dominant political and economic force in this century?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
