<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०८ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/08/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०८ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/08/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Another mAraNa strike</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/08/2005-08-27_another-marana-strike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/08/2005-08-27_another-marana-strike/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/08/27/another-marana-strike/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The amAtya had warned us that we would face a mAraNa strike anytime.&#xA;Sensing trouble we deployed the arrows of sharva around us. The archers&#xA;surrounded us completely to shield us from the kR^ityA which was to&#xA;strike. We were coursing in the grip of the kR^ityA, without much&#xA;apparent effect. But suddenly the ratha in which we travelled was&#xA;smashed completely. We were glad that the archers had kept us alive and&#xA;we escaped with life, though our ratha was completely smashed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The sleep of dhUmAvatI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/08/2005-08-20_the-sleep-of-dhumavati/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/08/2005-08-20_the-sleep-of-dhumavati/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/08/20/the-sleep-of-dhumavati/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have heard of the nairR^ita spell of dhUmA which overpowers you with tremendous force. Even as we were scanning the horizon for the nirR^iti attack, the spell found its mark on us with the ucChuShma-rudra wings. The torpor it induced was unbearable, we twice fell asleep in the very place in which we were. The spell also has a peculiar effect on the mind- it causes a mental vibration with lingering unpleasant and delusive images from which one cannot break free. It also induces a grave fear of the foe and all manner of bodily aches as it seizes you. Shortly after we awoke from the spell, the khANDvans attacked directly. We simply decided to brush them aside knowing that their power came from the spell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You cannot get away</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/08/2005-08-20_you-cannot-get-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/08/2005-08-20_you-cannot-get-away/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/08/20/you-cannot-get-away/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GK had been a rival of R. R had genuine knowledge, but GK merely&#xA;absorbed everything she read without much analysis or understanding.&#xA;Otherwise they were quite equally matched. GK oozed arrogance, but R&#xA;emanated genuine mental superiority over most. GK always had the ethnic&#xA;advantage in both the lokas, but R was in the “foreigners” category.&#xA;Still R was victorious over GK till the fourth year, after which she&#xA;departed for the quest of “higher glory”. GK had unbridled success after&#xA;the departure of R and soon became a young physician. GK felt elated&#xA;being at the peak of glory, when it is speculated that in the thrill of&#xA;the arrogance of being the most glorious, GK killed a patient&#xA;accidentally. GK was given a severe reprimand, but continued after&#xA;retreating to a little village keeping a low profile. The khaNDavans&#xA;whom we had conquered after a battle last year had made acquaintence&#xA;with GK. GK had apparently forgotten us just as we had forgotten GK.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back in the same place</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/08/2005-08-17_back-in-the-same-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/08/2005-08-17_back-in-the-same-place/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/08/17/back-in-the-same-place/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We were set to return to the same battlefield where we had last year&#xA;fought one of the most disastrous battles of our existence. This&#xA;battlefield was worse than the pAShaNDa hill: there we had lost out&#xA;right, but here we had won the battle and the booty we took home was&#xA;poisoned. It gave us no pleasure to go there but we had to do our part&#xA;in the larger struggle. When we went to tthat field last time our mind&#xA;was filled with a desperate sense of anxiety over the war that was to be&#xA;fought. We had carefully planned every move, and everything went as per&#xA;plan except a strange event which was a actually the shakuna we had&#xA;missed at that time. Our mantras fired in unison and it looked as though&#xA;we were the winners. We did not know the monstrous consequences that&#xA;were waiting for us like a rakSha. The shachiva had seen something amiss&#xA;but failed to alert us sufficiently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the dark zone</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/08/2005-08-14_in-the-dark-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/08/2005-08-14_in-the-dark-zone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/08/14/in-the-dark-zone/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We sat on the edge of the crater of sorrow, defeat and destruction,&#xA;which was much like the crater of a great volcano, with the inferal&#xA;interiors obscured by pumice and granite. We saw many yakShIs, apsaras,&#xA;pishAchis and rAkShasis pass by in silence. We were haunted by the&#xA;memories of the fierce battle at the pAShaNDa hill in our native land in&#xA;2003. It was a demon-haunted world into which we had slipped after that&#xA;battle. The chiefs assembled for the kuriltai, but we could not go there&#xA;because we wanted to avoid any further pain of the same prying&#xA;questions. We summoned the rAkShasas plaguing the internal world and&#xA;asked them what was the cause of this dismal darkness. One of them&#xA;replied: “it was daNDa yuddha which was your undoing.” The other&#xA;replied: “It does not matter whether you failed to use daNDayuddha in&#xA;the battle or not. It was all already destined that you would slip that&#xA;way.” Yet another replied that the rAkShasa mAyAvi was the cause. We&#xA;were drowning in this cacophonies of rAkShasas shouting in the demon&#xA;haunted world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post-khANDavan chaos</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/08/2005-08-14_post-khandavan-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/08/2005-08-14_post-khandavan-chaos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/08/14/post-khandavan-chaos/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We paused for a moment looking out from our high perch into the foggy&#xA;haze of the air around us. The joys of the world it appeared had&#xA;deserted us. The devas had sent the brief respite, but it was all over.&#xA;Why are we here we asked ourselves ?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our mind raced back to the days of war between October-December of the&#xA;year 2004. It was a fairly decisive period, but little did we know what&#xA;the seizure of khANDAva had in store for us. Looking back at the&#xA;correspondence of our amAtya and shachiva, we realized our mistakes with&#xA;20/20 hindsight. It is now clear that we were slipping inexorably&#xA;towards a deadly trap. In this situation is not surprising that the mind&#xA;all recedes to the same period in theyear 2003. The smashing defeat we&#xA;faced on the slopes of the pAShaNDa’s hill had sowed the seeds for the&#xA;future events. Our journey to the ruins of the ancient Jorwe cultures in&#xA;Nevasa had made us wonder who were those people. Then we observed&#xA;Mercury, low beside the horizon. At that point our shachiva was blinded&#xA;and made some mistakes, which embroiled us in the khANDava campaign. But&#xA;now we realized that the conquest of khANDava had brought us to a nadir&#xA;in our history. Everywhere the army was shaking from the multi-pronged&#xA;attacks, the state itself was in utter disarray. We felt that even&#xA;though we were a much better warrior, we were not a better king than our&#xA;sire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The dispatch from the slopes of Mount Kearsarge</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/08/2005-08-05_the-dispatch-from-the-slopes-of-mount-kearsarge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/08/2005-08-05_the-dispatch-from-the-slopes-of-mount-kearsarge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/08/05/the-dispatch-from-the-slopes-of-mount-kearsarge/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We circumambulated the large lake at the base of Mount Kearsarge with&#xA;mlechCha adventurer M. We were separated from the bandhas of samsAra at&#xA;that point. We saw the old va~nga chieftain at the end of it. The&#xA;va~nga had battled our old foe for a long time and outwitted him much&#xA;as we had. He enquired about R1, R2, R3, K1, K2 and S. These brought&#xA;very painful memories to our mind. It was as though we had fallen like&#xA;yayAti. We had mentioned earlier how we fell like yayAti after sporting&#xA;in the groves of the pAShaNDa’s hill in the daNDaka region. Then we&#xA;bored even deeper into pAtAla and then escaped the terrible guillotine&#xA;which we alluded to earlier. But after escaping the guillotine, we had&#xA;fallen into this new trap from which we were not sure there was a way&#xA;out. The va~nga reminded us of it. He asked me the pathway that led to&#xA;R. We illustrated it thus:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
