<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;DV guNDappa profiles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;DV guNDappa profiles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>‘Dharmaprakāśa’ Sajjan Rao (</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/dharmaprakasha-sajjan-rao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/dharmaprakasha-sajjan-rao/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;dharmaprakāśa-sajjan-rao-part-1&#34;&gt;‘Dharmaprakāśa’ Sajjan Rao (Part 1)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[‘Dharmaprakāśa’ Sajjan Rao (Part 1)&#x9;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prekshaa.in/dharmaprakasha-sajjan-rao-part1&#34;&gt;prekshaa&lt;/a&gt;]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Along with Mandi Hariyanna’s name, it is &lt;em&gt;Dharmaprakāśa&lt;/em&gt; S Sajjan Rao’s name that comes to mind.&#xA;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The two were always together, like the &lt;em&gt;Aśvini-devata&lt;/em&gt;s. Every morning, both of them would go for a walk, to get some air. It was the same routine every evening too. Their friendship gave the impression that a single soul existed in two bodies. If any friend encountered only one of them, it was normal to enquire, “How is it that you’re alone? Where is he?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avadhoota Mahadeva Sastri</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/avadhoota-mahadeva-sastri/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/avadhoota-mahadeva-sastri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[[Avadhoota Mahadeva Sastri&#x9;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prekshaa.in/avadhoota-mahadeva-sastri&#34;&gt;prekshaa&lt;/a&gt;]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dharmaprakasha&lt;strong&gt;Sajjan Rao&amp;rsquo;s&lt;a href=&#34;#_edn1&#34;&gt;[i]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; home named, “Lakshmi Nivasa” is located opposite the North East side of the &lt;strong&gt;Venkataramana Swamy Temple&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;Bangalore Fort&lt;/strong&gt;. The verandah of that house sported the photographs of some Sadhus and Sants. Among these photographs was that of an &lt;em&gt;Avadhoota&lt;a href=&#34;#_edn2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[ii]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; named &lt;strong&gt;Mahadeva Sastri&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although I have seen &lt;strong&gt;Mahadeva Sastri&lt;/strong&gt;, I don’t know much about his life. I have enquired at numerous places to learn more about him but didn’t find anyone who could tell me. It appears that he kept the details of his private life to himself. He wasn’t the one to fall in the hands of press reporters or election agents. Remaining obscure, he chose and lived a life of obscurity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dasappa and Varadacharya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/dasappa-and-varadacharya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/dasappa-and-varadacharya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[[Dasappa and Varadacharya&#x9;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prekshaa.in/dasappa-and-varadacharya&#34;&gt;prekshaa&lt;/a&gt;]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A distant relative of mine, who was quite well-to-do and had heard about my academic prowess agreed to provide me with some financial assistance. He, in fact, had seen a potential groom in me. This (his assistance) went on for five to six months. I joined the Fourth Form at the High School in the Maharaja college in Mysuru.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back then, among the teachers who taught in a manner that captured my heart were Bapu Subbaraya and B. Dasappa. Bapu Subbaraya had worked for Kannada literature. Belavadi Dasappa was extraordinary in his elucidation of English literature; he had authored texts in Kannada as well. I have heard from a different source that he was the warden of the college hostel and that, upon the recommendation of Ramadasappa, he had shown quite a lot of interest in my activities. I was to visit Dasappa’s house every Sunday to render the lessons he had taught. He taught us English at school. There were also instances where he provided explanations in Kannada during his lessons. He had great admiration for sports such as billiards, hockey and golf. He harboured an even greater curiosity for horse-riding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hanumantha Rao and Krishnaswamy Iyer</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/Hanumantha-rao-and-krishnaswamy-iyer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/Hanumantha-rao-and-krishnaswamy-iyer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[[Hanumantha Rao and Krishnaswamy Iyer&#x9;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prekshaa.in/Hanumantha-rao-and-krishnaswamy-iyer&#34;&gt;prekshaa&lt;/a&gt;]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My studies in Mysore spanned only seven-eight months. That year (1901) was quite unfortunate for my family. My grandfather had passed away in the year 1900 itself. After that in a short duration, my maternal grandmother, who used to take care of my family like a mother, also passed away. Her brothers, who were taking care of my family after that, also passed away in the next two years. All these unfortunate events worried me a lot. I lost interest in studies. I went back to my native for the holidays, never to come back to Mysore. Next year (1903) I joined the school for 5th form in Kolar itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Ātma-guru: N Narasimha Murthy (</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/narasimha-murthy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/narasimha-murthy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-ātma-guru-n-narasimha-murthy-part-1&#34;&gt;My Ātma-guru: N Narasimha Murthy (Part 1)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[My Ātma-guru: N Narasimha Murthy (Part 1)&#x9;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prekshaa.in/narasimha-murthy-part-1&#34;&gt;prekshaa&lt;/a&gt;]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My intention here is to write about my &lt;em&gt;Ātma-guru&lt;/em&gt;s. &lt;em&gt;Ātma-guru&lt;/em&gt; can mean several things: “The teacher of my choice”, “The teacher who taught me about the &lt;em&gt;Ātman&lt;/em&gt;”, “The teacher of prime importance” etc. The meaning that I have in my mind is: “favorite teacher”. It is not that I found him because I specifically searched for him. Neither did I specifically evaluate his capabilities and hence acquainted myself to him. It is purely out of luck that we got to know each other. I was influenced by him and I thought to myself that I should see such a noble person as a teacher. If I had revealed this to him, he would have disagreed with me outrightly. I considered him as a teacher, but he never treated me like a student.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paṅktipāvana Venkatakrishnaiah - </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/panktipavana-venkatakrishnaiah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/panktipavana-venkatakrishnaiah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;paṅktipāvana-venkatakrishnaiah---part-1&#34;&gt;Paṅktipāvana Venkatakrishnaiah - Part 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[Paṅktipāvana Venkatakrishnaiah - Part 1&#x9;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prekshaa.in/panktipavana-venkatakrishnaiah-part-1&#34;&gt;prekshaa&lt;/a&gt;]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While referring to Sri M. Venkatakrishnaiah we should first respectfully acknowledge the small number of his disciples who were serving him with utmost dedication. That highly devoted bunch extended much needed assistance promptly in the matters of his food, his health, and his public programs. In my opinion, it would not be possible for Sri M. Venkatakrishnaiah to have led such an able and long-lasting life without that devoted resourcefulness of the disciples. From where they came and what their whereabouts are now is unknown. They recognized the greatness and served. Salutations to them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pāśampalli Ādèppa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/pashampalli-adeppa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/pashampalli-adeppa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[[Pāśampalli Ādèppa&#x9;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prekshaa.in/pashampalli-adeppa&#34;&gt;prekshaa&lt;/a&gt;]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was young, I aspired to become a &lt;em&gt;paṭela&lt;/em&gt; (village headman, chief of a town). Not because the position would provide a lot of money. But because a &lt;em&gt;paṭela&lt;/em&gt; is a free man; he need not wait for someone else’s orders. The respect of people for a village headman is immense; all the villagers obey his command.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition to these two attractions, there was another. A headman did not have the burden of schooling; no plight of exams and results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ramadasappa (</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/ramadasappa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/ramadasappa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ramadasappa-part-1&#34;&gt;Ramadasappa (Part 1)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[Ramadasappa (Part 1)&#x9;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prekshaa.in/ramadasappa-part1&#34;&gt;prekshaa&lt;/a&gt;]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ramadasappa was my second teacher who taught me the English language. He was the first person to graduate with a BA degree from Mulbagal. I recall him coming there as the sub-registrar back in 1907. A sad incident occurred after 15-20 days of him assuming charge. Ramadasappa was originally from Mysore. In those days, Mulbagal was a far-off place from Mysore. Hence, to help him get settled, his father Sanjeevayya and his family members accompanied him to Mulbagal. After staying there for fifteen days, on his way back to Mysore, by the time Sanjeevayya reached Bowringpet, he became ill and passed away at the station platform. Ramadasappa had to perform the last rites of his father in Mulbagal itself. For this purpose, when he was at Shankara-tirtha, my father too was present there performing the last rites of my grandfather. Thus, Ramadasappa and my father met each other at a crematorium. Their acquaintance turned into friendship. Ramadasappa was also our neighbor. Between his house and ours there was a choultry. He had to pass in front of our house while going to or returning from his office. My grandfather’s brothers thus became close to Ramadasappa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ramanna’s discipline, affection (</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/ramanna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/ramanna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ramannas-discipline-affection-part-1&#34;&gt;Ramanna’s discipline, affection (Part 1)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[Ramanna’s discipline, affection (Part 1)&#x9;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prekshaa.in/ramanna-part1&#34;&gt;prekshaa&lt;/a&gt;]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ramanna is my &lt;em&gt;Cikka-tāta&lt;/em&gt; (grandfather’s younger brother). Sheikhdar Gundappa’s second son. I had briefly introduced him in my earlier writings. He initially worked as a government employee probably in the excise department and seemed to have saved some of the money he earned during that period. By the time I was born, he was not formally employed. He was self-reliant. A bit of money lending along with a stamp vendor job. As for the basic financial support, he had his father’s ancestral property, and his elder brother Sheshanna’s assistance in case there was a need for extra money &amp;ndash; With just this financial arrangement, he took care of the family responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sheenanna (</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/sheenanna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/sheenanna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;sheenanna-part-1&#34;&gt;Sheenanna (Part 1)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[Sheenanna (Part 1)&#x9;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prekshaa.in/sheenanna-part1&#34;&gt;prekshaa&lt;/a&gt;]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Out of my grandfathers, hasn’t it been evident that my third grandfather Sheenanna was very dear to me? But when it comes to him, will I be able to talk about every facet of his nature without hiding anything? Is it respectable? On the other hand, would it be appropriate if I tell only tell about his acceptable behaviour and skip the rest? Forget about being appropriate; will the readers benefit as much as they would have by my writings? This is the apprehension I have.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>T R Venkatarama Shastri (</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/t-r-venkatarama-shastri/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/t-r-venkatarama-shastri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;t-r-venkatarama-shastri-part-1&#34;&gt;T R Venkatarama Shastri (Part 1)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[T R Venkatarama Shastri (Part 1)&#x9;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prekshaa.in/t-r-venkatarama-shastri-part1&#34;&gt;prekshaa&lt;/a&gt;]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;T R Venkatarama Shastri can be called a disciple of Shivaswami Iyer. Sir S Varadachari, who retired after serving as a Federal Court judge and Venkatarama Shastri both practiced law in Shivaswami Iyer’s office and were assistants to him.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is worth sharing how Venkatarama Shastri was appointed as an intern under Shivaswami Iyer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;eligibility-test&#34;&gt;Eligibility Test&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By the time Shastri passed his BL, Shivaswami Iyer’s fame had spread far and wide. He was also renowned for his erudition. Shastri was particular about starting his career under such scholar and hence took a letter of recommendation from Sitarama Iyer, a relative of Shivaswami Iyer. Though Shastri and Iyer were both &lt;em&gt;drāviḍa brāhmaṇa&lt;/em&gt;s, they belonged to different sects. In the old days, there would be no marital relationships between these sects. Shivaswami Iyer belonged to one among the five or six sub-sects of the &lt;em&gt;Bṛhaccharaṇa&lt;/em&gt; sect. Venkatarama Shastri was from the &lt;em&gt;Coḻa-deśa&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Vaḍama&lt;/em&gt; sect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Flight of a Bird and Godavari Brahmanas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/flight-bird-and-godavari-brahmanas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/flight-bird-and-godavari-brahmanas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[[The Flight of a Bird and Godavari Brahmanas&#x9;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prekshaa.in/flight-bird-and-godavari-brahmanas&#34;&gt;prekshaa&lt;/a&gt;]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;extracts-from-the-preface&#34;&gt;Extracts from the Preface&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The profiles and lives of all the people portrayed in this volume deserve our respect at all times. My attempt here is to show how the people of an era in our country’s history lived, as well as the ideals they believed in. There’s the renowned verse from the Ishwara’s mouth in the &lt;em&gt;Bhagavadgita:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;yadyadācarati śreṣṭhaḥ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;tattadevetaro janaḥ&lt;/em&gt;।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Unalloyed Erudition of M. Hiriyanna</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/unalloyed-erudition-m-hiriyanna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/unalloyed-erudition-m-hiriyanna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[[The Unalloyed Erudition of M. Hiriyanna&#x9;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prekshaa.in/unalloyed-erudition-m-hiriyanna&#34;&gt;prekshaa&lt;/a&gt;]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best biography of Professor &lt;strong&gt;Mysore Hiriyanna&lt;/strong&gt; was written by Professor Mysore Hiriyanna himself not by using a paper and pen but by living life as he did. And that living revealed itself in every single sphere—in his personality, dressing, speech, conduct, values, teaching, and to the world as it knew him, in his writing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are a few samples of his writing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>V N Narasimha Iyengar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/v-n-narasimha-iyengar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/dv-guNDappa-lekhHAH/v-n-narasimha-iyengar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[[V N Narasimha Iyengar&#x9;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prekshaa.in/v-n-narasimha-iyengar&#34;&gt;prekshaa&lt;/a&gt;]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most popular personalities among the old Mysore citizens was one V N Narasimha Iyengar. He was also known as &lt;em&gt;mīsè&lt;/em&gt; (mustachioed) Narasimha Iyengar. The reason was: Narasimha Iyengar was the one who started the tradition of growing a moustache, which was not prevalent among the &lt;em&gt;Śrīvaiṣṇava&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa&lt;/em&gt;s. He was from the &lt;em&gt;Hebbār Śrīvaiṣṇava&lt;/em&gt; community. In the era of British Commissioners, the few who could reach better positions, owing to their educational capability, were largely &lt;em&gt;Hebbār Śrīvaiṣṇava&lt;/em&gt;s. The first who came into prominence was &lt;em&gt;Sāhukār&lt;/em&gt; Garudacharya (Grandfather of &lt;em&gt;Rao Bahadur&lt;/em&gt; Garudacharya), Paimastri Venkatacharya, Kolar’s Deputy Commissioner Krishna Iyengar, &lt;em&gt;Bhakshi&lt;/em&gt; Thimmappa, &lt;em&gt;Bhakshi&lt;/em&gt; Shingappa, B Venkatapathy Iyengar, V N Narasimha Iyengar, and others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
