<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/disease/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/disease/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Obs sleep apnea</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/disease/articles/obstructive-sleep-apnea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/disease/articles/obstructive-sleep-apnea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://unrollthread.com/t/1493936888415244288/&#34;&gt;Abhishek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The passing away of Mr. Bappi Lahri due to Obstructive sleep apnea (OSA) has brought back the limelight to this widely prevalent yet under recognised disease entity. But what exactly is OSA? &amp;amp; How to find out if you have OSA?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OSA is a disorder caused by the repetitive collapse of the upper airway during sleep due to the relaxation of the muscles supporting the soft tissues in your throat, such as your tongue and soft palate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revenue targets - India</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/disease/articles/revenue-targets-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/disease/articles/revenue-targets-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: BMJ&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The unethical revenue targets that India&amp;rsquo;s corporate hospitals set their doctors What can be done about financial targets for doctors working in profit driven hospitals that lead to expensive but unnecessary tests and surgery that also come with risk of harm, asks Meera Kay&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meera kay journalist, Bangalore&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;For seven years I had to bear the burden of doing unnecessary investigations and procedures, including angioplasty, under pressure from the management of the hospital,&amp;rdquo; Gautam Mistry, a cardiologist in Kolkata, told The BMJ.+++(5)+++ What Mistry is describing is one of the best kept secrets of India&amp;rsquo;s private healthcare sector—consultants hired by private hospitals have to meet targets for generating revenue by overprescribing diagnostic tests and avoidable surgeries. No data exist on the prevalence of such targets, and Mistry did not disclose details of what targets he had been set. &amp;ldquo;Significant numbers of patients must be advised to be admitted for surgery or medical procedures that bring in real financial profit for the hospital,&amp;rdquo; explained Kunal Saha, adjunct professor and HIV/AIDS consultant in Ohio, United States, and president of People for Better Treatment, a non-governmental organisation that promotes corruption free healthcare in India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
