<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;raja-yoga on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;raja-yoga on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>015 PREFACE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/015_preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/015_preface/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RAJA-YOGA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;preface&#34;&gt;PREFACE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the dawn of history, various extraordinary phenomena have been&#xA;recorded as happening amongst human beings. Witnesses are not wanting in&#xA;modern times to attest to the fact of such events, even in societies&#xA;living under the full blaze of modern science. The vast mass of such&#xA;evidence is unreliable, as coming from ignorant, superstitious, or&#xA;fraudulent persons. In many instances the so-called miracles are&#xA;imitations. But what do they imitate? It is not the sign of a candid and&#xA;scientific mind to throw overboard anything without proper&#xA;investigation. Surface scientists, unable to explain the various&#xA;extraordinary mental phenomena, strive to ignore their very existence.&#xA;They are, therefore, more culpable than those who think that their&#xA;prayers are answered by a being, or beings, above the clouds, or than&#xA;those who believe that their petitions will make such beings change the&#xA;course of the universe. The latter have the excuse of ignorance, or at&#xA;least of a defective system of education, which has taught them&#xA;dependence upon such beings, a dependence which has become a part of&#xA;their degenerate nature. The former have no such excuse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>016 INTRODUCTORY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/016_introductory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/016_introductory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introductory&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTORY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All our knowledge is based upon experience. What we call inferential&#xA;knowledge, in which we go from the less to the more general, or from the&#xA;general to the particular, has experience as its basis. In what are&#xA;called the exact sciences, people easily find the truth, because it&#xA;appeals to the particular experiences of every human being. The&#xA;scientist does not tell you to believe in anything, but he has certain&#xA;results which come from his own experiences, and reasoning on them when&#xA;he asks us to believe in his conclusions, he appeals to some universal&#xA;experience of humanity. In every exact science there is a basis which is&#xA;common to all humanity, so that we can at once see the truth or the&#xA;fallacy of the conclusions drawn therefrom. Now, the question is: Has&#xA;religion any such basis or not? I shall have to answer the question both&#xA;in the affirmative and in the negative.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>017 THE FIRST STEPS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/017_the_first_steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/017_the_first_steps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER II&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-steps&#34;&gt;THE FIRST STEPS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rāja-Yoga is divided into eight steps. The first is Yama — non-killing,&#xA;truthfulness, non-stealing, continence, and non-receiving of any gifts.&#xA;Next is Niyama — cleanliness, contentment, austerity, study, and&#xA;self-surrender to God. Then comes Âsana, or posture; Prānāyāma, or&#xA;control of Prāna; Pratyāhāra, or restraint of the senses from their&#xA;objects; Dhāranā, or fixing the mind on a spot; Dhyāna, or meditation;&#xA;and Samādhi, or superconsciousness. The Yama and Niyama, as we see, are&#xA;moral trainings; without these as the basis no practice of Yoga will&#xA;succeed. As these two become established, the Yogi will begin to realise&#xA;the fruits of his practice; without these it will never bear fruit. A&#xA;Yogi must not think of injuring anyone, by thought, word, or deed. Mercy&#xA;shall not be for men alone, but shall go beyond, and embrace the whole&#xA;world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>018 PRANA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/018_prana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/018_prana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER III&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;prana&#34;&gt;PRANA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prānāyāma is not, as many think, something about breath; breath indeed&#xA;has very little to do with it, if anything. Breathing is only one of the&#xA;many exercises through which we get to the real Pranayama. Pranayama&#xA;means the control of Prāna. According to the philosophers of India, the&#xA;whole universe is composed of two materials, one of which they call&#xA;Âkāsha. It is the omnipresent, all-penetrating existence. Everything&#xA;that has form, everything that is the result of combination, is evolved&#xA;out of this Akasha. It is the Akasha that becomes the air, that becomes&#xA;the liquids, that becomes the solids; it is the Akasha that becomes the&#xA;sun, the earth, the moon, the stars, the comets; it is the Akasha that&#xA;becomes the human body, the animal body, the plants, every form that we&#xA;see, everything that can be sensed, everything that exists. It cannot be&#xA;perceived; it is so subtle that it is beyond all ordinary perception; it&#xA;can only be seen when it has become gross, has taken form. At the&#xA;beginning of creation there is only this Akasha. At the end of the cycle&#xA;the solids, the liquids, and the gases all melt into the Akasha again,&#xA;and the next creation similarly proceeds out of this Akasha.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>019 THE PSYCHIC PRANA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/019_the_psychic_prana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/019_the_psychic_prana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER IV&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-psychic-prana&#34;&gt;THE PSYCHIC PRANA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to the Yogis, there are two nerve currents in the spinal&#xA;column, called Pingalā and Idā, and a hollow canal called Sushumnā&#xA;running through the spinal cord. At the lower end of the hollow canal is&#xA;what the Yogis call the &amp;ldquo;Lotus of the Kundalini&amp;rdquo;. They describe it as&#xA;triangular in form in which, in the symbolical language of the Yogis,&#xA;there is a power called the Kundalini, coiled up. When that Kundalini&#xA;awakes, it tries to force a passage through this hollow canal, and as it&#xA;rises step by step, as it were, layer after layer of the mind becomes&#xA;open and all the different visions and wonderful powers come to the&#xA;Yogi. When it reaches the brain, the Yogi is perfectly detached from the&#xA;body and mind; the soul finds itself free. We know that the spinal cord&#xA;is composed in a peculiar manner. If we take the figure eight&#xA;horizontally (¥) there are two parts which are connected in the middle.&#xA;Suppose you add eight after eight, piled one on top of the other, that&#xA;will represent the spinal cord. The left is the Ida, the right Pingala,&#xA;and that hollow canal which runs through the centre of the spinal cord&#xA;is the Sushumna. Where the spinal cord ends in some of the lumbar&#xA;vertebrae, a fine fibre issues downwards, and the canal runs up even&#xA;within that fibre, only much finer. The canal is closed at the lower&#xA;end, which is situated near what is called the sacral plexus, which,&#xA;according to modern physiology, is triangular in form. The different&#xA;plexuses that have their centres in the spinal canal can very well stand&#xA;for the different &amp;ldquo;lotuses&amp;rdquo; of the Yogi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>020 THE CONTROL OF PSYCHIC PRANA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/020_the_control_of_psychic_prana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/020_the_control_of_psychic_prana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER V&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-control-of-psychic-prana&#34;&gt;THE CONTROL OF PSYCHIC PRANA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have now to deal with the exercises in Prānāyāma. We have seen that&#xA;the first step, according to the Yogis, is to control the motion of the&#xA;lungs. What we want to do is to feel the finer motions that are going on&#xA;in the body. Our minds have become externalised, and have lost sight of&#xA;the fine motions inside. If we can begin to feel them, we can begin to&#xA;control them. These nerve currents go on all over the body, bringing&#xA;life and vitality to every muscle, but we do not feel them. The Yogi&#xA;says we can learn to do so. How? By taking up and controlling the motion&#xA;of the lungs; when we have done that for a sufficient length of time, we&#xA;shall be able to control the finer motions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>021 PRATYAHARA AND DHARANA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/021_pratyahara_and_dharana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/021_pratyahara_and_dharana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER VI&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;pratyahara-and-dharana&#34;&gt;PRATYAHARA AND DHARANA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next step is called Pratyāhāra. What is this? You know how&#xA;perceptions come. First of all there are the external instruments, then&#xA;the internal organs acting in the body through the brain centres, and&#xA;there is the mind. When these come together and attach themselves to&#xA;some external object, then we perceive it. At the same time it is a very&#xA;difficult thing to concentrate the mind and attach it to one organ only;&#xA;the mind is a slave.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>022 DHYANA AND SAMADHI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/022_dhyana_and_samadhi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/022_dhyana_and_samadhi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER VII&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;dhyana-and-samadhi&#34;&gt;DHYANA AND SAMADHI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have taken a cursory view of the different steps in Rāja-Yoga, except&#xA;the finer ones, the training in concentration, which is the goal to&#xA;which Raja-Yoga will lead us. We see, as human beings, that all our&#xA;knowledge which is called rational is referred to consciousness. My&#xA;consciousness of this table, and of your presence, makes me know that&#xA;the table and you are here. At the same time, there is a very great part&#xA;of my existence of which I am not conscious. All the different organs&#xA;inside the body, the different parts of the brain — nobody is conscious&#xA;of these.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>023 RAJA-YOGA IN BRIEF</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/023_raja-yoga_in_brief/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/023_raja-yoga_in_brief/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER VIII&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;raja-yoga-in-brief&#34;&gt;RAJA-YOGA IN BRIEF&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following is a summary of Rāja-Yoga freely translated from the&#xA;Kurma-Purāna.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The fire of Yoga burns the cage of sin that is around a man. Knowledge&#xA;becomes purified and Nirvāna is directly obtained. From Yoga comes&#xA;knowledge; knowledge again helps the Yogi. He who combines in himself&#xA;both Yoga and knowledge, with him the Lord is pleased. Those that&#xA;practice Mahāyoga, either once a day, or twice a day, or thrice, or&#xA;always, know them to be gods. Yoga is divided into two parts. One is&#xA;called Abhāva, and the other, Mahayoga. Where one&amp;rsquo;s self is meditated&#xA;upon as zero, and bereft of quality, that is called Abhava. That in&#xA;which one sees the self as full of bliss and bereft of all impurities,&#xA;and one with God, is called Mahayoga. The Yogi, by each one, realises&#xA;his Self. The other Yogas that we read and hear of, do not deserve to be&#xA;ranked with the excellent Mahayoga in which the Yogi finds himself and&#xA;the whole universe as God. This is the highest of all Yogas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>024 INTRODUCTION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/024_introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/024_introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PATANJALI&amp;rsquo;S YOGA APHORISMS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before going into the Yoga aphorisms I shall try to discuss one great&#xA;question, upon which rests the whole theory of religion for the Yogis.&#xA;It seems the consensus of opinion of the great minds of the world, and&#xA;it has been nearly demonstrated by researches into physical nature, that&#xA;we are the outcome and manifestation of an absolute condition, back of&#xA;our present relative condition, and are going forward, to return to that&#xA;absolute. This being granted, the question is: Which is better, the&#xA;absolute or this state? There are not wanting people who think that this&#xA;manifested state is the highest state of man. Thinkers of great calibre&#xA;are of the opinion that we are manifestations of undifferentiated being&#xA;and the differentiated state is higher than the absolute. They imagine&#xA;that in the absolute there cannot be any quality; that it must be&#xA;insensate, dull, and lifeless; that only this life can be enjoyed, and,&#xA;therefore, we must cling to it. First of all we want to inquire into&#xA;other solutions of life. There was an old solution that man after death&#xA;remained the same; that all his good sides, minus his evil sides,&#xA;remained for ever. Logically stated, this means that man&amp;rsquo;s goal is the&#xA;world; this world carried a stage higher, and eliminated of its evils,&#xA;is the state they call heaven. This theory, on the face of it, is absurd&#xA;and puerile, because it cannot be. There cannot be good without evil,&#xA;nor evil without good. To live in a world where it is all good and no&#xA;evil is what Sanskrit logicians call a &amp;ldquo;dream in the air&amp;rdquo;. Another&#xA;theory in modern times has been presented by several schools, that man&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;destiny is to go on always improving, always struggling towards, but&#xA;never reaching the goal. This statement, though apparently very nice, is&#xA;also absurd, because there is no such thing as motion in a straight&#xA;line. Every motion is in a circle. If you can take up a stone, and&#xA;project it into space, and then live long enough, that stone, if it&#xA;meets with no obstruction, will come back exactly to your hand. A&#xA;straight line, infinitely projected must end in a circle. Therefore,&#xA;this idea that the destiny of man is progressing ever forward and&#xA;forward, and never stopping, is absurd. Although extraneous to the&#xA;subject, I may remark that this idea explains the ethical theory that&#xA;you must not hate, and must love. Because, just as in the case of&#xA;electricity the modern theory is that the power leaves the dynamo and&#xA;completes the circle back to the dynamo, so with hate and love; they&#xA;must come back to the source. Therefore do not hate anybody, because&#xA;that hatred which comes out from you, must, in the long run, come back&#xA;to you. If you love, that love will come back to you, completing the&#xA;circle. It is as certain as can be, that every bit of hatred that goes&#xA;out of the heart of a man comes back to him in full force, nothing can&#xA;stop it; similarly every impulse of love comes back to him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>025 CONCENTRATION: ITS SPIRITUAL USES </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/025_concentration_its_spiritual_uses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/025_concentration_its_spiritual_uses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PATANJALI&amp;rsquo;S YOGA APHORISMS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;concentration-its-spiritual-uses&#34;&gt;CONCENTRATION: ITS SPIRITUAL USES&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;अथ योगानुशासनम् ॥१॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. Now concentration is explained.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;योगश्चित्तवृत्तिनिरोधः ॥२॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2. Yoga is restraining the mind-stuff (Chitta) from taking various&#xA;forms (Vrittis).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A good deal of explanation is necessary here. We have to understand what&#xA;Chitta is, and what the Vrittis are. I have eyes. Eyes do not see. Take&#xA;away the brain centre which is in the head, the eyes will still be&#xA;there, the retinae complete, as also the pictures of objects on them,&#xA;and yet the eyes will not see. So the eyes are only a secondary&#xA;instrument, not the organ of vision. The organ of vision is in a nerve&#xA;centre of the brain. The two eyes will not be sufficient. Sometimes a&#xA;man is asleep with his eyes open. The light is there and the picture is&#xA;there, but a third thing is necessary — the mind must be joined to the&#xA;organ. The eye is the external instrument; we need also the brain centre&#xA;and the agency of the mind. Carriages roll down a street, and you do not&#xA;hear them. Why? Because your mind has not attached itself to the organ&#xA;of hearing. First, there is the instrument, then there is the organ, and&#xA;third, the mind attached to these two. The mind takes the impression&#xA;farther in, and presents it to the determinative faculty — Buddhi —&#xA;which reacts. Along with this reaction flashes the idea of egoism. Then&#xA;this mixture of action and reaction is presented to the Purusha, the&#xA;real Soul, who perceives an object in this mixture. The organs&#xA;(Indriyas), together with the mind (Manas), the determinative faculty&#xA;(Buddhi), and egoism (Ahamkāra), form the group called the Antahkarana&#xA;(the internal instrument). They are but various processes in the&#xA;mind-stuff, called Chitta. The waves of thought in the Chitta are called&#xA;Vrittis (literally &amp;ldquo;whirlpool&amp;rdquo;) . What is thought? Thought is a force,&#xA;as is gravitation or repulsion. From the infinite storehouse of force in&#xA;nature, the instrument called Chitta takes hold of some, absorbs it and&#xA;sends it out as thought. Force is supplied to us through food, and out&#xA;of that food the body obtains the power of motion etc. Others, the finer&#xA;forces, it throws out in what we call thought. So we see that the mind&#xA;is not intelligent; yet it appears to be intelligent. Why? Because the&#xA;intelligent soul is behind it. You are the only sentient being; mind is&#xA;only the instrument through which you catch the external world. Take&#xA;this book; as a book it does not exist outside, what exists outside is&#xA;unknown and unknowable. The unknowable furnishes the suggestion that&#xA;gives a blow to the mind, and the mind gives out the reaction in the&#xA;form of a book, in the same manner as when a stone is thrown into the&#xA;water, the water is thrown against it in the form of waves. The real&#xA;universe is the occasion of the reaction of the mind. A book form, or an&#xA;elephant form, or a man form, is not outside; all that we know is our&#xA;mental reaction from the outer suggestion. &amp;ldquo;Matter is the permanent&#xA;possibility of sensations,&amp;rdquo; said John Stuart Mill. It is only the&#xA;suggestion that is outside. Take an oyster for example. You know how&#xA;pearls are made. A parasite gets inside the shell and causes irritation,&#xA;and the oyster throws a sort of enamelling round it, and this makes the&#xA;pearl. The universe of experience is our own enamel, so to say, and the&#xA;real universe is the parasite serving as nucleus. The ordinary man will&#xA;never understand it, because when he tries to do so, he throws out an&#xA;enamel, and sees only his own enamel. Now we understand what is meant by&#xA;these Vrittis. The real man is behind the mind; the mind is the&#xA;instrument his hands; it is his intelligence that is percolating through&#xA;the mind. It is only when you stand behind the mind that it becomes&#xA;intelligent. When man gives it up, it falls to pieces and is nothing.&#xA;Thus you understand what is meant by Chitta. It is the mind-stuff, and&#xA;Vrittis are the waves and ripples rising in it when external causes&#xA;impinge on it. These Vrittis are our universe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>026 CONCENTRATION: ITS PRACTICE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/026_concentration_its_practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/026_concentration_its_practice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PATANJALI&amp;rsquo;S YOGA APHORISMS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER II&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;concentration-its-practice&#34;&gt;CONCENTRATION: ITS PRACTICE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;तपः स्वाध्यायेश्वरप्रणिधानानि क्रियायोगः ॥१॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. Mortification, study, and surrendering fruits of work to God are&#xA;called Kriyā-yoga.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Those Samādhis with which we ended our last chapter are very difficult&#xA;to attain; so we must take them up slowly. The first step, the&#xA;preliminary step, is called Kriya-yoga. Literally this means work,&#xA;working towards Yoga. The organs are the horses, the mind is the rein,&#xA;the intellect is the charioteer, the soul is the rider, and the body is&#xA;the chariot. The master of the household, the King, the Self of man, is&#xA;sitting in this chariot. If the horses are very strong and do not obey&#xA;the rein, if the charioteer, the intellect, does not know how to control&#xA;the horses, then the chariot will come to grief. But if the organs, the&#xA;horses, are well controlled, and if the rein, the mind, is well held in&#xA;the hands of the charioteer, the intellect, the chariot reaches the&#xA;goal. What is meant, therefore, by this mortification? Holding the rein&#xA;firmly while guiding the body and the organs; not letting them do&#xA;anything they like, but keeping them both under proper control. &lt;em&gt;Study&lt;/em&gt;.&#xA;What is meant by study in this case? No study of novels or story books,&#xA;but study of those works which teach the liberation of the Soul. Then&#xA;again this study does not mean controversial studies at all. The Yogi is&#xA;supposed to have finished his period of controversy. He has had enough&#xA;of that, and has become satisfied. He only studies to intensify his&#xA;convictions. Vāda and Siddhānta — these are the two sorts of scriptural&#xA;knowledge — Vada (the argumentative) and Siddhanta (the decisive). When&#xA;a man is entirely ignorant he takes up the first of these, the&#xA;argumentative fighting, and reasoning pro and con; and when he has&#xA;finished that he takes up the Siddhanta, the decisive, arriving at a&#xA;conclusion. Simply arriving at this conclusion will not do. It must be&#xA;intensified. Books are infinite in number, and time is short; therefore&#xA;the secret of knowledge is to take what is essential. Take that and try&#xA;to live up to it. There is an old Indian legend that if you place a cup&#xA;of milk and water before a Rāja-Hamsa (swan), he will take all the milk&#xA;and leave the water. In that way we should take what is of value in&#xA;knowledge, and leave the dross. Intellectual gymnastics are necessary at&#xA;first. We must not go blindly into anything. The Yogi has passed the&#xA;argumentative state, and has come to a conclusion, which is, like the&#xA;rocks, immovable. The only thing he now seeks to do is to intensify that&#xA;conclusion. Do not argue, he says; if one forces arguments upon you, be&#xA;silent. Do not answer any argument, but go away calmly, because&#xA;arguments only disturb the mind. The only thing necessary is to train&#xA;the intellect, what is the use of disturbing it for nothing? The&#xA;intellect is but a weak instrument, and can give us only knowledge&#xA;limited by the senses. The Yogi wants to go beyond the senses, therefore&#xA;intellect is of no use to him. He is certain of this and, therefore, is&#xA;silent, and does not argue. Every argument throws his mind out of&#xA;balance, creates a disturbance in the Chitta, and a disturbance is a&#xA;drawback. Argumentations and searchings of the reason are only by the&#xA;way. There are much higher things beyond them. The whole of life is not&#xA;for schoolboy fights and debating societies. &amp;ldquo;Surrendering the fruits of&#xA;work to God&amp;rdquo; is to take to ourselves neither credit nor blame, but to&#xA;give up both to the Lord and be at peace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>027 POWERS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/027_powers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/027_powers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PATANJALI&amp;rsquo;S YOGA APHORISMS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER III&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;powers&#34;&gt;POWERS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have now come to the chapter in which the Yoga powers are described.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;देशबन्धश्चित्तस्य धारणा ॥१॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. Dhāranā is holding the mind on to some particular object.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dharana (concentration) is when the mind holds on to some object, either&#xA;in the body, or outside the body, and keeps itself in that state.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;तत्र प्रत्ययैकतानता ध्यानम् ॥२॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2. An unbroken flow of knowledge in that object is Dhyāna.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>028 INDEPENDENCE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/028_independence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/028_independence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PATANJALI&amp;rsquo;S YOGA APHORISMS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER IV&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;independence&#34;&gt;INDEPENDENCE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;जन्मौषधि-मन्त्र-तपः-समाधिजाः सिद्धयः ॥१॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. The Siddhis (powers) are attained by birth, chemical means, power of&#xA;words, mortification, or concentration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a man is born with the Siddhis, powers, of course, those he&#xA;had earned in his previous incarnation. This time he is born, as it&#xA;were, to enjoy the fruits of them. It is said of Kapila, the great&#xA;father of the Sānkhya philosophy, that he was a born Siddha, which means&#xA;literally a man who has attained to success.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>029 REFERENCES TO YOGA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/029_appendix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/raja-yoga/029_appendix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PATANJALI&amp;rsquo;S YOGA APHORISMS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;APPENDIX&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;references-to-yoga&#34;&gt;REFERENCES TO YOGA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shvetāshvatara Upanishad&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER II&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;अग्निर्यत्राभिमथ्यते वायुर्यत्राधिरुध्यते ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;सोमो यत्रातिरिच्यते तत्र सञ्जायते मनः ॥६॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6. Where the fire is rubbed, where the air is controlled, where the&#xA;Soma flows over, there a (perfect) mind is created.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;त्रिरुन्नतं स्थाप्य समं शरीरं&lt;br&gt;&#xA;हृदीन्द्रियाणि मनसा सन्निवेश्य ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;ब्रह्मोडुपेन प्रतरेत विद्वान्&lt;br&gt;&#xA;स्रोतांसि सर्वाणि भयानकानि ॥८॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;8. Placing the body in a straight posture, with the chest, the throat&#xA;and the head held erect, making the organs enter the mind, the sage&#xA;crosses all the fearful currents by means of the raft of Brahman.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
