<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;writings prose on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/writings_prose/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;writings prose on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/writings_prose/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>815 STRUGGLE FOR EXPANSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/writings_prose/815_struggle_for_expansion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/writings_prose/815_struggle_for_expansion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;struggle-for-expansion&#34;&gt;STRUGGLE FOR EXPANSION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Written by the Swami during his first visit to America in answer to&#xA;questions put by a Western disciple.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The old dilemma, whether the tree precedes the seed or the seed the&#xA;tree, runs through all our forms of knowledge. Whether intelligence is&#xA;first in the order of being or matter; whether the ideal is first or the&#xA;external manifestation; whether freedom is our true nature or bondage of&#xA;law; whether thought creates matter or matter thought; whether the&#xA;incessant change in nature precedes the idea of rest or the idea of rest&#xA;precedes the idea of change — all these are questions of the same&#xA;insoluble nature. Like the rise and fall of a series of waves, they&#xA;follow one another in an invariable succession and men take this side or&#xA;that according to their tastes or education or peculiarity of&#xA;temperaments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>816 THE BIRTH OF RELIGION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/writings_prose/816_the_birth_of_religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/writings_prose/816_the_birth_of_religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-birth-of-religion&#34;&gt;THE BIRTH OF RELIGION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Written by the Swami during his first visit to America in answer to&#xA;questions put by a Western disciple.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The beautiful flowers of the forest with their many-coloured petals,&#xA;nodding their heads, jumping, leaping, playing with every breeze; the&#xA;beautiful birds with their gorgeous plumage, their sweet songs echoing&#xA;through every forest glade — they were there yesterday, my solace, my&#xA;companions, and today they are gone — where? My playmates, the&#xA;companions of my joys and sorrows, my pleasures and pastime — they also&#xA;are gone — where? Those that nursed me when I was a child, who all&#xA;through their lives had but one thought for me — that of doing&#xA;everything for me — they also are gone. Everyone, everything is gone, is&#xA;going, and will go. Where do they go? This was the question that pressed&#xA;for an answer in the mind of the primitive man. &amp;ldquo;Why so?&amp;rdquo; you may ask,&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Did he not see everything decomposed, reduced to dust before him? Why&#xA;should he have troubled his head at all about where they went?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>817 FOUR PATHS OF YOGA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/writings_prose/817_four_paths_of_yoga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/writings_prose/817_four_paths_of_yoga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;four-paths-of-yoga&#34;&gt;FOUR PATHS OF YOGA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Written by the Swami during his first visit to America in answer to&#xA;questions put by a Western disciple.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our main problem is to be free. It is evident then that until we realise&#xA;ourselves as the Absolute, we cannot attain to deliverance. Yet there&#xA;are various ways of attaining to this realisation. These methods have&#xA;the generic name of Yoga (to join, to join ourselves to our reality).&#xA;These Yogas, though divided into various groups, can principally be&#xA;classed into four; and as each is only a method leading indirectly to&#xA;the realisation of the Absolute, they are suited to different&#xA;temperaments. Now it must be remembered that it is not that the assumed&#xA;man becomes the real man or Absolute. There is no becoming with the&#xA;Absolute. It is ever free, ever perfect; but the ignorance that has&#xA;covered Its nature for a time is to be removed. Therefore the whole&#xA;scope of all systems of Yoga (and each religion represents one) is to&#xA;clear up this ignorance and allow the Âtman to restore its own nature.&#xA;The chief helps in this liberation are Abhyāsa and Vairāgya. Vairagya is&#xA;non-attachment to life, because it is the will to enjoy that brings all&#xA;this bondage in its train; and Abhyasa is constant practice of any one&#xA;of the Yogas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>818 CYCLIC REST AND CHANGE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/writings_prose/818_cyclic_rest_and_change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/writings_prose/818_cyclic_rest_and_change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;cyclic-rest-and-change&#34;&gt;CYCLIC REST AND CHANGE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Written by the Swami during his first visit to America in answer to&#xA;questions put by a Western disciple.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This whole universe is a case of lost balance. All motion is the&#xA;struggle of the disturbed universe to regain its equilibrium, which, as&#xA;such, cannot be motion. Thus in regard to the internal world it would be&#xA;a state which is beyond thought, for thought itself is a motion. Now&#xA;when all indication is towards perfect equilibrium by expansion and the&#xA;whole universe is rushing towards it, we have no right to say that that&#xA;state can never be attained. Again it is impossible that there should be&#xA;any variety whatsoever in that state of equilibrium. It must be&#xA;homogeneous; for as long as there are even two atoms, they will attract&#xA;and repel each other and disturb the balance. Therefore this state of&#xA;equilibrium is one of unity, of rest, and of homogeneity. In the&#xA;language of the internal, this state of equilibrium is not thought, nor&#xA;body, nor anything which we call an attribute. The only thing which we&#xA;can say it will retain is what is its own nature as existence,&#xA;self-consciousness, and blissfulness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>819 A PREFACE TO THE IMITATION OF CHRIST</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/writings_prose/819_a_preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/writings_prose/819_a_preface/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-preface-to-the-imitation-of-christ&#34;&gt;A PREFACE TO THE IMITATION OF CHRIST&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Translated from an original &lt;a href=&#34;b6013_preface.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt; writing of the&#xA;Swami in 1889. The passage is the preface to his Bengali translation of&#xA;The Imitation of Christ which he contributed to a Bengali monthly. He&#xA;translated only six chapters with quotations of parallel passages from&#xA;the Hindu scriptures.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Imitation of Christ&lt;/em&gt; is a cherished treasure of the Christian&#xA;world. This great book was written by a Roman Catholic monk. &amp;ldquo;Written&amp;rdquo;,&#xA;perhaps, is not the proper word. It would be more appropriate to say&#xA;that each letter of the book is marked deep with the heart&amp;rsquo;s blood of&#xA;the great soul who had renounced all for his love of Christ. That great&#xA;soul whose words, living and burning, have cast such a spell for the&#xA;last four hundred years over the hearts of myriads of men and women;&#xA;whose influence today remains as strong as ever and is destined to&#xA;endure for all time to come; before whose genius and Sādhanā (spiritual&#xA;effort) hundred of crowned heads have bent down in reverence; and before&#xA;whose matchless purity the jarring sects of Christendom, whose name is&#xA;legion, have sunk their differences of centuries in common veneration to&#xA;a common principle — that great soul, strange to say, has not thought&#xA;fit to put his name to a book such as this. Yet there is nothing strange&#xA;here after all, for why should he? Is it possible for one who totally&#xA;renounced all earthly joys and despised the desire for the bauble fame&#xA;as so much dirt and filth — is it possible for such a soul to care for&#xA;that paltry thing, a mere author&amp;rsquo;s name? Posterity, however, has guessed&#xA;that the author was Thomas à Kempis, a Roman Catholic monk. How far the&#xA;guess is true is known only to God. But be he who he may, that he&#xA;deserves the world&amp;rsquo;s adoration is a truth that can be gainsaid by none.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
