<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०५ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2007/05/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०५ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2007/05/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jx evades a mAraNa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2007/05/2007-05-29_jx-evades-a-marana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2007/05/2007-05-29_jx-evades-a-marana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2007/05/29/jx-evades-a-marana/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whenever we have executed that loop by instinct, thus far, some vighna&#xA;has invariably come our way. This time again the mudgara-like blow of&#xA;the trailokya-stambhinI caused us new trouble. But we received a signal&#xA;to press on, undaunted. Jx who had been knocked out by the DAmarikA&#xA;strike after being routed by the chIna-s, scraped the rock-bottom of his&#xA;existence and fled further from bhAnu-kakSha to the township of&#xA;indra-jAla. Here, the spirit of bhR^igu and a~Ngira ancestors faintly&#xA;possessed him. He suddenly recovered and performed a purascharaNa of 8&#xA;months. It was around the culmination of this period that the 3rd hero&#xA;had broken forth. At that point a 3-pointed mAraNa attack was deployed:&#xA;one prong of it seized the amAtya but the muni deploying nidra-vArtAli&#xA;countered its fatal effects, even as the amAtya got enough time to&#xA;deploy the oShadhi prayoga. The other one headed towards to him who was&#xA;dwelling in indra-jAla. With his purashcharaNa complete the anAhata&#xA;chakra was filled with the presence of hamseshvara and hamseshvarI&#xA;surrounded by the 54 deities of the vAyavya mayUkha-s. He was unable to&#xA;grasp the full significance of this manifestation, but the spontaneous&#xA;power of manifestation of the shikhin yugma became clear – that fiery&#xA;manifestation of shiva-shivA in the circle surrounding the kaM bIja.&#xA;They verily say only one who has received the pUrNa-dIkSha can truly&#xA;withstand the force of the mistress of the kula path without being&#xA;confused. Past midnight the brahmAstra-vidyA crashed onto him with 4&#xA;successive strikes, but the power his own protective mantra was&#xA;unbelievable the prayoga which was so certain to effect mAraNa simply&#xA;rebounded off him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
