<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Churchill - famine</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/churchill-famine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/churchill-famine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1606729780493258753.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sir Winston Churchill neither caused nor contributed to the Bengal Famine of 1943.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As someone who has spent countless hours reading through hundreds of pages of primary sources, what was actually said and done, here&amp;rsquo;s what really happened.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Sources are cited at the end.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This thread is split into two parts:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cause of Famine &amp;amp; status of war in the region.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Churchill response &amp;amp; clearing up misconceptions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-cause&#34;&gt;The Cause:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On October 16th 1942, a cyclone hit Bengal &amp;amp; Orissa, wiping out the rice crop harvest in the process. Surrounding areas previously used to purchase foodstuff to alleviate famines/shortfalls had all fallen to Japan. This being in particular Burma but also Malaya, the Philippines &amp;amp; Thailand. Imperial Japan maintained a fleet in the Bay of Bengal from April 1942. Such a fleet was dangerous to merchant ships, as they could sink them - killing the men on board and destroying foodstuffs and equipment. This danger continued well into 1944. Dated 01/03/1944, Churchill&amp;rsquo;s copy of a paper for the Chiefs of Staff Committee of the War Cabinet&amp;hellip; demonstrated the closeness of potential Japanese battleship/carrier raiding force in the Bay of Bengal. They had surrounded the region from near the Maldives all the way to the south coast of Burma.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Churchill famine 2</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/churchill-famine-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/churchill-famine-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Utter imbecile @AndreasKoureas_ has the audacity to whitewash the war crimes of Winston Churchill who he says sent “900,000 tons of grain to India between August 1943 (when news of famine reached Westminster) and December 1944” which he claims Churchill sent out of “concern for Indians”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Winston Churchill’s actions during the Bengal Famine of 1943 were not just negligent - they were deliberate acts of genocidal cruelty fueled by racism and imperial greed. Claims like those of Andreas Koreas, attempting to paint Churchill as a mere &amp;ldquo;paternalistic imperialist&amp;rdquo;, collapse under the weight of historical evidence. Let’s debunk Andreas’s mendacious drivel claim by lying claim:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>dickens-1857</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/dickens-1857/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/dickens-1857/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dickens, in a letter to Emile de la Rue in 1857, about the Indian War of Independence of 1857:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I wish I were Commander in Chief over there [India]! I would address that Oriental character which must be powerfully spoken to, in something like the following placard, which should be vigorously translated into all native dialects, I, The Inimitable, holding this office of mine, and firmly believing that I hold it by the permission of Heaven and not by the appointment of Satan, have the honor to inform you Hindoo gentry that it is my intention, with all possible avoidance of unnecessary cruelty and with all merciful swiftness of execution, to exterminate the Race from the face of the earth, which disfigured the earth with the late abominable atrocities.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic impact</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/economic-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/economic-impact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Prathamesh Godbole on TW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;$45tr number is nonsense. The UK&amp;rsquo;s official estimate of its own national networth even TODAY is gbp 10tr. how would they take 45 100y ago? To put that number into perspective, $45tr is more than the worth of all gold mined in human history, which is estimated at $7tr. So unless England put pieces of the continental plate on ships and carted it off, forget 45, forget 7tr, even 10% of that isnt realistic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goa old new conquests</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/goa_old_new_conquests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/goa_old_new_conquests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/ShefVaidya/status/1876098297305403685&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Portuguese did NOT rule the whole of Goa as it is today for ‘450 years’. Do see the map attached. The areas in yellow are the so-called ‘new conquests’. They were added into Portuguese territory colonised in Goa in the 18th century CE, a much later date than the original three talukas that make up the Velhas Conquistas or &amp;ldquo;Old Conquests&amp;rdquo;, Salcete, Bardez and Tiswadi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maximum oppression of Hindus happened in the old conquista areas, where more than 600 Hindu temples, big and small, were destroyed in less than 5 years, as documented by the Portuguese missionaries themselves.+++(5)+++ Even today, the demography of these 3 talukas is predominantly Christian, because the Hindus were either forcibly converted, or forced to migrate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indian mercantile spread</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/indian-mercantile-spread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/indian-mercantile-spread/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thread by @JackRangaswami on Thread Reader App – Thread Reader App&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The British empire wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have happened without India. The sheer scale of Indian involvement is British colonization is mind blowing when one goes into the details. The military part should be better known by now. But India is why the British could conquer in the first place. But it goes way beyond that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See Burma. First Britain conquers it using the British Indian army. Then a lot of Indians come in to build the infra. The Indians bureaucrats come in to run the place. Then Indian merchants come in to run the merchant networks. Chettiars from Tamil Nadu setup money lending business which lends to Burmese farmers. Burma goes from subsistence farming to rice exporting powerhouse in a few decades. Half of Rangoon becomes Indians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jaishankar - China vs India narrative</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/jaishankar_china_vs_India_narratives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/jaishankar_china_vs_India_narratives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[Jaishankar]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No, I don&amp;rsquo;t think this is a result of what has happening in the last few years. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a results or what have happened for about 200 yrs. Because what happen was when British came &amp;amp; colonized India. The british systematically ran down our history. Whereas At that time they were very powerful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They had an interest in preserving and projecting Chinese History. Because they were afraid at that time that Tsarist Russia would come &amp;amp; occupy China. So if you look the 19th century for example. The biggest advocates of china were UK and America. Especially American missionaries. You know there&amp;rsquo;s a whole school promoting. Not now, not Kissinger. Not modern era. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about early 1800s. In fact Pearl S. Buck was an outcome of that kind stand up thinking. So building up china was always—for not always but for long time—a strategic objective of the west. Building them as a society. Praising their achievements, history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Racist Churchill</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/racist-churchill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/racist-churchill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Srouce: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1269795564650143746.html&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Afghanistan: Churchill said “all those who resist will be killed without quarter”, because the Pashtuns need “recognise the superiority of race” when referring to his tone spent in Afghanistan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cuba: in 1896, Churchill wrote he was concerned Cuba would turn into “another black republic”. By “another”, he was referring to Haiti, who were the first nation to abolish slavery in modern times.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;South Africa: Churchill created concentration camps in which 48,000 men, women and children died as a result of starvation and disease during the Boer War. He also planted the seed to strip black people of their voting rights in June 1906.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rajputana praja mandals - accession</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/rApjutAna-prajA-mandals-accession/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/rApjutAna-prajA-mandals-accession/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Praja mandals of Rajputana were all in favour of acceding to India. But Hamidullah Khan, the Nawab of Bhopal, and the chancellor of the Chamber of Princes  wanted to accede to Pakistan. But to connect Bhopal to Pakistan, Khan took the help of Udaybhan Singh of Dholpur, who sent letters to the states of Jaisalmer, Jodhpur &amp;amp; Mewar, to not accede to India or to stay independent. Hanvant Singh of Jodhpur, though he had previously declared to accede to India, changed his mind. When VP Menon tried to confront him, he put a gun to his head.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rAman &amp; jewish scientists</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/rAman_jewish-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/rAman_jewish-scientists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CV Raman’s plan to bring Jewish Scientists to India…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Professor Max Born was the mentor of the likes of Fermi and Oppenheimer. Heisenberg was once his assistant!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1933, just one month after Hitler became Chancellor, Born was fired by his university because he was Jewish. He fled to England taking a temporary position.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CV Raman was then the director of IISc Bangalore. He wrote to Born (both knew each other well in context of Raman Effect) - to join IISc as a professor and head of a new department Raman was setting up — and at a salary that would be higher than what he was getting in England!!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simla conference jixing</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/simla-conference-jixing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/simla-conference-jixing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Simla Conference opened on 25th June, a day after Wavell met and talked with Gandhi, Jinnah and Azad separately. In these talks, the caste complexion of Hindu representation in the Executive Council was removed and it was agreed that the composite Central Cabinet would comprise fourteen Indian Councillors, five each to be selected by the Congress and the League and four viceregal nominees. Among the last group would be a Sikh, two Harijans and Sir Khizr Hayat Khan, leader of the Unionist Party of the Punjab.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WW2 inflation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/ww2_inflation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/ww2_inflation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a primer on how they bankrupted India during WW2 to pay for an imperial war at the cost of the poorest Indian peasants.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Raj “paid” for all its purchases, and hence it was legitimate is the defense used by apologists of the Raj, but in reality the defense is not even gossamer think. The Raj paid for its purchases with scrips and not hard British Pounds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They also increased the debt levels. Collective Revenue (centre + provinces) went from Rs 180 crore in 39-40 to Rs 590 cr in 45-46. An increase of 3 times. Debt went from GBP 440 + Rs 450 in 39-40 to GBP 34 + Rs 2282 in 45-46. Basically the debt was all in worthless Indian currency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
