<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Huns, Uralics, and</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/2022-01-30_huns-uralics-and-empires-of-the-steppe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/2022-01-30_huns-uralics-and-empires-of-the-steppe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2022/01/30/huns-uralics-and-empires-of-the-steppe/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Huns, Uralics, and empires of the steppe&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.files.wordpress.com/2022/01/eurasia.png&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.files.wordpress.com/2022/01/eurasia.png?w=640&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://manasataramgini.files.wordpress.com/2022/01/eurasia.png?w=640&#34; alt=&#34;Eurasia&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A map by Savelyev et al. for the geographic orientation of the reader of&#xA;the below article.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-huns-of-europe&#34;&gt;The Huns of Europe&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“The lord of the Huns, King Attila, born of his father Mundzuk, lord of&#xA;the bravest tribes, who with unprecedented power alone possessed the&#xA;kingdoms of Scythia and Germania, and having captured their cities&#xA;terrorized both Roman empires and, that they might save their remnants&#xA;from plunder, was appeased by their prayers and took an annual tribute.&#xA;And when he had by good fortune accomplished all this, he fell neither&#xA;by an enemy’s blow nor by treachery, but safe among his own people,&#xA;happy, rejoicing, without any pain. Who therefore can think of this as&#xA;death, seeing that no-one thinks it calls for vengeance?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/2012-02-13_reconstruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/2012-02-13_reconstruction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.wordpress.com/2012/02/13/reconstruction/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reconstruction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.files.wordpress.com/2012/02/mongol-star.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.files.wordpress.com/2012/02/mongol-star.jpg?w=640&amp;amp;h=828&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://westhunt.files.wordpress.com/2012/02/mongol-star.jpg?w=640&amp;amp;h=828&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;mongol star&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;        mongol star&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There’s a cluster of Y-chromosomes found in inner Eurasia that vary only&#xA;slightly, and thus must have a recent common ancestor. They are&#xA;surprisingly common: there are something like 16 million carriers.+++(5)+++ The&#xA;analysts who discovered this (Zerjal et al) concluded the men with these&#xA;Y-chromosomes are the direct male-line descendants of Genghis Khan, the&#xA;Master of Thrones and Crowns. They have to be right: no one else&#xA;conquered such a vast empire and had his sons (and their sons, and so&#xA;on) rule and enjoy their harems for centuries. More than that, the&#xA;Golden Family continued to have high social status long after the fall&#xA;of the dynasties, even into recent times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 800th anniversary of the great khuriltai of 1206</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-10-14_the-800th-anniversary-of-the-great-khuriltai-of-1206/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-10-14_the-800th-anniversary-of-the-great-khuriltai-of-1206/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/10/14/the-800th-anniversary-of-the-great-khuriltai-of-1206/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was the year of the Tiger (1206 CE). At the head waters of the Onon&#xA;River, at the foot of the sacred mountain of Burkhan Khaldun, in&#xA;northern Mongolia a great throng of humanity was assembling. Jamuqa, the&#xA;once aristocratic leader of the Jadaran tribe had been executed and&#xA;there was one master of all Mongolia- Temujin. Thousands of horses,&#xA;sheep and cattle were herded in and enormous lines of felt gers (tents)&#xA;stretched in long lines leading to the grand central tent. In front of&#xA;that grand ger was erected the tall black horse-hair sulde, the magical&#xA;banner of the great warrior. The court shamans led by Teb Tengri were&#xA;getting into ecstatic séances to the eerie beat of the Mongolian drums.&#xA;Then there were the games- archery competitions, horse races and&#xA;wrestling and in the evening by the high fires the dances and throat&#xA;singing. Then on this great day the Master of all Mongolia, was lead to&#xA;the podium with his sulde in front of him. Then Temujin strode regally&#xA;on to a black felt carpet and his chief generals Bo’orchu, Muqali,&#xA;Jelme, Subedei, Jurchedei, Jebe and others raised him on that carpet&#xA;before the several thousands that were waiting for this moment. Temujin&#xA;was declared Chingiz(Chingis) Kha’khan- (Chin means strong, others say&#xA;Chingiz meant oceanic) the mighty ruler. Nine white horse tail banners&#xA;were raised. The announcer shouted that he was elected the supreme ruler&#xA;of the Turko-Mongol tribes and said that his power was derived from the&#xA;great god Köke Möngke Tengri. The announcer went on that the great Köke&#xA;Möngke Tengri had made Chingis Kha’Khan the law giver and the ruler of&#xA;all tribes and that he was ruling by the decree of the great tengri.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The rise and fall of Khan Abu’l Khair</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-05-29_the-rise-and-fall-of-khan-abul-khair/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-05-29_the-rise-and-fall-of-khan-abul-khair/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/05/29/the-rise-and-fall-of-khan-abul-khair/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An instructive lesson is offered by the eventful life of the Khan Abu’l Khair. The first son of Chingiz Kha’Khan was Jochi who founded the great Western hordes of the Mongols. His principal son was Batu who led the Mongol army during its great conquest of Europe. Batu and his brother Berke founded the Golden and White hordes of Jochid Ulus. The Golden and the White hordes were re-unified by the vigorous action of Khan Toqtamish, who also invaded Lithuania and subjugated it. Jochi’s other son Shayban had also distinguished himself in the great European campaign. At the time of Chingiz Kha’Khan death Shayban was alloted an Ulus (The Blue Horde) beside those of his above brothers East and Southeast of the Ural river including the province of Aktyubinsk. Shayban and his successors roamed in the territory bounded by the the Ural mountains and the Rivers Ilek and Irgiz, a tributaries of the Ural and wintered near the Sary Su river steppes. While the Shaybanids were not a major and remained obscure till the mid-1300s they held their territory against competing Mongol Khans from the White horde. In the mid-1300, an energetic Khan Uzbek stabilized and unified the disintegrating Ulus of Shayban. Subsequently, the other Jochid hordes collapsed as result of the expansion of Timur-i-lang and the Chingizids appeared to be receding into the background of the steppes. However, the fecundity of Chingiz Kha’Khan line revived its fortunes. All of a sudden the Shaybanids of the Blue Horde came to the fore. In 1428 at the age of 17, a young warrior Abu’l Khair was elected Khan of the Blue Horde in a Quriltai held on the Tura, west of Tobolsk in Siberia. After bowing to the Yak tail totem he proclaimed to restore the glory of Chingiz Khan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some great men from other cultures</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-03-24_some-great-men-from-other-cultures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-03-24_some-great-men-from-other-cultures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/03/24/some-great-men-from-other-cultures/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some great men transcend cultural boundaries and simply amaze you with the sheer enormity of their acts. In my opinion these first among these is the great Mongol leader Chingiz Kha’Khan. If anyone comes close to complete success then it is none other than the great Kha’Khan. Literally from rags after his father was killed by the Tatars he created a super-power nation, defeating in a two front war, Islam and China. Even the modern superpower with its entire panoply would not survive a two front war on both these fronts. His surge through Central Asia was studded with an unbroken string of victories in all kinds of circumstances, that no military leader after him has ever been able repeat. Not only that he set up an entire nation with administration, writing, currency and a postal system, where none existed before. Most importantly, he became the most prolific progenitor of Central Asia. And all this was achieved after being tied down in Mongolia in tribal conflicts till the age of 40.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The death of Chingiz Kha’Khan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-08-19_the-death-of-chingiz-khakhan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-08-19_the-death-of-chingiz-khakhan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/08/19/the-death-of-chingiz-khakhan/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the New moon day in August in 1227 AD the greatest of the military leaders of all times Chingiz Kha’Khan died. Born Temujin, and elected Kha’Khan- the Oceanic or mighty khan in 1206, destroyed in a span of 21 years the hegemony of China and Islam, two of the most dangerous powers in human history. This was very often done by waging war on both the fronts, something which, even superpowers like the United States today cannot really sustain if it were pitted against these same powers. Furthermore, this rise of Chingiz should be placed in the background of his immediate ancestors like Yessugai, Kabul and Kutula who while noted for their valor had no more an impact on the Central Asian history than any of the other khans who came and went. The other Turko-Mongol expansions such as the Huns of Motun-Tegin, the Uighurs of Tengri Bögü Kha’Khan and Gök Turks of Kül-tegin and Qapaghan khan were nowhere near Chingiz Khan in the organizational effort or result of their campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Warrior on the steppe</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/2003-11-20_warrior-on-the-steppe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/2003-11-20_warrior-on-the-steppe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/11/20/warrior-on-the-steppe/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Toqta Qiya had won many great battles and captured much territory. He was a better archer and a better swordsman than Urus Khan. Yet Urus Khan dominated the steppes due to his larger force and more reliable warriors. Toqta Qiya had earlier collaborated with Urus Khan, but he then broke off to establish his on Khanate. Now he was in a struggle with Urus in a low level conflict, but they still occassionally got together to raid the Russians. The fortress of Kesh was a long standing desire of Toqta Qiya. He had seen Urus and many other lesser warriors including some of his ex-naukers storm it and carry away heavy booty from the Chinese merchants. Yet, he had attempted to storm it on four occassions in four years and met with a crushing defeat on each occassion. On one occassion he thought he had taken the fort when his horse was shot under him and he barely escaped with life. On another occassion he tried a bold assault in winter and was flipped on his back by a blow from a club and nearly died on the snow. In the most recent attempt he had carefully sapped the fort for nearly 2 months and having picked up heavy booty from the Chinas was trying to get out when he was knocked over by a horse-shoe-headed arrow and fell badly wounded to the ground. He barely got out with his life. Now Toqta Qiya was offered a lesser province of Shadman, by Urus if he gave up his designs on Kesh for good. Alternatively, he faced a direct invasion from Urus and his allies like Suyurghatmish. Should he settle for Shadman or fight the battle of his life and hold his dignity. He could even lose his life in the latter option while he would at least have Shadman in the former. He was unable to decide. As though to mock him, fate had it that just then his lowly ex-nauker Narikeyan sacked Kesh and annexed to the Oezbeg Horde. For a winner of so many great the little stronghold of Kesh held the scales between a petty transient chief and a great Khan who transcended time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avar khanate</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/avar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/avar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A 🧵returning to some themes relating to Altaic Khaganates. For a general background one can read this summary we wrote (&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2022/01/30/huns-uralics-and-empires-of-the-steppe/&#34;&gt;Huns, Uralics, and empires of the steppe&lt;/a&gt;) recently.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One development that has happened since is the publication of another paper on multiple genomes from the Avar Khagnate. I began my first serious foray into Altaic history by reading René Grousset&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Empire of the steppes&amp;rdquo; and Chingiz Khan. It is fashionable these days, even though they have written no sweeping history like his, for modern Altaic scholar to crap on Grousset as otiose. Whatever our current improvements in understanding, I still feel it is important to read &amp;amp; appreciate the pUrvAchArya-s. The thrill of reading Grousset cover to cover as a kid is 1 of those indelible feelings &amp;ndash; it was followed by many an afternoon of wandering as though on horseback thinking about the various hypothesis of the ethnogenesis, warfare &amp;amp; cultural achievements of the people of the steppe going back to our own Aryan ancestors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chingiz Boerte offspring</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/chingiz_boerte_offspring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/chingiz_boerte_offspring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Order of Chingiz Khan&amp;rsquo;s 9 children through his 1st wife Börte (sons in brackets):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Qojin&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Jochi)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Chaghatai)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Ögedei)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Checheyigen&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Alaqa&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tümelün&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Tolui)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Al Altan&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4 sons + 5 daughters who survived to adulthood AFAI can tell; don&amp;rsquo;t know if any others died young. Good success for  her. Börte joined the Khan ~1178 CE around age 18. She bore her first daughter around 20 &amp;amp; was kidnapped around 21-22 which resulted in the uncertainty of the paternity of Jochi. Al Altan was born ~1196 CE. That would mean she was ~36 then, close to the limit of safe child-bearing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chingiz origin</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/chingiz-origin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/chingiz-origin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A form of the word Chingiz (spelt in many popular roman orthographies as Chinggis) is first attested in a Turkic stele commemorating the governor Alp Urungu of the Tuva region probably during the reign a later Uighur or Kirghiz Khan. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like the Chingiz in it is native to Turkic as it is not found in most Turkic branches &amp;amp; no where else in early Turkic (e.g. the Blue Turk steles). It is likely a Mongolic loan suggesting contact with pre-Chingizid Mongolic peoples &amp;amp; the nobility in the Uighur or the Kirghiz Khanates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daldaghai serbi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/daldaghai_serbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/daldaghai_serbi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1845336203475726600&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Khaghan Daldaghai of the Serbi was like a Chingiz Khan forgotten to history. He was remembered by his Khitan descendants with much respect over 700 years later.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He captured 1000 families of Japanese and made them his fishermen. Hou Han Shu&amp;rsquo;s provides an account of his attack on the Japanese:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the first year of the Kuang-ho reign period [178 A.D.]… The tribe’s [i.e. the Serbi’s] population was increasing daily, and their crops, livestock, and wild game were not enough to provide sustenance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>debter daftar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/debter_daftar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/debter_daftar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1594581012365082624.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The daftar of the Mogol tyrants of India has its roots in koko debter (the blue register) which was initiated by Shigi Qutuku the foster son of Chingiz Khan at his behest. The koko debter was first initiated in 1206 CE &amp;amp; included a census of the subjects of the Mongol Khaghanate. At 1st, the census only included the steppe peoples. In the time of Mongke Khan it was extended to the chIna, the rUs, and Mohd subjects. In 1235 CE S.Qutuku&amp;amp; Yelü Chucai carried out a massive census of the chIna-s for the debter. One of biggest pre-modern census efforts was that of Mongke in 1252 CE spanning much of their empire. It covered chIna, rUs, Iran and the Caucasus in addition to the core steppe lands.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geser Khan epic</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/geser-khAn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/geser-khAn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Geser Khan epic is one of the most remarkable texts where we can make out the layers of heathen religions piling one on top of the other. When the Mongolian version was finally published by the Manchus in 1716 CE it was part of their trilingual national formula with Manchu, Mongolian and Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The epic itself has roots in Tibet. The name of the protagonists Geser is believed by some to faint memory of Augustus or Julius but that is about it for any Roman memory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hun ethnicities</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/hun-ethnicities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/hun-ethnicities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1845557829110845696&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;xiongnu&#34;&gt;Xiongnu&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What were the ethnicities included in the Huns?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There has been much discussion about the ethnicity of the Huns and the Xiongnu and whether they are related at all. Otto Maenchen-Helfen, the great scholar of Hun studies, in my opinion, made a mistake by rejecting the Xiongnu-hUNa equation. The early chIna translators of Sanskrit texts clearly use the term Xiongnu for hUNa. They do not conflate it with several other ethnonyms of “barbarians” at their disposal. If they do not understand a Sanskrit ethnonym, they replace it with a calque or a phonetic rendering.+++(5)+++ This point was combined in the early 2000s by de la Vaissiere with several others to strongly revive the view that hUNa == Xiongnu.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kalmyks</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/kalmyks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/kalmyks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1977964225763946967&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;The Kalmyks are Oirat Mongols. They once had powerful Khagnates that on a smaller scale reenacted the Chingizid heydays under Esen Taiji who reunified the Mongols in 1449 CE and took the Chinese emperor prisoner. The Kalmyks are a remnant of the western branch of this old Khaghanate. Later, the Oirat Dzungar Khaghanate in their heartland was subject to a genocide by the Manchus and wiped out. A few of their cousins however still survive in Western Mongolia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Khitan scripts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/khitan-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/khitan-scripts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rattibha.com/thread/1593796931704193026?lang=en&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thought I posted this before but not finding it: &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/DsQZ981HNpM&#34;&gt;YT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several points of note regarding the 2 mysterious Khitan scripts &amp;amp; the efforts to decipher them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Khitan word for tiger Khaghanas might mean something like king of animals &amp;ndash; a taboo word. It is interestingly attested in an Arabic record of calendrical terms used by various peoples. Some of the other animal year terms show clear Mongolic relationships in their form suggesting that Khitan was indeed para-Mongolic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Daur Mongolian peoples of NE Asia, who were exterminated in large numbers by the Rus are likely surviving descendants of the Khitans though they today speak a Mongolic language. Their language does show hints of a substrate that was likely the Khitan language that was gradually replaced by Mongolian.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Another group of Khitan survivors again having lost the language live in South in the Yunnan region near modern Burma as a non-Han ethnic group. They are remnant of the Khitans who served as part of the Mongol conquest of China. They remained there after the end of the Yunnan Mongol kingdom that formed an alliance with Japan under the Khan vajra-varmin.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Many Khitans in the NE practice their ancient shamanistic religion and tomb of similar Khitan female shaman was recovered in Yunnan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Daur Khitan descendants show enrichment of a Y chromosome haplogroup that is a brother group to the expanded C-M217 clade attributed to the clan of Chingiz Khan. This again supports their para-Monogolic affinities &amp;amp; is consistent with the special sympathies Chingiz Khan showed to the Khitans.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First, he saw himself as avenging the overthrow of the Khitan empire by the Tungusid Jurchen.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Second, he appointed several notable Khitans to his administration like the gigantic Yelü Chucai.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Third, the Khitans played a key role in the conquest &amp;amp; admin of the Mohammedan lands in the ex-Iranosphere by Ilkhan Hülegü, the grandson of Chingiz.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, by thrashing Sultan Sanjar, they kept the East safe from Mohammedanization.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The chIna-s note an interesting parallel to other (para)Mongolic peoples among the Khitan-s: The male population was armed &amp;amp; if they were given a call to mobilize at dawn, within 2 hours they are said to have assembled into an army ready for battle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>khitan-circuits</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/khitan-circuits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/khitan-circuits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 5 circuits of the Khitan state the height of their power ~1100s. Each circuit had its own capital; the Khan did not stay in any 1 capital &amp;amp; moved around in the ancestral nomadic fashion. Sometimes he wandered in disguise in cities/towns to gather public opinion first hand.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is interesting that the Khitans &amp;amp;Mongols called their campsites in course of the wanderings as nat-pat or nand-bat from Skt nandi-pada = stop for refreshment or recreation. An example of an account of the Khitan Khaghan&amp;rsquo;s nat-pat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>khitan-poem</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/khitan-poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/khitan-poem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A poem by a chIna ambassador (translated by Pursey) on the Khitan court in 1090 CE. Evidently, it was when their Khaghan was camping in the Gobi desert &amp;ndash; a harsh land where strong folk are made.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In winter savage tents set up in the the desert,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Penned in together with a fence of cloth and reeds, it is called the “moving palace.”&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The officials who follow are scattered like stars among dunes that look like burial mounds,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;These cave-like tent abodes are bullied by the frosty wind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>khotanese Record</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/khotanese_record/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/khotanese_record/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Khotanese language was the successor of older East Iranic shaka language. A major bauddha text in it has come down to us in fragments: the book of Zambasta. It mentions the invasion of Khotan by 5 enemies who harmed Khotan: mAMkuya, Red Khocas, huna-s, ciMgga-s, supIya-s.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;mAMkuya rro Inda heinA kho—ca u huna ciMgga supIya | kye naa hvataana-kShIru bajo—ttanda ttu ju ye gSvu ne oysde ||&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Emmerick translated this as:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Khwarazm destruction inscription</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/khwarazm-destruction-inscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/khwarazm-destruction-inscription/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source &lt;a href=&#34;https://unrollthread.com/t/1484785239926976514/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The famous Chingiz stone inscription talking of the destruction of marUnmatta-s of the Khwarizm empire.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Činggis Qan, despoiling the Sartayul people, dismounting, the noblemen of the entire Mongol nation had gathered (at) Buqa Sočiyai&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(i.e. When Činggis Qan, having subjugated the Sartayul (= Muslim) people set up camp and the noblemen of the entire Mongol nation had gathered at Buqa Sočiyai.)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Yisüngge, when long-distance shooting, shot (an arrow) at long distance to 335 aldas,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(i.e. When Yisüngge shot at the long distance (shooting contest), he shot an arrow 335 fathoms.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lament</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/lament/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/lament/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The lament of the end of the empire: The Chingizid Mongol historian Saghang Sechen records a tragic poem of the last imperial Khan Toghon Temur on the end of their empire. Would there be such a reflection when the mahAmlechCha empire ends?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My vast and noble capital, my Dadu,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;my splendidly adorned and you my cool and delicious summer-seat, my Shangdu-Keibung.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;You, also, Yellow Plain of Shangdu, delight of my godlike ancestors.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I suffered myself to drop into dreams - and lo my empire was gone.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Ah! you my Dadu, built of navaratna-s,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Ah! my Shangdu-Keibung, the union of all perfection&#xA;Ah my Fame.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Ah my glory as Khaghan and Lord of the Earth.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;When I used to awake betimes and look forth,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;how the breezes blew loaded with fragrances.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And turn which way I would all was glorious perfection of beauty.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Alas for my illustrious name as the Khaghan of the World.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Alas for my Dadu, seat of Sanctity,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;glorious work of the Immortal Qubilai!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;All, all is rent from me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MamlUq yAsA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/mamlUq-yAsA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/mamlUq-yAsA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1803261610716254682&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the Egyptian Mamluq chronicler al-Maqrizi (13-1400s) states that a copy of Chingiz Khan yAsA was available in a Bagdad library. Notably, Mamluq Sultan Baibars wanted to incorporate the yAsA as a valid law in his kingdom overriding sharia in appropriate situations&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mamluq al Makrizi seems to have had genuine knowledge of the yAsA of the Khan. He notes that it was recorded from wisdom, Mon: bilik after the destruction of the Kerait&amp;amp; Naiman &amp;ndash; quriltai of 1206 CE. Another Mamluq amir Artash is supposed to have had deep knowledge of the yAsA&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>neguder</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/neguder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/neguder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1660032878569201667&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Venetian Marco Polo gives a curious account of the Negüderi horde. He says they were born of Indian mothers &amp;amp; Mongol fathers. They are said to possess capability for a &amp;ldquo;black magic&amp;rdquo;: they cause a darkness that lasts 7 days. While their victims are unable to see in this, they ride out to enslave &amp;amp; plunder them. They are said to have force of a tumen under them led by Negüder. Hülegü had crushed his irredentist ventures. The strike on Kashmir by his horde is recorded in joNarAja&amp;rsquo;s rAjataraMgiNI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PaNDits</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/paNDits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/paNDits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1978310645989671157&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AchArya lokesha chandra noted that narendrayashas had likely visited Mongolia during the Rouran khaghanate which later gave rise to the Avar state in the west. narendrayashas passed from kAshmIra to the city of nagarahAra (today unfortunately known as Jalalabad) in gandhAra. There he is said to have seen a shadow figure of the tathAgata, his calcined bones and teeth and his bowl before going on into central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The kAvyadarsha of daNDin was translated into Tibetan by Qubilai Khaghan&amp;rsquo;s Tibetan mantravAdin and the subsequent centuries received much attention from the Chingizid Mongol Sanskritists.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phrases</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/phrases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/phrases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;möngke-tengri-yin-küchün-dür&#34;&gt;Möngke Tengri-yin küchün-dür&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Mongol phrase: Möngke Tengri-yin küchün-dür; Qaghan-u suu-dur: By the might of the eternal Tengri, by the charisma of the Qaghan. That translation of suu-dur as by charisma is by M.Biran others mostly translate as the good fortune following a chIna rendering. Perhaps she is capturing a genuine element in this rendering &amp;ndash; the Khaghan&amp;rsquo;s charisma coming from Tengri was something the Mongols actually experienced and saw it as an important element of their success.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>qasar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/qasar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/qasar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The verses of Jamuqa describing Chingiz Khan&amp;rsquo;s brother Qasar, who he appears to have held in great regard as a warrior.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;His body is three fathoms high,&#xA;And he dines on three-year old cattle;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Wearing a three-layered armour,&#xA;He is pulled along in his cart by three bulls.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;When he swallows a man complete with quiver,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It does not get stuck in his throat.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;When he gulps down a whole man,&#xA;It does not fill his stomach.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qubilai rise</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/qubilai-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/qubilai-rise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Regarding Qubilai Khan in Fridman&amp;rsquo;s interview with J Weatherford: IMO, JW considerably downsizes Qubilai. He had challengers among the descendants of Chingiz Khan, his own brother Ariq Böke and the Qaidu, both of whom declared themselves as rival Khans. Nevertheless, Qubilai completing the Mongol conquest of China was an achievement of the highest order. We disagree with JW downplaying it and Qubilai.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our previous note on this remarkable campaign:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2018/02/26/mongolica-qubilai-khans-campaign-to-destroy-the-southern-song/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>qubilai-ministers</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/qubilai-ministers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/qubilai-ministers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rashid ad-din provides a list of 54 top officials of the Mongol empire during Qubilai Khan&amp;rsquo;s reign: 21 of these are ministers; 30 are military commanders; 19 belong to the Khan&amp;rsquo;s imperial guard. Many played more than one role hence the count goes over 54. e.g., Bayan&amp;amp; Turtaqa Noyan were both ministers&amp;amp; commanders. Bolad was both a minister &amp;amp; member of the imperial guard as the bauarchi &amp;ndash; a function overlapping with the imperial chef.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>quibilai-mahAkAla</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/quibilai-mahAkAla/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/quibilai-mahAkAla/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was an image of mahAkAla which was made for Qubilai Khan &amp;amp; had great significance among the Mongols. Its possession designated the Mongol Khan as the supreme upholder of the dharma-chakra. As the Mongol empire fragmented, it passed from one minor Khan to another. The final descendant of Chingiz Khan to possess the idol was Ligdan Khan of the Chakhar branch of Qublaiids.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He wanted the remaining Mongols to submit to him - but interested in keeping their uluses they formed an alliance with their former enemies the Jurchen. Chief among latter were the Khalkha Chingizids &amp;amp; Khorchin Khasarids. The princess of the Khorchins was the wife of Nurhachi of the Jurchen, soon to be Manchu. This entente defeated Ligdan Khan &amp;amp; he fled to Kokonor where he died. Some Mongols presented the idol &amp;amp; the Chingizid seal to Nurhachi&amp;rsquo;s half Mongol son Khung Taiji. Now in possession of that sovereignty conferring idol he was able to declare himself lord of all the Jurchen &amp;amp; Mongols. It is not known if the Maoists destroyed that idol or it has merely been lost somewhere in Manchuria.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qutlugh lament</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/qutlugh-lament/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/qutlugh-lament/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mongol general Qutlugh lamenting the conversion of his coethnics to Mohd&amp;rsquo;ism in the 1300s:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What have we done, that we have set aside the yasa and yosun of Chingiz Khan and taken up the religion founded in past by the Arabs that is divided into seventy-odd sects? And the choice of any these schools is a disgrace and an infamy, in that one of them allows marriage to one’s daughter, and the other to one’s mother and sister-in-law, God forbid either! We ought to return to the yasa and yosun of Chingiz Khan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>samarkaND-strikes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/samarkaND-strikes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/samarkaND-strikes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The route of Chingiz Khan&amp;rsquo;s remarkable western campaign with the strike on Samarqand as recorded by his ministers the Khitan Yelü Chucai &amp;amp; the Uighur Qaraiqachi Buyiruq. It is notable that after descending from the Irtysh, he followed a path close to that of the Khitan Khan Yelü Dashi&amp;rsquo;s strike on the Army of Islam led by the Turk Sanjar. This makes one think if Yelü Chucai was had preserved a memory of his ancestors&amp;rsquo; western campaign &amp;amp; Chingiz modeled his own after that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sengge-ragi-image</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/sengge-ragi-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/sengge-ragi-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1317961063384698881.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The notable image installed by the Uighur Bojianu, cavalry general of the left wing of the imperial corps of the Mongol Khan, at Baochengsi under the patronage of the grand princess Sengge Ragi, the great-granddaughter of Khubilai Khan, the governess of the state of Lu.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of all the various buddha-s the Tibetan lama-s tried to get the great Khan Khubilai interested in he was more drawn to the H deities absorbed by the tAthAgata-mata and has a special devotion to mahAkAla and his circle of deities. He had employed lama Phagspa to create the new Mongol script &amp;amp; had his student Dam pa to perform mahAkAla rituals for him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>senggun-demise</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/senggun-demise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/senggun-demise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1667754744872415233.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Mongols left behind a laconic account of the end of Ilqa Senggün, the son of Toghrul Wang Khan of the Kereit:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ilqa [Senggün] fled to the Tangut Kingdom, passing by Isina city and arriving at the [land of the] &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;Wolf Tibetans.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; Having plundered them, he still wished to live there. The &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;Wolf Tibetans&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; gathered their peoples and drove him out. [With his forces] scattering, he fled to the land of the Cherkesmen of Küsen (Kucha) city in the west. He was killed by one Qïlïnch-Qara.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sparing India</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/sparing-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/sparing-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The famous tale of the Indian rhinoceros &amp;amp; Mongols turning away from India as narrated by Saghang Sechen from Igor de Rachewiltz et al&amp;rsquo;s convenient romanized edition.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thereupon, when he (i.e. Činggis Qan), following the same course, rode against India, on crossing the mountain defile called Candanarang (“Brilliant Peak&amp;rsquo;) Pass, a wild animal called the serü (“rhinoceros&amp;rsquo;), which had a single horn on top of its head, came swiftly towards him; it made obeisance, kneeling three times before the Lord. While everyone marvelled at it, the Lord spoke thus and said,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yuan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/yuan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/MT_lekhAH/yuan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/2019625200308854814&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Mongol emperor Qubilai Khan chose the chIna name for his dynasty, Yuan (元), from a chIna book, the Yijing:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;大哉乾元&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Dà zāi qián yuán&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A machine-aided translation:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;大    Dà     Great&lt;br&gt;&#xA;哉    zāi     Indeed!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;乾    Qián The Qián hexagram: represents Heaven/Cosmic force (like R^ita of the H)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;元     Yuán Origin/Beginning&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Full Meaning: &amp;ldquo;Great indeed is the Primal Origin of the Cosmic force!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Qián hexagram has great significance in chIna thought and is taken to represent the Yang principle in the Yin-Yang diagram.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
