<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hindu refuge - male heavy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/articles/hindu-refuge-male-heavy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/articles/hindu-refuge-male-heavy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The genetic studies of Parsis of Pakistan show sharp contrast between genetic data obtained from mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) and Y-chromosome DNA (Y-DNA), different from most populations. Historical records suggests that they had moved from Iran to Gujarat, India and then to Mumbai and Karachi, Pakistan. According to Y-DNA, they resemble the Iranian population, which supports historical records. When the mtDNA pool is compared to Iranians and Gujaratis (their putative parental populations), it contrasted Y-DNA data. About 60% of their maternal gene pool originates from South Asian haplogroups, which is just 7% in Iranians. Parsis have a high frequency of haplogroup M (55%), similar to Indians, which is just 1.7% in combined Iranian sample. The studies suggest sharp contrast between the maternal and paternal component of Parsis. Due to high diversity in Y-DNA and mtDNA lineages, the strong drift effect is unlikely even though they had a small population. The studies suggest a male-mediated migration of Parsi ancestors from Iran to Gujarat where they admixed with the local female population during initial settlements, which ultimately resulted in loss of Iranian mtDNA.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sistan baloch rebellion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/articles/sistan-baloch-rebellion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/articles/sistan-baloch-rebellion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;970&#34;&gt;970&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Javidbalochi/status/1774800305424613790&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;King Ezad-al-Dolah: Kill them all, Kill anyone who follows the old religion(Zoroastrians), No Mercy for The lost souls.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In year 970, Ezd-Al-Dolah of Buyid house declared Jihad against Kuch &amp;amp; Baluch tribes of Kerman who had kept their Zoroastrian beliefs, 330yrs after  Islamic Conquest/Invasion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The House of Ilyas which was The Ruling house of Kerman and the ally of Samanids deceived the Zoroastrians to defeat the Buyid dynasty, Zoroastrians forces won the first battle against Buyids &amp;amp; cut the hand of Muiz-Al-Dolah, King’s brother…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
