<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०९ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/09/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०९ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/09/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Walking back</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/09/2004-09-11_walking-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/09/2004-09-11_walking-back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/09/11/walking-back/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had been chatting somewhat wastefully with an acquaintence of mine, on&#xA;topics ranging from the awful goddess dhumAvati to certain internet&#xA;personalities. Thereafter I was just planning to leave when I saw a call&#xA;flashing on my phone from a local but unfamiliar number. Fearing that it&#xA;may be something to do with my henchman who had landed in the hospital&#xA;due to some wierd illness, I picked it up. To my utter surprise I heard&#xA;ST’s voice. I asked her how on earth she was in this part of the world&#xA;when she was supposed to be in a time zone 3 hours away. She said she&#xA;was just 5 minutes away and asked me if I could swing by. So we were&#xA;soon attending to the ritual of bhojanaM yarning over some old days when&#xA;we scaled the pinnacles of Rajgad. ST still remained her same&#xA;extraordinarily competitive self, expressing a tinge of disappointment&#xA;at my recent successful strike on A20. To smoothen matters, I pacified&#xA;her by praising her successful, if somehwhat trivial, strike on the BIRs&#xA;and that dirty protein in the baculovirus. Then I gave her R’s number as&#xA;she wanted to talk to her. Observing silently through the corner of my&#xA;eye I could see that ST got tremendous pleasure in seeing how finally&#xA;she felt had overthrown R (R had been an un-attainable gold standard for&#xA;many). Whatever ST had fervently wanted, was it the good looks, or that&#xA;seat in MBBS, or that GRE score, or entry into the “top US university”&#xA;or even that cool mate, R used to easily achieve often washing aside ST&#xA;and other wannabes in the great saMgrAmas. When the currency finally&#xA;changed, R suddenly emerged a pauper (something that even I never could&#xA;fathom). But now ST after years of ardous penance, literally resembling&#xA;the ati-kR^icchra and the sAntapana had crossed that frontier which R&#xA;never had. It gave great pleasure to ST, as though rubbing it in, as she&#xA;repeatedly explained her conquests to R. Then ST and me started walking&#xA;back towards my dwelling. I heard what she had to say. To my surprise,&#xA;all that penance was like that of the buddha. ST sounded renunciatory,&#xA;like the ascetic described by shAkAyaNya, she was seeing truth in the&#xA;path of saMnyAsa. In the dim light of the street lamp, I looked at her,&#xA;from a kamalA she had transformed to a dhumAvati.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
