<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Drixler - infanticide 1660 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Drixler - infanticide 1660 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Introduction</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/01_Introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/01_Introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contested Worldviews and a Demographic Revolution&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deep in the mountains of Gunma, a chapel stands amid cedars and forest fl owers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Under its eaves, a wooden tablet has slowly surrendered its paint to two hundred years of wind and rain. Yet when the light falls from the right angle, the eroded image still calls out its warning to travelers: It is early spring. Th e branches of a&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;plum tree are still bare. In an open pavilion, a woman has just given birth. Next to her, a midwife kneels—and strangles the newborn. While the infant soul soars toward a bodhisattva, fl oating above on curled clouds, the midwife is destined for a darker place. On the right side of the panel, fl ames lick her face, and two devils break her body.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Three Cultures of Family Planning</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/02_Three_Cultures_of_Family_Planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/02_Three_Cultures_of_Family_Planning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometime in the early eighteenth century, a merchant named Shinbei traveled toward the great shrine of Itsukushima near Hiroshima. One evening as he was settling down at an inn, another guest suddenly rushed out. Puzzled, Shinbei turned to a pilgrim at his side. Could it be that there were robbers among the travelers? “In the lodging that we share, an odious thing has happened,” the man explained. “Th&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;e rest of us are also thinking about moving out. Apparently, there is someone from Tosa among the pilgrims. We always hear that when people in Tosa do not want to raise a child, they kill it on the fl oor of its birth. Th e other guest fl ed&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Humans, Animals, and Newborn Children</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/03_Humans_Animals_and_Newborn_Children/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/03_Humans_Animals_and_Newborn_Children/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;O F BU G S A N D BA B I E S&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Arai Nobuaki, a childrearing commissioner in Sendai domain, toured the villages of his quadrant to lecture against infanticide, he was intrigued to fi nd the countryside dotted with stelae dedicated to silkworms.1 In response to his inquiry, the locals explained that “when you boil silkworms to [harvest their] thread, you kill a living being.” Arai was moved to write a poem:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Infanticide and Immortality</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/04_Infanticide_and_Immortality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/04_Infanticide_and_Immortality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Logic of the Stem Household&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;T H E L AWS O F D I S I N H E R I TA N C E&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the years around 1680, a population explosion caused consternation in many parts of Japan.1 Some governments encouraged emigration to rid their lands of unwanted mouths, and others closed their borders to laborers from elsewhere.2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Th&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;roughout the archipelago, village assemblies and rulers issued laws restricting marriages and partible inheritance. One of these laws was the 1677 decree of Sendai domain that we have encountered in the previous chapter. “As we observe from the recent population registration,” it explained, “the number of people is increasing greatly, and we estimate that within ten or fi ft een years, there will be grain shortages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 The Material and Moral Economy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/05_The_Material_and_Moral_Economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/05_The_Material_and_Moral_Economy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;of Infanticide&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the last two chapters, we have seen why the barriers to infanticide were relatively low and how killing newborns could be justifi ed as benefi ting the household’s dead, living, and future members. Th&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;e latter argument rested in part on the&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;logic of the stem family, but was also rooted in a particular view of the costs and benefi ts of childrearing. Th&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;is chapter examines four material contexts for infanti-&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 The Logic of Infant Selection</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/06_The_Logic_of_Infant_Selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/06_The_Logic_of_Infant_Selection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A woman who followed Eastern Japan’s fertility norm and raised only three children would still, on average, give birth about six times.1 As couples faced the decision of which newborns to keep and which to discard, they could draw on an elaborate system of evaluating the promise of each child. Th e needs of the household played an important role, but so did a cosmology that understood time as patterned with peril and promise. Parents tried to balance the genders of their children but also paid close attention to whether the sex of a birth matched their predictions and whether a child arrived at an auspicious moment. Th is system of&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 The Ghosts of Missing Children</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/07_The_Ghosts_of_Missing_Children/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/07_The_Ghosts_of_Missing_Children/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*Four Approaches to Estimating the *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rate of Infanticide&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Th&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;e preceding chapters have explored the understandings of human life, family, responsibility, and time that permitted, motivated, and patterned infanticide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Th&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;is short chapter attempts to quantify its frequency through four diff erent approaches. Th&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;e fi rst of these consults the reports of contemporary observers who stated clearly what proportions of infants were killed at birth. Th e other&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;three derive estimates from the demographic record. One trace of missing children to be found there is the sex ratio pattern of surviving brothers and sisters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 Infanticide and Extinction</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/08_Infanticide_and_Extinction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/08_Infanticide_and_Extinction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;T H E D E P O P U L AT I O N C R I S I S O F T H E&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;L AT E E I G H T E E N T H C E N T U RY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the 1820s, the villagers of Aoki in Hitachi’s Makabe district chiseled the names of extinct households onto a large rock. In this village of 39 remaining households, their number came to 59.1 For more than a century, the logic of Funerary Buddhism and the stem family had held out the promise of achieving immortality with a little help from infanticide (see Chapter 4). Th&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 “Inferior Even to Animals”</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/09_Inferior_Even_to_Animals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/09_Inferior_Even_to_Animals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moral Suasion and the Boundaries of Humanity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the early winter of 1857, a group of fourteen men celebrated the completion of a hundred-temple circuit by dedicating a votive tablet. Fashioned from six wooden boards, this *ema * shows a young woman clad in layered robes of red and green. Still wearing the sweatband typical of women giving birth, she smothers a child on a reed mat. Diagonally above, she and the dying child appear once again. Her skin, white and smooth in the fi rst scene, has turned the same shade of green as her outer clothes, and buckles with knots and tensed muscles. From a mountainous bluish face, two embers glow above the scarlet leer of an angular jaw. Her hair, carefully tied up in the fi rst scene, is now a mane, pierced by two curved horns. All around the two fi gures, a long text furnishes further arguments against infanticide, borrowed like the images themselves from a printed pamphlet. Th e ema remains&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Subsidies and Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/10_Subsidies_and_Surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/10_Subsidies_and_Surveillance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For all the passion their creators poured into them, pamphlets and paintings were relatively cheap. Th&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;e perceived urgency of fi ghting infanticide is more impressively evinced by the prodigious resources that governments and individuals poured into far costlier countermeasures. If moral suasion redrew the boundaries of humanity and argued that infanticide was not compatible with a pleasant aft erlife, childrearing subsidies and pregnancy surveillance focused on the material conditions that their designers saw as motivating and permitting infanticide: poverty and impunity. Such policies reached into remote villages, consumed great quantities of paper, and tied up considerable administrative and fi nancial resources. Depending on the locality, a sizable fraction of parents received subsidies for their children.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 National security</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/11_National_security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/11_National_security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even a Strong Castle Cannot Be Defended without Soldiers&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Infanticide and National Security&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the culture of infanticide, reproductive restraint was a mark of responsibility toward others. As we have seen, it was considered the prudent alternative to&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“affl&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;icting six children with hunger and cold” or to “selling them in the spring of their sixth or seventh year.”1 Th&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;inning out children was an act of fi lial piety for&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Infanticide and the Geography of Civilization</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/12_Infanticide_and_the_Geography_of_Civilization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/12_Infanticide_and_the_Geography_of_Civilization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JA PA N A N D C H I NA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1794, Hara Nan’yō, personal physician to the lord of Mito, sent his newest book manuscript to Fujita Yūkoku. Fujita was young enough to be Hara’s child, but his actual parentage was far less illustrious. Th&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;e second son of a used-clothes seller in&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mito’s castletown, he had shown such prodigious promise as a scholar that at the age of eighteen he was raised to the rank of a warrior and made an editor on Mito’s Dai-Nipponshi historiographical project. Hara hoped that Fujita would write a foreword to his *Bokuyokuhen, * a learned treatise on infanticide. Fujita obliged him, but in a way that must have shocked the good doctor. His “Indeed, his foreword”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Epilogue</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/13_Epilogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/13_Epilogue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Infanticide in the Shadows of the Modern State&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Th&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;e fi nal chapter of habitual infanticide in Japan makes for a story full of surprises and contradictions. Aft er the Meiji Restoration of 1868, infanticide briefl y stood at the center of attention but then largely dropped from view. Abortion was designated a crime, but annual convictions remained in the hundreds at a time when late-term abortions and infanticides alone numbered in the tens of thousands. Imperial Japan had a rapidly growing population and an increasingly modern state apparatus, but contrary to its reputation, before the 1930s the modern state was less pronatalist than many domains of the Tokugawa system. Although it concerned itself far less with the reproductive lives of its subjects, the national government nonetheless presided over a surge in fertility and the fi nal retreat of infanticide, decades aft er the last targeted countermeasures had been fashioned and abandoned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Conclusion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/14_Conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/14_Conclusion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;C O N T I N U I T Y, C HA N G E , A N D D I F F U S I O N&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eastern Japan’s culture of infanticide lasted longer than the modern reproductive system of reliable contraceptives and safe abortions has so far endured in any part of the world. In some areas, it spanned more than two centuries, assuming its distinctive characteristics in the late seventeenth century and persisting into the age of cinema and motorcars. Infanticide was rooted in the most fundamental worldviews of those who employed it to plan their families. Springing from particular understandings of humanity, death, and immortality, it expressed ideals of responsible parenthood and obligations to elders, of how families should seek economic security and the respect of the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Index</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/00/Index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/drixler_infanticide_1660/00/Index/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*This page intentionally left blank *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;i n d e x&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Italic page numbers denote maps, plates, fi gures, and tables. *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;abandonment. *See * child abandonment&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;abortion (induced), frequency: estimated from&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;abortifacients and emenagogues, 28, 49, 56, 57,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;reported stillbirths, 119–23, &lt;em&gt;122&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;215&lt;/em&gt;, 216, 118, 175, 321n28&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;217&lt;/em&gt;, 218, 219; estimated from simulation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;abortion (induced): advertisements for, 28, 57,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;model, 112–13, &lt;em&gt;115&lt;/em&gt;, 320n9; relative to&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;117, 175, 94n6, 300n26, 302–3nn64–66;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;infanticide, 116–17, 196; summary of&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
