<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Goodall - window on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Goodall - window on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 GOMBE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/01_GOMBE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/01_GOMBE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I ROLLED OVER and looked at the time—5.44 A.M. Long years of early rising have led to an ability to wake just before the unpleasant clamour of an alarm clock. Soon I was sitting on the steps of my house looking out over Lake Tanganyika. The waning moon, in her last quarter, was suspended above the horizon, where the mountainous shoreline of Zaire fringed Lake Tanganyika. It was a still night, and the moon’s path danced and sparkled towards me across the gently moving water. My breakfast—a banana and a cup of coffee from the thermos flask—was soon finished, and ten minutes later I was climbing the steep slope behind the house, my miniature binoculars and camera stuffed into my pockets along with notebook, pencil stubs, a handful of raisins for my lunch, and plastic bags in which to put everything should it rain. The faint light from the moon, shining on the dew-laden grass, enabled me to find my way without difficulty and presently I arrived at the place where, the evening before, I had watched eighteen chimpanzees settle down for the night. I sat to wait until they woke.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 THE MIND OF THE CHIMPANZEE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/02_THE_MIND_OF_THE_CHIMPANZEE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/02_THE_MIND_OF_THE_CHIMPANZEE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OFTEN I HAVE GAZED into a chimpanzee’s eyes and wondered what was going on behind them. I used to look into Flo’s, she so old, so wise. What did she remember of her young days? David Graybeard had the most beautiful eyes of them all, large and lustrous, set wide apart. They somehow expressed his whole personality, his serene self-assurance, his inherent dignity—and, from time to time, his utter determination to get his way. For a long time I never liked to look a chimpanzee straight in the eye—I assumed that, as is the case with most primates, this would be interpreted as a threat or at least as a breach of good manners. Not so. As long as one looks with gentleness, without arrogance, a chimpanzee will understand, and may even return the look. And then—or such is my fantasy—it is as though the eyes are windows into the mind. Only the glass is opaque so that the mystery can never be fully revealed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 THE RESEARCH CENTRE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/03_THE_RESEARCH_CENTRE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/03_THE_RESEARCH_CENTRE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE GOMBE STREAM Research Centre grew from small beginnings to become one of the most dynamic field stations for the study of animal behaviour in the world. The first two research assistants joined me in 1964. It was not long before we found that there was more work than we three could manage, even though Hugo, my husband, was there to help as well. And so we sought additional funds to employ additional students. Almost all of them fell under the spell of Gombe and repaid our faith in them by helping us to collect more and ever more information about the lives of the chimpanzees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 MOTHERS AND DAUGHTERS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/04_MOTHERS_AND_DAUGHTERS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/04_MOTHERS_AND_DAUGHTERS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MANNERS MAKYTH MAN,” wrote the poet William of Wykeham. Ah—but what makyth the manners? We might, perhaps, venture ”Mother makyth manners“—along, of course, with a dash of early experience and more than a little spicing of genetic inheritance. The relative roles of ”nature“ versus “nurture” caused much bitter argument in scientific circles in recent years. But the flames of the controversy have now died down, and it is generally accepted that, even in the lower animals, adult behaviour is acquired through a mix of genetic make-up and experience gained as the individual goes through life. The more complex an animal’s brain the greater the role that learning is likely to play in shaping its behaviour, and the more variation we shall find between one individual and another. Information acquired and lessons learned during infancy and childhood, when behaviour is at its most flexible, are likely to have particular significance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 FIGAN’S RISE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/05_FIGANS_RISE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/05_FIGANS_RISE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FROM THE OUTSET it was obvious that Figan was endowed with exceptional intelligence: I gave many examples in my earlier book, &lt;em&gt;In the Shadow of Man.&lt;/em&gt; Equally clear was his determination to attain an ever higher position in male society. He developed an impressive charging display. This display serves to make a chimpanzee look bigger and more dangerous than he may actually be—his hair stands on end; he leaps up to shake the vegetation; he drags huge branches noisily along the ground, then hurls them ahead of him; he picks up and throws rocks with such vigour that they fly unpredictably ahead, behind or to the side; he stamps and slaps loudly upon the ground or some tree trunk; his lips are tightly compressed, pulling his face into a ferocious scowl. And the wilder and more impressive his display, and the more carefully it is planned and executed, the better his chance of intimidating his rivals without recourse to actual physical combat—during which he himself, as well as his opponent, might be injured. The smaller the individual the more it behooves him to work on his display.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 POWER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/06_POWER/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/06_POWER/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IT IS ONE THING to rise to the top-ranking position of a community. It is another matter to remain on top day after day, month after month. Figan had attained his goal thanks to the support of his brother—and Faben would not always be around, for every hour of every day. How would Figan manage then if one of the other males should challenge the new order?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The test came all too soon when Faben, involved in romantic dalliance with a female, vanished for three whole weeks to the northern part of the community range. Figan was extremely worried—and rightly so, for Humphrey and Evered might well have challenged their new alpha had they realized that his ally was so far away. Every so often Figan would climb a tall tree and, from the higher branches, gaze out in all directions as through searching for signs of his missing brother. Occasionally he would give the long, loud screaming calls that serve to attract the attention of friends in times of need—SOS screams, we call them. But Faben was too far away to hear and Figan was forced to rely on his own resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 CHANGE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/07_CHANGE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/07_CHANGE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IN MAY 1975 came a sudden night of terror: forty armed men came across the lake from Zaire and kidnapped four of the Gombe students. Afterwards there were many confused tales of what had happened, tales of courage as well as tales of horror. My old friend Rashidi was beaten over the head in a vain attempt to make him reveal the whereabouts of the key to the petrol store. He was deaf in one ear for months afterwards. The two young Tanzanian women working at Gombe then, Park Warden Etha Lohay and student Addie Lyaruu, flitted from one student’s house to the next, moving quickly through the dark forest, to warn everyone of the attack.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 GILKA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/08_GILKA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/08_GILKA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE CAREFREE DAYS of Gilka’s life ended when she was about four years old. As a small infant Gilka did not lack for companionship: her elder brother Evered was usually around, and her mother, Olly, spent much time with Flo and her family. But Evered was eight years older than Gilka—presumably Olly had lost at least one infant between the two of them—and he began to leave his family for extended periods when his sister was only five years old. At about the same time Olly began to avoid Flo because Figan, entering adolescence, not infrequently challenged his mother’s friend with blustering displays. And so Gilka spent hours, sometimes days at a time with only her timid mother for company. How happy for her we were when her infant brother was born. Soon he would be old enough to play with her and her days of loneliness would be over. But then came the grim days of the 1966 polio epidemic when Olly’s month-old infant became sick and died, and Gilka herself was particularly paralysed in one wrist and hand. Then, as though all this was not enough, two years later Gilka developed a bizarre fungus infection which, by the time she was eleven years old, had hideously disfigured her once elf-like, heart-shaped face. The grotesque swellings on her nose and brow ridge spread to her eyelids so that she could barely open her eyes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 SEX</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/09_SEX/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/09_SEX/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OLLY’S LINE had seemed doomed to extinction despite the fact that she had left two independent offspring when she died. Her daughter, Gilka, had failed to raise a single child and for a while we had thought that her son, Evered, forced into exile, was doomed to wander on the outskirts of the community range, alone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One Sunday morning Hamisi Mkono was walking along the lakeshore on his way to market. He was headed northward to the village of Mwamgongo that lies just outside the park boundary. He had, one by one, crossed each of the little streams that flow out into the lake from the watershed high up on the rift escarpment. First, after staff camp on the Kasekela Stream, comes Kasekela, then Linda, Rutanga and Busambo. Now he had reached the wide valley mouth where the Mitumba and Kavusindi Streams merge. There, up in an oil-nut palm not far from the beach, a chimp was feeding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 WAR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/10_WAR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/10_WAR/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE KASEKELA PATROL moved forward slowly and cautiously as it penetrated ever deeper into the territory of the Mitumba community. Satan was in the lead; five other males and Gigi, fully pink, followed close behind. All had their hair erect, bristling with apprehension and excitement. First one and then another bent to sniff the ground. Evered picked up a leaf and smelled it carefully; Figan stood upright to sniff the lowest branches of a tree. Repeatedly they paused to listen, staring into the dense undergrowth on either side. It was a wind-still day and the forest was silent but for the periodic shrilling chorus of the cicadas. Suddenly a twig snapped, a sharp, brittle sound. Satan turned to the others, his face split by a wide grin, part fear, part excitement—a gash of white teeth set in bright pink gums. Silently he embraced Jomeo who was behind him. Figan and Evered also threw their arms around one another, Mustard reached to touch Goblin. Like Satan, all were grinning hugely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 SONS AND MOTHERS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/11_SONS_AND_MOTHERS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/11_SONS_AND_MOTHERS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PATROLLING THE BOUNDARIES is but one of the many duties that the young male chimpanzee must learn if he is to grow to be a useful member of society. His adult experiences will be very different from those of a female. Thus it is not surprising that the milestones along the path he follows towards social maturity are different from those that mark the route for the female. Some, of course, are shared—such as the weaning process and the birth of a new baby in the family. But the initial break with the mother and the first journeys with the adult males not only come much earlier for the young male than for the female, but are of far greater significance. For it is here that he must learn many of the skills that he will need as an adult. The young male must challenge the females of his community, one by one, and then, when all have been dominated, he must begin to work his way into the dominance hierarchy of the adult males. The way in which the young male tackles each of these tasks, and the age at which he passes from one milestone to the next, depend heavily on his early family environment and the nature of his social experiences. This becomes very clear if we compare the development of Fifi’s sons, Freud and Frodo, with Passion’s son, Prof.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 BABOONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/12_BABOONS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/12_BABOONS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE INTERACTIONS between chimpanzees and baboons, as observed at Gombe, are more varied and more complex than those between any other two species in the animal kingdom—with the exception of our own interactions with other animals. Chimpanzees and baboons sometimes compete aggressively for food. Young baboons may be captured, killed and eaten by chimpanzees. The young of the two species sometimes play together—and young chimpanzees may even groom and try to play with adult baboons. Finally, they understand many of each other’s communication signals, and sometimes this results in what amounts to a joint effort to intimidate and repel a predator.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 GOBLIN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/13_GOBLIN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/13_GOBLIN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I FIRST SAW GOBLIN when he was just a few hours old in 1964. I wrote, at the time: “&amp;hellip;Melissa, looking down, stared long at the tiny face. Never had we imagined such a funny twisted-up little face. It was comical in its ugliness, with large ears, small, rather pursed lips, and skin incredibly wrinkled and bluish black rather than pink. His eyes were screwed tight shut against the fading light of the sun and he looked like some wizened gnome or hobgoblin.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 JOMEO</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/14_JOMEO/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/14_JOMEO/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JOMEO’S PERSONALITY was utterly different from that of Goblin. Where Goblin was fanatical in his determination to rise to a high social position and stay there, Jomeo, from adolescence onward, was almost entirely lacking in social ambition. He was the heaviest male we have known at Gombe, tipping the scale at just over one hundred and ten pounds, and he was a terrible enemy to individuals of neighbouring communities. Yet he did his best to avoid conflicts with the males of his own social group. A conundrum, was Jomeo, with a unique personality and a unique life history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 MELISSA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/15_MELISSA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/15_MELISSA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MELISSA CLEARLY MERITS special attention, if only as mother of one of Gombe’s most dynamic alpha males. Her life was remarkable in other ways too. For one thing, she gave birth, in 1977, to Gombe’s only known twins. I shall never forget my first sight of the babies—fraternal twins whom we named Gyre and Gimble. Melissa was sitting in the late afternoon sun, holding the two tiny bodies close to her breast so that they were all but invisible. One was suckling, the other seemed to be sleeping. When Melissa moved off, followed by her daughter Gremlin, I went with them and by the time I got back to the house that evening I had a real appreciation of the enormity of Melissa’s task. Most infants, by the time they are two or three weeks old, can cling to the mother without support for long periods of time. The twins gripped well enough. But one kept clinging to the other by mistake: then he would pull his brother loose and both would start to fall, uttering loud cries of distress. Melissa had to give them almost constant support, holding them close with one arm, or travelling with her legs bent so as to support their backs with her thighs. Once, that first afternoon, one of the twins half-fell and banged his head on the ground. He screamed loudly and this set the other crying too and it was several minutes before Melissa managed to quieten them. She also had a lot of trouble making her nest. I couldn’t see her well, for she was in dense foliage, but I heard a lot of crying from the babies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 GIGI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/16_GIGI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/16_GIGI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GIGI, UNLIKE MELISSA, will leave no descendants. Yet it would be difficult to overstate the extent to which this large sterile female has influenced the lives of the Kasekela chimpanzees, particularly the males. Since 1965 when she became sexually mature she has produced a new pink swelling, more or less regularly, every thirty days or so. Thus for more than twenty years she has been almost continually available to the Kasekela males for the gratification of their sexual desires. During that time her over-worked sex skin has swelled and shrivelled no less than two hundred and fifty times. By contrast, Fifi swelled only thirty times during the twenty-year period following &lt;em&gt;her&lt;/em&gt; first pinkness. As a result of this repeated and unnatural stretching Gigi’s swelling today is huge when compared with those of other Gombe females.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 LOVE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/17_LOVE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/17_LOVE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;POOR GIGI. Unable to bear young of her own, she has not been able to find the sort of reassuring relationships that typically exist between chimpanzee mothers and their grown young. Desperately she has sought contact with a series of infants, but one after the other they have grown away from her. Their bond is with their own mothers—and this bond is the strongest and most meaningful of all. Never again will an individual be so nurtured, protected and cared for as during infancy and early childhood. As the youngster matures, the relationship with the mother strengthens into a close, mutually supportive friendship that may last through life. A male, it is true, may forge a similar friendship with his brother, or even with a non-related community male. But a female, once she loses her own mother (either through death or if she, the daughter, transfers to a new community), will not know such a relationship again until her own youngsters are grown.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 BRIDGING THE GAP</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/18_BRIDGING_THE_GAP/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/18_BRIDGING_THE_GAP/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LOUIS LEAKEY sent me to Gombe in the hope that a better understanding of the behaviour of our closest relatives would provide a new window onto our own past. He had amassed a wealth of evidence that enabled him to reconstruct the physical characteristics of early humans in Africa, and he could speculate on the use of the various tools and other artifacts found at their living floors. But behaviour does not fossilize. His curiosity about the great apes was due to his conviction that behaviour common to modern man and modern chimpanzee was probably present in our common ancestor and, therefore, in early man himself. Louis was way ahead of most of his contemporaries in his thinking, and today his approach seems even more worthwhile in view of the surprising discovery that, as mentioned, human DNA differs from chimpanzee DNA by only just over one per cent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 OUR SHAME</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/19_OUR_SHAME/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/19_OUR_SHAME/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EVEN THE GOMBE chimpanzees are threatened by the relentless march of human expansion. I was thinking about this during a recent visit as I followed a large group of chimpanzees high up into the open wind-swept grasslands near the crest of the rift escarpment. I was out of breath when we arrived at our destination—a great stand of &lt;em&gt;muhandehande&lt;/em&gt; trees. As the chimps, with loud calls of delight, began to feast on the rich crop of yellow nectar-sweet fruits, I settled on a rock, that, shaded by one of the low, stunted trees, still held the coolness of the night air. We were almost at the topmost peak of the chimpanzee’s world, under the pale morning sky. Below us the ground fell away now steeply, now more gently, towards the blue-grey expanse of Lake Tanganyika. Lines and patches of green, starting just below the smooth golden-brown humps and ridges of the dry upper slopes, gradually became darker and thicker, then converged as they followed the maze of gullies and ravines that led down to the thickly forested valleys. To the north and to the south, valley succeeded valley, each leading its own swift-flowing stream westward, from the watershed, high in the hills, down to the lake.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 CONCLUSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/20_CONCLUSION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/20_CONCLUSION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IT IS THIRTY YEARS since I began to study chimpanzees. Thirty years during which there has been much change in the world, including the way in which we think about animals and the environment. My own personal journeys during this period, through the peaceful forests of Gombe and through the thorny jungles that have sprung up around issues of animal welfare and conservation, have led me a very long way from the naive young English girl who, with her mother, stepped so eagerly from the boat onto the Gombe beach. Yet she is still there, still part of the more mature me, whispering excitedly in my ear whenever I see some new or fascinating piece of chimpanzee behaviour—not only at Gombe, but sometimes in a captive situation also. I am as thrilled today, when I first see a new baby close up, when a mother reaches, with a slight pout of concern, to gather up her straying child, when one of the big males charges past, hair bristling, lips compressed in magnificent pride, as I was during the earliest months of the study.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 AFTERWORD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/21_AFTERWORD/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/21_AFTERWORD/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OVER THE TWENTY YEARS following the publication of &lt;em&gt;Through a Window,&lt;/em&gt; the total number of chimpanzees in Gombe has decreased. In the 1970s there were four communities. In the preceding pages we have seen how the males of the main study community, the Kasekela community, annihilated the Kahama community during the shocking Four Year War. The Kalande community, perhaps fifty strong, then moved northward, pushing the Kasekelan victors back on that front, while the equally strong Mitumba community pressed in from the north. Then, in 1987, there was a terrible epidemic of a flu-like disease that killed many chimpanzees in the Kasekela community and possibly the other two communities as well. By 1988, the Kasekela community had declined from about fifty to as few as thirty-eight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Index</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/00/Index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/pan/articles/goodall_window/00/Index/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The letters B, C, and CG indicate that the animal named is a baboon, a chimpanzee, or a chimpanzee at Gombe.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;adolescents, juveniles&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;extended dependency, [&amp;gt;], [&amp;gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;females, [&amp;gt;]–[&amp;gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“hero” worship, [&amp;gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;males, [&amp;gt;]–[&amp;gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;moves towards independence, [&amp;gt;], [&amp;gt;]–[&amp;gt;], [&amp;gt;]–[&amp;gt;], [&amp;gt;]–[&amp;gt;], [&amp;gt;]–[&amp;gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;sexual exploration, [&amp;gt;]–[&amp;gt;], [&amp;gt;], [&amp;gt;]–[&amp;gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;social activities, [&amp;gt;]–[&amp;gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See also individual chimpanzees&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Africa&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;chimpanzee population/ distribution, [&amp;gt;]–[&amp;gt;], [&amp;gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;conservation efforts, sanctuaries, [&amp;gt;]–[&amp;gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;habitat destruction, [&amp;gt;], [&amp;gt;]–[&amp;gt;], [&amp;gt;]–[&amp;gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
