<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Kemet on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/kemet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Kemet on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/kemet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Antiquity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/kemet/antiquity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/kemet/antiquity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;To fathom how long these have stood, Cleopatra is closer to u&amp;amp; me by 1000 yrs than she was to earliest Pharaoh&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;greek-recognition&#34;&gt;Greek recognition&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;plato-in-timaeus&#34;&gt;Plato in Timaeus&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He replied:-In the Egyptian Delta, at the head of which the river Nile divides, there is a certain district which is called the district of Sais, and the great city of the district is also called Sais, and is the city from which King Amasis came. The citizens have a deity for their foundress; she is called in the Egyptian tongue Neith, and is asserted by them to be the same whom the Hellenes call Athene; they are great lovers of the Athenians, and say that they are in some way related to them. To this city came Solon, and was received there with great honour; he asked the priests who were most skilful in such matters, about antiquity, and made the discovery that neither he nor any other Hellene knew anything worth mentioning about the times of old. On one occasion, wishing to draw them on to speak of antiquity, he began to tell about the most ancient things in our part of the world-about Phoroneus, who is called &amp;ldquo;the first man,&amp;rdquo; and about Niobe; and after the Deluge, of the survival of Deucalion and Pyrrha; and he traced the genealogy of their descendants, and reckoning up the dates, tried to compute how many years ago the events of which he was speaking happened. Thereupon one of the priests, who was of a very great age, said: O Solon, Solon, you Hellenes are never anything but children, and there is not an old man among you. Solon in return asked him what he meant. I mean to say, he replied, that in mind you are all young; there is no old opinion handed down among you by ancient tradition, nor any science which is hoary with age. And I will tell you why. There have been, and will be again, many destructions of mankind arising out of many causes; the greatest have been brought about by the agencies of fire and water, and other lesser ones by innumerable other causes. There is a story, which even you have preserved, that once upon a time Paethon, the son of Helios, having yoked the steeds in his father&amp;rsquo;s chariot, because he was not able to drive them in the path of his father, burnt up all that was upon the earth, and was himself destroyed by a thunderbolt. Now this has the form of a myth, but really signifies a declination of the bodies moving in the heavens around the earth, and a great conflagration of things upon the earth, which recurs after long intervals; at such times those who live upon the mountains and in dry and lofty places are more liable to destruction than those who dwell by rivers or on the seashore. And from this calamity the Nile, who is our never-failing saviour, delivers and preserves us. When, on the other hand, the gods purge the earth with a deluge of water, the survivors in your country are herdsmen and shepherds who dwell on the mountains, but those who, like you, live in cities are carried by the rivers into the sea. Whereas in this land, neither then nor at any other time, does the water come down from above on the fields, having always a tendency to come up from below; for which reason the traditions preserved here are the most ancient.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethnicity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/kemet/ethnicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/kemet/ethnicity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;depictions&#34;&gt;Depictions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;thumbnail&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;../images/seated_scribe_2600BCE.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;../images/seated_scribe_2600BCE.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;        Seated scribe ~ 2600 BCE&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;thumbnail&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;../images/heminunu_great_pyramid_architect_2600BCE.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;../images/heminunu_great_pyramid_architect_2600BCE.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;        Seated scribe ~ 2600 BCE&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mathildasanthropologyblog.wordpress.com/2008/07/22/the-faces-of-ancient-egypt/&#34;&gt;Old images&lt;/a&gt; . Note the contrasting depictions applied to Tutankhamen.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;[&lt;a href=&#34;https://mathildasanthropologyblog.wordpress.com/2008/03/04/fayum-portraits/&#34;&gt;Fayum portraits&lt;/a&gt; are burials of middle class Egyptians from Cleopatra&amp;rsquo;s era.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;dna-studies&#34;&gt;DNA studies&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/869797224334675968&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;There have been quite a few DNA studies on modern Egyptians, and to date, no noticeable amount of DNA from Italy or Greece has been detected, or DNA from anyone other than Arab, Berber and African. The same argument could equally point out that modern Egyptians could actually be darker than the ancient because of the Nubian invasion lead by Piye. Other DNA studies on prehistoric North Africa have revealed mostly Caucasian DNA (Taforalt site), and studies of the teeth, skulls and hair monotonously place Egyptians in the same category as modern North Africans – mainly Caucasian, a bit of African ancestry at the South.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Modern day Coptics, who speak a descendent of ancient Egyptian, are very fair. So are many of other modern Egyptians.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;blackness-of-egyptians-and-racism&#34;&gt;Blackness of Egyptians and Racism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Evidence indicates that ancient Egyptians were like neighboring levantine populations in appearence and genetics. They were neither &amp;ldquo;blacks&amp;rdquo; nor &amp;ldquo;whites&amp;rdquo; in contemporary terms. Yet, many people (with SJW tendencies, particularly in the America) say things like: &amp;ldquo;Kemeticism is a black religion&amp;rdquo; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Khenneferitw/status/1268427854972432385&#34;&gt;TW20&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;ldquo;Ancient Egyptians were blacks&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;I don’t care about genetics, that’s not what this is about. That’s why the other person was trying to talk about “biological racism”. These are social categories in a discourse of power.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/EPButler/status/1268744232627568643&#34;&gt;TW20&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
