<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;1 Towards the ninth general elections (1986–1989) on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;1 Towards the ninth general elections (1986–1989) on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1987; May 18–23: Meerut (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1987_May_1823_Meerut_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1987_May_1823_Meerut_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;61% Hindus, 36% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: BirBahadurSingh, Congress Party, September 1985–June 1988&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The city of Meerut (Uttar Pradesh) and the nearby areas of Moradnagar and Maliana were again the scene of ghastly violence. After twenty-five years, the memory of these horrors is still extremely vivid.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meerut&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On 14 February 1986, Muslims hoisted black flags in the city to protest against the opening of the lock that sealed the Babri Masjid in Ayodhya (Uttar Pradesh). They set fire to Hindu shops, leading to a small-scale riot. On 30 March 1987, large numbers of Meerut&amp;rsquo;s Muslims participated in a rally held by the Babri Masjid Action Committee (BMAC) in Delhi, where inflammatory speeches were delivered by the Shahi Imam Syed Abdullah Bukhari On April 14, a riot erupted during the Muslim festival of Shab-e-barat (the night of freedom), claiming ten lives. On May 16, the murder of a Hindu during a banal land dispute provided the spark for more extensive rioting. Violence flared up on May 18 in the Muslim-majority neighborhood of Hashimpura when a stand belonging to a Muslim was set on fire. Muslims attacked a Hindu shop in retaliation and stabbed its owner to death. The police and the Provincial Armed Constabulary (PAC) subsequently surrounded the area to arrest people. It was the Ramzan (Ramadan) period and Muslims were celebrating Iftar. Following appeals broadcast from the mosque&amp;rsquo;s loudspeaker, they pelted stones at the police. The violent and indiscriminate arrests that followed enraged the Muslim community, which started attacking Hindus. In the factories of Pillokhdi, ten to twelve persons (Hindus and Muslims) were burned alive. On May 19, a curfew was imposed. Hindu activists, helped by the PAC, looted and burned parts of the city. Many Muslims from poor backgrounds were burned alive, particularly in the area of Shastri Nagar where 33 persons (or more than 100 according to the residents) were killed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1987; May 19–22: Delhi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1987_May_1922_Delhi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1987_May_1922_Delhi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;81% Hindus, 12% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Delhi: none, Delhi was then considered a Union Territory, not a state&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A series of rumors about events happening in Meerut triggered communal violence in Delhi. On May 19, a mob killed the imam of a mosque in the Hauz Khaz area. A curfew was imposed but relaxed again on May 22 so that Muslims could offer prayers on the last day of Ramzan. A new bout of violence took place after afternoon prayers when mobs from the Jama Masjid and the Fatehpuri Masjid went on rampage. The media reported eight deaths. Other reports put the death toll at 15, among whom 12 were killed in shooting by police. The border between Meerut and Delhi was subsequently sealed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1988; May 17–20: Aurangabad (Maharashtra)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1988_May_1720_Aurangabad_Maharashtra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1988_May_1720_Aurangabad_Maharashtra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;52% Hindus, 29% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Maharashtra: Shankarrao Chavan, Congress Party, March 1986–June 1988&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Troubles erupted in the city of Aurangabad (Maharashtra) and in nearby villages after Municipal Corporation elections were held. Shiv Sena&amp;rsquo;s leader, Bal Thackeray, had held a rally in the town to ensure victory for his organization. But an alliance between the Congress (I), the Muslim League, and the Dalits enabled a Congress (I) candidate to win. Shiv Sena corporators (elected members of a municipal corporation in India) filed a petition with the high court to protest the outcome of the elections. On May 16, the day of the court hearing and a day before the Muslim festival of Id began, a large crowd gathered in front of the courthouse. A Shiv Sena mob started looting and burning parts of the city. Muslim criminals also stabbed Hindus. In all, the riot claimed 26 lives according to newspaper reports. Violence spread to the villages of Paithan and Bidkin; seven persons died in stabbing incidents in Paithan, and one person was shot dead in Bidkin. Two persons were also killed on May 20 in the nearby town of Jalna when the Shiv Sena attempted to hoist its flag near a mosque.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1988; October 8–11: Muzaffarnagar (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1988_October_811_Muzaffarnagar_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1988_October_811_Muzaffarnagar_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;58% Hindus, 40% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: Narain Dutt Tiwari, Congress Party, June 1988–December 1989&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Communal riots took place in the town of Muzaffarnagar (Uttar Pradesh). On October 8, Hindu communal organizations held a bandh (general strike) to counter a rally that was scheduled by the BMAC (Babri Masjid Action Committee) for October 14. Some Muslim shopkeepers refused to close their shops and violence flared up. One Muslim was stabbed and shops belonging to Hindus were burned. On October 11, a peace committee, mainly composed of Muslims, organized a demonstration in the town. It met a Shiv Sena mob. The two crowds started fighting, and 35 people, mainly poor rickshaw-pullers, were killed according to official accounts. The highest figures reported totaled 60 dead from the Muslim community and 27 victims from the Hindu community, bringing the total death toll to 87.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1989; April 16–20: Hazaribagh (Bihar)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1989_April_1620_Hazaribagh_Bihar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1989_April_1620_Hazaribagh_Bihar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;73% Hindus, 21% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Bihar: Satyendra Narain Sinha, Congress (I), March 1989–December 1989&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Violence engulfed Hazaribagh (Bihar). Communal tensions arose regarding the route that the Hindu Ram Navami procession was to follow; it was prevented by police from passing near the Jama Masjid (mosque). The VHP led an angry demonstration in the town in order to obtain the right to follow the ancient procession route-a demand finally agreed to by the district administration. On April 16, while the procession was taking place, a bomb exploded, sparking off a riot that claimed 19 lives according to official sources (but around 100 by unofficial accounts).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1989; February 24: Bombay (Maharashtra)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1989_February_24_Bombay_Maharashtra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1989_February_24_Bombay_Maharashtra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;67% Hindus, 19% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Maharashtra: Sharad Pawar, Congress Party, June 1988–June 1991&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On February 24, the first Friday after Ayatollah Khomeini issued a call to all Muslims declaring that the author Salman Rushdie should be killed for the publication of his book The Satanic Verses, a bandh was organized by some Muslim groups in Bombay. The book had already been banned by the Indian government in October 1988 (after intensive lobbying by Muslim organizations and also, it should be indicated, by secular lawyers), but Khomeini&amp;rsquo;s fatwa revived the mobilization. A protest march was held. This demonstration was not isolated: a transnational wave of protest had stirred up Muslim communities worldwide, with events having been organized not only in Delhi, Calcutta, Benares, and Darjeeling but also in Pakistan, the United Kingdom, Japan, Turkey, and France-to name but a few. In Bombay, the participants were young people associated with Islamic organizations. Disturbances started in the greatly stigmatized Muslim locality of Mohammed Ali Road after the police intervened to disperse the procession. Official figures put the toll at eleven dead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1989; October 14: Indore (Madhya Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1989_October_14_Indore_Madhya_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1989_October_14_Indore_Madhya_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;81% Hindus, 13% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Madhya Pradesh: Motilal Vora, Congress Party, January 1989–December 1989&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Communal troubles occurred in Indore (Madhya Pradesh), a predominantly Hindu city. The atmosphere in the city had become communalized ever since the «Shah Bano case» erupted. The «Babri Masjid/Ramjanmabhoomi issue» was another underlying factor that eventually helped trigger the riots. On September 30, a massive VHP rally was held. On October 4, a Ram Shila procession carrying consecrated bricks to build the projected Ram temple in Ayodhya, paraded through the city, creating resentment among Muslims. More than 25,000 people participated in the procession, among which BJP, RSS (Rashtriya Swayamsevak Sangh, National Volunteers&amp;rsquo; Organization) and VHP members could be found. Some Muslim leaders decided to counter this event by organizing an equally large procession in honor of the Prophet&amp;rsquo;s birthday on October 13. With the 1990 state assembly elections fast approaching, the Congress government, which had already given permission for the Hindu Ram Shila to be held, could not take the risk of further alienating Muslim voters: permission was granted for the Prophet&amp;rsquo;s birthday procession to take place. A riot ignited near the Ram Laxman Chowk area when crackers exploded at the end of the 30,000-strong Muslim procession, thereby panicking the crowd. Some armed marchers started rioting, which soon turned into a police–Muslim confrontation. Opponents of the chief minister, including those within the Congress, took advantage of the riots to demonstrate the incompetence of his administration. Engineer estimated that 27 people died in these riots (20 Muslims and seven Hindus), most of them in shooting by police. Official sources put the death toll at 23, including 19 Muslims. Unofficial reports say that the actual figure might be between 35 and 50 deaths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1989; October 22–28: Bhagalpur (Bihar)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1989_October_2228_Bhagalpur_Bihar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1989_October_2228_Bhagalpur_Bihar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;69% Hindus, 30% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Bihar: Satyendra Narain Sinha, Congress Party, March 1989–December 1989&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most remembered riots in India&amp;rsquo;s post-Independence history occurred in Bhagalpur (Bihar) and in 250 adjacent villages. The Justice Ramanandan Prasad Commission of Inquiry submitted a well-researched report in March 1995.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The «Babri Masjid/Ramjanmabhoomi controversy» had created communal tensions throughout the state of Bihar. The state government had issued directives to district and police authorities advising great caution. In the town of Bhagalpur, tension was simmering. The proximity of the festivals of Bihula Puja (Hindu) and Muharram (Shia) and the unsolved murder of a Muslim rickshaw-driver during the Hindu Bihula procession on August 20 had already antagonized the two communities. In October, local Hindu groups asked permission to organize a Ram Shila (carrying sacred bricks) procession to Ayodhya that was slated to pass through the Muslim-majority area of Tatarpur. The district administration, ignoring both the sensitivities involved in such a demand and the directives of the state government, acquiesced and granted the procession&amp;rsquo;s organizers permission to follow the proposed route.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1989; September 14: Kota (Rajasthan)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1989_September_14_Kota_Rajasthan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1989_September_14_Kota_Rajasthan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;79% Hindus, 16% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Rajasthan: Shiv Charan Mathir, Congress Party, January 1988–December 1989&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Riots took place in the city of Kota (Rajasthan). On September 14, a Hindu Anant Chaturdashi procession (held on the last day of the Ganesh festival; when Ganesh idols are immersed in lakes or rivers) marched in the town, shouting anti-Muslim slogans. Members of several akharas (traditional physical-training centers) and activists from Hindu communal organizations were present among the crowd. When the procession stopped near a mosque in the Ghantaghar area, Muslims riposted. Large-scale rioting ensued. Looting and burning by criminal elements took place. Muslim business groups were targeted, particularly the Bohras (a Shia sect). The media reported 16 deaths. Government reports counted 21 deaths but the Urdu newspaper; Tulu-e-Subh, established that, in all, 26 persons had lost their lives-22 Muslims and four Hindus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1989; September 28: Badaun (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1989_September_28_Badaun_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/1_Towards_the_ninth_general_elections_19861989/1989_September_28_Badaun_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;56% Hindus, 43% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: Narain Dutt Tiwari, Congress Party, June 1988–December 1989&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Riots erupted in Badaun (Uttar Pradesh). Tensions rose over the issue of Urdu-slated to become Uttar Pradesh&amp;rsquo;s second official language. On September 27, the ABVP (Akhil Bharatiya Vidyarthi Parishad, All India Students&amp;rsquo; Council) organized an anti-Urdu procession in the town. Riots occurred on September 28, the day the Urdu bill was introduced in the state&amp;rsquo;s legislative assembly. Students from Islamia Inter College organized a pro-Urdu march and attacked a Hindu college. Arson and killings began, with armed men firing at passers-by from the town&amp;rsquo;s rooftops. The riot claimed 27 lives according to some media reports. Other accounts assessed the total at more than 60 killed. Violence also spread to the countryside. During an attack on the Kasganj–Kashipur train, 13 passengers were killed by a mob. Other sources put the death toll of this attack at 24.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
