<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/wealth/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/wealth/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Corruption: INdia vs VieT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/wealth/articles/corruption_india-vs-vietnam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/wealth/articles/corruption_india-vs-vietnam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1554912943065554944.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A🧵&#xA;Forbes ranks India and Viet Nam as #1 and #2 in corruption in Asia.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately or fortunately, I have first-hand experience in doing business in both these countries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a background: We have a few million invested in IN; in VN, we have a few hundred.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My $0.02:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1/n&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If a thing is advertised to get done in 10 days, but you want to get it done in 2, you need to pay $2-5 bribe. If you don&amp;rsquo;t, it will get done in 10 days.&#xA;In IN, you need to pay bribe + Govt penalty + GST on the penalty to get anything done after your 10 days. Approx $200&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2/n&#xA;#2: Paying $20 gift/year/concerned Govt employee gets all your work done without a hitch. In return, they invite me for lunch/dinner, and even invitations to their kid&amp;rsquo;s birthday parties.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slow growth</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/wealth/articles/slow-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/wealth/articles/slow-growth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rawalactual/status/1729732201573458204&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the year 1952, when Pandit Jawahar Lal Nehru comfortably settled on the throne with his southern necessities, we had a GDP per capita of $1499 in today&amp;rsquo;s USD. It nearly halved by the year 1960 to $863.+++(5)+++ It was a hopeless basket case for decades.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Post-1990s reforms, we started bouncing back. Bounce back we did; by 2007 we finally surpassed the feudal British Raj-era GDP per capita - a number from a time when our literacy rate was just 16%, we had just endured a messy partition alongside an all-out war for Kashmir, and just a few years prior we were forced to fight a world war on behalf of the Englishmen in Europe, Africa and East Asia!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South India GDP - Hidden advantages</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/wealth/articles/south-india-gdp_hidden-advantages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/wealth/articles/south-india-gdp_hidden-advantages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: 2018 svarAjya mag&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lesson in economics, history, and logic for those who think that rest of India is a burden on the States of the south.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ever since floods ravaged Kerala in the south-western coast of India, an anti-north India propaganda (which serves no purpose in providing relief to the victims) is being stoked in some corners of social media. The alleged grievance of people furthering this narrative is that the states of the north have not come to the aid of Kerala, a claim which in itself is untrue. However, it doesn’t stop there. The case is then made that the ‘poor and backward’ north Indian states are a drag on the ‘prosperous and progressive’ south Indian states and that this is unfair to the south and is a legitimate reason to harbour a grievance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
