<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;lectures and discourses on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;lectures and discourses on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>414 THE METHODS AND PURPOSE OF RELIGION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/414_the_methods_and_purpose_of_religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/414_the_methods_and_purpose_of_religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-methods-and-purpose-of-religion&#34;&gt;THE METHODS AND PURPOSE OF RELIGION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In studying the religions of the world we generally find two methods of&#xA;procedure. The one is from God to man. That is to say, we have the&#xA;Semitic group of religions in which the idea of God comes almost from&#xA;the very first, and, strangely enough, without any idea of soul. It was&#xA;very remarkable amongst the ancient Hebrews that, until very recent&#xA;periods in their history, they never evolved any idea of a human soul.&#xA;Man was composed of certain mind and material particles, and that was&#xA;all. With death everything ended. But, on the other hand, there was a&#xA;most wonderful idea of God evolved by the same race. This is one of the&#xA;methods of procedure. The other is through man to God. The second is&#xA;peculiarly Aryan, and the first is peculiarly Semitic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>415 THE NATURE OF THE SOUL AND ITS GOAL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/415_the_nature_of_the_soul_and_its_goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/415_the_nature_of_the_soul_and_its_goal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-nature-of-the-soul-and-its-goal&#34;&gt;THE NATURE OF THE SOUL AND ITS GOAL&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The earliest idea is that a man, when he dies, is not annihilated.&#xA;Something lives and goes on living even after the man is dead. Perhaps&#xA;it would be better to compare the three most ancient nations — the&#xA;Egyptians, the Babylonians, and the ancient Hindus — and take this idea&#xA;from all of them. With the Egyptians and the Babylonians, we find a sort&#xA;of soul idea — that of a double. Inside this body, according to them,&#xA;there is another body which is moving and working here; and when the&#xA;outer body dies, the double gets out and lives on for a certain length&#xA;of time; but the life of the double is limited by the preservation of&#xA;the outer body. If the body which the double has left is injured in any&#xA;part, the double is sure to be injured in that part. That is why we find&#xA;among the ancient Egyptians such solicitude to preserve the dead body of&#xA;a person by embalming, building pyramids, etc. We find both with the&#xA;Babylonians and the ancient Egyptians that this double cannot live on&#xA;through eternity; it can, at best, live on for a certain time only, that&#xA;is, just so long as the body it has left can be preserved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>416 THE IMPORTANCE OF PSYCHOLOGY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/416_the_importance_of_psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/416_the_importance_of_psychology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-importance-of-psychology&#34;&gt;THE IMPORTANCE OF PSYCHOLOGY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The idea of psychology in the West is very much degraded. Psychology is&#xA;the science of sciences; but in the West it is placed upon the same&#xA;plane as all other sciences; that is, it is judged by the same criterion&#xA;— utility.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How much practical benefit will it do to humanity? How much will it add&#xA;to our rapidly growing happiness? How much will it detract from our&#xA;rapidly increasing pain? Such is the criterion by which everything is&#xA;judged in the West.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>417 NATURE AND MAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/417_nature_and_man/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/417_nature_and_man/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nature-and-man&#34;&gt;NATURE AND MAN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The modern idea of nature includes only that part of the universe that&#xA;is manifested on the physical plane. That which is generally understood&#xA;to be mind is not considered to be nature.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Philosophers endeavouring to prove the freedom of the will have excluded&#xA;the mind from nature; for as nature is bound and governed by law, strict&#xA;unbending law, mind, if considered to be in nature, would be bound by&#xA;law also. Such a claim would destroy the doctrine of free will; for how&#xA;can that be free which is bound by law?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>418 CONCENTRATION AND BREATHING</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/418_concentration_and_breathing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/418_concentration_and_breathing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;concentration-and-breathing&#34;&gt;CONCENTRATION AND BREATHING&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main difference between men and the animals is the difference in&#xA;their power of concentration. All success in any line of work is the&#xA;result of this. Everybody knows something about concentration. We see&#xA;its results every day. High achievements in art, music, etc., are the&#xA;results of concentration. An animal has very little power of&#xA;concentration. Those who have trained animals find much difficulty in&#xA;the fact that the animal is constantly forgetting what is told him. He&#xA;cannot concentrate his mind long upon anything at a time. Herein is the&#xA;difference between man and the animals — man has the greater power of&#xA;concentration. The difference in heir power of concentration also&#xA;constitutes the difference between man and man. Compare the lowest with&#xA;the highest man. The difference is in the degree of concentration. This&#xA;is the only difference.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>419 INTRODUCTION TO JNANA-YOGA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/419_introduction_to_jnana-yoga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/419_introduction_to_jnana-yoga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-jnana-yoga&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION TO JNANA-YOGA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the rational and philosophic side of Yoga and very difficult,&#xA;but I will take you slowly through it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yoga means the method of joining man and God. When you understand this,&#xA;you can go on with your own definitions of man and God, and you will&#xA;find the term Yoga fits in with every definition. Remember always, there&#xA;are different Yogas for different minds, and that if one does not suit&#xA;you, another may. All religions are divided into theory and practice.&#xA;The Western mind has given itself up to the theory and only sees the&#xA;practical part of religion as good works. Yoga is the practical part of&#xA;religion and shows that religion is a practical power apart from good&#xA;works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>420 THE VEDANTA PHILOSOPHY AND CHRISTIANITY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/420_the_vedanta_philosophy_and_christianity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/420_the_vedanta_philosophy_and_christianity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-vedanta-philosophy-and-christianity&#34;&gt;THE VEDANTA PHILOSOPHY AND CHRISTIANITY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Notes of a lecture delivered at the Unitarian Church, in Oakland,&#xA;California, on February 28, 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Between all great religions of the world there are many points of&#xA;similarity; and so startling is this likeness, at times, as to suggest&#xA;the idea that in many particulars the different religions have copied&#xA;from one another.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This act of imitation has been laid at the door of different religions;&#xA;but that it is a superficial charge is evident from the following facts:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>421 WORSHIPPER AND WORSHIPPED</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/421_worshipper_and_worshipped/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/421_worshipper_and_worshipped/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;worshipper-and-worshipped&#34;&gt;WORSHIPPER AND WORSHIPPED&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This lecture is reproduced from the &lt;em&gt;Vedanta and the West&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;../../volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/concentration.htm&#34;&gt;See Vol.&#xA;IV&lt;/a&gt;. )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in San Francisco area, April 9, 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have been taking up the more analytical side of human nature. In this&#xA;course we [shall] study the emotional side. . . . The former deals&#xA;with man as unlimited being, [as] principle, the latter with man as&#xA;limited being. . . . The one has no time to stop for a few tear-drops or&#xA;pangs; the other cannot proceed without wiping the tear-drop, without&#xA;healing that misery. One is great, so great and grand that sometimes we&#xA;are staggered by the magnitude; the other [is] commonplace, and yet&#xA;most beautiful and dear to us. One gets hold of us, takes us up to the&#xA;heights where our lungs almost burst. We cannot breathe [in] that&#xA;atmosphere. The other leaves us where we are and tries to see the&#xA;objects of life, [takes the limited] view. One will accept nothing&#xA;until it has the shining seal of reason; the other has faith, and what&#xA;it cannot see it believes. Both are necessary. A bird cannot fly with&#xA;only one wing. . . .&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>422 FORMAL WORSHIP</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/422_formal_worship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/422_formal_worship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;formal-worship&#34;&gt;FORMAL WORSHIP&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This lecture is reproduced from the &lt;em&gt;Vedanta and the West&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;../../volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/concentration.htm&#34;&gt;See Vol.&#xA;IV&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in San Francisco area, April 10, 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All of you who are students of the Bible . . . .understand that the&#xA;whole [of] Jewish history and Jewish thought have been produced by two&#xA;[types of] teachers — priests and prophets, the priests representing&#xA;the power of conservatism, the prophets the power of progress. The whole&#xA;thing is that a conservative ritualism creeps in; formality gets hold of&#xA;everything. This is true of every country and every religion. Then come&#xA;some new seers with new visions; they preach new ideals and ideas and&#xA;give a new push to society. In a few generations the followers become so&#xA;faithful to their masters&amp;rsquo; ideas that they cannot see anything else. The&#xA;most advanced, liberal preachers of this age within a few years will be&#xA;the most conservative priests. The advanced thinkers, in their turn,&#xA;will begin to hinder the man who goes a little farther. They will not&#xA;let anyone go farther than what they themselves have attained. They are&#xA;content to leave things as they are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>423 DIVINE LOVE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/423_divine_love/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_6/lectures_and_discourses/423_divine_love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;divine-love&#34;&gt;DIVINE LOVE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This lecture is reproduced from the &lt;em&gt;Vedanta and the West&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;../../volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/concentration.htm&#34;&gt;See Vol.&#xA;IV&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in San Francisco area, April 12, 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[Love may be symbolised by a triangle. The first angle is,] love&#xA;questions not. It is not a beggar. . . . Beggar&amp;rsquo;s love is no love at&#xA;all. The first sign of love is when love asks nothing, [when it] gives&#xA;everything. This is the real spiritual worship, the worship through&#xA;love. Whether God is merciful is no longer questioned. He is God; He is&#xA;my love. Whether God is omnipotent and almighty, limited or unlimited,&#xA;is no longer questioned. If He distributes good, all right; if He brings&#xA;evil, what does it matter? All other attributes vanish except that one —&#xA;infinite love.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
