<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Mongol on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Mongol on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chingiz Khan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/chingiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/chingiz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;../images/chingiz.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;../images/chingiz.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;        Chingiz Khakhan&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A scion of a noble Khamag Mongol lineage: Bodonchar Munkhag (also ancestor of Barlas mongols) …→  Khaidu …→ Khabul Khan → …→ Yesugei Baghatur → Chingiz. Yesugei  was a major chief.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From the lowest start in an abandoned family where he hunted for survival and spent time as a captive, he rose to form timely alliances, to recover his kidnapped wife, to raid others, thence to (revolutionarily) incorporate spared conquered and lowly people into his own band iteratively, all while repeatedly escaping death in battle, betrayal and traps, constantly improving war tactics and strategy (starting from roots in just basic hunting, raiding and herding instincts).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A shaman in his own right, he devised new laws and military organizational systems for his people; favored merit and loyalty over past lineage, made his people rise over their internecine conflicts. He inspired great loyalty. He set apart the Burkhan Khaldun mountain surroundings as a sacred and restricted area - which continues to this day. He came to be regarded as a great spirit, as an incarnation of Quormazda (~Ahura Mazda) Tengri.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Understanding where his mongol band stood relative to the surrounding powers and where riches from the sedentary people lay, he determined to found a hun-like steppe empire, secured his northern (sibir), western, eastern frontiers before learning seige craft, incorporating new war technology and engineering, herding captured civilians as human sheilds and laborers, buring farms and villages for pasture, setting up relay communication system, learning about enemy setups and divisions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Then he started picking off the Tanguts and the Jurchen controlled north China. And then the Uighurs, Khwarazm Turk sultanate. Then Persia, afghanistan, and the western qAra khitai. From Korea to Eastern Europe did his mongols go. In all this, novel technology and tactics were used including leveraging mobility by attacking from multiple points (crossing a desert unexpectedly in case of the Khwarazm), doing excellent propaganda - &amp;ldquo;surrender and be treated well, or resist and be fully slaughtered&amp;rdquo;, spawning and herding refugees, killing off all the old elite.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From his lineage sprang great conquerors and many able successors. Family tree &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Family_tree_of_Genghis_Khan&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Alas, his secularism and tolerance of abrahamisms sucked out mongolness and the grace of tengri from one islamized half; while sedentary decadance did the other major part in.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The biggest impact that has been uncovered to date appears to be that of Chingiz Kha’Khan, the founder of the great Mongol nation, who appears to have left behind 16 million male descendents in the modern world.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/12/23/founding-fathers-and-other-musings/&#34;&gt;MT05&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;If one accounts for females the number could be as many as double that. &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;low-start&#34;&gt;Low start&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Born in a lowly and poor family of the Borjigin tribe which lived on northern forested fringes of Mongol society which survived mostly by hunting (rather than herding) along with occassional raiding.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Even within his family, he was the son of his father&amp;rsquo;s second wife Hoelun. After his betrothal as a 8/9 year old to Beorte, his father died and he returned to see his family abandoned by the rest of the Tayichiyuds. Hoelun heroically marshalled the family and they scraped by with their hunts. His elder half-brother bullied him - and got hunted to death by himself and his brother as a result.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For this crime, he was made captive by the Tayichiyuds, whence he escaped thanks to the beneficence of a servant family.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;securing-family&#34;&gt;Securing family&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;He returned and grew older, brought Boerte home. Made an alliance with his father&amp;rsquo;s anda / blood brother, the Mongol Christian Ong Khan of the Kereyid.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Boerte was kidnapped by the Merkid to the north - with the grace of his home mount Burkhan Khaldun, he escaped. Giving thanks to the sacred mountain, with the help of Ong Khan and his vassal Jamuka (also Temujin&amp;rsquo;s adolescent blood brother/ anda) he recovered his now pregnant wife. Thence was born Jochi (guest) of uncertain parentage, whom he raised as his own.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In time were born Chagatai, Ogodei and Tolui.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;uniting-mongols&#34;&gt;Uniting mongols&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thence he split from Jamuka, who was treating him inequitably; joined the Jurchen inspired Ong Khan in raiding the Tatars to the east, then fought Jamuka (who now claimed to be Gurkhan) and Tayichiyuds. In the next Tatar raid, departing from past practice - he totally destroyed them -having postponed looting till after they could destroy all combatants; then he incorporated remnants into his own band as adapted family. He divided people into squads of multiples of tens (overriding tribe loyalty).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ong Khan rejected the now powerful Temujin&amp;rsquo;s marriage offer, then set a trap (allied with Jamuka) by fake acceptance. Temujin and his small party of ~17 men (including 3 muslims, many christians and buddhists) fled for days in the direction of Lake Baljuna. Thence he called forth his new tribe. They routed Ong Khan&amp;rsquo;s folks (most of whom anyway defected). Then he attacked the Naiman with his unpredictable skirmishes, &amp;ldquo;moving bush&amp;rdquo; tactics, wave-like attacks before switching to chisel formation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jamuka escaped, but was betrayed and executed with his betrayers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In next year&amp;rsquo;s kuriltai, he named his people &amp;ldquo;yeke mongol ulus&amp;rdquo; and became chingiz (wolf-like firm) khan. The shamans and his people said &amp;ldquo;huree huree&amp;rdquo; (~hurray).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;laws-and-ritual&#34;&gt;Laws and ritual&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thence he gave his people the great law -  the Ikh Yasag (the Great Yasa). He abolished previously common practices of intra-mongol slavery, bride kidnapping, bride selling, cross-family adultry, animal rustling - thereby increasing harmony. Further he restricted hunting to winter, instituted tolerance for all religions, election of the next khan by a family kuriltai, recognized group guilt.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Chingiz is also said to have formalized other rituals such as those of marriage. Walther Heissig noted that in eastern Mongolia they still recite this history during the pre-marriage ritual: “The fortunate Chingiz Kha’Khan, the incarnation of Qormusta Tengri, at the time when he took to wife Boerte [Footnote 3], the daughter of the Bayan of the Khunggirad tribe, the subject of Ughichud, sent his wise officials, led by the ministers Boghorju and Muqali [Footnote 4] and following the custom of the old, the custom was fulfilled to ask after the name and the year of birth of the bride. He is said to have introduced the ritual of anointing the yurt followed by the worship of the deities of the sun and moon and making offerings to the yurt hearth fire.” The last can be compared to the ritual offering to the gArhapatya fire in the Hindu tradition.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is notable that the yasag had an aspect paralleled the dharma of the Hindus and maat of the Egyptians. Just as dharma has the divine dimension of the laws laid down by the great gods Mitra and Varuṇa (captured in the śruti) at the base of the yasag was the old “divine law” of the Turks and Mongols known as the törü which is said to have been promulgated by the god Köke Möngke Tengri. On this rested the yasag of the great Khan which was like the smṛti brought to humans by Yama and our law-giver father Manu.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;later-influence&#34;&gt;Later influence&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The below heavily copies [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2017/07/30/mongolica-chingiz-khan-and-the-rest/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chingizid mongols</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/chingizids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/chingizids/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chingizid Menggu/Mengwu/ Mongol tribe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hun-connection&#34;&gt;Hun connection&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;From the famous rock-carving on the cliff overlooking the Tuula river facing north towards Ulan Bator dated to the 1000-1100s of CE depicting the ancestress doe (Qoa Maral) and the ancestress Alan Qoa suggest that the Mongols had re-established themselves in Mongolia by then.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2017/07/30/mongolica-chingiz-khan-and-the-rest/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is notable that the Chingiz Khan and his successors recognized this region and established their capital of Qara Qorum in this region. This supports the continuity hinted by Chingiz recognizing the Shanyu the Xiongnu as a temporal predecessor in his letter to the cīna sage Chiu Chuji. &amp;hellip; Chingiz does not acknowledge these Türks as his predecessors rather he skips them going back to the earlier Huns.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2017/07/30/mongolica-chingiz-khan-and-the-rest/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;legacy-of-chingiz&#34;&gt;Legacy of Chingiz&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The great chingiz temujin khAn conquered and started the empire (details &lt;a href=&#34;../chingiz/&#34;&gt;separate&lt;/a&gt;). General details about their foundational tactical, strategic, legal, ritual, administrative techniques are described there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Huns</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/huN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/huN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Hun Khanates starting from Shanyu Motun Tegin (probably originally pronounced as Shanyu Bagā’tur) learned the steppe Indo-Iranian style mobile warfare and made it a mechanism that allowed the Altaic people to overthrow the steppe Iranians and seize their steppe lands for themselves. They were able deploy this mode of warfare effectively on the Han Chinese empire and established a system where mobile steppe warriors could defeat much larger armies raised by sedentary populations. From the available record of conflicts in the meticulous cīna records we see that first Hun Khanate (the Xiongnu) defeated the Yueh-chih (including likely precursors of the Kuṣāṇa-s) to the west and the Tung Hu to the east to establish themselves in the Mongolian center.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Khitan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/khitan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/khitan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;liao-eastern-khitan-empires&#34;&gt;Liao (eastern khitan) empires.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;In their first phase the Khitans restored power of the Mongolic people through the conquest of northern China and the remnants of the Tang dynasty under their resourceful Khan Ambaqai (sinicized as Abaoji). Thus, they brought to the Mongolic world key political, administrative (e.g. the postal system) and knowledge developments that had occurred during the high-point of Chinese civilization.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2017/07/30/mongolica-chingiz-khan-and-the-rest/&#34;&gt;MT17&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;As the Tang empire was on decline, the Khitan Mongols under their great Khan Yelü Ambagai conquered the whole of Mongolia, Korea and Northern China in 907 CE and his successors eventually made the Han of the Song a vassal state. But over time they sinicized as the Liao dynasty and their Mongol traditions declined. The Han of the Song with aid from coethnic Hans within the Khitan empire made an alliance with the Khitan vassals, the Jurchen from Manchuria belonging to the Tungoosid branch of the Altaic peoples. The latter in 1124 CE defeated the Khitan and usurped all of their possessions in China, Manchuria and northern Korea.&amp;rdquo;  {&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2013/12/09/some-reflections-on-the-khans-qaidu-and-dua-and-the-great-khans-lost-legacy/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;}&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Toppled by Tungustic jurchen. The jurchen were in turn toppled and pushed south by Chingiz Khan; aided by khiTan remnants who acted as their bridge with Chinese.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;qara-khitai&#34;&gt;Qara Khitai&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yelü Dashi&amp;rsquo;s Qara (western/ black) khiTai uncharacteristically resisted conversion to Islam even while ruling over muslim subjects, in contrast with several other turkish and mongol branches.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yelü Dashi the Khan of the Khitan founded a smaller empire empire the Qara Khitai which occupied whole of Mongolia and Uighuristan after Uighurs accepted them as overlords to form an alliance against the Islamic onslaught. They routed the Ghazis led by Qarakhanids in the great battle of Balasagun in Khirgizstan. Then the combined army of Islam under the Qarakhanids and Saljuqs launched Jihad against the Qara Khitai but it was smashed in the battle of Qatwan after which Transoxiana was added to Mongolian domains. &amp;quot;  {&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2013/12/09/some-reflections-on-the-khans-qaidu-and-dua-and-the-great-khans-lost-legacy/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;}&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oirat mongols</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/oirat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/oirat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;rise&#34;&gt;Rise&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2015/01/21/some-notes-on-the-rise-of-oirat-power-and-the-jangar-tuuli/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The alliance comprised four major Western Mongol tribes: Khoshut, Choros, Torghut and Dörbet. Smaller tribes belonging to the confederation included the Khoits, Zakhchin, Bayids and Mangits.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;After 1370 CE the power of the Qubilaid Mongols declined precipitously leaving Mongolia in chaos, with several contenders jostling for supremacy but none gaining any ground. As they were fighting each other, the Kirghiz lord Ugechi routed the Qubilaid Khan Elbek and killed him in a battle in 1399 CE. &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;However, around the same time, (i.e. towards the end of the 1300s) a new Mongol confederation of tribes, the Oirat arose in Western Mongolia under their leader Mahamu. He formed an alliance with the chief of the Mongolized Arans (Alan; Airya&amp;gt;Ara), who were late-surviving steppe Iranians who had been close to the Qubilaids. Initially, they acted as though restoring Qubilaid power by overthrowing Ugechi and killing him. [Chingizid Puṇyaśrī briefly resurged but died in a dispute with Alans].&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Then Mahamu’s son Toghon Temür, who had succeeded his father, fell upon the Arans and routed them. They fled eastwards to Manchuria where they joined the horde of Adai the descendant of Qasar, the brother of Chingiz Khan, who made an attempt to establish himself as the lord of the Mongols. Adai defeated both the Chinese army sent against him and Toghon Temür to briefly establish himself as lord of Mongolia in 1425 CE, for the first time under a Qasarid emperor. But Toghon Temür patiently rebuilt his army and in 1428 CE and consolidated his power to the west by attacking Vais Khan, the Chagadaid ruler who wanted to wage a Jihad on the heathen Mongols. He routed Vais Khan in multiple battles and seized the Turfan basin from him. Having thus created strategic depth for himself in 1436CE he finally launched a major attack on Adai and slew him in a great battle for Mongolia.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;trouncing-mohammedan-kin&#34;&gt;Trouncing Mohammedan kin&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;On coming to power Esen started on an ambitious program of restoring unified heathen Mongol power. He began with a series of campaigns against the Mohammedan Chagadaids and brought them down in a battle fought on the shores of the Balkash. In the process he seized the Chagadaid princess Makhtum Khanim and made several renounce Mohammedanism. &amp;hellip; He then turned his attention west to conquer the ulus of the Chagadaid Toqtoa-buga and slew him.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
