<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणी-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणी-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The mysterious conflict between bhR^igu-s and gotama-s according to the tradition of the Urdhva-srotas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2008-07-14_the-mysterious-confliction-between-bhrigu-s-and-gotama-s-according-to-the-tradition-of-the-urdhva-srotas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2008-07-14_the-mysterious-confliction-between-bhrigu-s-and-gotama-s-according-to-the-tradition-of-the-urdhva-srotas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2008/07/14/the-mysterious-confliction-between-bhrigu-s-and-gotama-s-according-to-the-tradition-of-the-urdhva-srotas/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the R^igveda the gotama-s repeatedly and respectfully mention the&#xA;bhR^igu-s as the founders of the fire rite, which is consonant with&#xA;their position at the head of the shrauta gotra-pravara lists.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For example:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;dadhuSh TvA bhR^igavo mAnuSheShvA rayiM na chAruM suhavaM janebhyaH |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;hotAram agne atithiM vareNyaM mitraM na shevaM divyAya janmane ||RV&#xA;1.58.6&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Here nodhA gautama declares that the bhR^igu-s first established the&#xA;ritual fire in the midst of men. In fact nodhA gautama goes ahead to&#xA;mention this act of the bhR^igu-s again in RV 1.60.1:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;vahniM yashasaM vidathasya ketuM suprAvyaM dUtaM sadyo-artham |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;dvi-janmAnaM rayim iva prashastaM rAtiM bharad bhR^igave mAtarishvA&#xA;||&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Here the transmission of the ritual fire from mAtarishvan to bhR^igu,&#xA;the first founder of the rite amongst men is mentioned.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The other gautama, kakShivAn dairghatamasa, also mentions the bhR^igu-s&#xA;in positive light:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;pra yA ghoShe bhR^igavANe na shobhe yayA vAchA yajati pajriyo vAm |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;praiShayurna vidvAn || RV 1.120.5&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Here he compares his own chant to the ashvinau to that of the&#xA;bhR^igu-s.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;His father dirghatamAH auchAthya states:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;yamerire bhR^igavo vishvavedasaM nAbhA pR^ithivyA bhuvanasya majmanA&#xA;|&lt;br&gt;&#xA;agniM taM gIrbhirhinuhi sva A dame ya eko vasvo varuNo na rAjati || RV&#xA;1.143.3&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Here he states that the mighty bhR^igu-s first established the fire&#xA;sacrifice in the nave of the earth.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A similar view is also shared by the other great vipra amongst the&#xA;gotama-s, vAmadeva gautama:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;ayam iha prathamo dhAyi dhAtR^ibhir hotA yajiShTho adhvareShv IDyaH |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;yam apnavAno bhR^igavo viruruchur vaneShu chitraM vibhvaM vishe-vishe&#xA;|| RV4.7.1&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and&lt;br&gt;&#xA;AshuM dUtaM vivasvato vishvA yash charShaNIr abhi |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A jabhruH ketum Ayavo bhR^igavANaM vishe-vishe ||RV 4.7.4&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Here, apnavAna and his bhR^igu-s are described as having initiated the&#xA;fire rite that spread throughout the peoples.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;vAmadeva gautama also states:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;eved indrAya vR^iShabhAya vR^iShNe brahmAkarma bhR^igavo na rathaM |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;nU chid yathA naH sakhyA viyoShad asan na ugro .avitA tanUpAH || RV&#xA;4.16.20&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Here, vAmadeva says that he fashions a hymn for indra even as the&#xA;bhR^igu-s had made a car. Earlier in the same same sUkta vAmadeva states&#xA;that he is fashioning a hymn for indra even as the bhArgava ushanAH&#xA;kAvya had done in the past. Thus from all accounts in the R^igveda it&#xA;appear that the gotama-s like their other a~Ngirasa cousins the kaNva-s&#xA;and bharadvAja-s considered the bhR^igu-s as their models, and founders&#xA;of their ritual system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>parashurAmAyaNa-s and kArtavIryArjunIyaM-s</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2006-11-05_parashuramayana-s-and-kartaviryarjuniyam-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2006-11-05_parashuramayana-s-and-kartaviryarjuniyam-s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/11/05/parashuramayana-s-and-kartaviryarjuniyam-s/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The one great hero of our clan, the omnipresent and poly-faceted symbol&#xA;of brahmin-hood lives a strange life in the Hindu mythosphere.&#xA;rAmo-bhargava has become an avatAra puruSha of nArAyaNa but hardly&#xA;enjoys the status of devakI-putra or his name sake of the ikShvAku clan.&#xA;There are no major mantra-s devoted to him, and even in the mahAbhArata&#xA;where he makes a prominent appearance, only next the main protagonist&#xA;avatAra-s, the devakI-putra and baladeva, he is only once called an&#xA;avatAra. Yet, starting from the mahAbhArata he has an increasingly&#xA;prominent place in the Hindu mythosphere of the paurANic realm appearing&#xA;all over over the place in addition to his main encounter with the&#xA;haihaya king kArtavIryArjuna and his priest, datta the atri. He is seen&#xA;roguishly barging into shiva’ s abode and enters into a fight with&#xA;vinAyaka where he is said to break his tusk. The fierce bhArgava also&#xA;fights kumAra several times and is soundly beaten by the god. He is said&#xA;to have received a mace from kumAra that he wielded with great ability&#xA;in his many battles. He is seen transmitting shrIvidyA in the form of&#xA;the kaula kalpa-sUtras from dattAtreya to sumedhas. Elsewhere, he is&#xA;shown teaching kalki the ways of war for the final destruction of the&#xA;mlechCha-s and dasyu-s who are overruning bhAratavarSha. Despite his&#xA;vast popularity he does not receive the devotions like those rAmachandra&#xA;and kR^iShNa, nor his story widely followed like the rAmAyaNa or the&#xA;harivaMsha.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The bhR^igu-s, the country and the national epic</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2006-10-12_the-bhrigu-s-the-country-and-the-national-epic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2006-10-12_the-bhrigu-s-the-country-and-the-national-epic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/10/12/the-bhrigu-s-the-country-and-the-national-epic/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The imprint of the bhR^igu-s is not just all over the literature of&#xA;bhAratavarSha but also dotting the very expanses of the land of the&#xA;bhArata-s. While being a bhR^igu, I may be biased to see this imprint&#xA;more than others, the fact has been observed by many others. The&#xA;following is a purely parochial view of history seen through the lens of&#xA;my ancestry, yet I believe there are elements of real significance for&#xA;the history of the Hindu nation. Shrines of the bhArgava hero, the son&#xA;of jamadagni are seen throughout the country. The most hallowed and the&#xA;oldest to which we trace our antecedents [real or mythical] is the&#xA;shrine in Kangra with the inscription mentioning the members of the&#xA;bhArgava clan involved in the study of the paippalAda shAkha of the&#xA;atharva veda. These bhArgavas performed not only the shrauta rites as&#xA;but also the peculiarly atharvanic later day rites like the skanda yAga,&#xA;the saucer of nirR^iti, the making of the cake called the Aditya maNDaka&#xA;to indra and viShNu and yearly invocation of the terrifying kR^ityA of&#xA;the bhArgava-s, that first emerged from the fire of bhR^igu and then&#xA;from that of chyavAna, also worshiped as the goddess pratya~NgirA. The&#xA;muni visited this primal shrine and offered the sacraments for the&#xA;gotra-kR^it-s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>varmashiva</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2006-06-22_varmashiva/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2006-06-22_varmashiva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/06/22/varmashiva/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“tato devA rudraM nApashyaMs te devA rudraM dhyAyanti tato devA&#xA;UrdhvabAhavaH stunvanti&lt;br&gt;&#xA;brahmaikaM tvaM dvi-tridh-ordhvam adhash cha tvaM shAntish cha tvaM&#xA;puShTish cha tvaM tuShTish cha tvaM hutam ahutaM vishvam avishvaM dattam&#xA;adattaM kR^itaM akR^itaM paraM aparaM parAyaNaM cheti “&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The circumstances and the details of the migration of my ancestors from&#xA;the southern country to the northern zone, where they stayed for almost&#xA;4-5 centuries is poorly known. But inscriptional records and tantric&#xA;ogha-valli-s record one member of my clan from the period just after the&#xA;initial migration. While not much is known of others, this member of my&#xA;clan, nephew to my direct male ancestor, attained considerable fame in a&#xA;particular sense. The vaidiki “smArta-s” were always the source of&#xA;intellectual capital for diverse sectarian matas through their&#xA;defections to those paths. We have jayarAshI, the brahmin exponent of&#xA;the chArvAka-mata, others like vAsubandhu of the AghamarShaNa kaushika&#xA;gotra from puShpapura (now Peshawar in the Moslem Terrorist State)&#xA;benefitted the bauddha mata, and rAmAnuja expanded shrI-vaiShNavism.&#xA;This clansman of mine, varmashiva, was likewise a case of brain-drain,&#xA;but into the shaiva-mata. While I generally tend to identify myself with&#xA;saMkarShaNa in jayanta’s play, Agama-Dambara, I still have my sympathies&#xA;for varmashiva for certain reasons. Inscriptions records associated with&#xA;the vodAmayUtA temple of rudra clearly mention his pravara as being:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;pravara pa~NchakAnvito vatsa-bhArgava sugotra-maNDitaH| bhArgava-&#xA;chyAvanaka- ApnavAnakair- AurvvanAma-jamadagnibhir yutaH ||&lt;br&gt;&#xA;His father, my ancestor’s brother was vasAvaNa hailing from the village&#xA;of siMhapallI. Born in the north in the region of pa~ncha-gauDa he was&#xA;in Gujarat in very turbulent times after the Ghaznavid storm. He learnt&#xA;the atharva-veda at aNahilapATaka, the great pAshupata center. He also&#xA;studied the vaisheShika and nyAya of which he remained a great advocate&#xA;till the end and wrote a treatise building on the&#xA;padArtha-dharma-saMgraha. He performed the pAshupata vrata as per the&#xA;atharvaNa AdeshaH and became inclined towards the shaiva mata. He then&#xA;proceeded to the drAviDa desha in dakShiNa patha where he encountered&#xA;bauddhas and is said to have blasted them in fiery polemics. It was&#xA;there that he completed the study of various shaiva tantras of the&#xA;bhairava, bhUta, garuDa, vAma and siddhAnta srotas and became firmly&#xA;established in the siddhAnta stream. varmashiva became a great proponent&#xA;of the siddhAnta tantras, developing a school parallel to that of king&#xA;bhoja-deva of the paramAra-s, with a nyAya-vaisheiShika orientation. He&#xA;then journeyed to Kashmir, where debated with towering scholars of the&#xA;lAkulIsha kAlAmukha, trika and shrIvidyA schools and his scholarly and&#xA;independent philosophical abilties was much respected by his rivals. He&#xA;was honored by AnandarAja the lohara king of Kashmir. He also was widely&#xA;respected for his tAntric abilities in the KShudra vidyA-s acquiring the&#xA;yakShiNi, chUrNa, chetaka, DAmarikA and DAvI prayoga-s (latter for&#xA;invoking terrifying agents that can cause a variety of rogas in course&#xA;of uchChATana prayoga-s). varma then settled in the temple of&#xA;vodAmayUtA, where he was appointed as the head of a shaiva maTha. There&#xA;he acted in un-orthodox ways. He took as his primary student, a&#xA;brilliant shUdra named mUrtigaNa. mUrtigaNa was initiated into all the&#xA;tantric rahasya-s by varmashiva and became a great tantric himself. He&#xA;was made the preceptor of the Rathod king shUrapAla, despite being&#xA;shUdra on account of his learning. He succeeded varMashiva as the lord&#xA;of the maTha. At that time a nambUthiri from the chera country,&#xA;ishAnashiva, journeyed to vodamayUtA and impressed by mUrtigaNa became&#xA;his student. He then succeeded mUrtigaNa and became an illustrious&#xA;shaiva tantric himself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The bhR^igu-s of the R^igveda</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2006-05-21_the-bhrigu-s-of-the-rigveda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2006-05-21_the-bhrigu-s-of-the-rigveda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/05/21/the-bhrigu-s-of-the-rigveda/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the accounts of vedic tradition the bhR^igu-s were the foremost of&#xA;the R^iShi-s. It appears that they were the founders of the fire ritual&#xA;which is at the heart of the vedic religion. They are not authors of&#xA;many mantra-s of the R^ig veda, though their surrogate clan, the&#xA;shaunahotra-s, have a maNDala to themselves (RV2). Nevertheless, bhR^igu&#xA;or the bhR^igu-s are mentioned 27 times by name in the RV. A single&#xA;ancient member of the main-line bhR^igu clan ushanA kAvya, the grandson&#xA;bhR^igu, through his son kavi bhArgava, is mentioned by that name in 15&#xA;times in the RV. Another much latter main-line bhR^igu, jamadagni, is&#xA;mentioned as contemporary by two of the great RV R^iShis, vishvAmitra&#xA;(who was an ally jamadgni) and vasiShTha. He is mentioned 9 times in the&#xA;RV. Other bhR^igus are fleetingly mentioned by name, like apnavAna (at&#xA;least 2 times) and aurva, and, like ushanA kAvya are clearly historical&#xA;figures even for most of the RV composers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The vItihotras and kashirAjas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2006-04-11_the-vitihotras-and-kashirajas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2006-04-11_the-vitihotras-and-kashirajas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/04/11/the-vitihotras-and-kashirajas/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now we shall narrate the great AkhyAnaM of the vItihotras and the&#xA;kAshirAjas.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The vItahavya the descendent of sahasrArjuna, had restored the glory of&#xA;the haihayas after it was destroyed by rAmo bhArgava. He and his&#xA;numerous sons the vItahavyas were well-versed in the vedas and the&#xA;science of weapons, and were fierce warriors. They planned a great raid&#xA;on the kingdom of kAshI, when haryashva was its ruler. Having forded the&#xA;yamuna, vItahavya and his sons swept into the territory of the kAshis by&#xA;surprise. haryashva was caught with a small division and surrounded by&#xA;the vitihotras. In the battle that followed they surrounded haryashva&#xA;and riddled him with arrows killing him. Having collected a large booty&#xA;of wealth and cattle they returned to haihaya territory. haryashva’s son&#xA;sudeva ascended the throne and a righteous ruler restored the glory of&#xA;kAshi after a while. But this only attracted the vItahavyas to invade&#xA;the kashi realms again. In the battle that followed, the haihayas slew&#xA;sudeva and having laid waste to his capital itself returned to their&#xA;domains in the vatsa country [the region developed by the bhArgavas,&#xA;the erstwhile priests of the haihayas, before the dattAtreyas].&#xA;Realizing the threat from the vItahavya and his brother tAlajangha’s&#xA;sons the next king of the kAshis built elaborate fortifications in his&#xA;revived capital named vArANasi, with the help of the great indra. Under&#xA;divodAsa’s reign the kingdom teemed with prosperity and trade.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The death of reNukA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2006-03-06_the-death-of-renuka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2006-03-06_the-death-of-renuka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/03/06/the-death-of-renuka/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our ancestress reNukA, the ikShvAku princess and wife of jamadagni, is&#xA;supposed to have had a checkered career. She is supposed to have been&#xA;adultrous having had an affair with a yadu prince of mArtikavata, which&#xA;led to our illustrious ancestor jamadagni’s wrath and the famous story&#xA;concerning rAma that needs no repetition now. jamadagni was accused by&#xA;some modern interlocutors as being unjust to her (but I realized their&#xA;knowledge did not go beyond the tale narrated in the Amar Chitra Katha&#xA;comics, where jamadagni merely say she had ‘sinned’ without any&#xA;reference to what the sin was. After all this was for kids). But from&#xA;the genuine versions of the tale we see this is entirely unjustified.&#xA;jamadagni was pretty dutiful to reNukA. The tale goes that the mighty&#xA;jamadagni was practising archery, when she used to go and collect the&#xA;arrows he used to shoot at the targets. She was distressed in course of&#xA;this activity by the sun’s heat, when jamadgni is supposed to have&#xA;threatened to hit the sun with his great astras. This had the gods give&#xA;reNukA shade to help her with the sun. But there is not much doubt&#xA;despite later day euphemisms that she did clearly have an affair with&#xA;the prince of mArtikavata, and adultery as per Hindu law warranted&#xA;punishment, ever since the day uddAlaka AruNi saw his mother commit it.&#xA;But many have asked me the question what happened to reNukA after her&#xA;son rAma restored her to jamadagni’s grace. The history states that she&#xA;indeed redeemed herself. The fierce vItahavyas, protected by the&#xA;Atreya’s prayogas, bent on revenge, breached the defenses of jamadagni&#xA;and attacked him while he was deep in meditation. While a once fiery&#xA;archer, the old bhR^igu was now in meditation and his valiant sons were&#xA;far away. reNukA boldly picked up jamadagni’s weapons and stood in the&#xA;path of the vItihotras, tAlajhanga and tuNDikeras who rushed in with&#xA;their bows upraised. They struck her their missiles and killed her. It&#xA;is said she received 21 wounds before falling dead. Then they struck&#xA;jamadagni with the dattAtreya missiles. jamadagni’s brahman power was&#xA;vaporized by the weapons charged with the atri’s brahman and he dropped&#xA;dead. With that the Atreya had got back the brahman power of the atris&#xA;that had been sucked out by our fiery ancestor aurva.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The magic formula of the bhR^igus</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2004-12-05_the-magic-formula-of-the-bhrigus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2004-12-05_the-magic-formula-of-the-bhrigus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/05/the-magic-formula-of-the-bhrigus/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;प्र सुवनः सोम ऋतायुश् चिकेत&lt;br&gt;&#xA;+इन्द्राय ब्रह्म जमदग्निर् अर्चन्।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;वृषा यन्ता ऽसि, शवसस् तुरस्य&lt;br&gt;&#xA;+अन्तर्यच्छ गृणते धर्तं दृंह॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;pra suvAnaH soma R^itayush chiketendrAya brahMa jamadagnir archan /&lt;br&gt;&#xA;vR^iShA yantA .asi shavasas turasyAntaryachCha gR^iNate dhartaM dR^igMha //&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;soma, endowed with the R^ita becomes visible when extracted,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;jamadagni chants the hymn to indra;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;you are the mighty restrainer of impetuous force;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Ward it off and strengthen the scaffold for the sacrificer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>datta, the atri</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2004-09-26_datta-the-atri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2004-09-26_datta-the-atri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/09/26/datta-the-atri/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;datta, the atri, was endowed with lasting youthfulness and was the&#xA;embodiment of all the 3 guNas. In his early life was a great warrior and&#xA;was the prime minister and priest of haihaya emperor, kArtavIrya arjuna.&#xA;He led the haihaya troops to many great victories and participated in&#xA;the rise of the emperor. The haihaya king was un-paralleled in the use&#xA;of arms and having conquered the entire known world was crowned as&#xA;saMrAT by dattAtreya. The haihaya, however, had a deep enemity with the&#xA;bhR^igus. He stole the cow of the bhArgava R^ishi jamadagni. In due&#xA;course arjuna was challenged by rAma the son of jamadgni and axed to&#xA;death by him. dattatreya was furious and carried out many abhichAra&#xA;rites to destroy the bhArgavas. Aided by his spells, the vitIhotras or&#xA;the sons of arjuna slew the bhArgava R^ishi jamadgni. However, rAmo&#xA;bhArgava over came the spells with their own deadly incantations of the&#xA;atharvaNa shruti and prepared for war with the vItahavyas. In the battle&#xA;that followed they were protected by the brahman of dattAtreya and the&#xA;bhArgava could not over come them. However, finally with the&#xA;atri-destroying charm of the atharvaNa shruti rAma overcame the brahman&#xA;of datta. After that he pierced the vitahavyas with his deadly astras&#xA;and slew each of them. With the vItihotras dead, datta renounced the&#xA;world and practiced the sattva guNa. He lead the life a celibate ascetic&#xA;for long, teaching the principles of renunciation. In the final stage of&#xA;he became and embodiment of the tamoguNa and picked a beautiful woman as&#xA;his companion and wandered around with her in carefree indulgence,&#xA;bearing a trident and a bow and guarded by 4 dogs. The were continually&#xA;lost in dalliance, loud laughter, merriment and imbibition of vAruNi&#xA;beer, when rAmo bhArgava chanced upon them. In this state the atri&#xA;enlightened him on the tantric lores.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The rape of arajA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2004-04-01_the-rape-of-araja/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/2004-04-01_the-rape-of-araja/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/04/01/the-rape-of-araja/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the vamshAvalis of the founding fathers of my many branched clan there are many tales of confrontation with the rAjanyas. While the conflict between kArtavIryArjuna and rAma is well known, the much earlier showdown in the early career of ushanA kAvya is hardly well known.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The king daNDa of the line of the ikshvAkus was a powerful king who ruled over the Aryan realms based in his capital, madhumanta. He was a contemporary of the great luminary of the bhArgavas, ushanA kAvya, the descendent of bhR^igu. kAvya’s first daughter was the very beautiful arajA. In the intoxicating month of Chaitra, the king daNDa paid a visit to the Ashrama of the bhArgavas. There he saw arajA ranging the forest with carefree abandon. Her sight greatly aroused the king daNDa and with palpitating heart he ran to her.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deva sambandhAH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/deva-sambandhAH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/deva-sambandhAH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/2010967839386071347&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As an aside the bhR^igu-s have an ambivalent relationship viShNu as with the other daiva traditions:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;bhR^igu&amp;rsquo;s wife is beheaded by viShNu;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;bhR^igu kicking viShNu;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;bhArgava kAvya fighting viShNu before being crushed/blinded by him (also by rudra).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;bhArgava-s headed by chyavAna attacking indra.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;indra shattering dadhya~nch&amp;rsquo;s head. etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But on the other hand they also figure in pro-viShNu roles like rAma bhArgava.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post-bhArata mArkaNDeya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/post-bhArata-mArkaNDeya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/post-bhArata-mArkaNDeya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1459000053339762691&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1459000053339762691&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The pioneer of modern mahAbhArata studies, Sukthankar noted that the Mbh had probably been redacted by the bhR^igu clan. Here are the # occurrences of the bhR^igu/bhArgava &amp;amp; mArkaNDeya across the 18 parvan-s. (missing image)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;bhR^igu &amp;amp; his descendants through paulomI are frequently mentioned fromfrom the R^igveda onward in the saMhitA-s. However, the 2nd line from bhR^igu&amp;rsquo;s wife khyAti doesn&amp;rsquo;t receive any notable mentions. However, in the mahAbhArata we find the emergence of a key member of this lineage mAkarNDeya.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ushanas kAvya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/ushanas_kAvya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/articles/MT_articles/ushanas_kAvya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the RV, the great bhArgava, ushanas kAvya, is a votary of the deva-s. In the itihAsa &amp;amp; purANa he becomes an enemy of the gods &amp;amp; partisan of the asura-s. In the Iranian tradition, he is interestingly a great hero-figure with daiva affinities. The baudhAyana-shrauta-sUtra 18.46-47 &amp;amp; jaiminIya brAhmaNa 1.154 onwards which belong to the late vaidika tradition give an intermediate picture.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There, bR^ihaspati &amp;amp; kAvya have respectively become the purohita-s of the deva-s &amp;amp; asura-s. What ever rite the deva-s did the asura-s did the same in a reverse format: this we believe is an old memory of the emergence of the counter-religion among the Iranians with its normative inversion.+++(4)+++ Thus, they had reached a stalemate. indra was aware that a 3-headed gandharva, suryavarchas, who lived in the middle of the ocean with his wife on a golden ship has the capacity to prognosticate the basis for victory in the conflict. Hence, indra went to the wife of the sUryavarchas &amp;amp; talked her into asking her husband about his prognosis. indra becoming a ray of light overheard them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
