<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/fraud/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/fraud/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The fake scientist</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/fraud/articles/MT/2013-07-13_the-fake-scientist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/fraud/articles/MT/2013-07-13_the-fake-scientist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2013/07/13/the-fake-scientist/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He was born in the Gangetic doab in a clan of vaNija-s. He had inherited the skill honed by centuries of selection in business transactions of “cracking the situation”.+++(4)+++ However, he did not have deep introspective skills or a passion for acquiring knowledge in a wider sense. He passed his way through school and eventually reached college to get what in India is called an ordinary B.Sc. degree in something related to biology. After two more years of listless college life he added yet another degree in the same subject to his name, this time called the M.Sc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2019 indian rates</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/fraud/articles/MT/2019-indian-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/research/fraud/articles/MT/2019-indian-rates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1101297126880038914.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve some really bad news for Indians but it might give 1 explanation for our terrible performance after independence. The Department of Health and Human Services of the USA releases a list of cases where it has confirmed scientific fraud by data manipulation and faking from 2011 to date. A basic analysis of this data reveals the following summarized in the below table. It summarize the count of science fraud cases by population of origin: Indian (all of H origin);European, Chinese etc. The percentage of the total fraud cases and the number per million of involved in cheating. These are all the cases where the DHHS office of integrity has unequivocally determined that cheating was done in research funded by public money &amp;amp; almost all of this cheating relates to biochemistry/molecular biology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
