<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;3 Alternative-energy on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/3_alternative-energy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;3 Alternative-energy on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/3_alternative-energy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>10 Renewable Overview</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/3_alternative-energy/10_Renewable_Overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/3_alternative-energy/10_Renewable_Overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We now understand that the path human civilization has traveled to this pointa path paved by fossil fuels cannot lead very much farther before a new path must take over. One distinct possibility is a trek back toward a low-tech existence, but most people would consider such a development to be a failure. What would success look like, then?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sec. D.5 (p. 404) in the Appendices takes a look at the big picture of long-term human success, but for present purposes we will focus on the critical issue of energy: where could we get enough energy to replace the prodigious one-time gift of fossil fuels?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Hydroelectric Energy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/3_alternative-energy/11_Hydroelectric_Energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/3_alternative-energy/11_Hydroelectric_Energy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Energy has been harnessed from flowing water for ages. Milling operations were often located on streams so that water could turn a wheel attached to grinding machinery. Today, captured water flow is a significant contributor to electricity worldwide in the form of hydroelectricity. The U.S. gets about 2.8% of its current energy (and 7% of electricity) from hydropower. Globally, hydropower accounts for about 9% of energy, or 16% of electrical production (Table 7.2; p. 107).&#xA;Hydroelectricity taps into the solar-driven evaporation cycle, relying on the gravitational energy embodied in water lifted onto the land from lower bodies of water. In other words, solar energy lifts water, giving it gravitational potential energy, which is captured and converted to electrical energy.&#xA;While hydroelectric power is a simple and low-tech form of renewable energy that has been heavily exploited for over a hundred years, it is not one that is easy to expand beyond its current level of usage. This chapter will provide a better understanding of this mainstay of the renewable portfolio and its likely role in our future.&#xA;11.1 Gravitational Potential Energy&#xA;Gravitational force is incredibly weak. It may not seem so from daily experience, but consider the fact that a magnet held in your hand can lift a paperclip overwhelming the gravitational pull of the entire earth! By comparison, electromagnetic forces are forty orders-of-magnitude stronger than gravitational force. We don&amp;rsquo;t tend to notice because electric charges tend to balance out so that gravity is the most obvious force in our daily lives.1&#xA;Boulder Dam. Photo Credit: Tom Murphy&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Wind Energy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/3_alternative-energy/12_Wind_Energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/3_alternative-energy/12_Wind_Energy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;188&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;12 Wind Energy&#xA;189&#xA;have never met something so fast before. For a modern derivation of the Betz limit and how efficiency depends on tip speed, see &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The largest turbines having 150 m diameter rotors are rated for up to 10 MW of electrical power production.&#xA;Example 12.2.1 How much power could you expect a small (4 m diameter) 3-blade wind turbine situated atop your house to deliver in a respectable 5 m/s breeze?&#xA;The radius is 2 m and we&amp;rsquo;ll pick a middle-of-the-road efficiency of 45%; P=0.45&#xA;0.45. (1.25 kg/m3) 7 (2m)2. (5 m/s)3 comes to about 450 W 14&#xA;Besides the limit on how much power can be pulled out of the air by a single turbine, we also find limits on how densely they may be populated in a given area: how much space is required between turbines so that one does not disrupt the other. Obviously, it would not serve to put one turbine directly behind another, as they would at best split the available power arriving as wind. Even side by side, it is best to leave room between windmills so that additional rows are not deprived of wind power. A rule of thumb is to separate turbines by at least 5-8 diameters side-to-side, and 7-15 diameters15 along the (prevailing) wind direction. For the sake of illustration, Figure 12.5 shows a spacing on the denser side of the range, but otherwise we adopt the more recent recommendations and use 8 diameters side-to-side and 15 diameters deep [^75]. This works out to a 0.65% &amp;ldquo;fill factor,&amp;rdquo; meaning that 0.65% of the land area contains an associated rotor cross section.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;rotor (viewed from above)&#xA;prevailing wind direction&#xA;10D&#xA;16&#xA;5D&#xA;In order to compare to other forms of renewable energy, we can evaluate&#xA;a power per unit land area (in \(W/m^2\)) by the following approach:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Solar Energy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/3_alternative-energy/13_Solar_Energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/3_alternative-energy/13_Solar_Energy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now we come to the main attraction. As we saw in Chapter 10, all of the strictly renewable energy options are ultimately derived from the sun. The two resources of the last two chaptershydroelectricity and windrepresent tiny crumbs of the overall solar input to the planet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Practically speaking, it is difficult to concoct ways to harness more than a few terawatts of power from hydroelectric or wind-based resources. Similar limitations apply to biologically-derived energy, geothermal, tidal, ocean currents, wave energy, etc. This may be worrisome considering that human society currently demands 18 TW. Meanwhile, the sun delivers 83,000 TW to the earth&amp;rsquo;s surface (Fig. 10.1; p. 167, Table 10.2; p. 168). That&amp;rsquo;s almost 5,000 times more than the demand. By the numbers, then, the sun seems to offer all we might ever need. In fact, the quantitative imbalance is so extreme as to make one wonder why we would ever mess around doing anything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Biological Energy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/3_alternative-energy/14_Biological_Energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/3_alternative-energy/14_Biological_Energy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The renewable energy options discussed thus far have been rather different from the chemically-stored thermal energy provided by fossil fuels.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;These sources-hydroelectricity, wind, and solar-are good at making electricity,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;but are intermittent to various degrees and are not directly suitable for transportation, except via bulky batteries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Biologically-based energy is more similar to fossil fuels&lt;br&gt;&#xA;in that it is a form of chemical energy burned to create thermal energy.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;We will focus on two major forms: solid biomass and liquid biofuels.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The latter is well-suited to transportation:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;one of the few renewable energies that can make this claim.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;In some cases, the same plant can produce either food&lt;br&gt;&#xA;or bio-energy-depending on whether it is eaten by another biological form or by a machine.+++(5)+++&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Nuclear Energy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/3_alternative-energy/15_Nuclear_Energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/3_alternative-energy/15_Nuclear_Energy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Cooling towers of the decommissioned Satsop nuclear power plant in Washington.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Photo credit: Tom Murphy)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of the energy forms discussed thus far derive from sunlight— either contemporary input or fossilized storage. The fuel for nuclear energy is truly ancient, predating the solar system. The heavy elements participating in fission were produced by astrophysical cataclysms (most likely merging neutron stars), while the hydrogen building blocks for fusion originated in the Big Bang itself. In brief, fission involves the splitting of heavy nuclei into smaller pieces, while fusion builds larger nuclei from smaller ones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Small Players</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/3_alternative-energy/16_Small_Players/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/3_alternative-energy/16_Small_Players/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This short chapter serves to round out the menu of renewable energy options. While all of the entries are viable, at various levels of demonstration and implementation, none of them can scale up to be an important contributor to global power at the relevant level of many terawatts. In this sense, we might call the remaining resources &amp;ldquo;cute.&amp;rdquo; Because of this, items are kept brief-not warranting unjustified attention. Likewise for graphical adornment: the chapter is a little bare, in part because the subjects do not deserve much in the way of undue promotion.&#xA;Skipping this chapter will not sacrifice much in the way of knowledge vital to our future. It simply fills in the gaps and addresses some of the &amp;ldquo;but what about insert-scheme?&amp;rdquo; questions that may arise. The next chapter, Chapter 17, highlights the pros and cons of the full range of alternative energy resources, so this installment largely exists to provide a basis for the conclusions of that more important capstone.&#xA;16.1 Geothermal Energy&#xA;The interior of Earth is still hot from the initial collapse of mass in the formation of the planet. We can think of this as the thermal conversion of gravitational potential energy as pieces fell into the gravitational field of the earth, converting first to kinetic energy and then into thermal energy (heat) after collision. But that&amp;rsquo;s only half of the story. The other half is radioactive decay of long-lived unstable elements within the earth &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Of the radioactive decay part, 40% is from uranium (238U), 40% is from thorium (232Th), and 20% is from potassium (40K). As was indicated in Table 10.2 (p. 168), a total of 44 TW of geothermal power flows through the earth&amp;rsquo;s crust. Divided by total surface area, this amounts to less than&#xA;Lava seeping along east of Pu&amp;rsquo;u &amp;lsquo;O&amp;rsquo;o crater in Hawaii as an evident display of geothermal energy. Photo Credit: Tom Murphy&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Comparison of Alternatives</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/3_alternative-energy/17_Comparison_of_Alternatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/tom_murphy/energy_human-ambitions_finite-planet/3_alternative-energy/17_Comparison_of_Alternatives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagery from the groundbreaking movie The Matrix, by J. Rue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book has explored the energy surge of the last 150 years, largely casting it as a story of fossil fuels. Combining the finite nature of fossil fuels with their environmental cost makes it clear that we cannot expect fossil fuels to carry us into the indefinite future-and the sooner we transition away, the better. We have explored aspects of the chief alternatives in the preceding chapters. This chapter gathers key results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
