<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;catholic Ashrams on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;catholic Ashrams on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00 Preface</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/00_pre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/00_pre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Preface&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was early in 1987 that &lt;em&gt;Hinduism Today&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; sent to me reprints of&#xA;four articles that had been published in its issue of November/&#xA;December, 1986.&lt;a href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; Based on extensive research, the articles told&#xA;the story of some Catholic missionaries establishing &amp;ldquo;ashrams&amp;rdquo; in&#xA;different parts of India and doing many other things in order to look&#xA;like Hindu sannyasins. They also pointed out some glaring contradictions&#xA;between Hindu spiritual perceptions on the one hand and the basic&#xA;Christian beliefs on the other. One of the articles quoted from Vatican&#xA;sources to show how Church proclamations disagreed with the professions&#xA;of Christian &amp;ldquo;sannyasins&amp;rdquo;. Another asked the Christians as to how they&#xA;would look at a Muslim missionary appearing in their midst in the dress&#xA;of a Christian priest and adopting Christian rituals in a Church-like&#xA;mosque, but teaching the Quran instead of the Bible.&lt;a href=&#34;#3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt; I wrote to&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Hinduism Today&lt;/em&gt; that Voice of India would like to publish the articles&#xA;in the form of a booklet for the education of Hindus, many of whom had&#xA;been hoodwinked by this form of mission strategy. The permission was&#xA;readily granted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 CHAPTER 1 New Labels for Old Merchandise</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/01_ch01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/01_ch01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 1&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Labels for Old Merchandise&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The emergence of Catholic ashrams in several parts of the country is not&#xA;an isolated development. These institutions are links in a chain which&#xA;is known as the &amp;ldquo;Ashram Movement&amp;rdquo;, and which different denominations of&#xA;Christianity are promoting in concert. The Protestants and the Syrian&#xA;Orthodox have evolved similar establishments. Taken together, these&#xA;institutions are known as Christian ashrams. Several books and many&#xA;articles have already been devoted to the subject by noted Christian&#xA;writers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 CHAPTER 2         Indigenisation: A Predatory Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/02_ch02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/02_ch02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 2&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Indigenisation: A Predatory Enterprise&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The precedent cited most frequently by the literature of Indigenisation&#xA;is that which was set by the Greek Fathers when they used Greek cultural&#xA;forms for conveying Christianity to the pagans in the Roman Empire. Fr.&#xA;Bede recommends this precedent to the mission in India. &amp;ldquo;The Church,&amp;rdquo; he&#xA;says, &amp;ldquo;has a perfect model of how it should proceed today in the way it&#xA;proceeded in the early centuries. Christianity came out of Palestine as&#xA;a Jewish sect. Yet within a few centuries this Jewish sect had taken all&#xA;the forms of thought and expression of the Greco-Roman world. A&#xA;Christian theology developed in Greek modes of thought, as did a&#xA;Christian liturgy in Greek language and in Greek modes of expression; a&#xA;calender also developed according to Greek and Roman traditions. Surely&#xA;all that is a wonderful example meant for our instruction of how the&#xA;Church can present herself to an alien world, receiving forms into&#xA;herself while retaining her own Catholic message.&amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 The Patron Saint of Indigenisation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/03_ch03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/03_ch03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 3&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The Patron Saint of Indigenisation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;De Nobili, in fact,&amp;rdquo; observes Fr. Bede, &amp;ldquo;gives us the key to what was&#xA;wrong in the Christian approach to the Hindu and shows how the gospel&#xA;might have been presented to India in such a way as to attract its&#xA;deepest minds and its most religious men.&amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; He contrasts the way&#xA;of De Nobili with that of St. Francis Xavier for whom &amp;ldquo;all Hindus, but&#xA;especially Brahmins, were &amp;lsquo;devil-worshippers&amp;rsquo;.&amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; And he is not&#xA;alone in hailing De Nobili as the patron saint of Indigenisation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04  Mission&#39;s Volte-Face vis-a-vis Hindu Culture</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/04_ch04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/04_ch04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 4&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Mission&amp;rsquo;s Volte-Face vis-a-vis Hindu Culture&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The mission&amp;rsquo;s new-found love for Hindu culture is a sham. It is neither&#xA;spontaneous nor sincere at any point. On the contrary, it remains&#xA;forced, calculated and contrived throughout. Examined closely, it is no&#xA;more than a thin veneer that cracks at the very first probe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The language of Indigenisation indicates no change of heart on the&#xA;mission&amp;rsquo;s part vis-a-vis Hindu culture. All that we learn, as we read&#xA;between the lines, is that the mission is shifting its strategy in a&#xA;changed situation. The rising tide of resistance to Christianity in the&#xA;wake of the freedom movement had frightened the mission out of its wits.&#xA;The dawn of independence drove it into a panic. The need for&#xA;Indigenisation was felt by the mission for the first time when it was&#xA;gripped with fear for its future. It soon realized that the new ruling&#xA;class in India was its admirer rather than its adversary. Yet it felt&#xA;that it could still do with some cold-blooded camouflage for furthering&#xA;its designs and disarming opposition to it at the popular level.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 CHAPTER 5         The Ashram Movement in the Mission</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/05_ch05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/05_ch05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 5&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The Ashram Movement in the Mission&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As in the case of the &amp;ldquo;pioneers of indigenous Christianity,&amp;rdquo; historians&#xA;of the mission have been rummaging through the record in search of some&#xA;Christian institutions of the past which can be presented now as&#xA;&amp;ldquo;pioneers of the Ashram Movement&amp;rdquo;. The pride of place in this context&#xA;goes, of course, to the &amp;ldquo;ashram&amp;rdquo; of Robert De Nobili and his successors&#xA;at Madurai. We have already dealt with it in detail. Then there is a&#xA;long gap till we come to the short-lived ashram which Brahmabandhab set&#xA;up on the Narmada in the closing years of the nineteenth century.&#xA;Finally, from 1921 onwards we are presented with some mission stations&#xA;which styled themselves as ashrams, or are named so now, simply because&#xA;the inmates wore &lt;em&gt;khâdî&lt;/em&gt; and ate vegetarian food. The credit for placing&#xA;the Ashram Movement squarely on the map of the mission goes to P.&#xA;Chenchiah and company who included a chapter on it in their main thesis,&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Rethinking Christianity in India&lt;/em&gt;, presented to the IMC conference in&#xA;1938. It was followed with a full-fledged 326-page treatise, &lt;em&gt;Ashrams:&#xA;Past and Present&lt;/em&gt;, published in 1941.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 CHAPTER 6         The Trinity from Tannirpalli</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/06_ch06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/06_ch06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 6&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The Trinity from Tannirpalli&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The three names which have achieved celebrity in the Christian world, in&#xA;India as well as abroad, are those of Jules Monchanin, Henri Le Saux and&#xA;Bede Griffiths. All of them are associated with the Saccidananda Ashram&#xA;at Tannirpalli in the Tiruchirapalli district of Tamil Nadu. The first&#xA;two came from France and the third belongs to England. All three have&#xA;become known as Indian sages. Bede Griffiths is being hailed as a&#xA;&lt;em&gt;brahmavid&lt;/em&gt;, a claim advanced rarely even by ancient Hindu rishis. A&#xA;brief survey of the sayings and doings of this trinity will help in&#xA;determining the truth about their drumbeating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 CHAPTER 7 An Imperialist Hangover</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/07_ch07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/07_ch07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 7&lt;br&gt;&#xA;An Imperialist Hangover&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Christian mission equates the expansion of Christianity in different&#xA;parts of the world with the march of the Holy Spirit. The history of&#xA;Christianity helps us in understanding what the Holy Spirit really&#xA;stands for-the march of European military machines, the forcible&#xA;occupation of other people&amp;rsquo;s motherlands, the massacre of heathens or&#xA;their conversion at the point of the sword, the exercise of political&#xA;pressures by imperialist establishments, the use of money and manpower&#xA;and the mass media on a large scale, and the perfection of a scholarship&#xA;which excels in suppressio veri suggestio falsi (suppressing truth and&#xA;spreading falsehood). Christianity was a state enterprise for all&#xA;European countries, some of which became imperialist powers from the&#xA;sixteenth century onwards. The record of Christianity over the last&#xA;nearly two thousand years provides no evidence that it ever prevailed&#xA;over paganism by the moral or ethical or spiritual superiority of its&#xA;teachings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 CHAPTER 8 Catholic Ashrams Adopting and Adapting Hindu Dharma</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/08_ch08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/08_ch08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 8&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Catholic Ashrams&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Adopting and Adapting Hindu Dharma&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Shantivanam Ashram looks like a rishi&amp;rsquo;s home transported from Vedic&#xA;times to the banks of the sacred Cauvery River at a forested place near&#xA;Trichy in South India. A pilgrim&amp;rsquo;s first impressions are strong, and&#xA;very Hindu; the elaborately colourful Hindu shrine; the bearded,&#xA;saffron-robed &amp;ldquo;swami&amp;rdquo; seated cross - legged on a straw mat; devotees&#xA;practising yogic meditations, even chanting Hindu scriptures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 CHAPTER 9         The J.R. Ewing Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/09_ch09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/09_ch09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 9&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The J.R. Ewing Syndrome&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Television and movies struggle mightily to be dramatic, humorous,&#xA;tragic, colorful, sexy and outrageous. Video is modern man&amp;rsquo;s moving&#xA;canvas; like a painting, it can mimic but never match the real thing -&#xA;life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But perhaps it can help us interpret experience, find useful analogies,&#xA;study the human condition. In fact, it did just that last night. As we&#xA;pondered the front page story, seeking ways to explain the Hindu&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;profound concerns to the global Catholic community, our analogy appeared&#xA;on the screen. It was J.R. Ewing. That&amp;rsquo;s right, pardner, Dallas&#39;&#xA;powerful, scheming oil baron came to our rescue, This deserves a little&#xA;explanation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 CHAPTER 10         Interview with Father Bruno Barnhardt Emmaculate Heart Hermitage</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/10_ch10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/10_ch10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 10&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Interview with Father Bruno Barnhardt&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Emmaculate Heart Hermitage&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Father Barnhardt is a member of the same Catholic order-the Camaldolese&#xA;Monks-as Father Bede Griffiths and has spent time at the Shantivanam&#xA;Ashram. He shared some of his observations with Hinduism Today:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Q. What is your observation on how Shantivanam has been successful as a&#xA;means of conveying the Catholic message to the Indian people?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;*A. For a long while for Catholicism to go into another country it would&#xA;mean to bring some kind of European culture and implant it on top of the&#xA;indigenous culture. Ideally Christianity can become incarnate in any&#xA;different culture Father Bede&amp;rsquo;s experiment is a courageous experiment in&#xA;that direction and there has been quite a bit of resistance to it&#xA;throughout the Catholic Church within the Indian Episcopy of the church&#xA;but it is gaining favor because, effectively, the central authorities&#xA;have endorsed it. Actually on one level, it is not that far out, not&#xA;that advanced. On the liturgy, for instance, there are no radical&#xA;alternations of the Eucharist. He&amp;rsquo;s added on some readings at the&#xA;beginning which can come from Buddhist texts, Hindu texts, and others&#xA;and then it proceeds. The only thing that is different in the&#xA;sacramental gestures, there is use of flowers, fires, smoke, which is&#xA;very impressive. He rightly perceives that there is no problem, no&#xA;contamination of the Christian form by doing that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 CHAPTER 10         Interview with Father Bruno Barnhardt Emmaculate Heart Hermitage</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/11_ch10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/11_ch10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 10&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Interview with Father Bruno Barnhardt&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Emmaculate Heart Hermitage&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Father Barnhardt is a member of the same Catholic order-the Camaldolese&#xA;Monks-as Father Bede Griffiths and has spent time at the Shantivanam&#xA;Ashram. He shared some of his observations with Hinduism Today:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Q. What is your observation on how Shantivanam has been successful as a&#xA;means of conveying the Catholic message to the Indian people?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;*A. For a long while for Catholicism to go into another country it would&#xA;mean to bring some kind of European culture and implant it on top of the&#xA;indigenous culture. Ideally Christianity can become incarnate in any&#xA;different culture Father Bede&amp;rsquo;s experiment is a courageous experiment in&#xA;that direction and there has been quite a bit of resistance to it&#xA;throughout the Catholic Church within the Indian Episcopy of the church&#xA;but it is gaining favor because, effectively, the central authorities&#xA;have endorsed it. Actually on one level, it is not that far out, not&#xA;that advanced. On the liturgy, for instance, there are no radical&#xA;alternations of the Eucharist. He&amp;rsquo;s added on some readings at the&#xA;beginning which can come from Buddhist texts, Hindu texts, and others&#xA;and then it proceeds. The only thing that is different in the&#xA;sacramental gestures, there is use of flowers, fires, smoke, which is&#xA;very impressive. He rightly perceives that there is no problem, no&#xA;contamination of the Christian form by doing that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Returning to the Hindu Fold</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/12_ch11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/12_ch11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 11&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Returning to the Hindu Fold&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A Primer&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What can a person do who finds himself a Catholic and wants to rejoin&#xA;the Hindu faith of his ancestors? He need not wait until another&#xA;incarnation, for his situation admits of a fairly simple solution-formal&#xA;apostacy (&amp;ldquo;abandonment&amp;rdquo; from Catholicism, and readmission to the Hindu&#xA;fold). Hindu religious leaders have always taken a liberal view of the&#xA;return of converts to other faiths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 APPENDIX 1 Malaysia Hindus Protest Christian &#34;Sadhu&#34;1</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/13_ch11app1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/13_ch11app1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APPENDIX 1&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Malaysia Hindus Protest Christian &amp;ldquo;Sadhu&amp;rdquo;&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On November 8th and 9th, about 1,000 Hindus gathered at the Methodist&#xA;Church in Brickfields, Kuala Lumpur to protest and confront the&#xA;Pentecostal Christian, &amp;ldquo;Sadhu Chellapah,&amp;rdquo; who was making his third visit&#xA;to Malaysia. An active propagator of the Christian faith in Malaysian&#xA;estate and rural areas, he wears the orange robes (kavi) of Hindu monk&#xA;and styles himself as a Sadhu (Hindu term for a wandering monk). The&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Sadhu&amp;rdquo; declined a challenge to public debate with members of the&#xA;Malaysian Hindu Sangam and the Sri Maha Mariyamman Temple over his&#xA;statements on Hindus scriptures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 APPENDIX 2         Missionary&#39;s Dirty Tricks1</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/14_ch11app2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/14_ch11app2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APPENDIX 2&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Missionary&amp;rsquo;s Dirty Tricks&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;R.K. Deshpande, president of Kalyan Ashram in Madhya Pradesh, India,&#xA;submitted this news report translated from the Hindi newspaper Jansatta&#xA;to Hinduism Today last month, as part of a campaign by the ashram to&#xA;document and publicize the unethical conversion tactics practiced by&#xA;many Christian missionaries.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In early 1982, Father Joseph Parekatil of the Catholic Church of&#xA;Parasahi, Madhya Pradesh, destroyed the sacred murthi of the Goddess&#xA;Visweshwari Siddheswari enshrined on the nearby Nawain Tekdi hill. After&#xA;also burning a Forest Department tree plantation on the same hill, he&#xA;erected a small wooden cross. His stated intention to gain possession of&#xA;the sacred hill (presently government land) caused considerable&#xA;consternation among the village&amp;rsquo;s residents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 CHAPTER 12         The First Dialogue</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/15_ch12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/15_ch12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 12&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The First Dialogue&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hinduism Today&lt;/em&gt; invited some interesting letters from its readers,&#xA;Hindus as well as Christians. They are reproduced as below:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HINDUISM TODAY, APRIL-MAY 1987&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Catholic Ashrams&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The article on the above subject in your November-December issue exposes&#xA;a fraud which Catholic missionaries have been practising upon unwary&#xA;Hindus for a long time. An average Hindu does not know that the&#xA;missionary clad in ochre robes is no sadhu, but a scheming impostor. So&#xA;long as the Catholics stick to their exclusive theology, they will&#xA;remain aliens in the land of Sanatana Dharma, no matter what disguises&#xA;they don and what strategies of conversion they design&amp;hellip; They are&#xA;turning [Jesus] into a co-conspirator in their bid to subvert Hindu&#xA;society and culture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 CHAPTER 13 The Second Dialogue</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/16_ch13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/16_ch13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 13&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The Second Dialogue&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An article in praise of Fr. Bede Griffiths, published in the. &lt;em&gt;Indian&#xA;Express&lt;/em&gt; of Madras, provoked far more interesting exchanges, notably&#xA;between Swami Devananda Saraswati and Fr. Bede Griffiths.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;INDIAN EXPRESS, 18 MARCH 1987&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An Apostle of Peace&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(&lt;em&gt;By R.R&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Britain&amp;rsquo;s appropriate gift to India is Rev. Father Bede Griffiths, the&#xA;sage of Saccidananda Ashram, Shanti Vanam, Tannirpalli. The Trinity&#xA;Sat-Chit-Ananda, is a genuine experience of the Godhead. The Christian&#xA;experience leads to personal core identity at heart of the divine unity,&#xA;as in later Hinduism, specially the Bhagavad Gita. This is the mystery&#xA;of the trinity - dynamic identity to personal communion of love. This&#xA;generated cosmos through the logos. The word &amp;rsquo;trinitarian&amp;rsquo; is inadequate&#xA;to indicate the full significance. The primacy of the mystical -&#xA;experiential - God as loving presence has to be realised. Here,&#xA;categories of immanence and transcendence collapse - entering the core&#xA;of the heart (Guha) - there is an opening beyond all categories. All is&#xA;in us and we are in God (Pantheism).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 CHAPTER 14         The Third Dialogue</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/17_ch14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/17_ch14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 14&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The Third Dialogue&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This dialogue developed around a letter which K.V. Ramakrishna Rao wrote&#xA;to the &lt;em&gt;Indian Express&lt;/em&gt; in protest against Christian missionaries&#xA;masquerading as Hindu sannyasins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;INDIAN EXPRESS, 13 FEBRUARY 1989&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Crucifying the &amp;lsquo;Om&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sir,-Nowadays, we find several Christian missionaries putting up ashrams&#xA;at various places in India donning ochre robes, building temple-like&#xA;churches, reciting Sanskrit slokas and practising other Hindu rites in&#xA;the guise of &amp;lsquo;inculturation&amp;rsquo; - synthesis of Hinduism and Christianity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18  Bede Griffiths Drops the Mask</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/18_ch15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/18_ch15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER 15&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Bede Griffiths Drops the Mask&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hindus who are not conversant with the history and methods of the&#xA;Christian mission, have been taken in by the soft language adopted by&#xA;the mission strategists in recent years. Shri K. Swaminathan whose&#xA;letters to the &lt;em&gt;Indian Express&lt;/em&gt; have been reproduced in the previous&#xA;chapter, is a typical example. It is, therefore, necessary to point out&#xA;that soft language by itself means little if it does not spring from a&#xA;sincere mind, and is not good-intentioned. There is no evidence as yet&#xA;that the missionary mind has become sincere or well-disposed towards&#xA;Hindu society and culture, not to speak of Hinduism. On the contrary,&#xA;there is ample evidence that this mind remains as deceitful and&#xA;mischievous as ever before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Different Paths Meeting in God</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/19_ch15app1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/19_ch15app1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APPENDIX 1&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Different Paths Meeting in God&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an anthology&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; of 12 articles contributed by distinguished&#xA;theologians Catholic and Protestant, all belonging to prestigious&#xA;divinity schools and universities. Some authors speak more&#xA;philosophically, others more sociologically, but the book has a kind of&#xA;unity which comes from a shared outlook. The authors also met at the&#xA;Claremont Graduate school, California, where their first drafts were&#xA;subjected to mutual criticism, thus ensuring further unity in the final&#xA;product.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20  Back to Contents            Pagexa0xa0xa0 Back to VOI            Booksxa0xa0xa0 Back to Home </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/20_ch15app2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/20_ch15app2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APPENDIX 2&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Liberal&amp;rdquo; Christianity&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whether Christianity improves the general morals of its followers is&#xA;doubtful, but it is certain that it does not widen their intellectual&#xA;sympathies and does not open their hearts to the larger spiritual wealth&#xA;of different peoples and cultures. This is also true of Islam, another&#xA;revealed religion, but in the present discussion we shall restrict&#xA;ourselves to Christianity alone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From its early days, Christianity has claimed a monopoly of things&#xA;divine. It has held that there is no salvation outside of the Church.&#xA;But the world has considerably changed during the last two hundred&#xA;years. A wave of rationalism and humanism has reached the shores of&#xA;Europe. This has made Christian theology with its exclusive claims look&#xA;pretentious. This has also fostered a new spirit of liberalism and&#xA;universalism and also a new awareness of a wider human family, including&#xA;within itself members who are neither European nor Christian and yet are&#xA;rich in the things of the spirit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21          The Great Command and a Cosmic Auditing</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/21_ch15app3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/21_ch15app3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APPENDIX 3&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The Great Command and a Cosmic Auditing&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The volume surveys 788 most important evangelizing Plans produced by&#xA;Christianity during its career of over 19 hundred years. All these Plans&#xA;relate to the Great Commission - the command that Jehovah gave through&#xA;the mouth of His only Begotten Son, Jesus, to the believers to &amp;ldquo;go and&#xA;make disciples of all nations&amp;rdquo; (Mt. 28.19, 20). If there was also a&#xA;command to improve their morals, it was neglected, but the one to preach&#xA;and recruit more followers for their God was rather taken in earnest.&#xA;They promised Him to make &amp;ldquo;all the peoples of the earth know Him and&#xA;fear Him&amp;rdquo; (2 Chr. 6.33).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Christian Ashrams in India, Nepal and Sri Lanka</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/22_app1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/22_app1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APPENDIX I&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Christian Ashrams in India, Nepal and Sri Lanka&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This list has been compiled, in an alphabetical order, from several&#xA;Christian publications. The date of foundation, wherever available, has&#xA;been given in brackets.&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;India&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[TABLE]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nepal&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[TABLE]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sri Lanka&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[TABLE]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Footnotes:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#1a&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; This fist took into account relevant publications upto 1988.&#xA;More Christian Ashrams must have come up in the meanwhile (1993).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;index.htm&#34;&gt;Back to Contents Page&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;a href=&#34;http://voiceofdharma.org/books&#34;&gt;Back to VOI&#xA;Books&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;a href=&#34;http://voiceofdharma.org&#34;&gt;Back to&#xA;Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 APPENDIX II         A Glimpse of Mission Finance</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/23_app2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/23_app2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APPENDIX II&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A Glimpse of Mission Finance&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following figures of foreign funds flowing to a few of the Christian&#xA;organisations in India during 1986, were provided by the Government of&#xA;India. There are several hundred such organisations spread all over the&#xA;country.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have taken the figures from &lt;em&gt;Hinduism Today&lt;/em&gt; which cited them in its&#xA;issue of October, 1987:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[TABLE]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: We have not tried to collect figures for more Christian&#xA;organisations or subsequent years. We do not have to document the fact&#xA;that foreign funds flowing to Christian missions are fabulous.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/24_app3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/24_app3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APPENDIX III&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Thy Kingdom is the Third World&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tempted by Satan to number Israel, King David ordered a census of his&#xA;people. This angered Jehovah and He offered him three alternatives to&#xA;choose from : either three years of famine, or three months of&#xA;destruction at the hand of his enemies, or the three days of the Lord.&#xA;Counting on the great mercies of Jehovah, David chose to fall into His&#xA;hand rather than into the hand of man. Consequently, the Lord &amp;ldquo;sent a&#xA;pestilence upon Israel; and there fell seventy thousand men&amp;rdquo; (I Chron.&#xA;21).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Christianity Mainly for Export</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/25_app4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/25_app4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APPENDIX IV&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Christianity Mainly for Export&lt;br&gt;&#xA;God&amp;rsquo;s Legionaries&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Go into the world and preach the gospel to all creatures. He who&#xA;believes and is baptized will be saved, but he who does not believe will&#xA;be condemned&amp;rdquo; (Mk. 16.15-16), Jesus told his followers after he had died&#xA;and risen from the dead. Christian scholars now know this biblical&#xA;passage to be an interpolation but this fact has in no way cooled off&#xA;their zeal for proselytizing. It seems proselytizing needs little&#xA;biblical inspiration but embodies ecclesiastical aggrandizement and&#xA;follows its own vested interests, political and economic. At the&#xA;beginning of this decade, there were 249,000 missionaries in the&#xA;soul-saving business.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 Proselytisation as it is Practised</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/26_app5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/26_app5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APPENDIX V&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Proselytisation as it is Practised&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I did not realise I was stirring a hornet&amp;rsquo;s nest in reviewing the&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Mission Handbook&lt;/em&gt; (March 13, 14). It invoked many rejoinders, most of&#xA;them harsh. It helps inter-faith dialogue which the church has recently&#xA;invited.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many points have been made but, quite understandably I can only deal&#xA;with a few more salient ones, and that too briefly. Mr Kuruvilla Chandy&#xA;presents a justification for Christian proselytizing which is novel in&#xA;its being so openly avowed. He compares it with proselytizing in&#xA;politics where &amp;ldquo;fraud is proverbial&amp;rdquo;, and with &amp;ldquo;aggressive advertising&amp;rdquo;&#xA;of the commercial world. It is interesting that he finds nothing odious&#xA;in the comparison. He argues that &amp;ldquo;proselytizing is normal to fife.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Bibliography</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/27_bib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ram_swarup/catholic_Ashrams/27_bib/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bibliography&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;Benedictine Ashram,&lt;/em&gt; Douglas (England), 1961.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abhishiktananda, Swami (Henri Le Saux), &lt;em&gt;Hindu-Christian Meeting Point&lt;/em&gt;,&#xA;Delhi, 1976.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Animanand, B., &lt;em&gt;The Blade: Life and Work of Brahmabandhab Upadhay&lt;/em&gt;,&#xA;Calcutta, 1945.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ashram Review&lt;/em&gt;, January, 1942; April, 1945; July, 1947; October,&#xA;1948; July, 1955.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Baggo, Kaj, &lt;em&gt;Pioneers of Indigenous Christianity&lt;/em&gt;, Madras, 1969.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Barret, David B. (ed.), &lt;em&gt;World Christian Encyclopaedia&lt;/em&gt;, OUP, 1982.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Barret, David B. et el (ed.), &lt;em&gt;Seven Hundred Plans to Evangelize the&#xA;World: Rise of Global Evangelization Movement&lt;/em&gt;, 1989.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
