<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE MAKING OF PRIYAVRATA </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/2019-09-11_THE_MAKING_OF_PRIYAV/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/2019-09-11_THE_MAKING_OF_PRIYAV/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chamuks.in/article_view.php?chamuks=VDBSUk5FNUVTVFZQVkVVMVRWRTlQUT09&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;article_img/CHAMU-1582624465the_making_of_priyavrata.jpeg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;article_img/CHAMU-1582624465the_making_of_priyavrata.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;spf&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Buildings are built brick by brick. Priyavrata’s life is being built day&#xA;by day and hour by hour for the last fifteen years and ten months.&#xA;Passing out Tenali Maha Pariksha is only a beginning of a new chapter in&#xA;his life story, a story of purpose, perseverance and performance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Sri Devadatta Patil, in search of a real Guru, went to Kanchi and&#xA;requested 78 years’ old Sri Goda Subrahmanya Shastri to teach him Nyaya&#xA;Shastra, after much pursuance, Shastrigal who all his life lived for the&#xA;purpose of Shastra Shiksha and Shastra Raksha, made Devadatta Patil take&#xA;three vows, one of which was that Devadatta should not go for any&#xA;University job until he creates a few scholars like him. Devadatta Patil&#xA;got a purpose in life and created many firsts in the history of Shastra&#xA;learning and Tenali Maha Pariksha. Later Aparna also became his&#xA;Sahadharmini in that purpose. Purposeful life made their lives more&#xA;meaningful and colorful though full of challenges. Same is the story of&#xA;Sri Mohan Lal Sharma, Priyavrata’s Vyakarana Guru, who was accompanying&#xA;a Sant as his cook. The Sant stayed in Devadatta Patil’s Pathashala for&#xA;a week. Before leaving, young Mohan had made up his mind to come back&#xA;and study under Devadatta Patil. He not only came back within a week but&#xA;studied Nyaya initially under Devadatta Patil, later Vyakarana in Andhra&#xA;under Sri Kompella Satyanarayana Shastri as planned by Devadatta Patil,&#xA;passed Tenali Maha Pariksha with distinction and came back as Guru of&#xA;Priyavrata. Though Mohan Lal Sharma got an offer of Asst. Professorship&#xA;in a reputed Samskrit University due to his scholarship, by then he had&#xA;found the purpose of his life and hence the attractive pay scale did not&#xA;distract him from his life mission. That purpose in his life created a&#xA;wonder called Priyavrata. Purpose determines the performance. Priyavrata&#xA;is the fourth generation inheritor of that great Shastra Tradition in&#xA;our life time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genius Promethea</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/genius-promethea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/genius-promethea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Promethea Unbound&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A child genius raised in poverty, she wanted to change the world. A horrific act of violence nearly destroyed her.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By Mike Mariani&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The Atavist Magazine, No. 72&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For Georgia Smith, home was abeat-up red Plymouth Voyager minivan with a bad engine block. A Greek immigrant in her early forties, she had been evicted from her San Francisco apartment in the fall of 1996. Georgia didn’t want anyone to alert social services that she and her daughter Jasmine were destitute, so for several months they’d been living as nomads. She shuttled the five-year-old around the city by day before finding a parking lot where they could spend the night. They never stayed in one place for very long.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IAS ICS Crackers</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/IAS_crackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/IAS_crackers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/shrikanth_krish/status/1742012185105093000&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many Indians still don&amp;rsquo;t get it. Use your hard work and ingenuity to produce goods and services for the country. Don&amp;rsquo;t use all that energy to crack a silly exam. It&amp;rsquo;s a sad commentary on our dysfunctional culture, on our economy, on lack of opportunities for our youth. I was part of that crowd in my youth. Judging myself by my entrance exam rank. Feeling inferior or superior based on a single number. We have to outgrow that. Don&amp;rsquo;t be too hung up on these badges (be it JEE, CAT, UPSC). If you are so smart, try to make the world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Koch guru disciple relation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/koch_guru-disciple-relation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/koch_guru-disciple-relation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What makes the situation very difficult is the fact that in a traditional teaching in the guru-disciple relationship an objective discussion of facts is not admitted. Studying the authoritative texts does not mean that they be read, discussed, and their meaning discovered with a simple, unprejudiced mind. Instead, the guru teaches his disciples a particular ideology and shows them how this ideology can be “proven” referring to those authoritative texts, which are considered as a divine revelation. In this process, considerable violence is often done to the texts, and it happens that their meaning is turned into the exact opposite. If a student discovers that the teaching of the guru is in contradiction to the Vedas he is expected to believe that this contradiction is only due to his own limited understanding of things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>veda memorization in TN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/veda-memorization_TN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/veda-memorization_TN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: harish svAminAthan at &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1482606041376653319.html&#34;&gt;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1482606041376653319.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some people questioned why its a big deal to finish the taitireeya shaakha in 5 yrs. Well here are the details, if the intent is to just see book and chant (which is also not easy BTW,) you can complete it even in one year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The TN patashaala system has produced many vidwans who if woken up in the middle of the night can chant the asked portion without a blink. How is this possible ? The system is very rigorous and riddled with hardships.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vinay experience</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/vinay-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/vinay-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: ainvvy on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the last two years, I have been teaching high school children. Some reflections.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are a few things many schools get wrong. The first thing I ensured is that they don’t feel they are in a typical class&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(a) Students work around tables; not all are facing me.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(b) They talk amongst each other, thinking as a team is fine. So my typical class is noisy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(c) I only address them for a fourth of the class. They are exploring for the remaining time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(d) The problems they have to think about are usually challenging. Usually a solution takes 20 to 30 minutes to discover.+++(5)+++ In the process, they learn patience.  They realise problem solving is not some 30 second activity.+++(5)+++ They learn to work in teams. This interaction is what adds to the experience of learning.+++(5)+++&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(e) I am usually not satisfied with one way of solving. They learn there is usually more than one way to solve a problem.+++(5)+++  They also see multiple ideas from their peers, which tells them there is no one correct way.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My sessions are for 3 hours. The first time, I asked them if they wanted a break after 90 minutes. They refused saying it is not school! When children enjoy what they are doing, they don’t get tired. I have never asked this question again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>रविकुमाराभिप्रायः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/ravikumArAbhiprAyaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/ravikumArAbhiprAyaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What does your child want to do when he grows up?&#xA;Years ago, as a twenties-something kid, I offered parenting advice to my college senior Jo (older to me by a decade and already highly accomplished in her chosen field) and without batting an eyelid she said, “Hari, I too was an expert on parenting until I had my own child!”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I always recall her words when I am tempted to offer unsolicited advice to young parents. I refrain from giving advice to people but sometimes I find it difficult to remain silent when family members or close friends are taking the longer route—and I feel that I can offer immediate assistance that might make the journey easier for them. It could well be an aggrandized view of my perception but if it turns out to be helpful to them, what’s the harm?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
