<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Persia on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Persia on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Arab rule</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/arab_rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/arab_rule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For religious background, see &lt;a href=&#34;../religion/5_betrayal_to_islam/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;betrayal to islam&amp;rdquo; page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Forced conversions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;conquest&#34;&gt;Conquest&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Arab conquerors must have been astounded at how quickly they were able to overthrow the last Sasanian king. Yazdgard III (r. 632–651) had to abandon Ctesiphon, near the modern site of Baghdad, and fled for his life into the Asiatic steppe. But he was intercepted and killed. His sons and a few surviving aristocrats managed to reach China, where the Tang emperor welcomed them to his court at Chang’an. There, a Sasanian court in exile lasted for almost 200 years, and a few abortive attempts at reconquering Iran were launched.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;caliphs&#34;&gt;Caliphs&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Umayyad clan was the first Arabian dynasty to rule Iran. For nearly a century, it reigned from Damascus, attempting to enforce authority over the old Sasanian empire. Fifty-thousand Arabian troops stationed at the garrison city of Marv, in eastern Iran, took Persian wives and began adopting Iranian cultural practices. In 750, those troops rose in revolt and overthrew the Umayyads. The new dynasty, known to posterity as Abbasid, established their new capital in Baghdad, only about 20 miles from Ctesiphon.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Their civil administration imitated the customs of the Sasanian chancery, and a new generation of Iranian functionaries arose in service to the new empire, which took on an Iranian identity. The successors of Muhammad were instructed and edified by volumes of Persian literature, treatises on Iranian courtly manners, and the history of the Sasanians. The heritage of the Sasanian era—its literature, architecture, metal-working, glassware, carpets, and textiles—inspired subsequent mediaeval Persianate culture, and became part of the foundation of Classical Islamic civilisation.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Georgia</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/georgia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/georgia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Georgians don&amp;rsquo;t speak an IE language.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-religion&#34;&gt;Early religion&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;But what was their natural religion before being smothered by the evils of pretonmAda? The evidence from the victory announcements of the preta-s suggest that they were following the natural more eastern reflex of Iranian religion. So in a sense they are a parallel the Dravidians of India: different language family but same religion as their Arya neighbors. However, there are hints that there might have been an internal clash between Georgians who initially worshipped a more natural flavor of the Iranian religion &amp;amp; the Zoroastrians who insisted on uniconic worship. Later in a negotiation mediated by the shah-an-shah from Iran it appears that they adopted a fusion version with both Zoroastrian and non-Zoroastrian flavors side-by-side. The preta-s destroyed both on taking over.&amp;rdquo; - MT&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Il-Khan rule</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/il-khan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/il-khan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot; Il-Khans had conquered Mesopotamia after annihilating the Shi’a power of the Hashishins and the Sunni Kilafat. So the Mohammedans were no longer a political force in Mesopotamia. Yet they were able to destroy the external influences and re-establish the Shari’a.&amp;quot; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2011/05/20/some-notes-on-rashid-ad-din-bin-imad-ud-dawla-abul-khair-and-his-times/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Due to the Mohammedan persecution of various groups favored by Arghun he came up with a plan to conquer Mecca and restore heathen worship there with construction of temples of buddhakapAla and heruka, but due to other preoccupations he failed to do so. Indeed, during the Ilkhanid regime multiple temples to buddhakapAla, kAlachakra and hevajra had been built in Baghdad, Tabriz and in some places in the province of Khurasan.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2011/05/20/some-notes-on-rashid-ad-din-bin-imad-ud-dawla-abul-khair-and-his-times/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ghazan&#34;&gt;Ghazan&lt;/a&gt;, shortly before he overthrew &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baydu&#34;&gt;Baydu&lt;/a&gt;, converted to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Islam&#34; title=&#34;Islam&#34;&gt;Islam&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zoro empires</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/zoro-empires/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/zoro-empires/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-times&#34;&gt;Early times&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Iranian power in the world system arose somewhat later than ours. Although they were around in west Asia for sometime since 1000 BCE, they were not exactly a mighty force.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; [I] hold that a branch of these steppe kuru-s re-emerged with another allied clan the kamboja much later on the Iranians side to form the elite of the hAkamAnashIya dynasty. - MT&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hākamanshiya-empire&#34;&gt;Hākamanshiya empire&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although they were around in west Asia for sometime since 1000 BCE, they were not exactly a mighty force. But in the steppe-borderland there were still mighty clans of the Indo-Iranian continuum which had played a major role in the rise of Aryan power in India. Among them were the Kuru and Kamboja and it was perhaps in a confederation of such tribes that the Hākamanshiya arose. Their king the great Kurush (Cyrus), named after Kuru, established a great world empire stretching from the eastern reaches of Soghdiana to the western end of Asia Minor sometime between 600-530 BCE. He conquered in succession his Iranian cousins the Medians, the Lydians, who were relatives of the Hittites, and the Babylonians and their vassals, besieging and taking fortified strongholds one after the other like no one had ever before done in West Asia. Finally, while fighting the Śaka-Hindu alliance that was arrayed against him with their elephant force during his invasion of Śakastana, a Hindu spearman stabbed Kurush in the liver resulting in his death. &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
