<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;hindu resistance to muslims on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_resistance_to_muslims/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;hindu resistance to muslims on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_resistance_to_muslims/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 CHAPTER I NATIONAL PERSPECTIVE ON INDIAN HISTORY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_resistance_to_muslims/01_ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_resistance_to_muslims/01_ch1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER I&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATIONAL PERSPECTIVE ON INDIAN HISTORY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mathew Arnold had composed his famous lines with reference to a particular context. He had the Buddha and similar Hindu sages in mind when he wrote the following famous lines:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The East bowed low before the blast,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;In patient deep disdain;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;She let the legions thunder past,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And plunged in thought again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Little did the poet suspect that his tribute to Hindu spirituality would be twisted to embellish an imperialist version of Indian history according to which the “meek Hindu” had always been preoccupied with sterile speculations, and seldom stood up in defence of his country and culture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 CHAPTER II ARAB FAILURE IN SINDH, KABUL AND ZABUL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_resistance_to_muslims/02_ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_resistance_to_muslims/02_ch2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER II&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARAB FAILURE IN SINDH, KABUL AND ZABUL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Chapter I of his book, Dr. Misra gives dates as well as details regarding the rapid conquests made by the armies of Islam after the death of its prophet in AD 632. The Byzantine provinces of Palestine and Syria fell to them after a six month’s campaign in AD 636-637. Next came the turn of the Sassanid empire of Persia which included Iraq, Iran, and Khorasan. The Persians were defeated decisively in AD 637, and their entire empire was overrun in the next few years. “By A.D. 643 the boundaries of the Caliphate touched the frontiers of India.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The Turkish speaking territories of Inner Mongolia, Bukhara, Tashkand, and Samarkand, etc. were annexed by AD 650. Meanwhile, in the west, the Byzantine province of Egypt had fallen in AD 640-641. The Arab armies marched over North Africa till they reached the Atlantic and crossed over into Spain in AD 709.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 CHAPTER III FRUSTRATION OF THE GHAZNAVIDS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_resistance_to_muslims/03_ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_resistance_to_muslims/03_ch3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER III&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRUSTRATION OF THE GHAZNAVIDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The standard text-books of Indian history taught in our schools and colleges do not highlight at all the stupendous failure of the Islamised Arabs in the face of heroic Hindu resistance. What they highlight instead is the series of successful raids made by Mahmud Ghaznavi into the heartland of India, and the subsequent crumbling of Hindu kingdoms in North India before the determined onslaughts of Muhammad Ghuri. The two Islamic invaders are presented as the rulers of a small sultanate in Afghanistan as against the powerful Hindu kingdoms of the Shahiyas, the Gurjara-Pratiharas, the Parmaras, the Rashtrakutas, the Chandellas, the Chaulukyas, the Chauhans, the Gahadvads, and the Senas. The impression that is left at the end of it all is that northern India was more or less a walk-over for the “warriors of Islam”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 CHAPTER IV PERFIDY WINS WHERE VALOUR FAILED</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_resistance_to_muslims/04_ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_resistance_to_muslims/04_ch4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER IV&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PERFIDY WINS WHERE VALOUR FAILED&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The theologians of Islam had laid down, in the opening years of this imperialist ideology, that the &lt;em&gt;kāfirs&lt;/em&gt; who could not be subdued by force should be subverted by fraud. The prophet of Islam had himself initiated the first lessons in this lore when he practised what came to be known as &lt;em&gt;Siyāsat-i-Madīnah&lt;/em&gt; in later times, that is, to take the&#xA;&lt;em&gt;kāfirs&lt;/em&gt; one by one and that too when they are least expecting an&#xA;attack. One of his famous sayings, sanctified as his Sunnah, was that “war is perfidy”. This &lt;em&gt;hadīs&lt;/em&gt; came in handy to Muizzuddin Muhammad bin Sam who is known in Indian history as Muhammad Ghuri.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 CHAPTER V THE LESSONS WE HAVE TO LEARN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_resistance_to_muslims/05_ch5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_resistance_to_muslims/05_ch5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER V&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE LESSONS WE HAVE TO LEARN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Misra’s monograph is pertinent not only to a past period of Indian history but also to our situation at present. The lessons which this learned study draws for us can be ignored by us only at our own peril.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Firstly, it highlights Hindu heroism in the face of an inveterate Islamic imperialism. Such heroism has seldom been seen in the annals of any other people. Read with the record of similar heroism in a later period and in a continued struggle with the same foe, the story can help us correct the current notion that Hindus have always been, and continue to be, a race of lily-livered cowards who have invariably run away from every contest. The notion has become prevalent not only among the non-Hindus but also among the Hindus themselves due to a wrong teaching of Indian history over a long period of time. Hindus have to revive and re-affirm their old tradition of heroism. They have to make it known to all concerned that they are not going to tolerate those forces and factions which question the independence and integrity of their country, nor remain passive towards those elements which are trying to temper with the Hindu character of their homeland in the name of Secularism, or composite culture, or minority rights, or some other subversive slogan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 CHAPTER VI THE NATURE OF NATIONAL FRONTIERS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_resistance_to_muslims/06_ch6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_resistance_to_muslims/06_ch6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER VI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE NATURE OF NATIONAL FRONTIERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At times and in certain situations, the frontiers of a nation are not merely physical; they are also ideological. We shall never be able to overcome our predicament vis-a-vis Pakistan unless we understand her ideological frontiers and define our own.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Compared to us Pakistan is much smaller in size and population. She is much poorer in industrial infrastructure and other resources. Yet she has attacked us not once but three times in the short span of 24 years. And she is preparing feverishly to attack us again as soon as she feels that the time is opportune. This is not the normal behaviour of a normal nation. This is evidence enough that the basic motive of her behaviour lies elsewhere than in the cold-blooded calculations of military balance, strategic or tactical.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
