<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०७ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/07/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०७ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/07/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Strange and frightening conversation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/07/2006-07-30_strange-and-frightening-conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/07/2006-07-30_strange-and-frightening-conversation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/07/30/strange-and-frightening-conversation/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I received a call and we set off for the evening. The women-folk wanted&#xA;to make their stock of powders and pickles for the quarter and had spent&#xA;the day collecting their ingredients. As we converged at the&#xA;pre-destined venue. While the women milled away at the kitchen, Marc and&#xA;me had planned to re-live some youthful fancies that we much missed- we&#xA;had planned some experiments. R had told Marc of the dIpAvallI vacation&#xA;of ekAdashAnta, when she and me had experimented extensively with what&#xA;in bhArata were known as snake-tablets. Marc obsessed over them and&#xA;wanted to make his own snake tablets. While he was certain he had&#xA;reached a recipe he did not have all the substances at home for the&#xA;synthesis. Instead we decided to settle for other stuff that we thought&#xA;might also entertain the kids usefully while the women milled away their&#xA;powders. We first decided to make “hydrogen bombs”- basically exploding&#xA;mixtures of oxygen and hydrogen trapped in soap suds following&#xA;electrolysis. We also wanted to make pure silicon. Many years back&#xA;during the same dIpAvalI vacation R and I had made use of our stash of&#xA;Mg wire to isolate silicon, but we ended up with a somewhat dangerous&#xA;result with our test-tube exploding in the vigorous heating. But Marc&#xA;now managed this step with great ease and then let it cool. The moment&#xA;of reckoning came when we dumped the mixture into the acid solution and&#xA;watched the spectacular pyrotechnics as the silicon precipitated to the&#xA;bottom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jx etc</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/07/2006-07-17_jx-etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/07/2006-07-17_jx-etc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/07/17/jx-etc/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We heard from Jx that through the sAdhana-s his preceptor had bestowed&#xA;on him he had completely repulsed the abhichAra. He was finally relieved&#xA;from the flight of the crane: it was confirmed, but it had taken a&#xA;severe toll on him. Most ill-effects except one on which the vairi had&#xA;invested the most had been reversed. MM was considerably relieved that&#xA;her mantras had rescued him. We had seen how the the siddhi of kAtyAyanI&#xA;had visited MM, and later the most hallowed skanda had also visited her,&#xA;so we did not doubt her abilties at all. We had also known how the&#xA;shachIva having obtained the rakShohA agni from her had tided over some&#xA;troubles. However, the vairi was far more accomplished than her in the&#xA;vidyA-s, and somewhere down the lane her own distractions did not allow&#xA;her to grow further. PM was not as accomplished as the vairi, but was&#xA;able to hold on with his yoga for a while, till he sadly entered into&#xA;the strife arising from petty matters dragging all of us with that into&#xA;the sapping battle, which terminated his span of life somewhat&#xA;prematurely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the quest for food</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/07/2006-07-08_in-the-quest-for-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/07/2006-07-08_in-the-quest-for-food/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/07/08/in-the-quest-for-food/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;bhR^igu, the founder of our race, had said that food was brahman. In&#xA;that quest we set out to the city center. They say no journey in the&#xA;company of a true friend is ever long. They say no wait in the company&#xA;of a comely and amiable young woman is too long. But a journey in the&#xA;company of a false friend or even the briefest wait in the company of a&#xA;rAkShasi-like woman is a passage through naraka. We had made the long&#xA;journey to city center in all these companies- with our friend with whom&#xA;we were united in mind, with the apsara-like girl who bathes all the&#xA;senses in soma-like bliss (verily called somAnanda), in the company of a&#xA;piShAchi when every nimesha of the mAnusha feels like one of brahma. And&#xA;then we were making it alone. When you make it alone, all you are left&#xA;with are the reflections in the atmAn. As the reflections fleeted&#xA;through the chit, or was it the manas (we would never know?), we could&#xA;identify with the pratikriyA that shuddhodana-putra had felt on his&#xA;first journey outside the royal cocoon. It was all there roga, jara,&#xA;mR^ityu. Yet on the other side there was the Ananda of the bhoga of&#xA;anna, pAna, kAma ityAdi being enjoyed by many. First the words of the&#xA;wise eldest pANDu came to mind, but then the unity with vArtAlI was&#xA;felt. It was that flow of prakR^iti who was manifest as vArAhi and the 8&#xA;mothers that we were a part of. We then attained bliss in food.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
