<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Stock taking of sangh parivAr on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Stock taking of sangh parivAr on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Introduction</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/01_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/01_intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The credit for the present compilation goes wholly to Dr. Shreerang&#xA;Godbole. It was his letters written to us in August-September 1996 which&#xA;prompted us to circulate in October 1996 an 8-page brochure - &lt;em&gt;Time For&#xA;Stock Taking: A Swayamsevak Speaks&lt;/em&gt; - which we reproduce below:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Shreerang Godbole is a young medical practitioner at Pune in&#xA;Maharashtra. He has been a swayamsevak of the Rashtriya Swayamsevak&#xA;Sangh (RSS) for seventeen years. We have received from him the two&#xA;documents which we are reproducing in the pages that follow. He has&#xA;given us permission to circulate them widely among the Hindu&#xA;intelligentsia with a view to elicit Hindu response.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 1. A Call for an Intellectual (Bauddhika) Kshatriya DAVID FRAWLEY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/02_chi1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/02_chi1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. A Call for an Intellectual&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Bauddhika&lt;/em&gt;) Kshatriya&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;DAVID FRAWLEY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We live in the age of the information revolution, which has taken a&#xA;quantum leap since the introduction of computers. The information flood&#xA;is changing the nature of the society in which we live, in ways that we&#xA;do not yet know and for which there is no precedent. This information&#xA;revolution is in many respects an information war, with different groups&#xA;struggling to put their views out to the general public as the truth. It&#xA;is often a disinformation war as well, with groups trying to discredit&#xA;those who have different views, using the media as their weapon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 2. Ideological Defence of Hindu Society SITA RAM GOEL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/03_chi2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/03_chi2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Ideological Defence of Hindu Society&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;SITA RAM GOEL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. Ideological aggression, if not resisted in proper time, leads&#xA;invariably to physical aggression.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2. Instead of promoting a physical clash, ideological defence&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;i. prevents it most of the time because the aggressor stands warned&#xA;that he would be resisted;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ii. or minimises one-sided violence because the victim also stands&#xA;well-prepared;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;iii. and often helps the aggressor to drop his habit because he comes&#xA;to know that the other side knows his designs or that there is another&#xA;side of the story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/04_chii1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/04_chii1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. G.V. Ashtekar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the outset, I must acknowledge the truth in the objections raised by&#xA;Dr. Shreerang Godbole. I also take this opportunity of expressing my&#xA;deep respect and reverence about the work done by &lt;strong&gt;Voice of India&lt;/strong&gt; for&#xA;awakening Hindu scholars for the new outlook as well as for presenting&#xA;them with the perceptions and facets of Hindutva which had remained&#xA;elusive for centuries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I firmly believe that the leadership of the RSS which has consented to&#xA;this new step, do know these facts very well.&lt;/strong&gt; However, as per the&#xA;typical RSS way of functioning, there have been no explanations on this&#xA;stand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05  APPENDIX Senate Joint Resolution 165 97th Congress 2nd Session IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES April 5, 1982</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/05_chii2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/05_chii2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Professor G.C. Asnani&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. I broadly agree with the stand taken by Dr. Shreerang Godbole.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2. In a labour organisation concerned with purely economic problem, why&#xA;bring religion - Sarva Dharma, etc.?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3. We were five student friends studying in Karachi College in the&#xA;beginning of 1940’s. One of us started taking interest in the RSS. The&#xA;rest of us vehemently opposed him, calling him communalist; we were&#xA;nationalists, secularists, congressites. We believed in Mahatma Gandhi’s&#xA;approach of love and Hindu-Muslim &lt;em&gt;bhai-bhai&lt;/em&gt;. When Mahatma Gandhi&#xA;failed in his vow to oppose partition of India, and he succumbed to&#xA;Muslim demand for partition, we got shaken and somewhat disillusioned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06  FIRST DOCUMENT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/06_chii3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/06_chii3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Deep Chandra Awasthi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the very outset I would like to say that the eight formulations&#xA;popularised by Sangh Parivar in recent years as stated, is not the whole&#xA;fact. There may be even some more such formulations put forth by&#xA;individuals as social hypothesis yet to be put to tests before being&#xA;accepted as useful practices. The most that can be said is that the&#xA;Sangh Parivar may also be in a mood to carry out some such tests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/07_chii4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/07_chii4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. P. N. Awasthi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have gone through both the letters written by a Pune Swayamsevak for&#xA;the RSS organisation. The issue pointed out in the letters is quite&#xA;genuine and crucial, particularly after the formation of Pakistan and&#xA;Bangla Desh. We had the same Constitution before also, but partition&#xA;could not be prevented in spite of the sacrifice of Mahatma Gandhi -&#xA;showering liberties on a people bent on separation.  Retaining the same&#xA;Constitution automatically invites the same happenings repeatedly. If&#xA;this is really intended, at least after the partition the country should&#xA;have been named as ‘Secularistan’ or ‘Sam Dharmastan’ or something like&#xA;that to indicate its proper nature. If this was put to vote people would&#xA;have known what they were preferring. But calling it ‘India’ and&#xA;‘Hindustan’ with a permanent policy of strangulating the original&#xA;inhabitants of this land - forced to be recognised by the foreign&#xA;identification ‘Hindus’ - who did not convert, in spite of all the&#xA;atrocities, to recently originated religions, born in the places once&#xA;under the umbrella of the culture and civilization of this land, has&#xA;confused the people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/08_chii5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/08_chii5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. S. K. Balasubramanian&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You have performed a service by circulating the note of Dr. Shreerang&#xA;Godbole. The note raises pertinent questions about the usefulness of the&#xA;movement for equality amongst religions as. presently conceived by the&#xA;RSS leadership. His observations are also relevant at the international&#xA;level.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People who ask Hindus to treat all religions equally are barking up the&#xA;wrong tree. Pluralism in faith is part of the baggage that every Hindu&#xA;carries from cradle to grave. But genuine equality is a two-way street,&#xA;and all parties should subscribe to certain commonalities in a sincere&#xA;manner. I suggest the following steps:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/09_chii6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/09_chii6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Abhas Chatterjee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the hierarchy of the Rashtriya Swayamsevak Sangha, Dr. Shreerang&#xA;Godbole is only a &lt;em&gt;Swayamsevak&lt;/em&gt;. One wishes he was the &lt;em&gt;Sarsanghchãlak&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;or the &lt;em&gt;Sarkaryavãh&lt;/em&gt;. For, the ideological clarity, historical&#xA;perception, understanding of national issues and intellectual awareness&#xA;that he has exhibited in his two short write-ups, have been so sadly&#xA;lacking in the top-brass of the organisation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The RSS was started by its illustrious founder Dr. K.B. Hedgewar because&#xA;of his prime conviction that Mahatma Gandhi’s efforts during the&#xA;Khilafat agitation to coalesce Hindu and Muslim national aspirations&#xA;into one, were misplaced and futile. Dr. Hedgewar had realized that&#xA;Hindus had the right as well as need to pursue their national interests&#xA;in their own homeland. He correctly perceived that Muslim intransigence&#xA;born out of their loyalty to an alien culture and ex-ruler syndrome and&#xA;their consequent separatist demand, were bound to come in conflict with&#xA;Hindu national aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/10_chii7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/10_chii7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. G.C. Chaudhary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Shreerang Godbole has actually given vent to his deep anguish which&#xA;is gnawing at the heart and mind of the Hindu intelligentsia today. He&#xA;has spoken THE TRUTH - may it be bitter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am writing these lines not only from my knowledge but from my&#xA;experience and from what I have seen, and the events of recent past&#xA;which I have lived and borne.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Muslims of India propounded the two nation theory purely on the basis of&#xA;Islam, the only true religion. They claimed that they had a ‘different’&#xA;culture, tradition, language, living and that they could not co-exist in&#xA;Hindu-dominated India. Jinnah declared, “If the Congress wanted war,&#xA;Indian Muslims will accept the offer unhesitatingly. We shall have India&#xA;divided or India destroyed.” Muslims ultimately succeeded in&#xA;partitioning the country gaining Pakistan. So what remained was&#xA;naturally Hindusthan. But the majority of Muslim agitators who were from&#xA;Bengal, Bihar and U.P., stayed back with their mental aberrations&#xA;intact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/11_chii8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/11_chii8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. S. K. Dalvi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I received a pamphlet from you entitled “Time for Stock Taking”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since 1930 I have been a devotee of Hindutva, having been in association&#xA;with the people who at that time used to be called ‘Savarkarites’ at&#xA;Ratnagiri.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although I did not/do not possess the qualities of a leader, writer or&#xA;an orator, since then I have contributed to the cause of Hindutva&#xA;according to my capacity, even at the cost of being teased sarcastically&#xA;as a Votary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/12_chii9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/12_chii9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Ashoke Dasgupta&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am in receipt of the booklet detailing two documents of Dr. Shreerang&#xA;Godbole. I am grateful for the same. My response on these two documents&#xA;is as under:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is evident that ‘Sarva Panth Samãdar Manch’ is launched because a new&#xA;avenue is being sought in order to frame a policy in respect of the&#xA;Muslim question in the Indian polity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is rather an approach - an approach to be in touch of the Muslim&#xA;community so that the political untouchability towards BJP propagated by&#xA;the Secularists can be overcome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/13_chii10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/13_chii10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Jitendra D. Desai&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FIRST DOCUMENT:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. What is the harm in adding Jesus and Muhammad to the 33 crore Hindu&#xA;gods and goddesses?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Response:&lt;/strong&gt; What is the need? Why do we want to add two more gods to&#xA;33 crore gods and goddesses? Is this a genuine desire to assimilate two&#xA;communities following two Semitic religions?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, the Sangh leadership is guided by BJP leadership, which&#xA;in turn is guided by desire to achieve political supremacy at any cost,&#xA;and this desire (of political power at any cost) has brought down the&#xA;BJP leadership to the lowly depths of electoral arithmetic - votes&#xA;count, votes of Christians and Muslims also count. Hindu leadership may&#xA;recommend addition of two more idols of Jesus and Muhammad in the Hindu&#xA;pantheon, but are Hindus prepared to worship them? Are Christians and&#xA;Muslims prepared to accept this accommodation?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 DOCUMENT 1: MY ANSWERS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/14_chii11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/14_chii11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11. Nachiketa Dogra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Received your “Time for Stock Taking”. Each and every word of this&#xA;pamphlet especially from Dr. Godbole spoke my heart and mind. I bow down&#xA;before you and Godbole for such an unbeatable logic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hindu intellectuals should expose Quran and Hadith i.e. Islam. Islam in&#xA;itself is very very weak and fragile without any reason and philosophy.&#xA;It is medieval and unscientific. So it will not at all stand the test of&#xA;time. It violates human rights mercilessly. So it will crumble down with&#xA;double of the speed with which it rose up, once it is declothed. Muslims&#xA;and Secularists have covered it up with a black cloth like the one in&#xA;Mecca. Islam will depreciate in the mind of Muslims themselves when&#xA;Hindus start showing the real face of it.  Majority of the Muslims&#xA;(especially Indian Muslims) don’t know Quran and Hadith. Some Muslim&#xA;intellectuals (rather Muslim fanatics) have now started interpreting&#xA;Islam and Quran in a modified way so that its ugly face is not exposed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/15_chii12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/15_chii12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;**12.  Adwayanand R. Galatge **&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Shreerang Godbole, an RSS worker from Pune, has done some plain&#xA;speaking to the Sangh leaders on the question of Muslims. It is tragic&#xA;to find that they really deserve it. It is a measure of the level to&#xA;which the RSS has been reduced by its leaders’ recent preoccupation with&#xA;politics. The sordid drama recently enacted on the Gujarat stage exposes&#xA;the hazards of politics to which RSS is open and can ill-afford. The&#xA;small-time ‘shows’ like ‘Sarva Panth Samãdar Manch’ and the political&#xA;gimmicks like the ‘eight formulations’ that Dr. Godbole has cited (and&#xA;criticised), are the natural fall-out of this preoccupation. They are,&#xA;if anything, the ‘saffron brand of secularism’. If the Sangh leaders&#xA;believe that these exercises will win the confidence of the Muslims for&#xA;the political gains of the BJP, they are deceiving themselves. The&#xA;sooner they disabuse their minds of this misconception, the better. Nor&#xA;does it show any political maturity on their part to believe that these&#xA;exercises will bring the Muslims into the national mainstream. It makes&#xA;one wonder whether Sangh leaders also are so obtuse as to be incapable&#xA;of learning from history like those whom they criticise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/16_chii13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/16_chii13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13. K. B. Ganapathy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have your request for response to the circular titled ‘Time for Stock&#xA;Taking’ and here is my response for the first document given item-wise&#xA;in order to keep it to the minimum.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. It may be possible in the next 100 years or so to add Jesus Christ&#xA;as one of the many Gods (33 crore Hindu gods and goddesses) as Jesus&#xA;is a Godhead for Christians and Christians have no objection for&#xA;portraying Jesus and his disciples in the form of idols and pictures&#xA;just as Hindus have added Buddha as one of the Avataras.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17  Letter to the Organiser Re: &#34;DURGA&#34; in the VANDE MATARAM song as composed by Bankimchandra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/17_chii14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/17_chii14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14. Padmashri Shalil Ghosh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am grateful to you for sending me a copy of “Time for Stock Taking” by&#xA;Dr. S. Godbole.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I fully agree with his contentions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hindus, throughout the ages, especially our so-called ‘MAHATMAS’, never&#xA;understood the Muslim mind and fell an easy prey to Muslim&#xA;manipulations. Hindus were always on the defensive for no reason at all,&#xA;(see my enclosed letter to Organiser weekly, Delhi, dated 2.8.1996, as&#xA;an example).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/18_chii15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/18_chii15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15. Bhagwati Prasad Goenka&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am thankful to you for a copy of ‘Time for Stock Taking’ booklet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Religions are made for people to shape their lives, in short, to&#xA;establish a code of conduct for themselves. A religion which preaches&#xA;that other religions are inferior, cannot be equated with a religion&#xA;which preaches that all are equal and that all can attain salvation&#xA;whatever way they adopt. For this matter the comparing of Islam or&#xA;Christianity with Hinduism is not only impractical but totally naive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/19_chii16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/19_chii16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16. Shiv Goud&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have received your pamphlet “Time for Stock Taking”, and gone through&#xA;it in detail.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your first document mentions the attitude of Hindu organizations towards&#xA;the Muslims problem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Only Hindus who are unware of the Vedas, say that there is no harm in&#xA;adding Jesus and Mohammed to the 33 crore Hindu gods and goddesses. It&#xA;is an indication of the slave mentality of Hindus. Christianity and&#xA;Islam are Semitic religions. Both of them waged religious wars against&#xA;each other but did not accept the religion of the other party, as equal&#xA;to their own.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/20_chii17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/20_chii17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17. S. C. Gupta&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I refer to the pamphlet “TIME FOR STOCK TAKING - A SWAYAMSEVAK SPEAKS.”&#xA;which you have sent for my comments. The following pages contain my&#xA;comments on Dr. Shreerang Godbole’s two documents, points by point, in&#xA;the same order as the points in the pamphlet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Document&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a Hindu resurgence but not to the extent it should be.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is also true that in spite of Hindu resurgence, the Hindu&#xA;organisations are becoming softer towards Islam and Muslims. There is no&#xA;corresponding change in the Muslim attitude towards Hindus or Hinduism.&#xA;These Hindu organisations sometimes take a seemingly harder attitude&#xA;towards Islam but the next moment they melt and behave as M.K. Gandhi&#xA;behaved towards Muslims and Islam. Such varying attitudes on the part of&#xA;Hindu organisations are indeed confusing to the Hindu masses in general.&#xA;It seems to me that if such a thing continues repeatedly a few more&#xA;times, the Hindu masses will consider the hard attitudes of Hindu&#xA;organisations as mere gimmicks having no steadfastness and teeth at all.&#xA;This will be also entirely harmful to the Hindu Renaissance we expect in&#xA;India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/21_chii18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/21_chii18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;**18. B.L. Jaju **&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have received the circular ‘Time For Stock Taking’. You have desired&#xA;that the intelligentsia, particularly the Hindu intelligentsia, should&#xA;offer their opinion about the ideology of Islam and how do they react to&#xA;the same.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am liberally educated, having an open mind, and have no prejudices or&#xA;preconceived thoughts about any religion, much less against Christianity&#xA;or Islam.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my opinion Hinduism or Sanatan Dharma has a long history of&#xA;toleration. They have never tried to see the darker side of any culture&#xA;or religion, and have always tried to accept and respect the points of&#xA;view of others. I think this is the reason why Sanatan Dharma has&#xA;survived during the last five thousand years. I am particularly grateful&#xA;to Dr. Godbole for asking the opinion and to elicit the Hindu response.&#xA;I have read with great interest the tenets of Christianity and Islam. I&#xA;am afraid that unlike Hinduism they do not allow any equality, much less&#xA;respect for other religions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/22_chii19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/22_chii19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19. H.C. Joshi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is a tragedy that the 3 different wings, namely, the BJP which is a&#xA;political institution for establishment of Bharatiya (Hindu) Rashtra,&#xA;the RSS which is an organisational wing of BJP, and the VHP which is a&#xA;religious platform for Hindus, are not able to work in unison for a&#xA;common cause - establishment of Bharatiya (Hindu) Rashtra, which is the&#xA;need of the hour to prevent threats of Muslim rule, either direct on by&#xA;proxy in the name of secular, democratic Bharat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/23_chii20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/23_chii20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20.  Dr. S.D. Kulkarni&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semitic Faiths are Political Creeds, not Religions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since its inception, Islam is being practised as a political creed. It&#xA;is not a religion. These two terms creed and religion are poles apart.&#xA;Creed is a dogmatic belief system as propounded by a person who claims&#xA;himself to be a prophet like the Jewish prophet Moses or the Islamic&#xA;prophet Muhammad, or a super-intelligent person, or a thinker like Marx,&#xA;next only to God. Whatever they say or do is the revealed truth. The&#xA;followers are not to question, why? They have only to put implicit faith&#xA;in what the prophet ordains them to do. They have no other choice.&#xA;Religion, on the other hand, is a system of beliefs agreed upon by a&#xA;group, particularly in the matter of worship of God who is taken to be&#xA;the Creator. Religion thus is a mode of worship of the Creator.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24  II</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/24_chii21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/24_chii21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21.  S.D. Laghate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have come across the booklet “Time for stock taking: a swayamsevak&#xA;speaks”. Since responses are invited on the opinions expressed therein,&#xA;I am writing this piece. I fully agree with the views expressed by Dr.&#xA;Shreerang Godbole in the booklet and I think concepts about Islam and&#xA;Muslim problem should be made clear to every intelligent Hindu so that&#xA;he may not be beguiled by propaganda which has gained authenticity and&#xA;support from the powers that be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25  Equality of Religions as Secularism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/25_chii22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/25_chii22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22.  Professor K. Lakshminarayana&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Document&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With reference to Dr. Godbole’s analysis of the eight conceptions of the&#xA;so-called Hindu Organizations regarding the Muslim Problem, his first&#xA;two responsive comments reiterate the fact that Cults of Uniformism&#xA;masquerading as religions are bound to be imperialist aggressors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Regarding the third conception – ‘Islam is good but Muslims are bad’ -&#xA;Dr Godbole has rightly reiterated that the difficulty resides in the&#xA;Cult that is fundamental to the group consciousness of the Muslims. The&#xA;problem, however, seems to be more complicated. On the one hand, there&#xA;are the ‘Hindu Caste’ Muslims (HCMs). On the other hand there are those&#xA;whom the HCMs call ‘Musalmans’ (MMs)*. The latter appear to recognize&#xA;themselves as foreigners and as erstwhile and would-be rulers. They tend&#xA;to align themselves strategically with our ‘Secular Progressives’.&#xA;Hindus will have to interact differently with these two groups, but&#xA;interact they must. Healthy interaction with the HCMs cannot be based&#xA;either on appeasement or on aggression. Before anything in the way of&#xA;fruitful interaction can happen, Hindu Society has to get organically&#xA;strengthened. The synthetic top-to-down organization is doomed to fail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/26_chii23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/26_chii23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23. Professor K.S. Lal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. S. Godbole’s comments at a Seminar in Pune and his letter to Shri&#xA;K.S. Sudarshan, published by the Voice of India in the form of a&#xA;brochure titled Time for Stock Taking, raise issues of vital importance&#xA;to the Majority population of Hindus in the country. There are many&#xA;minority groups in India. But except the Muslims, they pose no serious&#xA;problem. The Muslim position has been intractable both before and after&#xA;Partition. I would like to react to points raised by Dr. Godbole in the&#xA;sequence published in the brochure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/27_chii24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/27_chii24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24. Professor R. R. Mangasuli&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No organization has so far found any solution to merge the Muslims in&#xA;India with Hindu society. National Congress, Bahujan Samaj Party, Janata&#xA;Dal and such parties have only succeeded in increasing the rift between&#xA;the two &lt;em&gt;creeds&lt;/em&gt; and making Muslims more stubborn. Muslims are like an&#xA;idiotic son of negligent parents. Careful attention only can correct&#xA;him. Muslim as an individual is quite accommodative like other human&#xA;beings. He is fanatic when he poses as a follower of Islam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/28_chii25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/28_chii25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25. T. G. Mohandas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before going into the questions raised by Dr. Godbole, let us understand&#xA;the stage where we stand and discuss.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today’s Bharath, a Hindu is a Hindu because his father is a Hindu. So&#xA;is the case with a Muslim or a Christian. Generally, nobody knows or&#xA;even bothers to know the guiding principles of one’s own faith, leave&#xA;alone understanding someone else’s faith. Hindus go to temples, perform&#xA;some rituals (of which they do not have any understanding) and claim to&#xA;be devout Hindus. Same is the case with Muslims and Christians.&#xA;Consequently, everybody forms an opinion about each religion from the&#xA;occasional speeches they hear, stories that are being told, debates that&#xA;appear in newspaper columns etc. This process brings out only the&#xA;beautiful and acceptable facets of all religions because everybody wants&#xA;to score debating points and entertain his readership / audience. In&#xA;short, people are led by perceptions and not by truth. As such,&#xA;everybody is offended the moment his religion’s flaws are pointed out.&#xA;This has created a situation in which one who tries to tell bitter&#xA;truths is immediately branded as communal and fanatic. To overcome this,&#xA;one is compelled to put at least a facade of ‘Sarva Panth Samãdar’, or&#xA;he will not be able to catch the attention of his target group.&#xA;Precisely, this writer feels, this is the reason or logic behind the&#xA;occasional utterances of Hindu leaders as outlined by Dr. Godbole.&#xA;Nevertheless, I am sure that Dr. Godbole will agree with me if I say&#xA;that no serious policy document, resolution, communique or publication&#xA;belonging to any of the organisations of the Sangh Parivar, advocates&#xA;any of the eight arguments. This writer had the good luck of listening&#xA;to innumerable Baudhiks from none other than Param Poojaneeya Guruji to&#xA;a not-so-learned humble pracharak who talks to a small group of five or&#xA;six Swayamsevaks. I must categorically state that during the last 37&#xA;years of my life as a Swayamsevak, I have not heard a single Baudhik&#xA;which prompted me to believe that Islam is in any way equivalent to&#xA;Hindutva. However, the points shown by Dr. Godbole are occasionally&#xA;heard in public speeches and therefore are to be treated as statements&#xA;or overtures made to create a conductive atmosphere for a meaningful&#xA;dialogue with Muslims. This writer feels that to save Muslims from the&#xA;clutches of Islam, the Quran is to be discussed and exposed. For this,&#xA;it is better to tell Muslims that we are ready to accept the Quran but&#xA;have serious reservations on the preaching of Islam and Quran vis-à-vis&#xA;Hindus. This could possibly initiate a dialogue and open-minded Muslims,&#xA;howsoever minuscule in numbers, could be forced to read the Quran and&#xA;ponder over the facts presented by us. Conversely, if we start with a&#xA;head-on confrontation, that will invite only blind rebuttals and voice&#xA;of reason will be lost from both sides.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/29_chii26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/29_chii26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26.  Professor S. G. Mujumdar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I entirely agree with Dr. Shreerang Godbole’s view on the likelihood of&#xA;confusion being created by the leaders of the Sangh Parivar, owing to&#xA;its contradictory stances on its approach towards the Muslim problem.&#xA;The Mantra of &lt;em&gt;“Sarvadharmasamabhãva”&lt;/em&gt; has clogged the mind of Hindu&#xA;leaders for too long. Firstly, how many of these leaders who have&#xA;interiorized this concept can claim to be aware of the tenets of&#xA;Christianity and Islam which have time and again wreaked havoc on Hindu&#xA;Society? Secondly, how many of the Sangh leaders can demonstrate the&#xA;&lt;em&gt;“Sarvadharmasamabhãva”&lt;/em&gt; being practised by the Muslim Clergy and the&#xA;Christian Missionaries? Thirdly, what is the logic of equating Hinduism&#xA;with exclusive ideologies like Islam and Christianity which have never&#xA;had anything to do with the spirit of pluralism, either in theory or in&#xA;practice? Will the Sangh leaders care to find out in the spirit of&#xA;&lt;em&gt;“Sarvadharmasamabhãva”&lt;/em&gt;, as to how many of Muslims and Christians who&#xA;are presently touted as “secularists par excellence” will invite or&#xA;install a Hindu God adjacent to their Allah or Jesus. Fourthly, how can&#xA;Muslims and Christians, who have a tyrannical record in the past of&#xA;subjugating the majority Hindus in their own homeland, be termed as a&#xA;“minority”? Fifthly, if the leaders of the Sangh Parivar really believe&#xA;in the equality of religions, why do they oppose movements of&#xA;conversions and introduce movements like &lt;strong&gt;“Shuddhi, Ghar Vãpasî,&#xA;Parãvartan”&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/30_chii27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/30_chii27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;27.  P. R. K. Naidu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks for mailing the small but thought provoking pamphlet &lt;strong&gt;“TIME FOR&#xA;STOCK TAKING”&lt;/strong&gt;. I very much appreciate your gesture of inviting the&#xA;responses from the Hindu Mind.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. The Indian National Congress from the very inception was not for the&#xA;welfare of Hindusthan and its citizens, especially the Hindus and their&#xA;culture, but for the unhindered continuation of the British rule.&#xA;Pseudo-Nationalist leaders steeped in Western culture took over and gave&#xA;the call of Nationalism, which was taken up by the common man and became&#xA;a mass frenzied Nationalism, an outcome of the Westernised Indian&#xA;leaders. This Nationalism is devoid of Bharatiya culture or well defined&#xA;patriotism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/31_chii28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/31_chii28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;28.  S. Omkar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I refer to the document “Time For Stock Taking”. I am surprised that the&#xA;Sangh Parivar has been popularizing these eight slogans. Obviously, the&#xA;leaders of the Sangh Parivar have not read either the Bible or the&#xA;Quran. If they had read them, they would not be making such ridiculous&#xA;statements. &lt;strong&gt;With friends like these, Hindus do not need enemies.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1. What is the harm in adding Jesus and Muhammad to the 33 crore Hindu&#xA;gods and goddesses?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I do not know where this number 33 crore came from because even a&#xA;language rich in vocabulary such as Sanskrit does not have 33 crore&#xA;words. In any case, all the Hindu deities are different representations&#xA;of the one God, and believing in one does not involve denial of others.&#xA;Jesus and Muhammad do not fall in the category of deities. Also,&#xA;according to the New Testament and the Quran, if one does not believe in&#xA;Jesus or Allah (together with Muhammad) respectively as the only&#xA;saviour, then one is doomed to eternal hell. If one believes in Jesus or&#xA;if one believes in Allah (with Muhammad), then it is not permissible to&#xA;worship any other deity. Therefore, Jesus and Allah (with Muhammad)&#xA;cannot be included in Hindu deities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/32_chii29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/32_chii29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;29. Virendra V. Parekh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Shreerang Godbole has issued a timely warning against cosy soporific&#xA;slogans currently mouthed by leaders of some prominent Hindu&#xA;organisations. His documents display a clarity of mind and courage of&#xA;conviction that is rare among Hindu intellectuals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While one agrees entirely with the tone and tenor of the documents, some&#xA;of Dr. Godbole’s formulations need improvement. It is sufficient to say&#xA;that the openness of Hinduism should not be misused to sanction those&#xA;dogmas of other religious groups which breed exclusiveness, intolerance&#xA;and aggressiveness. The quotation from David Frawley is not apt in this&#xA;context. If the Muslims want to search for spirituality in Islam, the&#xA;Hindus have no reason to object, however futile the search may seem to&#xA;them. The Hindus should concentrate on fighting the politics of Islam&#xA;and resist all ideological, political and territorial demands made in&#xA;its name.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>33  II</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/33_chii30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/33_chii30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;30. Hem Raj Prabhakar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am replying to the issues raised by your brochure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. The doctrine of Islam is Unity. The Koran say that Allah is one and&#xA;alone, without a second. In Christianity, Jesus is the Son of God, which&#xA;means he is second to God. Thus other men cannot be sons of God and will&#xA;go to Heaven or Hell for ever, not according to their actions but on the&#xA;recommendations of Jesus. Muhammad will sit near Allah and similarly&#xA;recommend Heaven for Muslims and Hell for Kafirs. He destroyed the idols&#xA;in the Kaaba, and killed all persons who persisted in the pre-Islamic&#xA;creed. It shows that there is no room for other gods in Islam and&#xA;Christianity. Nor can Jesus and Muhammad be accommodated in the Hindu&#xA;pantheon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34  Hindus Muslims India 700 million 120 million Pakistan nil &#39;&#39; 130 &#39;&#39; Bangladesh 10 &#39;&#39; 130 &#39;&#39; Total 710 &#39;&#39; 380 &#39;&#39; </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/34_chii31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/34_chii31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;31. Baljit Rai&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We cannot be sufficiently grateful to Dr. Godbole for having questioned&#xA;the validity of a thesis advanced by the BJP think-tank and its allied&#xA;organisations with a view to creating a constituency among the Indian&#xA;Muslims who form barely 12% of the total population of India. The BJP&#xA;brains trust has devised an agenda of which the eight formulations&#xA;pointed out by Dr. Godbole form the core. Dr. Godbole has debunked each&#xA;of the formulations with irrefutable and cogent arguments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/35_chii32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/35_chii32/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;32. Dr. H. Ramarao&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks for sending the booklet ‘Time for Stock Taking’. I have noted&#xA;that the author has shown his utmost concern regarding the&#xA;‘Hindu-Muslim’ problem nagging the country even after partition in a new&#xA;form, i.e., Secularism vs. Communalism, and the Congress policy of&#xA;appeasement of Muslims going on merrily as before with help of its&#xA;allies (Communists, Casteists and Communalists) to the detriment of the&#xA;Majority community. If the trend is not checked immediately, the country&#xA;may go for a few ‘mini’ partitions, to accommodate a few miniature&#xA;Pakistans here and there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>36 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/36_chii33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/36_chii33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;33. B.K. Rao&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After Kumbhakarna had practised severe austerities, Brahmã appeared&#xA;before him and said, “I am pleased with your tapasyã, what boon would&#xA;you have?”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“God, give me plenty of sleep: good, long sleep, for I enjoy it most!”&#xA;replied Kumbhakarna.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“So be it,” blessed Brahmã and disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And thereafter, goes the story, Kumbhakarna used to sleep for six months&#xA;at a stretch, wake up for a day to eat and drink, and go back to sleep&#xA;for another six months.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>37 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/37_chii34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/37_chii34/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;34. (Mrs) Veda Sampath&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Document:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. Muhammad is Allah’s messenger, and a mortal human being. Hence he&#xA;is only an intermediary, which is also the claim made by his votaries.&#xA;Some sentimental Hindus may have no objection to count him as a saint.&#xA;But there is no question of his being included in the category of&#xA;Hindu Gods.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jesus is considered as the Son of God. But according to Christian&#xA;belief, he presented himself as a martyr for the sake of humanity. No&#xA;Hindu God is known to have suffered as a martyr. On the contrary,&#xA;Hindu Gods are known to have protected their devotees and eliminated&#xA;evil people with might and force. Hence there is no scope for Jesus&#xA;being counted among Hindu Gods.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>38 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/38_chii35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/38_chii35/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;35. Smt.  M. Sandhya&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am reacting only to one of the points raised in Dr. Godbole’s Second&#xA;Document, namely, the similarity between Christianity, Islam and Marxism&#xA;as distinguished from true religions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;David Frawley in his book, &lt;em&gt;Hinduism; The Eternal Tradition&lt;/em&gt;, says that&#xA;“the attempt to connect human being with the Eternal is the very essence&#xA;of true religion”. He further elucidates that true religions base&#xA;themselves upon something Universal and function harmoniously with the&#xA;World and Nature. They are assimilative, inclusive, spiritual and&#xA;tolerant. The individual in true religions has absolute freedom to&#xA;choose his own path, evolve his own methodologies and practices to&#xA;realise the True Self (God). The true religions like Hinduism, Taoism,&#xA;Zoroastrianism, Buddhism, Jainism, the Pagan religions, and the&#xA;Indigenous religions of Africa and the Americas have evolved over long&#xA;periods of time through the process of assimilation. They promote&#xA;universality of vision and strive for spiritual experience. As they are&#xA;organically connected to Nature and the Earth, they are peaceful and&#xA;passive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>39 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/39_chii36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/39_chii36/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;36. K. Satya Deva Prasad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am in receipt of your pamphlet “Time for Stock Taking: A Swayamsevak&#xA;Speaks” wherein you solicited response to the issues raised therein from&#xA;Hindus in general and Swayamsevaks in particular.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I can see, you sent the pamphlet to me for only one reason, that is,&#xA;myself being one of the participants of the Prajna Bharati Seminar of&#xA;July’96 at Pune. I see no other reason why you should know my&#xA;whereabouts.* As such I am responding as a Swayamsevak. My association&#xA;with Sangh is of two decades. I have great respect and admiration for&#xA;Sangh. In my view it is the only organisation that is working to implant&#xA;love for our motherland and Hindu tradition deep in common people’s&#xA;minds on a large scale. If today I am seriously interested in issues&#xA;concerning Hinduism and Hindu society, it is totally due to the&#xA;inspiration I derived from the Sangh. Therefore I insist that wherever I&#xA;differ from what we call Sangh’s view or formulations, I do so as an&#xA;ardent follower of Sangh but with an independent viewpoint of my own on&#xA;certain issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>40 A resident of Kullu in Himachal Pradesh, the writer has formed his view of Islam from his contact with a Muslim classmate in F.C. College, Lahore, and a study of the governments functioning in several Islamic countries.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/40_chii37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/40_chii37/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;37. Jagannath Sharma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Islam -The Unknown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For years, Mahatma Gandhi made his congregation recite with devotional&#xA;spirit: &lt;em&gt;“Raghupati Raghav Raja Ram… Ishwar Allah tere naam, Sabko&#xA;sanmati de Bhagwaan”.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hindus of all hues were carried away by these chantings, and even after&#xA;about half a century of his demise, or so to say, bloody partition of&#xA;the country, this hymn is heard on AIR, DD and through loudspeakers on&#xA;2nd October and 31st January from year to year. None has ever bothered&#xA;to know if Allah actually means what Hindus perceive as Ishwar. Hindus&#xA;simply consider Allah a literal translation of Ishwar, which to them&#xA;carries the same philosophical qualities as they see in Ishwar. Just as&#xA;an elephant and &lt;em&gt;haathi&lt;/em&gt; are the same in different languages. It may&#xA;sound strange, but it is true that what Allah ordains upon his followers&#xA;is not what Ishwar expects from his believers, and even non-believers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>41 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/41_chii38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/41_chii38/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;38. Ajit Singh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is with reference to the pamphlet “Time For Stock Taking: A&#xA;Swayamsevak Speaks” published by &lt;strong&gt;Voice of India&lt;/strong&gt;. Myself and many&#xA;others who read it are appalled to learn that R.S.S. leaders have&#xA;floated a “Sarva Panth Samãdar Manch” which includes, in the definition&#xA;of panth, religions other than the Sanatan Dharma sects, such as Islam&#xA;and Christianity, whose fundamentalist and regimented beliefs are&#xA;diametrically opposed to the spiritual democracy of Hindu Dharma. It is&#xA;all the more shocking for a person like me who has been a devoted&#xA;Swayamsevak since 1943 and has boldly faced the adverse situations even&#xA;at the risk of my job etc. during the Emergency. Departure from the&#xA;basic principles of the Sangh has come as a bolt from the blue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>42 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/42_chii39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/42_chii39/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;39.  Ram Autar Singh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reference pamphlet “Time for Stock Taking”, my views on the two&#xA;documents from Dr. Shreerang Godbole are enumerated as under&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FIRST DOCUMENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1. What is the harm in adding Jesus and Mohammad to the 33 crore Hindu&#xA;gods and goddesses?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;There is difference between love and infatuation. Infatuation can be&#xA;one-sided but love is reciprocal. Devotion is blind. Quite a few Hindus&#xA;appear infatuated with Muslims. First the Sikhs sang – &lt;em&gt;“Pahle Allah&#xA;Noor Upjaya”&lt;/em&gt;, and adorned themselves with blue uniform like that of&#xA;Mullahs and Sufis, yet Guru Teg Bahadur, Guru Arjun Dev, Guru Govind&#xA;Singh and Banda Bairagi were made martyrs by Muslim tyrants. Pakistan&#xA;helped Khalistanis against Hindus. Gandhiji too sang, &lt;em&gt;“Ishwar Allah&#xA;tere nam”&lt;/em&gt; and of unity of Ram and Rahim, but with no effect, response&#xA;or echo from Muslims. The treachery continued. In Hindi films, Hindus&#xA;are shown singing the word “Khuda” or “Allah” but never with reciprocity&#xA;from the Muslim characters, who never utter Rama or Krishna. In fact,&#xA;the real question is whether Islam allows addition of any God other than&#xA;Allah, not whether Hindus are willing to include Mohammad or Allah among&#xA;their Gods. The fact is that Hindus have been doing it since the Muslim&#xA;invaders entered India, but the Muslims have yet to show any flexibility&#xA;or cracks in their dogmas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>43  Miracle of Balancing Votes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/43_chii40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/43_chii40/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;40. Vikram Singh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Shreerang Godbole, a Swayamsewak of the RSS for 17 years, put forth&#xA;his views frankly and plainly on “Hindu Organisations and the Muslim&#xA;Problem” at a Seminar in the presence of the think-tanks of the Sangh&#xA;Parivar. Immediately after that, he wrote a letter to Shri K.S.&#xA;Sudarshan, Sah-Karyawaha R.S.S., bemoaning the formation of the “Sarva&#xA;Panth Samãdar Manch” by the Sangh.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Voice of India both the documents are now available to the&#xA;interested persons. As far as the aforesaid letter is concerned, the&#xA;analysis presented by Dr. Godbole is clear and complete and needs no&#xA;addition. The analysis regarding the “Eight Formulations” of the Sangh&#xA;Parivar is no doubt elaborate. Even then it needs some additions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>44 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/44_chii41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/44_chii41/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;41. Dr. Vinay Kumar Sinha&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I quite agree with what Dr. Godbole has opined about Islam and&#xA;Christianity and the concept of Secularism or Sarvadharma Sambhãv or&#xA;Sarva Panth Samãdar etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, it is utterly wrong to bracket Hinduism (and its offshoots like&#xA;Buddhism, Jainism and Sikhism) with such exclusivist ideologies as Islam&#xA;and Christianity. It is in fact wrong to regard Christianity and Islam&#xA;as Dharmas. Let us discuss why.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>45 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/45_chii42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/45_chii42/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;42. Shrikant G. Talageri&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Godbole’s views are stated so succinctly, so concisely and so&#xA;comprehensively that there is really little need for any comments on&#xA;them: it is for the Sangh leadership to read his views very carefully&#xA;and repeatedly, and to seriously ponder over the matter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, I would like, nevertheless, to make the following elaborations&#xA;of my views on the following points raised by Dr. Godbole as well as by&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Voice of India&lt;/strong&gt; in their comments on his views:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>46 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/46_chii43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/46_chii43/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;43. Mrs. Leela Tampi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Document&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We Hindus find it deeply distressing that quite a few Rashtriya&#xA;Swayamsevak Sangh (RSS) leaders of national stature have taken to&#xA;propagating among the Hindu public certain proposition to propitiate the&#xA;Muslims. These propositions, besides being false and misleading, are&#xA;highly dangerous to Hindu society as they implant Negationism - the&#xA;denial of the centuries-long Muslim havoc in India - in the Hindu mind.&#xA;They also conceal the truth that it is Islamic theology, based on&#xA;Quranic exhortations, that is the direct inspiration for all Islamic&#xA;atrocities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>47 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/47_chii44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/47_chii44/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;44. B. K. Verma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am highly grateful to you for sending to me the views of Dr. Godbole&#xA;on the recent efforts of some Hindu organisations at bringing Muslims&#xA;into Indian mainstream by preaching equal respect for every religion.&#xA;But the exercise is futile and will only weaken the structure of the&#xA;nation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Instead, we must give serious thought to the ailments which are&#xA;bedevilling the nation. Why even after so much accommodation of almost&#xA;every demand, reasonable or unreasonable, Muslims make a show of&#xA;disaffection and dissatisfaction? What is wrong with our approach? Why&#xA;there is non-assimilation of Muslims in the Indian ethos? Particularly&#xA;when the breed of Indian Muslims is of indigenous origin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>48 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/48_chii45/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/48_chii45/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;45. R. C. Waswani&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. Yes, we would not mind including Jesus and Muhammad to the list of&#xA;33 crore Gods if they include one of our Gods to their’s. Tolerance&#xA;cannot be a one-sided affair. Why do we have to do that in the first&#xA;place? Let them live their religion, whatever that is, and let us live&#xA;ours. Tripping on our religion at the drop of a hat, should be put to an&#xA;end. Let the Kaba be opened first to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>49 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/49_chii46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/49_chii46/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;46. P. S. Yog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was indeed very nice of you to give me an opportunity to express my&#xA;views on the important points raised by Dr. Godbole of Pune.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alas! every word of Dr. Godbole is true. This truth has been brought out&#xA;clearly in many documented publications on Christianity and Islam.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Sarva Dharma Samabãhva”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People, who think on these lines commit the blunder of believing that&#xA;Islam is only Namaz, Roza, Zakat and Hajj which are of course common to&#xA;all religions in one form or the other. The fact is, and it needs to be&#xA;widely known, that individual and communal effort for converting other&#xA;people to Islam and Jihad for achieving it, is as much a part of&#xA;religious duty prescribed by the Quran and the Hadis for every Muslim.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>50 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/50_chii47/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/50_chii47/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;47. Brief Responses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I. Dipen Banerjee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At first I must thank you, for sending such a valuable document written&#xA;by Dr. Shreerang Godbole to a man like me of no importance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now I like to say something as a Hindu in general. Though I am not a&#xA;Swayamsevak, I am closely related with the R.S.S. So I feel sad when I&#xA;see that even a Nationalistic organisation like B.M.S. fails to&#xA;understand the basic ideologies of the monotheistic traditions like&#xA;Islam, Christianity and Judaism, and harps on the much vaunted theory of&#xA;Sarva Pantha Samãdar. I fully see eye to eye with Dr. Godbole in his&#xA;view that Sarva Pantha Samãdar goes against the basic principles of the&#xA;monotheistic traditions and that what we need is not Sarva Pantha&#xA;Samãdar but Sarva Pantha Chikitsã. Dr. Godbole has rightly pointed out&#xA;that the basic problem is in those exclusivist ideologies which have&#xA;been propagated for long as Dharma. It is sad that we do not go through&#xA;the basic texts and try to understand the tenets of Islam and&#xA;Christianity. The educated Hindus should read the Quran, the Hadith and&#xA;the Bible if they want to know what has gone wrong with the minorities&#xA;in India. Then they will see that, inspired by demonic traditions, they&#xA;are getting ready to destroy the age-old and the most humanistic&#xA;tradition of the world i.e. Hinduism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>51 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/51_chiii1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/51_chiii1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Sarva Dharma Samabhãva&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;or Sarva Dharma Sambhrama?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;(Unity or Confusion of Religions?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;David Frawley&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A common tenet of Hinduism is “Sarva Dharma Samabhãva,” which literally&#xA;means that all Dharmas are equal to or harmonious with each other. In&#xA;recent times this statement has been highlighted as meaning that “all&#xA;religions are the same” - that all religions are merely different paths&#xA;to God or the same spiritual goal. Based on this logic the religious&#xA;path that one takes is a matter of personal preference, like choosing&#xA;whether to eat rice or chapatis in order to fill one’s stomach. One’s&#xA;choice in religion is merely incidental and makes no real difference in&#xA;the spiritual direction of one’s life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>52 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/52_chiii1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/52_chiii1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Sarva Dharma Samabhãva&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;or Sarva Dharma Sambhrama?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;(Unity or Confusion of Religions?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;David Frawley&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A common tenet of Hinduism is “Sarva Dharma Samabhãva,” which literally&#xA;means that all Dharmas are equal to or harmonious with each other. In&#xA;recent times this statement has been highlighted as meaning that “all&#xA;religions are the same” - that all religions are merely different paths&#xA;to God or the same spiritual goal. Based on this logic the religious&#xA;path that one takes is a matter of personal preference, like choosing&#xA;whether to eat rice or chapatis in order to fill one’s stomach. One’s&#xA;choice in religion is merely incidental and makes no real difference in&#xA;the spiritual direction of one’s life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>53 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/53_chiii2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/53_chiii2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Meaning of Conversions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Suresh Desai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Suresh Desai, writer and journalist, was invited to speak on his&#xA;perceptions of the Christian Missionary activities at St. Pius Seminary&#xA;at Goregaon, Mumbai, on 10th March 1997. The Seminary trains Christians&#xA;in priesthood.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The audience was composed of 70 to 80 trainee priests, Father Julian who&#xA;teaches at the college, a couple of lecturers and Mr. Arvind Singh from&#xA;Hindu Vivek Kendra. Father Julian introduced Suresh Desai to the&#xA;audience.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>54 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/54_chiv1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/54_chiv1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Roll Over, Rushdie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Daniel Pipes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In March 1989, shortly after Ayatollah Khomeini issued his decree&#xA;sentencing Salman Rushdie to death for his novel &lt;em&gt;The Satanic Verses&lt;/em&gt;,&#xA;London’s &lt;em&gt;Observer&lt;/em&gt; newspaper published an anonymous letter from&#xA;Pakistan. “Salman Rushdie speaks for me,” wrote its author, who&#xA;explained: “Mine is a voice that has not yet found expression in&#xA;newspaper columns. It is the voice of those who are born Muslims but&#xA;wish to recant in adulthood, yet are not permitted to on pain of death.&#xA;Someone who does not live in an Islamic society cannot imagine the&#xA;sanctions, both self-imposed and external, that militate against&#xA;expressing religious disbelief. ‘I don’t believe in God’ is an&#xA;impossible public utterance even among family and friends… So we hold&#xA;our tongues, those of us who doubt.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>55 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/55_chiv2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/55_chiv2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Standing Up to Scrutinize Islam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;G.A. Wells&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why I Am Not a Muslim&lt;/em&gt;, By Ibn Warraq (Amherst, N.Y.: Prometheus&#xA;Books, 1995) 402 pp., $25.95 cloth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why I Am Not a Muslim&lt;/em&gt; certainly deserves the epithet “courageous” with&#xA;which R. J. Hoffmann introduces it in his Foreword, not so much because&#xA;of its thesis that Islamic civilization often reached magnificent&#xA;heights despite the religion of Islam, as because almost all the&#xA;fundamental tents of Islam are here scrutinized uncompromisingly.&#xA;Moreover, Ibn Warraq’s criticisms are no idiosyncrasies, but supported&#xA;with very extensive references to scholarly works. His book is&#xA;particularly valuable as a means of acquainting oneself with this&#xA;scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>56 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/56_chiv3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/56_chiv3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Turning away from Mecca&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Antony Flew&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why I am not a Muslim&lt;/em&gt;, Ibn Warraq, Prometheus Books,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Buffalo, 1995 $25.99. (UK Agent 10 Crescent View,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Loughton, IG10 4PZ).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book was written by a man who was raised in a totally Muslim&#xA;environment in an overwhelmingly Muslim country. But he has since moved&#xA;to one of the NATO states which have since World War II been accepting&#xA;mass immigrations from such countries. &lt;em&gt;Why I am not a Muslim&lt;/em&gt; is&#xA;apparently the first book of its kind to have appeared in the English&#xA;language.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>57 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/57_chiv4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/57_chiv4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Islam is religious fascism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Ibn AI-Rawandi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why I am not a Muslim&lt;/strong&gt; by Ibn Warraq&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(Prometheus Books, £15 to RPA members).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In one of his early works the traditionalist writer Frithjof Schuon&#xA;makes an acute observation about the mentality of Muslims: ‘The&#xA;intellectual - and thereby the rational - foundation of Islam results in&#xA;the average Muslim having a curious tendency to believe that non-Muslims&#xA;either know that Islam is the truth and reject it out of pure obstinacy,&#xA;or else are simply ignorant of it and can be converted by elementary&#xA;explanations; that anyone should be able to oppose Islam with a good&#xA;conscience quite exceeds the Muslim’s power of imagination, precisely&#xA;because Islam coincides in his mind with the irresistible logic of&#xA;things.’ (&lt;em&gt;Stations of Wisdom&lt;/em&gt;) How true this is will strike anyone who&#xA;has tried to have a rational discussion on religion with a Muslim born&#xA;of Muslim parents and raised in a Muslim culture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>58 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/58_chiv5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/58_chiv5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Courageous author puts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;his life on the line&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why I am not a Muslim&lt;/em&gt; by Ibn Warraq, Prometheus Books, UK ISBN 0 87975&#xA;984 4. £22. Rationalist Press Association members: £ 15, Including&#xA;postage, from RPA, Bradlaugh House.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Review: Daniel O’Hara&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My own attempt to engage with Islam has, before reading this book,&#xA;mainly been through talking with a group of Islamic students from Kings&#xA;College, London, who regularly set up a lunchtime stall outside their&#xA;college gates in The Strand, opposite the church of St. Mary Overy.&#xA;Their views are extreme, but appear entirely within the mainstream&#xA;Islamic tradition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>59 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/59_chiv6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/59_chiv6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Far more dangerous than Nazism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Dr. Jan Knappert&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ibn Warraq : &lt;em&gt;Why I am not a Muslim&lt;/em&gt;, Prometheus Books, New York 1995,&#xA;xvi, 402 pages, ISBN: 0-87975-984-4.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ibn Warraq grew up in a Muslim family. Islam is a jealous religion so&#xA;that any man who grew up in a Muslim family and is, for that reason&#xA;considered a Muslim, not by his own volition, has to remain a Muslim for&#xA;life, or else he is sentenced to death, and this sentence will be&#xA;carried out as soon as a Muslim assassin can get him in the crossed&#xA;hairs. Apostasy, in Arabic &lt;em&gt;irtidad&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;ridda&lt;/em&gt;, is considered “treason”&#xA;and a “danger to the (Islamic) state”. An apostatic woman is not&#xA;executed but imprisoned until she agrees to be a Muslim again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>60 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/60_chv1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/60_chv1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Indian Express&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 15 August 1994&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;1. Legacy of hate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Hindus and Muslims must endeavour&lt;br&gt;&#xA;to undo partition&lt;br&gt;&#xA;By K. R. Malkani&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Hindu-Muslim problem is a fact of Indian life. This problem is a&#xA;legacy of the past, particularly that of the recent past, when the&#xA;British gave it a new and dangerous twist, resulting in the partition of&#xA;India. And it is a problem that sours relations, distorts the whole&#xA;Indian polity and acts as a drag on the country. The task of Indian&#xA;statesmanship is to resolve this problem amicably in the light of&#xA;historic experience and the Indian genius of harmonisation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>61 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/61_chv2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/61_chv2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Times of India&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 2 March 1995&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;2. BJP shifts stand to woo Muslims&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;By S.N.M. Abdi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;KISHANGANJ, March 1 - The BJP is wooing the electorate in this&#xA;Muslim-dominated district, 18 km from the Indo-Bangladesh border, by&#xA;inviting Bangladeshis to enter “not in a clandestine manner but through&#xA;the front door”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The change in the BJP’s rigid stand on “infiltration” has given the&#xA;party a foothold in Thakurganj, Bahadurganj and Kishanganj&#xA;constituencies, which go to the polls shortly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>62 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/62_chv3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/62_chv3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Indian Express&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 7 April 1995&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;3. BJP promoting a ‘minority-friendly’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;image for elections&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Express New Service&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;New Delhi - While declaring that liberation of the Varanasi and Mathura&#xA;temples was not on its agenda, the Bharatiya Janata Party has not&#xA;entirely foreclosed the potentially emotional issues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fashioning an ambivalent strategy ahead of the next year’s general&#xA;elections, the BJP after its Panaji session, has sought to don a&#xA;“minority-friendly” image, while insisting that its “basic image will&#xA;stay intact”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>63 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/63_chv4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/63_chv4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Indian Express&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 7th April, 1995&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;4. BJP looks for Muslim plank&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;to move towards Delhi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Ashwini Kumar&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NEW DELHI - The Goa session of the Bharatiya Janata Party’s national&#xA;executive might be seen as a minor milestone in what the party describes&#xA;as its “onward march to Delhi”. The party sent out a signal to its&#xA;cadres to reach out to the Muslims, and acknowledged the community’s&#xA;“very valuable contribution” to its recent success at the polls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>64 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/64_chv5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/64_chv5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Navabharat Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 9 April 1995&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;5. BJP girds up to appease Muslim&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Shrikant Sharma&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NEW DELHI, 8, April.  After BJP clearly announced in Goa that ‘Muslim&#xA;vote’ is no more ‘the forbidden fruit’ in the elections, BJP leaders&#xA;have started making all-out efforts for looking more secular than the&#xA;Congress and, on the other hand, they are out to have some special&#xA;programmes to lure Muslim voters.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this venture of attracting Muslim voters, BJP will depend more upon&#xA;its Muslim rather than its Hindu leaders. It was quite evident in the&#xA;zeal with which Muslim leaders were talking on their way back from Goa.&#xA;While talking to the press, Muslim leaders sent out signals that in the&#xA;forthcoming parliamentary elections they were planning to work with&#xA;quicker paces in this direction. This will include public meetings&#xA;alongwith person-to-person interactions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>65 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/65_chv6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/65_chv6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Sunday Observer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 9-15 April 1995&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;6. Khurana’s go-slow on migrants&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;issue irks hawks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Shubhendu Parth&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NEW DELHI, APRIL, 8 - Delhi Chief Minister Madan Lal Khurana has decided&#xA;to go slow on the issue of deporting illegal Bangladeshi migrants from&#xA;the National Capital Territory [NCT] region, belying expectations that&#xA;his government would take a cue from its counterpart in Maharashtra,&#xA;where his Bharatiya Janata Party is ruling in alliance with the Shiv&#xA;Sena.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>66 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/66_chv7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/66_chv7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Indian Express&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 16 April 1995&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;7. Pampering the minority ego&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Talveen Singh&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are there no limits to what Muslims can demand, and get away with, in&#xA;the imagined cause of their religion? India is not a Muslim country and,&#xA;by the grace of our 30 million gods, never will be. So there is no&#xA;reason why our political leaders should have to start kowtowing and&#xA;running scared everytime a bunch of semi-literate &lt;em&gt;mullahs&lt;/em&gt; gets up and&#xA;starts making a noise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>67 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/67_chv8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/67_chv8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Indian Express&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 21 April 1995&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;8. BJP to bring out Koran in Sanskrit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Sujata Anandan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BOMBAY - The Koran in Sanskrit? The idea is not as bizarre as it may&#xA;sound.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the Bharatiya Janata Party’s spoonful of honey for the Muslim&#xA;minorities in the country as opposed to their earlier acerbic rhetoric&#xA;that the party has been finding hard to live down since the demolition&#xA;of the Babri Masjid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>68 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/68_chv9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/68_chv9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Times of India&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 22 April 1995&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;9. Vajpayee for diluting stand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;on ‘Hindutva’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BOMBAY, APRIL 21 - Leader of Opposition in the Lok Sabha Atal Behari&#xA;Vajpayee has urged toning down of the Hindutva stand of the BJP to avoid&#xA;alienating Muslims.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Muslims had supported the party in large numbers in the recent assembly&#xA;elections. He is understood to have told a closed door national level&#xA;conclave of the party at Virar in Thane district.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>69 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/69_chv10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/69_chv10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Times of India&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 29 April, 1995&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;10. More Space for ‘namaaz’ urged&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;By Vidyadhar Date&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BOMBAY, April 28.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some leaders of the Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) in Maharashtra have&#xA;proposed that the floor space index (FSI) for mosques in Bombay be&#xA;increased to accommodate a larger number of people offering &lt;em&gt;namaaz&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;(prayers). This would also help end offering of prayers on the roads&#xA;outside mosques.*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The offering of &lt;em&gt;namaaz&lt;/em&gt; on roads had caused considerable tension in&#xA;Bombay two years ago with the Shiv Sena and the BJP voicing strong&#xA;protests and organising &lt;em&gt;maha artis&lt;/em&gt; on the roads.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>70 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/70_chv11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/70_chv11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Indian Express&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 12 July 1995&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;11. Chhabildas sticks to his guns&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;on minority votes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Deepak Trivedi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GANDHINAGAR - Former Gujarat Chief Minister Chhabildas Mehta has called&#xA;for drastic measures by the Congress to win back majority support which,&#xA;he claims, was lost in the search for minority votes. This, he said,&#xA;should be done after washing away the impression from the majority that&#xA;the Congress was interested only in the minority.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>71 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/71_chv12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/71_chv12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hindustan Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 4 June 1995&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;12. Advani allays minorities fears&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;HT Correspondent&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NEW DELHI, June 3 - In his first wide-ranging television interview on&#xA;the attitude and policies of the BJP if it were to form a government&#xA;after the next elections, Mr. L.K. Advani has said that it will be his&#xA;responsibility to allay the fears of the minorities. Predicting better&#xA;relations with Pakistan, the BJP President also promised a tougher&#xA;Kashmir policy “without kid gloves”. Mr. Advani promised to abrogate&#xA;Article 370 “as swiftly as rapidly as possible” and said his government&#xA;would revoke any political concession made to Kashmir along the lines of&#xA;Prime Minister Rao’s recent statement in the Lok Sabha. But the BJP&#xA;president went out of his way to remove doubts created by his senior&#xA;party members regarding the BJP’s attitude to foreign investment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>72 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/72_chv13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/72_chv13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Indian Express&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 27 July 1995&lt;br&gt;&#xA;‘One country, one people’&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;13. Secret of BJP’s success&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;K.R. Malkani&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Only a year ago when the BJP did not get as many seats in UP, MP and&#xA;Himachal Pradesh as expected, many people thought that the party had&#xA;passed its peak. Not many of them paused to consider that even in its&#xA;reduced state the party had polled one crore votes more - and won a&#xA;hundred seats more - than the Congress. And so now the same people find&#xA;that the party has not only peaked higher than ever before, it is poised&#xA;to attain even bigger heights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>73 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/73_chv14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/73_chv14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hindustan Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 24 August 1995&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;14. Advani woos Indian expatriates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;in London, assails Govt’s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Kashmir policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;By L.K. Sharma&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LONDON, August 23 - Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) president L.K. Advani&#xA;criticised the Rao government’s Kashmir policy, promised a tougher&#xA;approach if his party came to power and urged the Indian community in&#xA;Britain to counter the lobbying by the Pakistanis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He sought to mobilise the Indian community at a meeting organised by the&#xA;“Overseas Friends of the BJP” and said that there could be no dialogue&#xA;with terrorists. A BJP government would “scrap Kashmir’s constitutional&#xA;status and recover the third of the state’s territory under illegal&#xA;Pakistani occupation.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>74 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/74_chv15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/74_chv15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Times of India&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 16 October, 1995&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;15. BJP bid to woo Muslims&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The Times of India News Service&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ALIGARH, October 15 - The BJP today kicked off its pre-election campaign&#xA;to woo Muslim voters by promising to provide a “riot-free India in which&#xA;human rights of all sections would be protected”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Addressing the first state convention of the newly-formed minority front&#xA;of the BJP, former national president of the party Murli Manohar Joshi&#xA;urged Muslims to take a “fresh look” at the BJP, if they wished to&#xA;escape from the clutches of the Congress, which he alleged had been&#xA;“exploiting them over the past several decades”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>75 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/75_chv16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/75_chv16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Sunday Observer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, November 19-25, 1995&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;16. ‘How can any Muslim in this&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;country say that he does&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;not respect Ram?’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(We reproduce some of the questions and answers in an interview given by&#xA;Dr. Murli Manohar Joshi in Bombay to two journalists from the weekly,&#xA;Rajeev D. Pai and Firdaus Ashraf, on 13 November 1995.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why has the BJP now relegated the temple issue to the backburner?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It’s there. It’s in our manifesto.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>76 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/76_chv17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/76_chv17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Indian Express&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 21 November 1995&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;17. Malhotra’s statement on&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Ayodhya annoys Chavan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Express News Service&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NEW DELHI, November 20 - The demolition of the disputed Ayodhya&#xA;structure once again created ripples in the meeting of Parliament’s&#xA;Consultative Committee attached to the Home Ministry here today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Bharatiya Janata Party MP, Mr. Vijay Kumar Malhotra, asserted that&#xA;he regarded the demolition of the disputed structure as a matter of&#xA;national pride. This elicited a sharp, albeit belated, reaction from the&#xA;Home Minister, Mr. S.B. Chavan, who warned that if some forces were&#xA;determined to say that they took pride in the demolition of religious&#xA;places, the Government was equally determined to see that these forces&#xA;did not succeed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>77 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/77_chv18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/77_chv18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hindustan Times,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 16 August 1996&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;18. BJP bid to win over Muslims&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;From Gautam Chaudhuri&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CALCUTTA, Aug. 15 - Desperately seeking ways to make inroads into the&#xA;minority vote bank in Uttar Pradesh, the BJP has set up a core group of&#xA;six Muslim leaders, who have been asked to concentrate on the minority&#xA;pockets in UP before the forthcoming Assembly elections, in order to woo&#xA;the Muslims to give bigger support to the BJP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>78 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/78_chv19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/78_chv19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Sunday Observer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 18-24 August 1996&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;19. RSS wants Muslims for friends&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;DEEPALI NANDWANI&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The fiery Rashtriya Swayamsevak Sangh is on a friendship mission. And&#xA;the target is none other than its ‘erstwhile enemy’, the Muslim&#xA;community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The RSS functionaries, sources say, are now meeting Muslim leaders to&#xA;‘get itself rid of the fascist tag’ - just last week the top brass led&#xA;by deputy general secretary K.S. Sudarshan conducted heart-to-heart&#xA;talks with the Muslim leaders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>79 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/79_chv20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/79_chv20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hindustan Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 19 August 1996&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;20. Babri or “Barabari”?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sudheendra Kulkarni on Muslims’ choice&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two Prime Ministers, one present and the other his immediate&#xA;predecessor, have last week made statements about Indian Muslims which,&#xA;despite the sharp differences in their political ideologies, reveal a&#xA;remarkable commonality of observation. H.D. Deve Gowda, in an interview&#xA;given to a major Hindi daily, has stated that “the socio-economic&#xA;conditions of Muslims in some parts of the country are worse than those&#xA;of Dalits.” Earlier in the week, addressing a meeting of the Minorities&#xA;Morcha of the BJP in the Capital, Atal Behari Vajpayee observed that the&#xA;real issue before Indian Muslims was “not Babri but &lt;em&gt;Barabari&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;(equality).^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;)” Implicit in this remark is the admission that a&#xA;majority of Muslims in India are, indeed, victims of inequity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>80 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/80_chv21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/80_chv21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hindustan Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 31 August 1996&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;21. Bihar BJP’s first-ever Muslim&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;leader emerges&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;HT Correspondent&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PATNA, Aug. 30 - A growing realisation in the BJP that the support of&#xA;the minorities may prove crucial to its hopes of ruling the country&#xA;appears to have set the stage for the emergence of the party’s&#xA;first-ever top ranking Muslim leader in Bihar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If things work out to a plan, Prof. Azfar Shamshi - State chief of the&#xA;party’s Minority Front for the past three years - may soon be rubbing&#xA;shoulders with the top brass of the Bihar BJP. Already, the party&#xA;leadership has been sending out signals that it rates the ‘ideologically&#xA;correct’ professor rather highly and has high hopes of him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>81 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/81_chv22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/81_chv22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Indian Express&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 25 September 1996&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;22. J.K. Hindu exiles eulogise Thackeray&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;BY SUJATA ANANDAN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MUMBAI, Sept. 24: As the Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) attempts to shrug&#xA;off the Shiv Sena, which in recent days has become an albatross round&#xA;its neck, it might find that it is losing ground to its ally where&#xA;matters relating to the Hindu heart are concerned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The BJP’s dilly-dallying over hardcore Hindutva issues has already&#xA;earned it the ridicule of the extreme right of the Hindu fundamentalist&#xA;forces. With the Sena all set to dent its vote bank in Uttar Pradesh,&#xA;their latest support base to be plundered is that of Kashmiri Hindus in&#xA;exile.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>82 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/82_chv23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/82_chv23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Navabharat Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 17 November 1996&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;23. Secularism is the very colour&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;of our blood: Vajpayee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Pankaj Sharma&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JAIPUR: BJP’s imminent strategy is going to be crystal clear now. Days&#xA;to come would give the BJP a secular-socialist colour. BJP’s top&#xA;leadership at a Jaipur meeting decided that initiatives would have to be&#xA;taken to bring the Muslim community close to it at all costs, that a&#xA;movement would have to be launched to fight corruption at every level,&#xA;that the poor’s welfare oriented economic policies would have to be&#xA;forcefully advocated, that a movement would have to be launched against&#xA;foreign companies, and that a fight to the finish would have to be&#xA;started against the forces retarding BJP’s march to power.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>83 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/83_chv24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/83_chv24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hindustan Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 10 February 1997&lt;br&gt;&#xA;LETTERS&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;24. A good augury&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sir, - It is heartening to note that the Bharatiya Janata Party, of&#xA;late, has realised its folly of isolating Muslims. In Kerala it is&#xA;organising meetings in which intellectuals of both the communities&#xA;exchange their views so as to remove the misunderstandings and&#xA;misconceptions between them. In these conclaves, efforts are made to&#xA;cultivate and establish healthy relationship between the two&#xA;communities. It has also been reported in newspapers that in a number of&#xA;districts in Kerala Muslims have not only joined the BJP but have been&#xA;given berth in the party’s executive committees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>84 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/84_chv25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/84_chv25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Times of India&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Mumbai, 2 March 1997&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;25. Muslims in Behrampada voted&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;in a pragmatic way&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;By Anil Singh&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MUMBAI: Simply put, it was gutter-level politics, quite literally, which&#xA;helped the Shiv Sena win the civic seat from Behrampada. The Sena was&#xA;the only party which got the drains cleaned and had toilets built for&#xA;the women of this Muslim-dominated slum in Bandra east.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apart from their work in the area, a host of other factors went into&#xA;ensuring the Sena’s victory in the slum which witnessed some of the&#xA;bloodiest communal riots in December 1992-January 1993.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>85 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/85_chv26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/85_chv26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;THE INDIAN EXPRESS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 9 March 1997&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;26. Joshi sparks off row&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;over Religion Bill&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;PRANATI MEHRA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MUMBAI, MARCH 8 - Chief Minister Manohar Joshi’s assurance to a&#xA;delegation of Catholic leaders, last month, has surprised Mangalprabhat&#xA;Lodha, BJP MLA from Malabar Hill.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The issue is the Maharashtra Freedom of Religion Bill, introduced by&#xA;Lodha as a private member’s Bill in the last Assembly session at Nagpur.&#xA;The Bill seeks to make the use of force or allurement for religious&#xA;conversion a cognisable offence in the State.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>86 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/86_chv27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/86_chv27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Statesman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 29 March 1997&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;27. VHP drops plan to ‘liberate’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Kashi, Mathura&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;MORAN SAHAY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AYODHYA.  March 28 - The Vishwa Hindu Parishad in a major policy shift&#xA;has dropped its “Direct action Plan” to “liberate” Kashi and Mathura.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the three-day in-camera proceedings of the VHP which concluded at&#xA;Karsevakpuram here today, the front ranking leaders of the parishad&#xA;abandoned programmes to launch movement to “liberate” the two shrines by&#xA;taking possession of the Gyanvapi Mosque in Varanasi and the Shahi&#xA;Mosque in Mathura which they consider encroachment upon the Lord&#xA;Vishwanath Temple and Sri Krishna Janmabhoomi Temple respectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>87 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/87_chv28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/87_chv28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hindustan Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 1 May 1997&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;28. Govt seeks revision of&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;order on Naib Imam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;HT Correspondent&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NEW DELHI, April 30 - The Delhi Government filed a petition in the Delhi&#xA;High Court seeking revision of a court order refusing permission to the&#xA;Government to drop sedition charges against Naib Iman of Jama Masjid&#xA;Syed Ahmed Bukhari.^(&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mr Justice J.K. Mehra issued notice to the respondents, Naib Imam&#xA;Bukhari and the Court of Metropolitan Magistrate and posted the matter&#xA;for hearing on May 7.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>88 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/88_chv29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/88_chv29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hindustan Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 6 June 1997&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;29. BJYM’S meet on June 7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;HT Correspondent&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NEW DELHI, June 5 - The Bharatiya Janata Yuva Morcha (BJYM), the youth&#xA;wing of the BJP, will organise a conference of the Muslim youth to mark&#xA;the golden Jubilee celebrations of the independence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Addressing a joint Press conference here today, BJYM’s all India general&#xA;secretary Shahnawaz Hussain and Delhi unit president Begraj Kathana,&#xA;said that conference at national level will be held here on June 7. It&#xA;will be presided over by Ms Uma Bharati. Prominent leaders, who will&#xA;also address the conference, include Mr Sikander Bakht, MP and Mr&#xA;Krishan Lal Sharma, MP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>89 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/89_chv30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/89_chv30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Indian Express&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi, 8 June 1997&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;30. Vande Mataram ‘dispute’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;at BJP Muslim meeting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Express News Service&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NEW DELHI, JUNE 7 - A MISUNDERSTANDING between firebrand BJP leader Uma&#xA;Bharati and her senior Sikander Bakht over &lt;em&gt;“Vande Mataram”&lt;/em&gt; created a&#xA;flutter at the National Muslim Youth Convention organised by the&#xA;Bharatiya Janata Yuva Morcha here today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a departure from BJP tradition, the convention did not begin with the&#xA;national song, inviting Bakht’s wrath. Chiding the Muslim community for&#xA;what he called its well-known objections to &lt;em&gt;Vande Mataram&lt;/em&gt;, the BJP&#xA;leader told the gathering that he was “ashamed” by this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>90 II</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/90_appi1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/90_appi1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Tabligh Movement or Millions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;of Bearded Militants on the March&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sita Ram Goel&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Sarva Panth Samãdar Manch is supposed to work for national&#xA;integration. One wonders, however, if Dattopant Thengdi or any other&#xA;stalwart of the Sangh Parivar cared to find out who Maulana Wahiduddin&#xA;Khan was and what he stood for before they invited him to “sanctify” the&#xA;Samadhi of Dr. Hedgewar by his “august” presence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Maulana Wahiduddin, currently the director of the Islamic Center,&#xA;Delhi, resigned from a prominent position in the Jammat-i-Islami of&#xA;India in 1960.”&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;¹&lt;/a&gt; We shall take up the Jamaat-i-Islami at a later&#xA;stage in this chapter. We have to take up the Tablighi Jammat first&#xA;because it prepares the ground for the Jamaat-i-Islami or in other words&#xA;the Jamaat-i-Islami takes over from where the Tablighi Jamaat leaves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>91  Table 1.1: Population in West Bengal 1941-91</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/91_appii1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/rss/articles/Stock_taking_of_sangh_parivAr/91_appii1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Population Explosion in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;West Bengal: A Survey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(A Study by South Asia Research Society, Calcutta)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On account of the Partition of the Indian subcontinent in 1947, refugees&#xA;moved from Pakistan, without much interruption, to various parts of&#xA;India, especially to West Bengal, till 1971, when political boundaries&#xA;in South Asia were redrawn. Even after the emergence of Bangladesh as an&#xA;independent country in 1971, however, the march of refugees to West&#xA;Bengal appeared to be ceaseless. Nevertheless, there is one great&#xA;difference in the patterns of migration before and after 1971. In the&#xA;days of Pakistan, nearly all refugees coming to West Bengal were members&#xA;of the minority communities in East Bengal (East Pakistan), viz.&#xA;Buddhists, Christians and Hindus. In the Bangladesh era, however, in&#xA;addition to the forced migration of members of minority community (the&#xA;overwhelming majority being Hindus) to West Bengal, there has been&#xA;largescale voluntary infiltration of Bangladeshi Muslims (forming the&#xA;majority community in that country) to West Bengal and other parts of&#xA;India. Certainly, the Government of India and the Government of West&#xA;Bengal are not unaware of this grim phenomenon. Occasionally, the Home&#xA;Minister of the Government of India and the Chief Minister of West&#xA;Bengal have expressed serious concern over this problem. This brief&#xA;survey - its brevity attributable to the barrier of needless secrecy&#xA;against the free flow of census data (unexpected in a democratic country&#xA;like India) - aims at unraveling the mystery of population explosion in&#xA;a progressive state like West Bengal, as also at arousing the&#xA;consciousness of the public about the factor of migration /infiltration&#xA;underlying this explosion, which cannot but pose a mounting challenge to&#xA;vital national interests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
