<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;27 The Apostles A D 30-95 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/27_The_Apostles_A_D_30-95/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;27 The Apostles A D 30-95 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/27_The_Apostles_A_D_30-95/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 PETER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/27_The_Apostles_A_D_30-95/01_PETER/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/27_The_Apostles_A_D_30-95/01_PETER/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHRISTIANITY arose out of Jewish apocalyptic—esoteric revelations of the coming Kingdom; it derived its impetus from the personality and vision of Christ; it gained strength from the belief in his resurrection, and the promise of eternal life; it received doctrinal form in the theology of Paul; it grew by the absorption of pagan faith and ritual; it became a triumphant Church by inheriting the organizing patterns and genius of Rome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 PAUL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/27_The_Apostles_A_D_30-95/02_PAUL/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/27_The_Apostles_A_D_30-95/02_PAUL/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-the-persecutor&#34;&gt;1. The Persecutor&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The founder of Christian theology was born at Tarsus, in Cilicia, about the tenth year of our era. His father was a Pharisee, and brought up the youth in the fervent principles of that sect; the Apostle of the Gentiles never ceased to consider himself a Pharisee, even after he had rejected the Judaic Law. The father was also a Roman citizen, and transmitted the precious franchise to his son. Probably the name Paul was the Greek equivalent of the Hebrew Saul, so that both names belonged to the apostle from infancy.22 He did not receive a classical education, for no Pharisee would have permitted such outright Hellenism in his son, and no man with Greek training would have written the bad Greek of the Epistles. Nevertheless, he learned to speak the language with sufficient fluency to address an Athenian audience, and he occasionally referred to famous passages in Greek literature. We may believe that some Stoic theology and ethics passed from the university environment of Tarsus into the Christianity of Paul. So he uses the Stoic term &lt;em&gt;pneuma&lt;/em&gt; (breath) for what his English translators call spirit. Like most Greek cities, Tarsus had followers of the Orphic or other mystery religions, who believed that the god they worshiped had died for them, had risen from the grave, and would, if appealed to by lively faith and proper ritual, save them from Hades, and share with them his gift of eternal and blessed life.23 The mystery religions prepared the Greeks for Paul, and Paul for the Greeks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 JOHN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/27_The_Apostles_A_D_30-95/03_JOHN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/27_The_Apostles_A_D_30-95/03_JOHN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The accidents of history have transmitted Paul to us in comparative clarity, and have left the apostle John in obscurity and mystery. Besides three epistles, two major works have come down to us under his name. Criticism tentatively assigns the Book of Revelation to the year 69-70,72 and to another John, “the Presbyter” mentioned by Papias (135).73 Justin Martyr (135) attributes this powerful Apocalypse to the “beloved” apostle;74 but as early as the fourth century Eusebius75 noted that some scholars doubted its authenticity. The author must have been a man of considerable prominence, for he addresses the churches of Asia in a tone of menacing authority. If the apostle wrote it (and we may provisionally continue to think so), we can understand why, like his brother James, he was called &lt;em&gt;Boanerges,&lt;/em&gt; Son of Thunder. In Ephesus, Smyrna, Pergamum, Sardis, and other cities of Asia Minor, John, rather than Peter or Paul, was looked upon as the highest head of the Church. Tradition as reported by Eusebius76 held that John had been banished to Patmos by Domitian, and had on that Aegean isle written both the Fourth Gospel and the Apocalypse. He lived to so great an age that people said he would never die.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
