<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;08 Literature Under the Revolution 145-30 B C on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/08_Literature_Under_the_Revolution_145-30_B_C/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;08 Literature Under the Revolution 145-30 B C on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/08_Literature_Under_the_Revolution_145-30_B_C/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 LUCRETIUS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/08_Literature_Under_the_Revolution_145-30_B_C/01_LUCRETIUS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/08_Literature_Under_the_Revolution_145-30_B_C/01_LUCRETIUS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AMID this turbulent transformation of economy, government, and morals, literature was not forgotten, and did not quite escape the fever and stimulus of the age. Varro and Nepos found safety in antiquarian scholarship or historical research; Sallust retired from his campaigns to defend his party and disguise his morals with brilliant monographs; Caesar stooped from empire to grammar and continued his wars in his &lt;em&gt;Commentaries;&lt;/em&gt; Catullus and Calvus sought refuge from politics in the pursuit and poetry of love; timid and sensitive spirits like Lucretius hid themselves in the gardens of philosophy; and Cicero retreated now and then from the heat of the Forum to cool his blood with books. But not one of them found peace. War and revolution touched them with pervasive infection; and even Lucretius must have known the restlessness which he describes:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 DE RERUM NATURA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/08_Literature_Under_the_Revolution_145-30_B_C/02_DE_RERUM_NATURA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/08_Literature_Under_the_Revolution_145-30_B_C/02_DE_RERUM_NATURA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If we try to reduce to some logical form the passionate disorder of Lucretius’ argument, his initial thesis lies in a famous line:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tantum-religio-potuit-suadere-malorum&#34;&gt;Tantum religio potuit suadere malorum—&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“to so many evils religion has persuaded men.”6 He tells the story of Iphigenia in Aulis, of countless human sacrifices, of hecatombs offered to gods conceived in the image of man’s greed; he recalls the terror of simplicity and youth lost in a jungle of vengeful deities, the fear of lightning and thunder, of death and Hell, and the subterranean horrors pictured in Etruscan art and Oriental mysteries. He reproaches mankind for preferring sacrificial ritual to philosophical understanding:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 LESBIA’S LOVER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/08_Literature_Under_the_Revolution_145-30_B_C/03_LESBIAS_LOVER/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/08_Literature_Under_the_Revolution_145-30_B_C/03_LESBIAS_LOVER/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 57 B.C.. the Caius Memmius to whom Lucretius dedicated his poem left Rome to serve as propraetor in Bithynia. After the growing custom of Roman governors he took with him an author—not Lucretius, but a poet different from the other in everything but the strength of his passion. Quintus (or Caius) Valerius Catullus had come to Rome some five years before from his native Verona, where his father was of sufficient standing to be frequent host to Caesar. Quintus himself must have had a substantial competence, for he owned villas near Tibur and on Lake Garda and had an elegant house in Rome. He speaks of these properties as choked with mortgages, and repeatedly proclaims his poverty; but the picture we form of him from his poems is that of a polished man of the world who did not bother to earn a living, but enjoyed himself unstintingly among the wilder set in the capital. The keenest wits, the cleverest young orators and politicians belonged to this circle: Marcus Caelius, the impecunious aristocrat who was to become a communist; Licinius Calvus, brilliant in poetry and in law; and Helvius Cinna, a poet whom Antony’s mob would mistake for one of Caesar’s assassins and beat to death. These men opposed Caesar with every epigram at their disposal, unaware that their literary revolt reflected the revolution in which they lived. They were tired of old forms in literature, of the crudity and bombast of Naevius and Ennius; they wished to sing the sentiments of youth in new and lyric meters, and with a refinement and delicacy of execution known once in the Alexandria of Callimachus, but never yet seen in Rome. And they were resentful of old morals, of the &lt;em&gt;mos maiorum&lt;/em&gt; perpetually preached upon them by their exhausted elders; they announced the sanctity of instinct, the innocence of desire, and the grandeur of dissipation. They and Catullus were no worse than other young literary blades of their generation and the next; Horace, Ovid, Tibullus, Propertius, even the shy Virgil in his youth, made life and verse revolve around any woman, married or not, who fed their muses with facile casual love.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 THE SCHOLARS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/08_Literature_Under_the_Revolution_145-30_B_C/04_THE_SCHOLARS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/08_Literature_Under_the_Revolution_145-30_B_C/04_THE_SCHOLARS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How were Latin books written, illustrated, bound, published, sold? For school exercises, short letters, transient commercial records, the Romans through antiquity wrote with a stylus upon waxed tablets and erased with the thumb. The oldest literary Latin known to us was written with quill and ink upon paper manufactured in Egypt from the pressed and glued leaves of the papyrus tree. In the first centuries of our era parchment made from the dried skins of animals began to rival papyrus as a receptacle of literature and important documents. A folded sheet of membrane, or &lt;em&gt;vellum,&lt;/em&gt; constituted a &lt;em&gt;diploma,&lt;/em&gt; or twofold. Usually a literary work was issued as a roll &lt;em&gt;(volumen,&lt;/em&gt; “wound up”), and was read by unrolling as the reading progressed. The text was customarily written two or three narrow &lt;em&gt;columnae&lt;/em&gt; to a page, often without punctuation of clauses or even separation of words. Some manuscripts were illustrated by ink drawings; Varro’s &lt;em&gt;Imagines,&lt;/em&gt; e.g., consisted of 700 portraits of famous men, each picture accompanied by a biographical note. Anyone could publish a manuscript by hiring slaves to make copies, and selling the copies. Rich men had clerks who copied for them any book they wished to own. Since copyists were fed rather than paid, books were cheap. First “printings” were usually of a thousand copies. Booksellers bought wholesale from publishers like Atticus, and sold at retail in arcade bookstalls. Neither publisher nor bookseller gave the author anything except courtesy and occasional gifts; royalties were unknown. Private libraries were now numerous; and about 40 B.C. Asinius Pollio made his great collection the first public library in Rome. Caesar planned a still larger one, and made Varro its director; but this, like so many of his ideas, waited upon Augustus for its fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 CICERO’S PEN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/08_Literature_Under_the_Revolution_145-30_B_C/05_CICEROS_PEN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/2_THE_REVOLUTION_145-30_B_C/08_Literature_Under_the_Revolution_145-30_B_C/05_CICEROS_PEN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Proud of his speeches, and aware that they were making literature, Cicero felt keenly the criticism of the “Attic” school, and defended himself in a long series of treatises on oratorical art. In lively dialogues he sketched the history of Roman eloquence and laid down the rules for composition, prose rhythm, and delivery. He did not admit that his own style was “Asian”; he had modeled it, he claimed, upon that of Demosthenes; and he reminded the Atticists that their cold and passionless speech drove audiences to sleep or flight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
