<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Post coal on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/post-coal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Post coal on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/post-coal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jevons on coal</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/post-coal/jevons_coal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/post-coal/jevons_coal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jevons Coal Question was about &lt;em&gt;British coal extraction&lt;/em&gt; (peaked in 1913) &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;Britain&amp;rsquo;s supremacy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jevons got wrong was in underestimating the incipient oil industry, he couldn&amp;rsquo;t have known that Britain would 1 day find North Sea oil (now in terminal decline)&#xA;Jevons wasn&amp;rsquo;t unique, similar concerns were expressed by William Armstrong (the famous arms maker), Louis Simonin, Alfred Russell Wallace (co-discoverer of evolution) who wrote against exporting coal &amp;amp; any man who understood basic geology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>London coal 1700</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/post-coal/london-coal-1700/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/post-coal/london-coal-1700/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.journal18.org/issue15/restorations-coal-smoke-and-time-in-london-circa-1700/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Restorations: Coal, Smoke, and Time in London, circa 1700&#xA;Aleksandr Bierig&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Early modern London was the planet’s first coal-fired city.+++(5)+++&#xA;While the causes and timing of its transition to fossil fuel are still debated,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;historians have argued that the change was initially triggered in the early seventeenth century,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;when apparent timber shortages began driving up firewood prices in the metropolis.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;At the same time, the chance existence of waterways near the coalfields of Durham and Northumberland, three hundred miles north of London,+++(5)+++&lt;br&gt;&#xA;afforded the possibility of shipping fossil fuel along the eastern English seaboard during a period of highly constrained transportation.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;While coal had been extracted from these areas for centuries,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;its scale was always limited;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;coal remained a specialty fuel,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;considered appropriate only for heat-intensive activities like firing limekilns or blacksmithing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Owen, Williams, Jevons on coal</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/post-coal/owen_williams_jevons_on_coal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/post-coal/owen_williams_jevons_on_coal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2694975&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Almost from the beginning of the industry, it would seem, fears have been anxiously expressed that one day (and possibly one day quite soon) the coal would run out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;owen&#34;&gt;Owen&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1603, George Owen, author of a Description of Pembrokeshire, remarked that ‘the Countrie people’ feared that the export of coal ‘in time [would] wholely weare out the Coale and so leave the Countrie destitute of fuell’.75&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;williams&#34;&gt;Williams&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The earliest writer to have given the topic more than a passing comment appears to be John Williams, a Scottish mineral surveyor, whose Natural History of the Mineral Kingdom was published in 1789.76&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peel on coal 1838</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/post-coal/peel_on_coal_1838/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/post-coal/peel_on_coal_1838/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/books/edition/The_Opinions_of_the_Right_Hon_Sir_Robert/7qlPAAAAcAAJ?hl=en&amp;amp;gbpv=1&amp;amp;dq=robert+peel+a+period+of+400+or+500+years&amp;amp;pg=PA441&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sea-coal-duty-reduction&#34;&gt;Sea coal duty reduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;COALS.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If it were clearly established that there was a surplus revenue, and that a remission of taxation could properly be made, I know of no duty which I should be more forward to repeal than the tax on sea-borne coals. I know of no one measure which could produce greater benefit, physical and moral, to the poorer classes, than that which would facilitate their obtaining a sufficient supply of coals at a moderate price.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rooke 1612</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/post-coal/rooke_1612/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/post-coal/rooke_1612/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People claimed coal grows back in 1600&amp;rsquo;s England but Rooke Church in his 1612 text &amp;ldquo;An olde thrift newly revived&amp;rdquo; was already writing on the need for tree planting to plan for when coal is gone&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For if Coale should faile&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(as it is too apparant it beginneth to grow deere and scarce,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and in many places there is none to be had)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;how then should we doe for this materiall of fuell?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;for doe we thinke that wood alone&lt;br&gt;&#xA;can beare the brunt to satisfie every mans chimney?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;assuredly now, except it were more plentifull.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Then must there needs be some speedy means used&lt;br&gt;&#xA;for prevention of felling whole woods of timber,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and grubbing up of Copies&lt;br&gt;&#xA;at pleasure to convert them into pasture, arrable, or meadow grounds,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;else in short time, this waste and scarcitie will grow to a consummation of the whole.35&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Williams on coal</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/post-coal/williams_on_coal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/post-coal/williams_on_coal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Natural History of the Mineral Kingdom (1789), John Williams&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When our coal mines are exhausted, the prosperity and glory of this flourishing and fortunate island are at an end. Our cities and great towns must then become ruinous heaps for want of fuel, and our mines and manufactories must fail from the same cause, and then consequently our commerce must vanish. In short, the commerce, wealth, importance, glory, and happiness of Great Britain will decay and gradually dwindle to nothing, in proportion as our coal and other mines fail; and the future inhabitants of this island must live, like its first inhabitants, by fishing and hunting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
