<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Health on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Health on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blood vessels</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/blood_vessels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/blood_vessels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chemical-determinants&#34;&gt;Chemical determinants&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;cholesterol&#34;&gt;Cholesterol&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One important determinant of blood vessel health is cholesterol levels, with the LDL subtype of cholesterol being bad for your arteries and HDL being good. Smoking reduces HDL.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;lipid-profile&#34;&gt;Lipid profile&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some use TG/HDL ratio - &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/mindmusclepro/status/1669254306409873408&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;apolipoprotein-b&#34;&gt;Apolipoprotein B&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Relying on LDL is deprecated as a biomarker for pharmaceutical intervention for lowering blood lipids. Apolipoprotein B is the atherogenic particle - hence marker of concern. If ApoB is high, take a statin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Death causes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/death_causes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/death_causes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Consider the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.healthmap.org/en&#34;&gt;health map&lt;/a&gt; to track epidemics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;temperate-leukosphere&#34;&gt;Temperate Leukosphere&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Leading causes of death in developing countries according to [&lt;a href=&#34;http://ucatlas.ucsc.edu/cause.php&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt;]:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HIV/AIDS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lower respiratory infections&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ischaemic heart disease&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;usa&#34;&gt;USA&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most common conventional causes of death in the USA, according to &lt;a href=&#34;http://danger.mongabay.com/causes_of_death_percent.htm&#34;&gt;[Ref]&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heart disease : 30%.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cancer: 24%.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stroke, respiratory diseases and accidents contribute around 5% each.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;heart-disease&#34;&gt;Heart disease&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;12.6 percent of deaths worldwide were from ischemic heart disease. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.who.int/entity/whr/2004/en/report04_en.pdf&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt;] Ischemic heart disease is the leading cause of death in developed countries, but third to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AIDS&#34; title=&#34;AIDS&#34;&gt;AIDS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lower_respiratory_infection&#34; title=&#34;Lower respiratory infection&#34;&gt;lower respiratory infections&lt;/a&gt; in developing countries. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://ucatlas.ucsc.edu/cause.php&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heart attack rates are higher in association with intense exertion, be it &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stress_%28psychology%29&#34; title=&#34;Stress (psychology)&#34;&gt;psychological stress&lt;/a&gt; or physical exertion, especially if the exertion is more intense than the individual usually performs. Quantitatively, the period of intense exercise and subsequent recovery is associated with about a 6-fold higher myocardial infarction rate (compared with other more relaxed time frames) for people who are physically very fit. For those in poor physical condition, the rate differential is over 35-fold higher. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://circ.ahajournals.org/cgi/reprint/97/18/1837.pdf&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;diabetes&#34;&gt;Diabetes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are numerous theories as to the exact cause and mechanism for diabetes related insulin resistance, but &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Central_obesity&#34; title=&#34;Central obesity&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;central obesity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (fat concentrated around the waist in relation to abdominal organs, and not subcutaneous fat, it seems) is known to predispose individuals for insulin resistance, possibly due to its secretion of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adipokine&#34; title=&#34;Adipokine&#34;&gt;adipokines&lt;/a&gt; (a group of hormones) that impair glucose tolerance. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diabetes_mellitus_type_2&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt;]&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Many Asian people, particularly South Asians, are also more prone to abdominal obesity, the study noted. Skinny people with thick middles are particularly prone to developing Type II Diabetes, which helps explain why the disease is spreading in places where people are, on average, quite thin. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.time.com/time/world/article/0,8599,1902100,00.html?xid=rss-world&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cancers&#34;&gt;Cancers&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Several cancers that are extremely common in the United States— &lt;strong&gt;colon, prostate and breast cancer&lt;/strong&gt; —are relatively rare in other parts of the world, occurring only 1/10th or 1/20th as often. &amp;hellip; Even if people in other parts of the world stay put, but adopt a U.S. lifestyle, their risk of cancer rises; as Japanese have embraced Western habits, their rates of colon, breast and prostate cancer have skyrocketed. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newsweek.com/id/141495/page/1&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About a third of the twelve most common cancers worldwide are due to nine potentially modifiable risk factors. Men with cancer are twice as likely as women to have a modifiable risk factor for their disease. The nine risk factors are tobacco smoking, excessive alcohol use, diet low in fruit and vegetables, limited physical exercise, human papillomavirus infection (unsafe sex), urban air pollution, domestic use of solid fuels, and contaminated injections (hepatitis B and C). [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140673605677252/fulltext&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;infection&#34;&gt;Infection:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The levels of potentially harmful waterborne microorganisms in rivers, lakes and other recreational waterways may be highest when the water is most crowded with swimmers. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2007/07/070702145113.htm&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;More than one in four train commuters in UK has bacteria from faeces on their hands. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/health/7667499.stm&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Close to 300 cases of tick-borne disease were confirmed in Washington from 1989 to 2000. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.doh.wa.gov/ehp/TS/Zoo/WATickDiseases.htm&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;std-s&#34;&gt;STD-s&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;STD&amp;rsquo;s are the most common infectious diseases. Top three infections among these are chlamydia, gonorrhea and AIDS. It found that nearly half of the African-American girls surveyed had at least one STD, the rate was 20% among white and Mexican-American teenagers. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/americas/7290088.stm&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;accidents&#34;&gt;Accidents:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After 10 pm one in five drivers is under the influence of something or other &amp;ndash; and after 2 am it&amp;rsquo;s one in four. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://marriage.about.com/b/a/053340.htm&#34;&gt;Weak Ref&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fertility</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/fertility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/fertility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;age&#34;&gt;Age&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A study published in the Archives of General Psychiatry reveals that men over 40 are six times more likely to father a child with autism than men aged 15 to 29. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smart-kit.com/s143/dont-wait-too-long-to-father-children/&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A French study of over 12,200 couples having fertility treatment suggests the chance of a successful pregnancy falls when the man is aged over 35. It adds that the chance is significantly lower if he is over 40. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/health/7492323.stm&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt;]  The heaviest men had a higher proportion of abnormal sperm, as well as other problems. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/health/7494777.stm&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surgery</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/surgery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;downsides&#34;&gt;Downsides&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Invasive surgery can cause more harm than good - and should be elected with care.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;examples&#34;&gt;Examples&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An artificial knee may get infected, leading to pus discharge, swelling and pain. Immune system cells have a harder time getting there and cleaning up.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Myopes considering &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Refractive_surgery&#34; title=&#34;Refractive surgery&#34;&gt;refractive surgery&lt;/a&gt; are advised that surgically correcting their nearsightedness may actually be a disadvantage after the age of 40 when the eyes become presbyopic and lose their ability to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accommodation_%28eye%29&#34; title=&#34;Accommodation (eye)&#34;&gt;accommodate&lt;/a&gt; or change focus because they will then need to use glasses for reading. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Presbyopia&#34;&gt;Wikipedia article on Presbyopia&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weight loss</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/weight-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/weight-loss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;guruanerobic-advice&#34;&gt;GuruAnerobic advice&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;LCHP IF - the way forward diet: LC (Low Carbohydrate) HP (High Protein) IF (Intermittent Fasting)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;PARTIT LA FT - the way forward (exercise) - PA (Physical Activity) RT (Resistance Training) IT (Interval Training) LA (Lactic Acid Acidosis) FT (Fast Twitch Muscle)&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;As well as helping you lose fat, this is your code for dynamic strength, fitness and robust health. It will enable you to achieve the physical targets in Gang Fit 2. Most of this they don&amp;rsquo;t teach at school (another example of why school doesn&amp;rsquo;t prepare you for real life, even though they say it does)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At first glance this may seem like a lot; it isn&amp;rsquo;t - it&amp;rsquo;s the normal life of a wild carnivore. That&amp;rsquo;s what you should be. It&amp;rsquo;s only a lot of work for people who are used to wall-to-wall comfort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
