<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Shiva age on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Shiva age on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Anand Rao Bhosle</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/AnandarAvaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/AnandarAvaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Half brother of shivAjI. Able commander, who assisted svarAjya in several critical campaigns. Even acted as (unofficial) sarnobat for a while.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bahirji Naik</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/Bahirji_Naik/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/Bahirji_Naik/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shivaji&amp;rsquo;s great spy, who led his master &amp;amp; the army thru secret mountain tracks known to him alone during the diler khan campaign.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>bAji prabhu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/bAji_prabhu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/bAji_prabhu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baji_Prabhu&#34;&gt;bAji prabhu&lt;/a&gt; deshpANDe, a chandrasenIya kAyastha prabhu (dejure quasi-kShatriya dvija), who sacrificed his life at ghoD khiND delaying the enemy while ensuring shivAji&amp;rsquo;s escape. (Joke &lt;a href=&#34;../../../images/snippets/bAji-prabhu-joke.png&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;). His son Pilaji, who was taken Prisoner by the Sidi of Janjira and converted to Islam, reverted to Hinduism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>bALAjI vishvanAtha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/bALAjI_vishvanAtha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/bALAjI_vishvanAtha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;bALAjI (=baLLAla = gaNesha) vishvanAtha (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Balaji_Vishwanath&#34;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/KteqMeH.jpg&#34;&gt;family tree&lt;/a&gt;), kauNDinya-gotra, peshva who overcame internal friction within marATha empire, won over kAnhoji Angre, consolidated shAhu&amp;rsquo;s position, subdued the mughal system. &amp;ldquo;Balaji convinced Shahu to alter Shivaji&amp;rsquo;s old constitution of the Maratha state, whereby the nobles were salaried employees of the ruler. Henceforth, nobles would be feudatories with grants of land over which they ruled as vassal princes.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;The Maratha tax collection system from a wide swathe of nominally Mughal provinces was based on a widespread network of agents and collectors.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhanaji Jadhav</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/Dhanaji_Jadhav/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/Dhanaji_Jadhav/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(1650–1708), able commander, harassed the mughals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>dIpAmbA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/dIpAmbA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/dIpAmbA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;dhArmika wife of ekoji the lesser half-brother of shivAjI, much admired by shivAjI for her personality and role during their interaction when he came down to tanjore to settle ekoji&amp;rsquo;s anti-svarAjya activities,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;who brought up her son shAhAjI the fine abhinavabhoja &lt;a href=&#34;http://guruguha.org/vidya/2019/09/25/deepamba-the-lamp-of-dharma/&#34;&gt;GGH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;who spread dhArmika activities in her realm - establishing agrahAra-s, settlement of Bhagavatamela artistes, facilitating pilgrimages, gathering scholars, sponsored dharmashAstra works such as tryambakamakhin&amp;rsquo;s strIdharmapaddhati and its marAThI translation Pativratadharma.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;who counselled young shAhAji to intervene on behalf of the setupati and check missionaries&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>hambirrAv mohite</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/hambirrAv_mohite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/hambirrAv_mohite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;commander in chief of shivAjI and shambhu, father of Tarabai.&#xA;-  In early 1676, Hambirrao led a daring raid into Mughal territory as far as Bharuch in Gujarat &amp;amp; after much heroic fighting, brought back a large booty to the Raigad treasury. Later, during the karNATaka campaign, when shivAji had to rush back to raigarh, hambirrAv defeated Adil shAh armies and Ekoji.&#xA;- During the attack on diler khAn and mogols while aiding Adil shAh - he saved shivAji&amp;rsquo;s trapped army and trounced diler&amp;rsquo;s army.&#xA;- He harassed the mogols under sambAji- &amp;ldquo;Shahabuddin Khan, father of Nizam-ul-Mulk, advanced with a huge army to take Raigad. Crisis once again! And yet again it was Hambirrao&amp;rsquo;s cavalry which fell upon d besiegers routing them completely! Hambirrao immediately followed that up with another counter attack. 60 miles South East of Pune, Aurangzeb had setup an elephant stable with a large number of elephants. Hambirrao&amp;rsquo;s cavalry swooped down upon it, massacred the Mughal garrison drove off d entire herd of elephants! &amp;hellip; Shivaji had massacred Afzal Khan&amp;rsquo;s army in the forests below Pratapgad. It was Sarja&amp;rsquo;s turn now. Hambirrao drew Sarja Khan&amp;rsquo;s army deeper into the dense jungles around Mahabaleshwar &amp;amp; suddenly fell upon them. &amp;hellip; The Mughals were completely surrounded &amp;amp; massacred. But just at that moment of a decisive victory a most tragic event happened. Hambirrao was hit by a stray gun shot &amp;amp; fell dead.&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;- &amp;ldquo;Then the Mogol mined two of the hill slopes leading up to Mahabaleshwar plateau where the Maharattas were stationed and filling them with explosives, detonated it. Shaken by these two explosions the Maharattas began to flee helter-skelter. The Mogols soon rolled their heavy artillery and opened heavy fire on Hambirrao’s army. Hambirrao realized that his men would not hold out much longer and a defeat more or less guaranteed the end the Maharatta resistance to the Mogols in Maharashtra. Unless he turned the tide right there there was no hope stopping the Mogols from marching right through. With a chosen group of 100 ace commandos he rushed straight at Sarja Khan with the aim of killing him. This Maharatta band fought with unbelievable fury leaving a lane of blood and severed heads through the Mogol army. The swordsmanship of Mohite was unrivalled as he cut deep into the Mogol troops bringing down all before him and reaching the artillery line. His men fell upon the Mogol heavy artillery and destroyed the operators and wetted the powder. Seeing the tables turning, the fleeing rank and file of the Maharatta army recovered and fell upon the Mogols with renewed fury. The Mogols were completely swept away by the attack destroyed. However, in the midst of this Sarja Khan surrounded Hambirrao. The Mohite’s horse was shot down under him, but he continued fighting on foot and struck Sarja with his sword killing him. He was attacked on all sides and his strength was ebbing from the cuts he received. But leaning against a tree Hambirrao continued fighting keeping the Moslem assilants at bay till head was finally cut off. However, the surge of the Maharatta army was so great that the Mogol army was completely destroyed.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/06/02/the-death-of-hambirrao/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;]&#xA;- &amp;ldquo;But the cost of this last great victory of the Maharatta army in Sambhaji’s reign was most expensive. In intelligent leadership, knowledge of the terrain and strategy, Hambirrao had been unmatched. Further, he was the only one who had dared to challenge Kalash and mitigate his negative effect on Sambhaji. As Kincaid the British commentator states, had the brave Hambirrao lived he had all the skill and resources to repulse the Mogol offensive. But with his death the Maharatta army in Maharashtra became rudderless. This was followed soon after by Sambhaji’s capture and execution by the Mogols.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kAnhojI jEDhE deshmukh</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/kAnhojI_jEDhE_deshmukh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/kAnhojI_jEDhE_deshmukh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;deputed by Shahaji himself to protect shivAjI, who as a senior nobleman at a crucial juncture (during the Afzal Khan campaign) inspired and convinced all the deshkumkh-s to fight for svarAj rather than buckle towards Adil Shah, played major role in planning and executing battle of pratApgaD against Afzal Khan.&#xA;- &amp;ldquo;Kanhoji Jedhe went to Rajgad with the firmans received from Afzal Khan and publicly declared that he would relinquish his lands and his earnings to Shivaji but not join Afzal Khan. This simple act of bravery and farsightedness had an electrifying effect : that someone with the experience and seniority of Kanhoji Jedhe was supporting Shivaji meant that Swarajya was an idea they could and should fight for. All defections to Afzal Khan immediately stopped.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mAdanna akkanna</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/mAdanna_akkanna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/mAdanna_akkanna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Madanna_and_Akkanna&#34;&gt;madaNNa and akkaNNa&lt;/a&gt;, who protected the dharma as powerful ministers under qutub shAhis, collaborators with shivAji.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The family of mAdaNNA came from the town of Hanamkonda, Northeast of Bhaganagari, where under rudradeva kAkatIya a large temple of viShNu and sUrya had been constructed. The father of the brothers, bhANu-jI paNDita was a revenue administrator of the town and was named after one of the deities of the town. The son mAdhava paNDita (mAdaNNA) and arkarAja paNDita (akkaNNa) were also named after the two deities of the temple. They had other siblings, one of whose sons was rAmadasa, the legendary South Indian classical musician whose tale is told in every traditional South Indian brAhmaNa household.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Based on various lines of evidence it is clear that the brothers were polyglots who were fluent in Sanskrit, Hindi/Urdu, Marathi, Telugu and Persian [the fact they used the Modi script by default has been taken as the strongest support for their origins in mAhArAShTra]. There is an account of the Dutch agents regarding how mAdaNNA used to translate documents extempore between different languages in the court.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;rise-to-power&#34;&gt;Rise to power&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;They two brothers were initially appointed to aid the Persian official Sayyid Muzaffar in administration. It was then that they initiated the Hindu subversion of the Sultanate. In 1674 they intrigued with the new Sultan who had come to throne after the death of his father Abdullah Qutbshah to get Muzaffar dismissed from office and divested of his weapons and troops. The Mohammedan faction, especially backed by Turks and Persians, tried to restore Muzaffar but mAdaNNA maneuvered to keep him out and had himself appointed as Vazir. He quickly dismissed many of the powerful mullahs in the court and appointed Hindus to key positions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;He then induced the Sultan to place his cousin yengaNNA paNDita as a military general so that he could get a handle over the army, which was still dominated by the Mohammedans. By the treaty of Gulbarga he moved to place his brother akkaNNA to keep a tab on the Adilshahi sultanate too. &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;He appointed nephews lingaNNa and gopaNNa (aka rAmdAs) as district admins.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;plan-to-save-dharma&#34;&gt;Plan to save dharma&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;An year later (1675) he formulated the plan to restore peninsular India under Hindu control so that it could be a bulwark against the Mogol incursion to the South. He realized that he needed a Hindu military arm and saw that shivAjI was the man in this regard – an ideal brahma-kShatra alliance of yore could be forged. He right away contacted shivAjI and his brAhmaNa minister aNNAjI paNDit to devise a plan whereby shivAjI would be the mighty protector of the whole south against the Afghans and Mogols. shivAjI, raghunAth hanmante and aNNAjI reasoned that as soon as the Mogols were engaged in the North by other conflicts he could conquer the South completely.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;He built many temples and awarded grants to hindu institutions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;He ably aided shivAjI in his southern campaign and getting acqueisance of qutb shAh by a combination of territorial enticement and reminding of the mogol threat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tax-reforms&#34;&gt;Tax reforms&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Islamic agents had their goons who would bash the tax collectors if they did not rake in the money, and in turn the local tax collectors would terrorize the local population to extract the money. In the reform by the brothers, firstly the Moslem agents were dismissed and replaced by Hindu agents under honest brAhmaNa-s. The tax administrators were then given attractive and regular salaries and a fixed schedule to remit their taxes directly to the revenue office under mAdaNNA. The taxes were assessed based on productivity to the locality and the collectors were kept under multiple layers of surveillance to cut out embezzlement. The Sultan was kept as a pensioner by the brothers and the treasury was to a good measure controlled by them. The revenue reforms by mAdaNNA found a remarkable resonance in a parallel move by shivAjI. He destroyed the old Adilshahi and Mogol system of administration under jAgir-s. Instead, he appointed a regular revenue office that would assess tax and have it remitted directly to the royal treasury. The military was then paid directly from the royal treasury. &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>murAr bAji the kAyastha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/murAr_bAji_the_kAyastha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/murAr_bAji_the_kAyastha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;who successfully defended purandara fort defiantly and with astounding energy despite superior enemy firepower and numbers [&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Murarbaji&#34;&gt;W&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parshuram Tryambak Kinhaikar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/Parshuram_Tryambak_Kinhaikar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/Parshuram_Tryambak_Kinhaikar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(1660–1718 CE) / pant pratinidhi, an able general and administrator who assisted rAjArAm, tArAbAi, and later shAhu.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pratAprAv gujjar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/pratAprAv_gujjar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/pratAprAv_gujjar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;a gifted general who defeated mogols at salher, made the mistake of releasing AdilshAhi general bahlol khan with troops and supplies at Nesari. shivAji scolded him in a letter, so he rode alone (followed by 6 others) in a suicide charge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>raghunAtha nArAyaNa hanmante</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/raghunAtha_nArAyaNa_hanmante/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/raghunAtha_nArAyaNa_hanmante/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;author of  rAjavyavahArakosha (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Rjrasva/status/536370856206020609&#34;&gt;ref&lt;/a&gt;), who left the service of Tanjore&amp;rsquo;s Ekoji (aka vyAnkoji) Bhonsle to join his half-brother the brilliant shivAji, who counselled merciful quelling of ekoji&amp;rsquo;s despicable forwarding of muhammedan interests. He was made governor of the resulting southern conquests. He similarly publicly rebuked a wayward sambhAji.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rAjArAm</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/rAjArAm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/rAjArAm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;second son of shivAjI, who continued the struggle for svarAjya from Ginjee after Sambhaji&amp;rsquo;s murder, escaped to jinjI through keladi ruled by channamma, under whose reign the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adnyapatra&#34;&gt;AjJNApatra&lt;/a&gt; was created.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;See his proclamation to general Hindus to harrass the mogul army.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Chitnis Bakhar mentions Rajaram as saying:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Time and again we have grappled with thc Mogul armies. The Emperor is camped at Aurangabad, in our homeland, and there I intend to lead the attack in person; bring home to the Emperor that the army that Shivaji built still exists and that Rajaram is a part of it. Prove to him that the Maratha spirit is not extinct.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rAmachandra panta</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/rAmachandra_panta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/rAmachandra_panta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ramchandra_Pant_Amatya&#34;&gt;panta&lt;/a&gt; amAtya (1650–1716), the ably effected transition in times of trouble, who authored the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adnyapatra&#34;&gt;AjJNApatra&lt;/a&gt;, who assisted shivAji, rAjArAm (as his regent when he was in flight), sambhAji, tArAbAyi, who instituted the &amp;ldquo;capture land from mughal-s, then own it&amp;rdquo; policy to encourage fightback, who adapted the policy of selling forts to the mughals (only to recapture them). He defeated the British march on puNe assisted by the traitor raghunAth rAv.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Santaji Mhaloji Ghorpade</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/Santaji_Mhaloji_Ghorpade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/Santaji_Mhaloji_Ghorpade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(1660-1696) of the broader bhosale community, named by Shivaji on his death bed to be among six pillars of Maratha Empire, who in a daring feat cut the ropes of Aurangzeb’s tents and took the imperial golden pinnacles and fled boosting marATha morale and confidence, argued oft with rAjArAm over decisions and was sacked.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>shAhu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/shAhu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/shAhu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chattrapati_Shahu&#34;&gt;shAhu&lt;/a&gt; kShatrapati, son of sAmbhAji, who bounced back from mughal captivity (and very poor education in his own religion [&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ColonelGerard/status/632523169375502336&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;]) to take over the throne after defeating tArAbAyi, who was wise enough to let the most able men take power. Yet he sadly held bAjIrAv back when it came to completely uprooting the mogol empire[&lt;a href=&#34;https://agnimaan.wordpress.com/2016/01/14/bajiravs-hindu-delhi-empire-plan-thwarted/&#34;&gt;WP&lt;/a&gt;], held the mogol emperor in such regard and alleigence as to stop bAjIrAv from even constructing a gate facing north [&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ColonelGerard/status/769971907689115651&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>shambhu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/shambhu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/shambhu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sambhaji&#34;&gt;shambhAji&lt;/a&gt;, son of shivAji, who fought the siddi, Portuguese and mughals, who died rather than convert, [&lt;a href=&#34;http://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/06/13/the-end-of-sambhaji/&#34;&gt;M&lt;/a&gt;1] who tried to induce a pan-Indian hindu unity against the yavana-s [&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2010/04/25/the-scope-of-shivajis-plan-of-svarajya/&#34;&gt;M2&lt;/a&gt; letter to rAmasimha] [battles 1680-1707 &lt;a href=&#34;https://aneeshbooks.wordpress.com/references-used-while-writing-brahmaputra/chhatrapati-sambhaji-battles-fought-during-maratha-war-of-independence-1680-to-1707/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nicolai Manucci reported that shambhu showed him his sword and said that he beheaded 30 of his traitorous officers himself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sambhaji was given to women and drink in the company of a brave but lazy Kanyakubja brahmin poet Kalash. .. Sambhaji remained lazy and missed a golden opportunity even as Awrangzeeb pressed home his fierce attacks on Bijapur and Golconda.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>shivAjI शिवराजः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/shiva/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/shiva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;shiva/ &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shivaji&#34;&gt;shivAji&lt;/a&gt; kShatrapati (6 April 1627 or &lt;strong&gt;19 Feb. 1630&lt;/strong&gt;  – 3 April 1680 Julian)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;impact&#34;&gt;Impact&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;यथान्यैरुक्तम् -&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;नैकदुर्गविजेतारं धर्मकण्टकनाशनम्। शिवराजं वन्देऽहं खानोदरविदारकम्॥&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;प्रातिपश्चन्द्रलेखैव वर्धिष्णुर् विश्ववन्दिता। शाहसूनोश् शिवस्यैषा मुद्रा भद्राय राजते॥&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;कासिहू ते कला जाती मथुरा मसीद होती सिवाजी न होतो तौ सुनति होत सबकी - &lt;a href=&#34;http://bharatendu.com/2009/10/30/bhushana-sivaji-na-hoto-tau-sunnati-hota-sabaki/&#34;&gt;भूषणः&lt;/a&gt;।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;brilliant-concept&#34;&gt;Brilliant concept&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;under divine guidance, conceptualized and realized hindu svarAjya (evident even at a young age - see letter written to Dadaji Naras Prabhu at age 15 or 18 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.academia.edu/22259519/Transitions_and_Translations_Regional_Power_and_Vernacular_Identity_in_the_Dakhan_1500_1800_SUMIT_GUHA&#34;&gt;SG-academia&lt;/a&gt;),&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;sought to rid hindusthAna of the Islamist menace (letter to Jayasimha &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/stream/DeliverranceOrTheEscapeOfShivajiTheGreatFromAgra#page/n289/mode/2up&#34;&gt;archive&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/B10P1KzCIAAKDkZ.jpg:large&#34;&gt;P1&lt;/a&gt; points 51 to 70,&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In south: &amp;ldquo;using the Qutbshah’s resources shivAjI conquered the fort of Gingee and extended his domain into the south ending the careers of several Jihadis and putting a check on the mlechCha-s who were surrounding the coast. As the drAviDa historian of the kOvaLan clan, nArAyaNan kOn put it he restored the rule of law in those regions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;had measured regard for brAhmaNa-s taken to other dharma-s (&lt;a href=&#34;https://imgur.com/wSWxvEV&#34;&gt;IMG&lt;/a&gt;), who convened the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ashta_Pradhan&#34;&gt;aShTha-pradhAnas&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;brought out the best in people (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sanskritimagazine.com/history/forgotten-heroes-fought-alongside-shivaji/#&#34;&gt;S1&lt;/a&gt;),&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;who resanskritified marAThi (Surendranath Sen &lt;a href=&#34;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/B3GT75dCIAAzcf0.png:large&#34;&gt;snip&lt;/a&gt;, rAjavyavahArakosha &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Rjrasva/status/536370856206020609&#34;&gt;ref&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;brilliant-execution&#34;&gt;Brilliant execution&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;brilliant strategist [&lt;a href=&#34;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/B1z-DAFIIAA_lU0.jpg:large&#34;&gt;E1&lt;/a&gt;],&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;considered temporarily joining Awrangzeb [&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ColonelGerard/status/834464411398004736&#34;&gt;CG17&lt;/a&gt;] to smash Adil shAh and Qutb shAh - but retained dignity and escaped when it did not go well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;religious-policy&#34;&gt;Religious policy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shivaji&amp;rsquo;s regulations regarding the behaviour of his soldiers in enemy country were, according to Sabhasad, as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tArAbAyi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/tArAbAyi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/shiva-age/tArAbAyi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;wife of rAjArAm, daugher of hambIr-rAv, who kept up the fight against the mughal-s.&#xA;- She was later sidelined by a newly released shAhu and bAlAjI vishvanAtha. She propped up an impostor ( Rajaram II) and attempted various vain strategems - only to be foiled by bAlAjI. &amp;ldquo;On 14 September 1752, the two took oaths at Khandoba temple in Jejuri, promising mutual peace. At this oath ceremony, Tarabai also swore that Rajaram II was not her grandson, but an impostor from the Gondhali caste.[6] Nevertheless, Peshwa retained Rajaram II as the titular Chhhatrapati and a powerless figurehead.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
