<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hate and derangement</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/MT/hate_and_derangement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/MT/hate_and_derangement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hate-and-derangement&#34;&gt;Hate and derangement&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1736446489449189644.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyone who is obsessed with Modi loses all their sanity. Not a single exception to this in public life. There is something about Modi that once you start hating him wholeheartedly, you lose your intellectual frame and even start erring in your specialized domains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is interesting that this is a general phenomenon: we have derangement syndromes triggered by nAri~NgapuruSha &amp;amp; rUspati just like the lATarAT. I&amp;rsquo;ve also seen several people flip from total bhagat to dviT from one term to another. I think there&amp;rsquo;re 3 distinct (but may be related) psychologies involved here:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hunter gatherer fitness - political ideology</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/MT/hunter-gatherer-fitness_political-ideology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/MT/hunter-gatherer-fitness_political-ideology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conservatives exhibit higher levels of health, beauty, fertility, strength, size, testosterone, and spatial intelligence, while liberals excel in social skills and verbal intelligence. Higher trait intensities should correlate with more extreme political attitudes, with exceptions of course.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aporiamagazine.com/p/the-hunter-gatherer-fitness-model&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While we agree with several directions presented in the article,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;we do not entirely endorse its claims.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;We believe the waters have been muddied by:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;more complex selection trajectories in settled differentiated populations since the neolithic.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;We believe &amp;ldquo;differentiation&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sedentariness&amp;rdquo; imposed huge selective forces in Eurasia and parts of pre-Euro America.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Further, the effects of the females as the primarily dispersing sex in Homo sapiens&lt;br&gt;&#xA;has likely placed selective pressures on them,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;such as easier ideological switching.+++(5)+++&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Based on insect models and their extrapolation to Homo,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;selection for increased male-fitness favorable traits&lt;br&gt;&#xA;probably harms daughters&amp;rsquo; fitness&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and vice-versa for female traits:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;so there is a balancing selection from tradeoff.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There also appears to be a bet-hedging strategy in group fission societies that would feed into this.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In modern, occidentally induced left-liberal movements,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;we have to seriously consider the cannon-fodder hypothesis,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;wherein a relatively small elite mobilizes forces of lower IQ and low status masses for their own benefit&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by fostering memetic diseases center on utopian promises&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leader speciality</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/MT/leader-speciality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/MT/leader-speciality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1762736947875770368.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ancient world, unlike many neo-occidentally conditioned folks, recognized that leadership of men was related to something special &amp;ndash; it could be seen as a the charisma seen only in a true leader. That&amp;rsquo;s why we have approximately equivalent words: Skt: shrI; Iranic: Xvarena, Turkic: kut, Mongolic: suu, Chinese: yun, Arabic: dawlat. That it cuts across religions and ethnicities in Eurasia indicates that it is something primal. Even the Austronesia Maoris had something called mana.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On modellers</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/MT/on-modellers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/MT/on-modellers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;spengler&#34;&gt;Spengler&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1751080041859993709&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spengler did not understand Darwin&amp;rsquo;s evolutionary theory correctly, but he correctly apprehended the evolutionary dynamics of civilization as a whole. While at one level, energetics might explain aspects of it (e.g., Tainter), Spengler had his finger on something more subtle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
