<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Analysis</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/2012-04-08_strategic-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/2012-04-08_strategic-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.wordpress.com/2012/04/08/strategic-analysis/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Strategic Analysis&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have been asked to discuss Iran’s nuclear weapons potential – and I&#xA;will, but I’m going to take a broader look.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The short answer is that the centrifuge approach that Iran is pursuing&#xA;is capable (when mature) of producing either low-enriched uranium(LEU),&#xA;useful for power reactors, or HEU, highly-enriched uranium, which can be&#xA;used to make a fission bomb, among other things. Just for general&#xA;information, natural uranium is about 0.7% U-235. LEU means that the&#xA;fraction of U-235 is somewhere under under 20% (3%-5% in light water&#xA;reactors) , while HEU is more highly enriched. Typical uranium nuclear&#xA;weapons are usually &amp;gt;85% U-235, although the real nuclear players use&#xA;plutonium cores nowadays . You can make a gun-type fission bomb with&#xA;highly enriched HEU, which is simpler to develop than implosion,&#xA;although less efficient.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sogdia and India</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/sogdia_and_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/sogdia_and_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Sogdians were a merchant people of the silk-road &amp;amp; were extensively settled in China. Like all Central Asians, they were influenced deeply by Indian Civilization not only in terms of language but also religion &amp;amp; iconography. For example, the Sogdians called the leaders of their merchant communities &amp;amp; caravans as s&amp;rsquo;rtp&amp;rsquo;w. This is a loanword from Sanskrit सार्थवाहन (leader of a caravan of merchants). This term would be loaned into Chinese as &amp;ldquo;sabao&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; applied to leaders of the Sogdian community. Some other loanwords from Sanskrit and Prakrit that we see in Sogdian. A lot of these words are related to commerece (sārtha, sārthavāhana, mūlya) while others are related to bureaucratic necessities like (lekha, prastha). Some of the Sogdians were Hindus. For example, this is a famous wall painting of Lord Shiva from Panjikent (Tajikistan).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
