<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;१२ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;१२ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The ghost again</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-29_the-ghost-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-29_the-ghost-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/29/the-ghost-again/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was disastrous day. Unfazed by the disasters we were returning. We paused on our path for we distinctly saw some strange dark object like a coat lying on our a path a few feet away. I reached the object somehow drawn by curiousity to examine it. Just before I reached it I was distracted for a moment as I looked to the side due to a scrapping noise. I turned back and the black object was gone! Where it lay I say some ungainly stains like smeared flesh or blood of a dead animal. I heard the scrapping noise again and there was just no sign of the black object that I had clearly seen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The scooter circuit</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-25_the-scooter-circuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-25_the-scooter-circuit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/25/the-scooter-circuit/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We performed our peculiar scooter circuit that year. Earlier it was the cycle circuit. We were like the pAshupata, distanced from the plebian world. We we passed in the midst of the plebians, we heard their chatter, we saw them indulge in the pleasures of the world and suffer from the pains of the world. They reflected in us, like a scenery in a mirror. We moved right in their middle but they stuck not to us like water on a oiled surface. There were fumes around us, but we did not breathe them. Some performing huDDukAra, other aTTahAsa, and yet others jumbaka nR^itya, came to us but we remained entirely silent. We existed on crags of the “far away land”. There we roamed like an all-knowing gandharva in the constant embrace of our dazzling apsarA. We spoke endlessly with our apsarA on the Topics. We only stopped thrice a day for food and drink. Rest of the time it was the non-stop discourse. We slept in the highest realm of pleasure. We knew that we knew all. A stone hit the lake surface. Ripples permeated through it. Our knowing slipped through the troughs in the waves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The rosary pea</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-21_the-rosary-pea/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-21_the-rosary-pea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/21/the-rosary-pea/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many seeds greatly fascinated me when I was young (actually they&#xA;continue to do so) . One of these was the rosary pea (Abrus&#xA;precatorius). The other was the castor seed. When we had beheld the&#xA;all-bewitching Kappa Hayastanika, like most other mortals, we had&#xA;uttered the words:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://srimadbhagavatam.com/a/aho&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“aho rUpaM aho dhAma aho asyA navaM vayaH / ka~Nja-palAshAkShi vAmoru&#xA;mathnatIva manAMsi naH /tvaM asi sharIriNAM sarvendriya-manaH-prItiM //&#xA;“&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://srimadbhagavatam.com/n/nah&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The long drawn encounter</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-19_the-long-drawn-encounter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-19_the-long-drawn-encounter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/19/the-long-drawn-encounter/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We repulsed another attack on our position by the brigade from&#xA;dundubhidurga. Seeing that dundudbhidurga was strategically placed to&#xA;fire rockets at us, we decided to use the confusion of our foe to take&#xA;the fort. I set out with a force of commandos and attacked&#xA;dundubhidurga. We detonated a part of the wall an got in. We face some&#xA;opposition but as our men had taken the commanding heights we were able&#xA;to kill the defenders. We destroyed much of the defending party and a&#xA;few survivors go away. We are however in a quandry as to whether to&#xA;garrison the fort or simply blow it up. We still have a few days to&#xA;decide, but the news reached us that our ally in suvarNapura was facing&#xA;a grim assault. If he is overthrown we may face a dire situation and may&#xA;need to withdraw any garrison placed for this fort. If we blow up the&#xA;fort we simply may have no leverage on the enemy territory. The enemy&#xA;had cleverly moved all their supplies and resources from dundubhidurga-&#xA;so in a sense it was an empty conquest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New moves in the saMgrAma</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-14_new-moves-in-the-samgrama/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-14_new-moves-in-the-samgrama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/14/new-moves-in-the-samgrama/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We had beaten back the fierce thrust launched by our foes on our fort.&#xA;We knew that we could fend off their assault as long as we held the&#xA;fort. However, on realistically assessing the situation we realized that&#xA;this hardly meant that we had won the war. We had been greatly weakened&#xA;by the several years of constant war on the frontiers. For an empire to&#xA;remain in good health a lot actually depends on the internal conditions.&#xA;The years of war on the frontier had sapped our resources and even the&#xA;scaffold of the empire was stretched thin. We needed to take steps to&#xA;keep the empire running now and calque the fissures that were emerging.&#xA;The last year, since our terrible defeat in the Battle of the Bard’s&#xA;hill had been like one of those yugas in downward cycle of the jaina&#xA;mythology, dominated by the prati-vAsudeva. We realized that our enemies&#xA;possessed enough resources to keep the war going. Now with even our&#xA;escape routes sealed by rudhira dhvaja and tiryagnetra, we were left&#xA;with little to no options but hold this fort as long as we can. With&#xA;these new considerations it has become clear that a defeat here will&#xA;essentially mean a severe dent to the empire. If we survive we may&#xA;retire from the helm and leave it to our successor to fight the future&#xA;wars with a much truncated kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Report from spies</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-11_report-from-spies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-11_report-from-spies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/11/report-from-spies/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our sachIva had proposed a long and intricate escape plan that had&#xA;promising aspects to it. It needed a particular maneuver that was&#xA;difficult but could be achieved with the help of my greatest ally. I had&#xA;started considering it seriously as an option in the event we face a&#xA;defeat on the front #3. However, I suddenly realized that this escape&#xA;route could very well turn out the route for exit from this earth. I&#xA;sent my able spy who knew all happenings of those regions to check out.&#xA;Not un-expectedly, I learnt from his reliable investigations that a&#xA;scorpion’s journey down a solifugid’s lair awaited us. The well-know&#xA;sapatnas, whom we had thrashed in the past, rudhira-dhvaja prAchya and&#xA;tiryagnetra could easily burn us if we took that route. “na mama” I said&#xA;and scrapped the plan. I issued orders to the sachIva to drop&#xA;preparations and consider alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>viel Schwerter klirren und blitzen</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-09_viel-schwerter-klirren-und-blitzen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-09_viel-schwerter-klirren-und-blitzen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/09/viel-schwerter-klirren-und-blitzen/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So will ich liegen und horchen still,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Wie eine Schildwach, im Grabe,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Bis einst ich höre Kanonengebrüll&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Und wiehernder Rosse Getrabe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dann reitet mein Kaiser wohl über mein Grab,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Viel Schwerter klirren und blitzen;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Dann steig ich gewaffnet hervor aus dem Grab,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Den Kaiser, den Kaiser zu schützen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Around midday we hear a huge explosion on the western ramparts. An&#xA;enormous hostile horde was trying to make its way through the western&#xA;wall. We retaliated with rocket fire and advanced a wing of our&#xA;wall-guards to kill the enemy sappers and fusiliers. While the rockets&#xA;broke down and blew away many of the hostile climbers quite a few made&#xA;it to the lower point in the fort via the gapping irrepairable hole we&#xA;had talked about. A fierce hand to hand fight was fought there. Our men&#xA;retreated under the intense assault and the foes started aiding a second&#xA;sapping party. We were suffering from fever like Lachit Barphukan on the&#xA;day of that historic encounter on the Brahmaputra against the army of&#xA;Awrangzeb. We despatched our sachiva with a force counter the thrust at&#xA;the breach. 15 minutes later I noticed the tide turning and our men were&#xA;driving them out. We rolled in some rockets to hold the breach. The&#xA;enemy had erected a 200 feet tower with platforms across the lower&#xA;battlement and was preparing to launch rockets. There was an immense din&#xA;on the walls of the lower fort as the storming parties were clashing&#xA;swords with our men. Heads, arms, bodies were being hacked and streams&#xA;of blood were flowing. We ordered an attack with trebuchets on the&#xA;tower. The tower was hit twice but they quickly raised two new ones for&#xA;the attack.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flashback</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-08_flashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-08_flashback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/08/flashback/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the year of dvAdashAnta, MP found every neuron in his brain captured&#xA;by R. I believe every waking and perhaps non-waking hour of the day he&#xA;was only occupied by R. In the company of other males he spoke only of R&#xA;and how he may impress her. On what he thought to be the day of&#xA;reckoning, our duhitaram kalashaja non-chalantly asked MP whether some&#xA;eight-carbon ring with alternating double bonds will be an acid or a&#xA;base. MP looked clueless and puzzled. R then asked him if some polyene&#xA;would be planar or not. . Leave alone planarity, MP did not even know&#xA;that such compounds could exist. #Flashback: The remarkable battle&#xA;between R and the prodigious one was much more evenly match than this.&#xA;All three of us who have routed the pretty sugar cake take great&#xA;pleasure these gavishTis sometimes. # MP never received much audience&#xA;there after. The pendulum swung a 180 degrees. MP soon acquired our&#xA;secret Neel-bumb technology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards the battle of kAla-nirNaya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-08_towards-the-battle-of-kala-nirnaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-08_towards-the-battle-of-kala-nirnaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/08/towards-the-battle-of-kala-nirnaya/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our spies provided us with speculative intelligence that the hostile&#xA;forces may be preparing a trap for us. However, we were not able to&#xA;confirm it based on other reports. The princess of Hayastan, with calves&#xA;like the quivers of kAma, gave us one of those Mona Lisa smiles and&#xA;drove away on her ratha. As ever, if one meets her the right way one is&#xA;transported to the shores of the ocean of bliss. She expressed deep&#xA;Schadenfreude that R had been plunged into her current condition. She&#xA;laughed like chAmuNDA as she said: “Imagine if R were not reduced to&#xA;certifying pesticides, we might have had nothing left to do.” But she&#xA;added: ” I would be happy if my daughter turned out be half as her.” I&#xA;told she was not the first or even the second who had wished secretly or&#xA;even openly that R plunge into shit, very literally, like the&#xA;dharmashAstras pronounce for certain unfortunate souls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainity remains</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-06_uncertainity-remains/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-06_uncertainity-remains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/06/uncertainity-remains/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Seeing that our foes had not fired the expected salvos, we were growing&#xA;curious like the legendary cat. There was a heated discussion amongst&#xA;our staff whether to counter-attack or lie and wait. While we had gained&#xA;an advantage on front #3, a counter-attack could prove costly, as our&#xA;resources had run out. Towards night I could not bear the wait and&#xA;ordered a cautious counter-attack. The hostile forces behaved unusually.&#xA;At first they put up a strong fight and then retreated into inaccessible&#xA;terrain. We stopped pursuing at the point, for even a victory could&#xA;prove empty and costly. It is possible they are hiding something and&#xA;have a plan to strike us unexpectedly. Today again we sent a&#xA;reconnaisance force to probe their actions. They retreated quickly after&#xA;a brief encounter. We have now decided to wait and watch though we are&#xA;not certain of their ploys in battle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enemy strategy on front #1</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-04_enemy-strategy-on-front-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-04_enemy-strategy-on-front-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/04/enemy-strategy-on-front-1/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The enemy forces did not strike on front #1 as we had expected. Our&#xA;spies inform us that they have decided to instead pause futher&#xA;hostilities on front #1 and instead resort to the Trojan horse strategy.&#xA;In our “Gaugamela”, which was in a month of blazing heat we had fallen&#xA;prey to that strategy and lost terribly. We, however, learnt our lesson,&#xA;even if it came at a high cost. We get the temptation to attack but&#xA;given our inability to hit the capital we have decided to wait&#xA;silently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The bleak winter evening</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-04_the-bleak-winter-evening/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-04_the-bleak-winter-evening/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/04/the-bleak-winter-evening/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was standing alone in the railway station in the bleak winter air.&#xA;There was not a single sound and the air hung eerily as though weighed&#xA;down by the cold. Suddenly the air quivered with the fluttering of a&#xA;pigeon’s wings as it made its roostward retreat and then there was&#xA;silence again- the shakuna! The sun sunk on the pashchima mayukha,&#xA;leaving behind the gloaming and the azure depths of dyaus turned inky&#xA;dark. There was a sharp cry of the wind, reminiscent of the howl of The&#xA;god (sa devaH). The shadows of the stones in the cemetery beyond grew&#xA;rapidly even as the the last beams of the dusk retreated. They seemed to&#xA;transform into the agents of the lord of the animals. “oM yo vai rudraH&#xA;sa bhagavAn yashcha mR^ityus tasmai vai namo namaH”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Battle of himaprArambha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-03_battle-of-himaprarambha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-03_battle-of-himaprarambha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/03/battle-of-himaprarambha/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We saw that front #3 was a grand success in yesterday’s hostilities. We&#xA;first blunted the attack by raising the water in the moat and causing&#xA;the enemy troops to retreat. Then we used the naphta trick that we&#xA;discovered after a terrible defeat a few winters ago. Invoking deva&#xA;savitA and taking our time to launch counter-offensive we went heavy on&#xA;naptha again today. The hostile forces suffered heavy losses and&#xA;retreated in disarray. We pursued them relentlessly and destroyed the&#xA;pockets of resistance. Thus, we had contained the enemy name “kosha”. On&#xA;front #2 we were pressed hard but out fortifications held fine and the&#xA;baggage train was protected even as the enemy made several attempts to&#xA;bang it. Thus, the enemy named “gandharva ratha” could not make&#xA;significant progress against us and retreated. On front #1 we were the&#xA;weakest. We kept shielding it from the enemy vision with smoke screens.&#xA;The enemy could launch a strong attack on this front to retaliate agains&#xA;the defeat in front #3. We cannot do much but the simply wait and take&#xA;the attack, because the gaping hole was just too much to repair. Over&#xA;the next few days fighting may intensify on this front. The first salvo&#xA;could come as early as in an hour from now. But I will be retiring to&#xA;rest after heavy fighting and will leave it to the staff to tackle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encounter continues</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-02_encounter-continues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-02_encounter-continues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/02/encounter-continues/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we have a long day ahead of us tommorow we shall be curt. We did&#xA;surprisingly well on front #3 and we hope the gods favor us again in a&#xA;similar encounter tommorow. We also obtained some clue regarding our&#xA;ranking in the midst of the warring states. We believe we were evenly&#xA;matched with our adversary. But as every one knows battles can be lost&#xA;on small points. Certain unusual delays that our rivals were subject to&#xA;favored us on the front. More mysteriously the same omen continues&#xA;unabated, but we are not bothering to check it means good or bad&#xA;according to the shakuna shAstra.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 3 front war</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-01_the-3-front-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/12/2004-12-01_the-3-front-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/01/the-3-front-war/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We completed the fortifications on various crags and they stood&#xA;reasonably. Shortly after we had done so the hostile forces opened a&#xA;massive assault on front #3. Our fortifications fended the attack, but&#xA;were severely tested. We then strengthened some further outposts, and&#xA;called off all diplomats. Then, tired as never before, we retired to&#xA;rest. After that we went to inspect one of the fortifications, when a&#xA;massive hostile thrust occurred on front #1. A gaping hole was seen in&#xA;the fortification that simply could not be repaired. We had always known&#xA;our weakness on front #1 and yet again it was starkly haunting us. We&#xA;felt like Maharana Pratap facing the Mogol artillery. Even as we were&#xA;taking stock of the situation, a massive thrust was launched on front&#xA;#3. We have now decided to take the extreme step of flooding the moat in&#xA;an attempt to save front #3. Off to the front.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
