<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Clothing-Intro on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/clothing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Clothing-Intro on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/clothing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cargo wear</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/clothing/cargo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/clothing/cargo/</guid>
      <description>Belt Useful not only for holding up pants tightly to the waist, ensuring good weight distribution, but also enables attachments like pouches.
Buy a synthetic material belt, ideally one which can be used in professional circumstances, with very little metal (no big belt buckle), so that it need not be removed for airport security checks.
Cargo pants/ shorts Can be found in military stores or online. Professional look is achievable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/clothing/low-temperature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/clothing/low-temperature/</guid>
      <description>General strategy Layer up Dressing with multiple layers of clothing essential, due to the wide use of heated buildings. It also insulates better.
Wear a warm clothing a few minutes before stepping out - then, air will be trapped inside the clothes.
Accesorize use faceguards, gloves, etc.. for extremities. This provides additional comfort. Eg: a hood not attached to the jacket provides improved mobility.
Maintenance Look for machine washable and dryable clothes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extremities</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/clothing/extremities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/clothing/extremities/</guid>
      <description>Shoes Heavy or formal use Use water proof, breathable boots, with minimal heaviness. It must be usable even on formal occasions.
Lace Shoes that don’t require lace-tying are generally looser and more uncomfortable during brisk walks.
There are shoes which can be easily (un)tied by just pulling a loop. Use these.
Use easy to tie lace: lock/ elastic/ speed/ quick/ lace.
Avoid plastic shoes Leather boots, rather than plastic boots, are breathable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High temp</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/clothing/normal-temperature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/clothing/normal-temperature/</guid>
      <description>Materials Cotton is popular. Absorbs sweat etc.. Better is something which wicks away moisture: like nylon weave.
Underwear Purpose Prevent outer garments from being soiled by body fluids, body oils and perspiration. Provide support for genitalia.
Lower body Use good (Jockey) boxer briefs with the elastic band embedded inside the cloth.
Upper body Use T shirts next to the body. Use collarless, light colored ones if wearing a formal shirt above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Special</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/clothing/special/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/clothing/special/</guid>
      <description>Rain clothing Breathable rain clothing, with sealed seams are good.
Full zip rain pants are easy to wear and remove.
Swimwear Wetsuits, fast drying underwear.
Hindu ceremonial dress KachchE panche with uttarIya or with a jubba: wearing technique explained in customs survey.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>