<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#43;NATO expansion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/nato-expansion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/nato-expansion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kennan&amp;rsquo;s thoughts in 1997 in his diary on NATO expansion:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That the Russians will not react wisely and moderately to the decision of NATO to extend its boundaries to the Russian frontiers is clear. They are already reacting differently&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The deep commitment of our government to press the expansion of NATO right up to the Russian borders is the greatest mistake of the entire post–Cold War period. I feel that I should state that view publicly. But then it would be wrong to do this without notifying the few friends&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AryAMsha on euro dark age</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/AryAMsha_on_euro-dark-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/AryAMsha_on_euro-dark-age/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1393224110000336905.html#google_vignette&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thread by @arya_amsha on Thread Reader App – Thread Reader App&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1025, Private Letters between two Catholic Scholars - Raoul of Liège and Ragimbold of Cologne tell us that Catholic Europe lacked basic geometrical knowledge such as the sum of the angles of a triangle makeup 180 degrees. Why was this?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See: &lt;a href=&#34;https://vriitrahan.wordpress.com/2021/05/14/pagan-science-in-christian-rome-i/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reason was simple, Latin Christian Europe had been cutoff for 800 years from the Science &amp;amp; Philosophy of the Ancient Greeks after the Roman Empire collapsed &amp;amp; fluency in Ancient Greek vanished from Western Europe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knight training</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/knight-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/knight-training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/TPeshwa/status/1943104649726226792&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Now cased in armour, he would practise leaping on to the back of a horse; anon, to accustom himself to become long-winded and enduring, he would walk and run long distances on foot, or he would practice striking numerous and forcible blows with a battle-axe or mallet. In order to accustom himself to the weight of his armour, he would turn somersaults whilst clad in a complete suit of mail, with the exception of his helmet, or would dance vigorously in a shirt of steel; he would place one hand on the saddle-bow of a tall charger, and the other on his neck, and vault over him…He would climb up between two perpendicular walls that stood four or five feet asunder by the mere pressure of his arms and legs, and would thus reach the top, even if it were as high as a tower, without resting either in the ascent or descent…When he was at home, he would practice with the other young esquires at lance-throwing and other warlike exercises, and this continually… fully armed in a coat of mail, he could climb right to the top of the underside of a scaling ladder leaning against a wall, simply swinging from rung to rung by his two hands – or without the coat of mail, by one hand only”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Medieval war barbarity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/medieval-war-barbarity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/medieval-war-barbarity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1946286816782348455.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t know much about the 10th century or that general time period if you think the Vikings were somehow different.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;William the Conqueror&amp;rsquo;s harrowing of the North for example.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Warfare in general was aimed at people and resources. Quick gains and quick destruction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Crops pillaged. Houses and barns burned. Captives taken, bystanders scattered and killed. The stuff that went on regularly at the English Scottish border makes the vikings look like a bunch of secular humanists.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sanctions effectiveness</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/sanctions-effectiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/sanctions-effectiveness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Western nations have in the past week imposed the most sweeping economic sanctions against a major country in recent decades, moves that are likely to cripple the Russian economy and sharply raise the costs of the country’s invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whether it will be enough to cause Russian President Vladimir Putin to withdraw his troops from Ukraine, or even weaken his hold on power, however, is far less likely, according to experts on sanctions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>W Europe predatory powers</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/western-europe-predatory-powers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/western-europe-predatory-powers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tressel.xyz/threads/1496749537448316930&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Historically some u2 states of Western Europe, both Germanic and Romance, &amp;amp; their offspring, have excelled as long range predatory powers. This trend started with the crusades in response to the u3 jihad &amp;amp; later in alliance with the u3s against the Rus &amp;ndash; French+Eng+Turk alliance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In contrast, despite heathen Germanic elite, who lay at the heart of the long-range  predatory impulse of Western Europe before the infection by the unmAda, Rus began like a classic Khanganate inspired by contact with Turko-Mongol neighbors. Their mode of action is that of a classic land-power that exerts powers on conterminous regions. But their infection by the other strain of the unmAda has meant conflict along the fundamental schism in pretonmAda between the western churches &amp;amp; the orthodox church, c.f. like sunni &amp;amp; shia in marUnmAda.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Washington 1912</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/washington_1912/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/articles/washington_1912/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*** START OF THE PROJECT GUTENBERG EBOOK 61223 ***&#xA;cover&#xA;THE MAN FARTHEST DOWN&#xA;BY THE SAME AUTHOR&#xA;Up From Slavery: An Autobiography&#xA;The Story of the Negro&#xA;Working With the Hands&#xA;Character Building&#xA;My Larger Education&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;title page&#xA;THE MAN&#xA;FARTHEST DOWN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A RECORD OF OBSERVATION AND&#xA;STUDY IN EUROPE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BOOKER T. WASHINGTON&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WITH THE COLLABORATION OF&#xA;Robert E. Park&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;logo&#xA;Garden City       New York&#xA;DOUBLEDAY, PAGE &amp;amp; COMPANY&#xA;1912&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
