<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Samurai &amp; sacred on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Samurai &amp; sacred on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/00/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/00/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;CONTENTS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Way of the Gods&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Buddha and the Bushi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Gods Go to War&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Warriors of the Pure Land&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Onward, Christian Samurai!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Samurai and the Secret&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zen and the Samurai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Ways of the Warrior&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From Samurai to Spirit&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Epilogue&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Endnotes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Select Bibliography&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Glossary&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 INTRODUCTION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/01_INTRODUCTION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/01_INTRODUCTION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fudō, ‘the immoveable one’, shown holding a sword in his right hand and a rope in his left hand while surrounded by flames. This statue is in the courtyard of the Yashimaji near Takamatsu.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the year 1592, as the Japanese invasion fleet was about to set sail to attack Korea, there was a slight pause in the proceedings while Matsuura Hōin Shigenobu (1549–1614) performed a brief religious ritual. Dressed in his finest robes and holding aloft a &lt;em&gt;heihaku&lt;/em&gt; (a symbolic offering made of paper), he climbed up on to the raised deck of his ship and turned to face in the general direction of the distant Iwashimizu shrine, which was dedicated to Hachiman, the &lt;em&gt;kami&lt;/em&gt; (god) of war. He bowed three times. Guns were fired and his followers gave three war cries. Shigenobu’s commander-in-chief, Toyotomi Hideyoshi (1536–98), sent a messenger to enquire after the reason for the noise. Shigenobu reported back that on board his ship they were paying their respects to the Hachiman shrine in acknowledgement of the similar occasion in ancient times when the Empress Jing had led an invasion of Korea. Toyotomi Hideyoshi was delighted.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 THE WAY OF THE GODS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/02_THE_WAY_OF_THE_GODS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/02_THE_WAY_OF_THE_GODS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;torii&lt;/em&gt; gateway under snow at the Shintō shrine on Mount Iimori, Aizu-Wakamatsu.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The worship of the &lt;em&gt;kami&lt;/em&gt; was practised for centuries before other religions entered the Japanese scene, and even to the most casual visitor to Japan today, ‘the way of the gods’ appears to have very ancient and deep-rooted foundations. The proliferation of Shintō shrines in Japan, their presence usually indicated by the presence of a &lt;em&gt;torii&lt;/em&gt; (a gateway in the shape of the Greek letter ‘pi’), leads any visitor to think that the religion &lt;em&gt;kami&lt;/em&gt; represent is a long-established, crucial element of Japanese culture, providing it with a distinctive religious system found nowhere else on earth. Just as in the example of Matsuura Shigenobu, the &lt;em&gt;kami&lt;/em&gt; are prayed to so that they will provide blessings of a this-world variety, such as success in exams and easy childbirth.1 On visiting a Shintō shrine people wash their hands and rinse their mouths in a sacred fountain. Coins are thrown into a box as an offering, and the bell is rung to summon the &lt;em&gt;kami&lt;/em&gt;. Hands are clapped and heads are bowed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 BUDDHA AND THE BUSHI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/03_BUDDHA_AND_THE_BUSHI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/03_BUDDHA_AND_THE_BUSHI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The association between Chinese culture and the Japanese imperial family of the Nara Period is beautifully illustrated here at the Zenkōji in Nagano. In this picture we see two &lt;em&gt;komainu&lt;/em&gt; (Chinese dogs) in front of a curtain bearing the imperial chrysanthemum.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The religion of Buddhism was founded in India by Skyamuni, an Indian prince who pondered on the nature of human suffering, which to him seemed to be everywhere. With his conclusion – that the reason for suffering was human desire, and that desire was itself illusory because, as nothing is permanent, nothing can ever be possessed – he achieved enlightenment and became Buddha (‘The Enlightened One’).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 THE GODS GO TO WAR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/04_THE_GODS_GO_TO_WAR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/04_THE_GODS_GO_TO_WAR/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nitta Yoshisada throws his sword into the sea as an offering to the gods during the battle of Kamakura in 1333. As a result of his prayer the tide pulled back and his army crossed on dry land.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Few passages in the &lt;em&gt;gunkimono&lt;/em&gt; (war tales) of Japan elicit a chuckle. With their concentration on the inevitable working out of remorseless fate against a background of the degenerate age of Buddhism, there is not much space for humour. One exception, albeit unintentionally, occurs in &lt;em&gt;Taiheiki&lt;/em&gt;, the epic chronicle of the 14th-century civil wars, when a reverse during the siege of Chihaya is attributed to, of all things, the losing side’s inability to write decent poetry:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 WARRIORS OF THE PURE LAND</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/05_WARRIORS_OF_THE_PURE_LAND/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/05_WARRIORS_OF_THE_PURE_LAND/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Komizucha, a warrior monk from Negorodera in Kii province, a temple of the Shingi (‘new meaning’) branch of the Shingon sect. The monks of Negorodera fought alongside the Ikkō-ikki against Oda Nobunaga and were early converts to firearm technology. This print illustrates the final defeat of Negorodera by Toyotomi Hideyoshi in 1585.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the degenerate age of &lt;em&gt;mappõ&lt;/em&gt; one message of hope was embraced above all others: the reassurance provided by the &lt;em&gt;hongan&lt;/em&gt; (original vow) of Amida Buddha not to attain Supreme Enlightenment so long as any human beings remained unsaved.1 On their death the faithful would be taken to him in the western paradise of the Jōdo (Pure Land). Amidism, as this belief is known, took root in Japan by the mid-7th century, and was given a new prominence by the deep pessimism of the Heian Period.2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 ONWARD, CHRISTIAN SAMURAI\!</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/06_ONWARD_CHRISTIAN_SAMURAI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/06_ONWARD_CHRISTIAN_SAMURAI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The classic image of the death-defying samurai swordsman, to whom the world of the sacred was an ever-present reality. A Christian samurai was no different from any other in his attitude to fighting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As mentioned throughout this book, not only do Japan’s various religious traditions intermingle, but the Japanese have always seemed content to take part in different religious rites. At the time of the samurai, foreign and indigenous elements were blended institutionally and ritually in a coherent whole that was largely cooperative. The anger of Nichiren was directed at those whom he reckoned had sullied the purity of the faith that otherwise they all so firmly maintained.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 THE SAMURAI AND THE SECRET</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/07_THE_SAMURAI_AND_THE_SECRET/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/07_THE_SAMURAI_AND_THE_SECRET/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The largely Christian Shimabara Rebellion of 1637–38 was the only serious challenge to be mounted against the rule of the Tokugawa in two and a half centuries. In this detail from the Shimabara Screen we note that inscriptions have been written on the inside of the walls. They are probably prayers to encourage the defenders. Above the planking wall is a wooden framework from which bamboo curtains have been suspended to hide the defenders from outside gaze. Women and children of the community are preparing a meal for the defenders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 ZEN AND THE SAMURAI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/08_ZEN_AND_THE_SAMURAI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/08_ZEN_AND_THE_SAMURAI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before the Tokugawa Period very few swordsmen were able to lift the art of the samurai sword on to a higher philosophical plane. The men who succeeded were the &lt;em&gt;kengõ&lt;/em&gt; (master swordsmen) like Miyamoto Musashi, who went on ‘warrior pilgrimages’ (&lt;em&gt;musha shgyõ).&lt;/em&gt; This painting of the great swordsman is in Kumamoto.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Throughout this book the point has been made that the world of the samurai and the world of the sacred were not opposing entities. Instead, the two aspects coalesced into one unitary world view. To the Western mind there is no better evidence of this fact than the link that is frequently made between the samurai and Zen Buddhism. To many outsiders Zen &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; Japanese religion, and is therefore used to explain everything about the samurai from the battlefield to the tea house. This chapter will show that Zen does not provide the sole answer to ‘what made the samurai tick’, neither in art nor in warfare. Other influences contributed to the complex nature of the samurai’s religious beliefs, and to the survival of the cultural legacy of the samurai and the sacred.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 THE WAYS OF THE WARRIOR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/09_THE_WAYS_OF_THE_WARRIOR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/09_THE_WAYS_OF_THE_WARRIOR/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The archetypal image of &lt;em&gt;bushidõ&lt;/em&gt;: a samurai fighting bravely among a fall of cherry blossom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just as Shintō means ‘the way of the gods’, so does the well-known expression &lt;em&gt;bushidõ&lt;/em&gt; mean ‘the way of the warrior’. There is a strange parallel between the emergence of the two terms. The word ‘Shintō’ was introduced to provide a label for something that had been going on for centuries and had required no name until it was felt necessary to distinguish it from something else. As noted earlier, scholars are divided as to whether this happened when Buddhism was introduced, or when the founding fathers of the Meiji government sought to create a new ideology. &lt;em&gt;Bushidõ&lt;/em&gt; has a similarly confusing genesis. No event was more important to its creation, development and dissemination than the publication as late as 1905 of a book called &lt;em&gt;Bushido: The Soul of Japan&lt;/em&gt;, written in English by Inazo Nitobe. It carries the subtitle ‘an exposition of Japanese thought’, and is widely regarded as a classic, particularly by people who have not actually read it.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 FROM SAMURAI TO SPIRIT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/10_FROM_SAMURAI_TO_SPIRIT/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/10_FROM_SAMURAI_TO_SPIRIT/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A dying samurai stands transfixed with a sword through his neck. This ghastly image sums up the horror of the ‘Realm of the Beasts’ that was the Japanese battlefield.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The birth pangs of modern Japan began during the last few years of the Tokugawa Shogunate when conflict arose over the future of Japan. The opening up of the ‘closed country’, forced upon the Shogunate by the arrival of Commodore Perry’s fleet in 1854, was a development that was far from welcome to many in Japanese society. Whereas the supporters of the Shogun cooperated with the Western nations by signing treaties and promoting trade, their opponents believed that his acquiescence to Western demands was a sign of weakness and a betrayal of traditional Japanese values. The perceived threats that this posed also brought out into the open many dissenters who had been dissatisfied in general terms with other policies followed by the Tokugawa family over the years. These people had their own ideas of how to face the new dangers posed by foreign nations, and soon came to believe that the main obstacle hindering the expulsion of the ‘barbarians’ was the continued existence of the Shogunate, which should be replaced by the restored rule of the emperor. Political opinion was profoundly divided, and was backed up by terrorist acts from both sides of the argument. Modern Japan was therefore born out of years of feuding and tension when samurai swords found many victims.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 EPILOGUE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/11_EPILOGUE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/11_EPILOGUE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mounted combat between two samurai.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It would be completely wrong to leave the reader with the impression that the image of the samurai and the sacred in modern Japan is manifested only through violence. The examples cited earlier of the Red Brigade and Aum Shinrikyō are aberrations, where the link between the samurai and the sacred has been seized upon and misused for political ends. The development of the martial arts as training for the mind and for the body, the appreciation of Japanese culture through Zen and other artistic expression, is the sacred legacy to which we must cling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 ENDNOTES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/12_ENDNOTES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/12_ENDNOTES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 From &lt;em&gt;Matsuura Hõin Seiken Nikki&lt;/em&gt; in Kuwada et al. (eds), &lt;em&gt;Chõsen no eki&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Nihon no Senshi&lt;/em&gt;, Vol.5), Tokyo (1965) p.252.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Kuroda, Toshio, ‘The Discourse on the “Land of the Kami” (shinkoku) in Medieval Japan: National Consciousness and International Awareness’, &lt;em&gt;Japanese Journal of Religious Studies&lt;/em&gt;, 23 (1996) pp.353–385.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3 Hori, Ichiro et al., &lt;em&gt;Japanese Religion: A Survey by the Agency for Cultural Affairs&lt;/em&gt;, Tokyo (1972) p.12.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4 For two different interpretations of the Jing myth see Arima, Toshio, ‘The Myth of the Goddess of the Undersea World and the Tale of Empress Jing’s Subjugation of Silla’, &lt;em&gt;Japanese Journal of Religious Studies&lt;/em&gt;, 20 (1993) pp.95–185; and Allen, Chizuko, ‘Empress Jing: a Shamaness Ruler in Early Japan’, &lt;em&gt;Japan Forum&lt;/em&gt;, 15 (2003) pp.81–98.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 SELECT BIBLIOGRAPHY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/13_SELECT_BIBLIOGRAPHY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/13_SELECT_BIBLIOGRAPHY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Adolphson, Michael, &lt;em&gt;The Gates of Power: Monks, Courtiers and Warriors in Premodern Japan&lt;/em&gt;, Honolulu (2000)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Antoni, Klaus, ‘The “Separation of Gods and Buddhas” at Omiwa Jinja in Meiji Japan’, &lt;em&gt;Japanese Journal of Religious Studies&lt;/em&gt;, 22 (1995) pp.139–159&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bitō, Masahide, ‘The Akō Incident (1701–1703)’, &lt;em&gt;Monumenta Nipponica&lt;/em&gt;, 58 (2003) pp.149–169&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Boxer, Charles, &lt;em&gt;The Christian Century in Japan 1549–1650&lt;/em&gt;, Manchester (1951)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Breen, John and Teeuwen, Mark (eds), &lt;em&gt;Shinto in History: Ways of the Kami&lt;/em&gt;, Richmond (2000)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 GLOSSARY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/14_GLOSSARY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/samurai-sacred/14_GLOSSARY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amaterasu&lt;/strong&gt; the Shintō ‘Sun-Goddess’   &lt;strong&gt;ankokuji&lt;/strong&gt; temples for the war dead   &lt;strong&gt;bosatsu&lt;/strong&gt; a bodhisattva; one who is dedicated to assisting all sentient&lt;br&gt;&#xA;beings achieve complete Buddhahood   &lt;strong&gt;bushidō&lt;/strong&gt; the way of the warrior   &lt;strong&gt;butsudan&lt;/strong&gt; family Buddhist altar   &lt;strong&gt;chadō&lt;/strong&gt; the way of tea   &lt;strong&gt;ch&lt;/strong&gt; loyalty   &lt;strong&gt;daimyō&lt;/strong&gt; warlord   &lt;strong&gt;Dainichi&lt;/strong&gt; the ‘great’ or ‘central’ Buddha   &lt;strong&gt;danka&lt;/strong&gt; temple registration system under the Tokugawa   &lt;strong&gt;dog&lt;/strong&gt; clay figures of females dating from the Jōmon Period   &lt;strong&gt;dōtaku&lt;/strong&gt; bronze bell-shaped artefacts dating from the Yayoi Period   &lt;strong&gt;eboshi&lt;/strong&gt; a cap worn by courtiers and samurai   &lt;strong&gt;feng shui&lt;/strong&gt; Chinese geomancy   &lt;strong&gt;Four Noble Truths&lt;/strong&gt; the fundamental insight or enlightenment of Buddha, relating to the existence of suffering and its cessation   &lt;strong&gt;fumi-e&lt;/strong&gt; image trampling to reveal secret Christians   &lt;strong&gt;goryō shinkō&lt;/strong&gt; vengeful spirits   &lt;strong&gt;goshintai&lt;/strong&gt; the object that houses a &lt;em&gt;kami&lt;/em&gt; in a shrine   &lt;strong&gt;gunkimono&lt;/strong&gt; war tales   &lt;strong&gt;Hachiman&lt;/strong&gt; the Shintō god of war   &lt;strong&gt;hondō&lt;/strong&gt; the main hall of a Buddhist temple   &lt;strong&gt;hongan&lt;/strong&gt; original vow of Amida Buddha   &lt;strong&gt;honji suijaku&lt;/strong&gt; theory that Buddha manifested himself as the &lt;em&gt;kami&lt;/em&gt;   &lt;strong&gt;ihai&lt;/strong&gt; memorial tablet   &lt;strong&gt;jing&lt;/strong&gt;-&lt;strong&gt;ji&lt;/strong&gt; shrine/temple complex   &lt;strong&gt;jinja&lt;/strong&gt; a Shintō shrine   &lt;strong&gt;junshi&lt;/strong&gt; following in death by suicide   &lt;strong&gt;kaihyōgō&lt;/strong&gt; ‘marathon’ pilgrimage on Mount Hiei   &lt;strong&gt;Kakure Kirishitan&lt;/strong&gt; Hidden Christians   &lt;strong&gt;kami&lt;/strong&gt; gods of Shintō   &lt;strong&gt;kami kaze&lt;/strong&gt; divine wind   &lt;strong&gt;kamidana&lt;/strong&gt; god shelf in the home   &lt;strong&gt;kannushi&lt;/strong&gt; a Shintō priest   &lt;strong&gt;kare-sansui&lt;/strong&gt; dry landscape garden   &lt;strong&gt;kata&lt;/strong&gt; style or form   &lt;strong&gt;kengō&lt;/strong&gt; master swordsman   &lt;strong&gt;Kirishitan&lt;/strong&gt; Christian of the 16th century   &lt;strong&gt;kō&lt;/strong&gt; filial piety   &lt;strong&gt;kōan&lt;/strong&gt; theme or problem in Zen   &lt;strong&gt;kofun&lt;/strong&gt; large burial mounds   &lt;strong&gt;kokugaku&lt;/strong&gt; national learning   &lt;strong&gt;kydō&lt;/strong&gt; Japanese archery   &lt;strong&gt;mandala&lt;/strong&gt; artistic presentation of Buddhism   &lt;strong&gt;mappō&lt;/strong&gt; age of descent into chaos   &lt;strong&gt;matsuri&lt;/strong&gt; Shintō shrine festival   &lt;strong&gt;mikkyō&lt;/strong&gt; esoteric Buddhism   &lt;strong&gt;mikoshi&lt;/strong&gt; portable shrine   &lt;strong&gt;monto&lt;/strong&gt; disciple or believer   &lt;strong&gt;mujō&lt;/strong&gt; impermanence of all phenomena   &lt;strong&gt;musha shgyō&lt;/strong&gt; warrior pilgrimage   &lt;strong&gt;nembutsu&lt;/strong&gt; invoking Amida’s name in prayer   &lt;strong&gt;norito&lt;/strong&gt; Shintō prayers   &lt;strong&gt;onryō&lt;/strong&gt; angry ghost   &lt;strong&gt;rōnin&lt;/strong&gt; masterless samurai   &lt;strong&gt;sabi&lt;/strong&gt; appreciation of that which is old, faded and rustic   &lt;strong&gt;senpuku Kirishitan&lt;/strong&gt; secret Christians under the Tokugawa   &lt;strong&gt;seppuku&lt;/strong&gt; suicide by disembowelment (&lt;em&gt;hara kiri&lt;/em&gt;)   &lt;strong&gt;shaku&lt;/strong&gt; the wooden wand carried by Shintō priests   &lt;strong&gt;shikken&lt;/strong&gt; regency   &lt;strong&gt;shimenawa&lt;/strong&gt; the rope used to enclose sacred spaces in Shintō   &lt;strong&gt;shintai&lt;/strong&gt; same as &lt;em&gt;goshintai&lt;/em&gt;   &lt;strong&gt;Shintō&lt;/strong&gt; religious system concerned with the worship of &lt;em&gt;kami&lt;/em&gt;   &lt;strong&gt;Shogun&lt;/strong&gt; the military dictator of Japan from 1192 to 1868   &lt;strong&gt;shōji&lt;/strong&gt; sliding paper screens   &lt;strong&gt;sōhei&lt;/strong&gt; warrior monk or priest soldier   &lt;strong&gt;sutra&lt;/strong&gt; Buddhist scriptures   &lt;strong&gt;Taoism&lt;/strong&gt; a belief system formulated in China by Laozi in the 5th century BC   &lt;strong&gt;torii&lt;/strong&gt; shrine gateway in the shape of the Greek letter ‘pi’   &lt;strong&gt;ujiko&lt;/strong&gt; shrine adherents   &lt;strong&gt;wabi&lt;/strong&gt; quietness and tranquillity   &lt;strong&gt;yamabushi&lt;/strong&gt; mountain ascetic   &lt;strong&gt;yamato damashii&lt;/strong&gt; spirit of Japan   &lt;strong&gt;ygen&lt;/strong&gt; mystery   &lt;strong&gt;zazen&lt;/strong&gt; sitting in meditation&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
