<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Rjrasva on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/rjrasva/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Rjrasva on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/rjrasva/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Oil</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/rjrasva/oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/rjrasva/oil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ww1&#34;&gt;WW1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Senator Bérenger warned Prime Minister Georges Clemenceau that the country would run out of oil by March 1918 just when the next spring offensive was set to begin. Supplies were so low that France could sustain no more than three days of heavy German attacks, such as those experienced at Verdun, where massive convoys of trucks had been needed to rush reserves to the front and hold off the German assault. On December 15, 1917, Clemenceau urgently appealed to President Wilson that an additional hundred thousand tons of tanker capacity be made immediately available. Declaring that gasoline was &amp;ldquo;as vital as blood in the coming battles,&amp;rdquo; he told Wilson that &amp;ldquo;a failure in the supply of gasoline would cause the immediate paralysis of our armies.&amp;rdquo; He ominously added that a shortage might even &amp;ldquo;compel us to a peace unfavorable to the Allies.” Wilson responded quickly, and the necessary tonnage was swiftly made available.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rail</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/rjrasva/rail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/rjrasva/rail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Rjrasva/status/1739658973135954344&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dunkirk evac wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been possible without rail.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Bulk of freight &amp;amp; troop movement in US was rail.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Rail was so imp in USSR that Stalin created special medals for rail workers.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Even today rail is very imp for Rus military efforts, the Russian military maintain what are called Railway troops who specialize in building, restoring, &amp;amp; operating rail during war.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In WW2 US produced 6 of 7 billion barrels of oil consumed by allies &amp;amp; had domestic oil production 700 times Japan&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Last I checked almost all light &amp;amp; heavy road vehicles run on diesel or gas while trains can run on coal or electricity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
