<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Goubert peasants - regional example</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/goubert_peasants_regional-eg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/goubert_peasants_regional-eg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE FRENCH PEASANTRY OF THE SEVENTEENTH CENTURY: A Regional Example*&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Goubert&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Translated by G. Rudé.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 C:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE SEVENTEENTH CENTURY IS TERRA INCOGNITA AS FAR AS THE land is concerned,&amp;quot; wrote Marc Bloch in 1942, to explain a &amp;ldquo;sad deficiency&amp;rdquo; in his Caractères Originaux. For England and the Netherlands this is no longer true. But Marc Bloch was thinking only of France, and there his remark remains valid and will do so until Jean Meuvret publishes his great work on Le Problème des Subsistances au temps de Louis XIV, the first volume of which will deal with agriculture and rural society throughout the kingdom of France.&amp;quot; My intention in the present study is more modest and more limited in scope. I propose to examine rural society in a fairly small region, the Beauvaisis.&amp;rsquo; The Beauvaisis forms a link between the great cereal-producing plains of Picardy, semi-pastoral Normandy, and the rich and varied lands of the Ile-de-France. This region had already by the seventeenth century acquired a degree of unity, by virtue of its past history (it corresponds to the old civitas Bellovacorum), and of the predominating influence exerted on it by the town of Beauvais, its regional capital, which was then of some importance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
