<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;2 Becoming Genghis Khan on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/2_Becoming_Genghis_Khan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;2 Becoming Genghis Khan on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/2_Becoming_Genghis_Khan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>5 Messenger of Light</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/2_Becoming_Genghis_Khan/5_Messenger_of_Light/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/2_Becoming_Genghis_Khan/5_Messenger_of_Light/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the nearly twenty-five years he spent consolidating the steppe tribes and bringing them under his leadership, Temujin had encountered no khan worthy of imitation, no successful ideal to follow, no contemporary heroes who could compare with the near mythical glory of the ancient Hun and Turkic khans. He had seen little to emulate in the courts of Ong Khan and Tayang Khan, but the one thing that had caught his attention was the importance of writing. It enshrined laws and seemed to offer both a connection to the past and the promise of future recognition. Led by the desire to create a writing system for his emerging nation, Temujin ended up connecting the Mongols to one of the most unusual cultural and religious traditions in the world. It would play a crucial role in the political and spiritual orientation of his future empire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Jesus of the Steppe</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/2_Becoming_Genghis_Khan/6_Jesus_of_the_Steppe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/2_Becoming_Genghis_Khan/6_Jesus_of_the_Steppe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After Ong Khan fled and was killed by his Naiman enemies, Temujin installed Jaqa Gambu, Ong Khan’s younger brother and frequent rival, as a khan over the Kereyid. At first, he allowed the Kereyid a loose rein under their new khan. Although he had killed most of the aristocratic men who had fought against him, he recognized something unique and useful in their women. The Naiman and Kereyid women were some of the most sophisticated and cosmopolitan women he had encountered. They were very much women of the steppe—riding horses, shooting arrows, drinking fermented mare’s milk, and participating fully in political life—but their Christian faith gave them knowledge of a world beyond the steppe and connected them to some of the most important centers of civilization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 The Making of the Mongol Nation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/2_Becoming_Genghis_Khan/7_The_Making_of_the_Mongol_Nation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/2_Becoming_Genghis_Khan/7_The_Making_of_the_Mongol_Nation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With an alphabet and an army, Temujin was ready to create a nation. To mark a distinctly new beginning he chose a short, yet august, title for himself. He had no interest in the traditional title &lt;em&gt;Gurkhan&lt;/em&gt; because too many wicked men with that title had come to bad ends, and in the words of a Christian priest, “its glory was forever tarnished.”1 Instead, he chose to call himself &lt;em&gt;Chinggis&lt;/em&gt;, a new Mongol title that represented firmness, strength, constancy, and commitment—some of the same qualities suggested by his name, Temujin. The Mongolian word &lt;em&gt;chin&lt;/em&gt; meant “determined” or “strong willed,” so he became the “Sovereign of the Strong” or “Khan of the Strong.” The earliest Chinese mention of his title, in a 1221 report to the Sung monarch by his envoy Chao Hung, says that his title meant “granted by Heaven.”2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Guardians of the Flame</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/2_Becoming_Genghis_Khan/8_Guardians_of_the_Flame/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/2_Becoming_Genghis_Khan/8_Guardians_of_the_Flame/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;History shows repeatedly that one person, no matter how strong or dedicated, cannot exercise total control. Often rulers rely on their family to extend their reach, suspicious of all outsiders, but having been betrayed repeatedly by his relatives, Genghis Khan turned instead to a small circle of close companions known as the &lt;em&gt;Nokor&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Nökör&lt;/em&gt;). The &lt;em&gt;Nokor&lt;/em&gt; were mostly men he had known before the founding of the nation whose loyalty had proven unshakable. They usually came from lower-ranking clans and had joined him at a young age, sometimes with the consent of their families, but some had run away from home to join him, proving that their loyalty to him was greater than to their families. Like self-made men in many societies, they honored achievement and disparaged birth and nobility. They owed their success to bravery, discipline, and total commitment to their fellow warriors and to Genghis Khan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
