<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;lectures from colombo to almora on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;lectures from colombo to almora on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>125 FIRST PUBLIC LECTURE IN THE EAST</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/125_first_public_lecture_in_the_east_%28colombo%29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/125_first_public_lecture_in_the_east_%28colombo%29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-public-lecture-in-the-east&#34;&gt;FIRST PUBLIC LECTURE IN THE EAST&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in Colombo&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After his memorable work in the West, Swami Vivekananda landed at&#xA;Colombo on the afternoon of January 15, 1897, and was given a right&#xA;royal reception by the Hindu community there. The following address of&#xA;welcome was then presented to him:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SRIMAT VIVEKANANDA SWAMI&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;REVERED SIR,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In pursuance of a resolution passed at a public meeting of the Hindus of&#xA;the city of Colombo, we beg to offer you a hearty welcome to this&#xA;Island. We deem it a privilege to be the first to welcome you on your&#xA;return home from your great mission in the West.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>126 VEDANTISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/126_vedantism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/126_vedantism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vedantism&#34;&gt;VEDANTISM&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following address of welcome from the Hindus of Jaffna was presented&#xA;to Swami Vivekananda:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SRIMAT VIVEKANANDA SWAMI&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;REVERED SIR,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We, the inhabitants of Jaffna professing the Hindu religion, desire to&#xA;offer you a most hearty welcome to our land, the chief centre of&#xA;Hinduism in Ceylon, and to express our thankfulness for your kind&#xA;acceptance of our invitation to visit this part of Lanka.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our ancestors settled here from Southern India, more than two thousand&#xA;years ago, and brought with them their religion, which was patronised by&#xA;the Tamil kings of Jaffna; but when their government was displaced by&#xA;that of the Portuguese and the Dutch, the observance of religious rites&#xA;was interfered with, public religious worship was prohibited, and the&#xA;Sacred Temples, including two of the most far-famed Shrines, were razed&#xA;to the ground by the cruel hand of persecution. In spite of the&#xA;persistent attempts of these nations to force upon our forefathers the&#xA;Christian religion, they clung to their old faith firmly, and have&#xA;transmitted it to us as the noblest of our heritages Now under the rule&#xA;of Great Britain, not only has there been a great and intelligent&#xA;revival, but the sacred edifices have been, and are being, restored.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>127 REPLY TO THE ADDRESS OF WELCOME AT PAMBAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/127_reply_to_the_address_of_welcome_at_pamban/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/127_reply_to_the_address_of_welcome_at_pamban/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply-to-the-address-of-welcome-at-pamban&#34;&gt;REPLY TO THE ADDRESS OF WELCOME AT PAMBAN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the arrival of Swami Vivekananda at Pamban, he was met by His&#xA;Highness the Raja of Ramnad, who accorded him a hearty welcome.&#xA;Preparations had been made at the landing wharf for a formal reception;&#xA;and here, under a pandal which had been decorated with great taste, the&#xA;following address on behalf of the Pamban people was read:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MAY IT PLEASE YOUR HOLINESS,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>128 ADDRESS AT THE RAMESWARAM TEMPLE ON REAL WORSHIP</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/128_address_at_the_rameshwaram_temple_on_real_worship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/128_address_at_the_rameshwaram_temple_on_real_worship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;address-at-the-rameswaram-temple-on-real-worship&#34;&gt;ADDRESS AT THE RAMESWARAM TEMPLE ON REAL WORSHIP&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A visit was subsequently paid to the Rameswaram Temple, where the Swami&#xA;was asked to address a few words to the people who had assembled there.&#xA;This he did in the following terms:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is in love that religion exists and not in ceremony, in the pure and&#xA;sincere love in the heart. Unless a man is pure in body and mind, his&#xA;coming into a temple and worshipping Shiva is useless. The prayers of&#xA;those that are pure in mind and body will be answered by Shiva, and&#xA;those that are impure and yet try to teach religion to others will fail&#xA;in the end. External worship is only a symbol of internal worship; but&#xA;internal worship and purity are the real things. Without them, external&#xA;worship would be of no avail. Therefore you must all try to remember&#xA;this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>129 REPLY TO THE ADDRESS OF WELCOME AT RAMNAD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/129_reply_to_the_address_of_welcome_at_ramnad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/129_reply_to_the_address_of_welcome_at_ramnad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply-to-the-address-of-welcome-at-ramnad&#34;&gt;REPLY TO THE ADDRESS OF WELCOME AT RAMNAD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At Ramnad the following address was presented to Swami Vivekananda by&#xA;the Raja:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;His Most Holiness,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sri Paramahamsa, Yati-Rāja, Digvijaya-Kolāhala, Sarvamata-Sampratipanna,&#xA;Parama-Yogeeswara, Srimat Bhagavān Sree Ramakrishna Paramahamsa&#xA;Karakamala Sanjāta, Rājādhirāja-Sevita, SREE VIVEKANANDA SWAMI, MAY IT&#xA;PLEASE YOUR HOLINESS,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We, the inhabitants of this ancient and historic Samsthānam of Sethu&#xA;Bandha Rameswaram, otherwise known as Rāmanāthapuram or Ramnad, beg,&#xA;most cordially, to welcome you to this, our motherland. We deem it a&#xA;very rare privilege to be the first to pay your Holiness our heartfelt&#xA;homage on your landing in India, and that, on the shores sanctified by&#xA;the footsteps of that great Hero and our revered Lord — Sree Bhagavān&#xA;Rāmachandra.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>130 REPLY TO THE ADDRESS OF WELCOME AT PARAMAKUDI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/130_reply_to_the_address_of_welcome_at_paramakudi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/130_reply_to_the_address_of_welcome_at_paramakudi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply-to-the-address-of-welcome-at-paramakudi&#34;&gt;REPLY TO THE ADDRESS OF WELCOME AT PARAMAKUDI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paramakudi was the first stopping-place after leaving Ramnad, and there&#xA;was a demonstration on a large scale, including the presentation of the&#xA;following address:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SREEMAT VIVEKANANDA SWAMI&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We, the citizens of Paramakudi, respectfully beg to accord your Holiness&#xA;a most hearty welcome to this place after your successful spiritual&#xA;campaign of nearly four years in the Western world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We share with our countrymen the feelings of joy and pride at the&#xA;philanthropy which prompted you to attend the Parliament of Religions&#xA;held at Chicago, and lay before the representatives of the religious&#xA;world the sacred but hidden treasures of our ancient land. You have by&#xA;your wide exposition of the sacred truths contained in the Vedic&#xA;literature disabused the enlightened minds of the West of the prejudices&#xA;entertained by them against our ancient faith, and convinced them of its&#xA;universality and adaptability for intellects of all shades and in all&#xA;ages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>131 REPLY TO THE ADDRESS OF WELCOME AT SHIVAGANGA AND MANAMADURA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/131_reply_to_the_address_of_welcome_at_shivaganga_and_manamadura/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/131_reply_to_the_address_of_welcome_at_shivaganga_and_manamadura/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply-to-the-address-of-welcome-at-shivaganga-and-manamadura&#34;&gt;REPLY TO THE ADDRESS OF WELCOME AT SHIVAGANGA AND MANAMADURA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At Manamadura, the following address of welcome from the Zemindars and&#xA;citizens of Shivaganga and Manamadura was presented to the Swami:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TO SRI SWAMI VIVEKANANDA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MOST REVERED SIR,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We, the Zemindars and citizens of Shivaganga and Manamadura, beg to&#xA;offer you a most hearty welcome. In the most sanguine moments of our&#xA;life, in our widest dreams, we never contemplated that you, who were so&#xA;near our hearts, would be in such close proximity to our homes. The&#xA;first wire intimating your inability to come to Shivaganga cast a deep&#xA;gloom on our hearts, and but for the subsequent silver lining to the&#xA;cloud our disappointment would have been extreme. When we first heard&#xA;that you had consented to honour our town with your presence, we thought&#xA;we had realised our highest ambition. The mountain promised to come to&#xA;Mohammed, and our joy knew no bounds. But when the mountain was obliged&#xA;to withdraw its consent, and our worst fears were roused that we might&#xA;not be able even to go to the mountain, you were graciously pleased to&#xA;give way to our importunities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>132 REPLY TO THE ADDRESS OF WELCOME AT MADURA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/132_reply_to_the_address_of_welcome_at_madura/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/132_reply_to_the_address_of_welcome_at_madura/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply-to-the-address-of-welcome-at-madura&#34;&gt;REPLY TO THE ADDRESS OF WELCOME AT MADURA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Spelt now as Madurai)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Swami was presented with an address of welcome by the Hindus of&#xA;Madura, which read as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MOST REVERED SWAMI,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We, the Hindu Public of Madura, beg to offer you our most heartfelt and&#xA;respectful welcome to our ancient and holy city. We realise in you a&#xA;living example of the Hindu Sannyasin, who, renouncing all worldly ties&#xA;and attachments calculated to lead to the gratification of the self, is&#xA;worthily engaged in the noble duty of living for others and endeavouring&#xA;to raise the spiritual condition of mankind. You have demonstrated in&#xA;your own person that the true essence of the Hindu religion is not&#xA;necessarily bound up with rules and rituals, but that it is a sublime&#xA;philosophy capable of giving peace and solace to the distressed and&#xA;afflicted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>133 THE MISSION OF THE VEDANTA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/133_the_mission_of_the_vedanta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/133_the_mission_of_the_vedanta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-mission-of-the-vedanta&#34;&gt;THE MISSION OF THE VEDANTA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the occasion of his visit to Kumbakonam, the Swamiji was presented&#xA;with the following address by the local Hindu community:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;REVERED SWAMIN,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On behalf of the Hindu inhabitants of this ancient and religiously&#xA;important town of Kumbakonam, we request permission to offer you a most&#xA;hearty welcome on your return from the Western World to our own holy&#xA;land of great temples and famous saints and sages. We are highly&#xA;thankful to God for the remarkable success of your religious mission in&#xA;America and in Europe, and for His having enabled you to impress upon&#xA;the choicest representatives of the world&amp;rsquo;s great religions assembled at&#xA;Chicago that both the Hindu philosophy and religion are so broad and so&#xA;rationally catholic as to have in them the power to exalt and to&#xA;harmonise all ideas of God and of human spirituality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>134 REPLY TO THE ADDRESS OF WELCOME AT MADRAS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/134_reply_to_the_address_of_welcome_at_madras/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/134_reply_to_the_address_of_welcome_at_madras/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reply-to-the-address-of-welcome-at-madras&#34;&gt;REPLY TO THE ADDRESS OF WELCOME AT MADRAS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the Swami Vivekananda arrived at Madras an address of welcome was&#xA;presented to him by the Madras Reception Committee. It read as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;REVERED SWAMIN,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On behalf of your Hindu co-religionists in Madras, we offer you a most&#xA;hearty welcome on the occasion of your return from your Religious&#xA;Mission in the West. Our object in approaching you with this address is&#xA;not the performance of any merely formal or ceremonial function; we come&#xA;to offer you the love of our hearts and to give expression to our&#xA;feeling of thankfulness for the services which you, by the grace of God,&#xA;have been able to render to the great cause of Truth by proclaiming&#xA;India&amp;rsquo;s lofty religious ideals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>135 MY PLAN OF CAMPAIGN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/135_my_plan_of_campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/135_my_plan_of_campaign/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-plan-of-campaign&#34;&gt;MY PLAN OF CAMPAIGN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at the Victoria Hall, Madras&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the other day we could not proceed, owing to the crowd, I shall take&#xA;this opportunity of thanking the people of Madras for the uniform&#xA;kindness that I have received at their hands. I do not know how better&#xA;to express my gratitude for the beautiful words that have been expressed&#xA;in the addresses than by praying to the Lord to make me worthy of the&#xA;kind and generous expressions and by working all my life for the cause&#xA;of our religion and to serve our motherland; and may the Lord make me&#xA;worthy of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>136 VEDANTA IN ITS APPLICATION TO INDIAN LIFE </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/136_vedanta_in_its_applications_to_indian_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/136_vedanta_in_its_applications_to_indian_life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vedanta-in-its-application-to-indian-life&#34;&gt;VEDANTA IN ITS APPLICATION TO INDIAN LIFE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a word which has become very common as an appellation of our&#xA;race and our religion. The word &amp;ldquo;Hindu&amp;rdquo; requires a little explanation in&#xA;connection with what I mean by Vedantism. This word &amp;ldquo;Hindu&amp;rdquo; was the name&#xA;that the ancient Persians used to apply to the river Sindhu. Whenever in&#xA;Sanskrit there is an &amp;ldquo;s&amp;rdquo;, in ancient Persian it changes into &amp;ldquo;h&amp;rdquo;, so&#xA;that &amp;ldquo;Sindhu&amp;rdquo; became &amp;ldquo;Hindu&amp;rdquo;; and you are all aware how the Greeks found&#xA;it hard to pronounce &amp;ldquo;h&amp;rdquo; and dropped it altogether, so that we became&#xA;known as Indians. Now this word &amp;ldquo;Hindu&amp;rdquo; as applied to the inhabitants of&#xA;the other side of the Indus, whatever might have been its meaning in&#xA;ancient times has lost all its force in modern times; for all the people&#xA;that live on this side of the Indus no longer belong to one religion.&#xA;There are the Hindus proper, the Mohammedans, the Parsees, the&#xA;Christians, the Buddhists, and Jains. The word &amp;ldquo;Hindu&amp;rdquo; in its literal&#xA;sense ought to include all these; but as signifying the religion, it&#xA;would not be proper to call all these Hindus. It is very hard,&#xA;therefore, to find any common name for our religion, seeing that this&#xA;religion is a collection, so to speak, of various religions, of various&#xA;ideas, of various ceremonials and forms, all gathered together almost&#xA;without a name, and without a church, and without an organisation. The&#xA;only point where, perhaps, all our sects agree is that we all believe in&#xA;the scriptures — the Vedas. This perhaps is certain that no man can have&#xA;a right to be called a Hindu who does not admit the supreme authority of&#xA;the Vedas. All these Vedas, as you are aware, are divided into two&#xA;portions — the Karma Kānda and the Jnāna Kānda. The Karma Kanda includes&#xA;various sacrifices and ceremonials, of which the larger part has fallen&#xA;into disuse in the present age. The Jnana Kanda, as embodying the&#xA;spiritual teachings of the Vedas known as the Upanishads and the&#xA;Vedanta, has always been cited as the highest authority by all our&#xA;teachers, philosophers, and writers, whether dualist, or qualified&#xA;monist, or monist. Whatever be his philosophy or sect, every one in&#xA;India has to find his authority in the Upanishads. If he cannot, his&#xA;sect would be heterodox. Therefore, perhaps the one name in modern times&#xA;which would designate every Hindu throughout the land would be&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Vedantist&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Vaidika&amp;rdquo;, as you may put it; and in that sense I always&#xA;use the words &amp;ldquo;Vedantism&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Vedanta&amp;rdquo;. I want to make it a little&#xA;clearer, for of late it has become the custom of most people to identify&#xA;the word Vedanta with the Advaitic system of the Vedanta philosophy. We&#xA;all know that Advaitism is only one branch of the various philosophic&#xA;systems that have been founded on the Upanishads. The followers of the&#xA;Vishishtādvaitic system have as much reverence for the Upanishads as the&#xA;followers of the Advaita, and the Vishishtadvaitists claim as much&#xA;authority for the Vedanta as the Advaitist. So do the dualists; so does&#xA;every other sect in India. But the word Vedantist has become somewhat&#xA;identified in the popular mind with the word Advaitist, and perhaps with&#xA;some reason, because, although we have the Vedas for our scriptures, we&#xA;have Smritis and Purānas — subsequent writings — to illustrate the&#xA;doctrines of the Vedas; these of course have not the same weight as the&#xA;Vedas. And the law is that wherever these Puranas and Smritis differ&#xA;from any part of the Shruti, the Shruti must be followed and the Smriti&#xA;rejected. Now in the expositions of the great Advaitic philosopher&#xA;Shankara, and the school founded by him, we find most of the authorities&#xA;cited are from the Upanishads, very rarely is an authority cited from&#xA;the Smritis, except, perhaps, to elucidate a point which could hardly be&#xA;found in the Shrutis. On the other hand, other schools take refuge more&#xA;and more in the Smritis and less and less in the Shrutis; and as we go&#xA;to the more and more dualistic sects, we find a proportionate quantity&#xA;of the Smritis quoted, which is out of all proportion to what we should&#xA;expect from a Vedantist. It is, perhaps, because these gave such&#xA;predominance to the Paurānika authorities that the Advaitist came to be&#xA;considered as the Vedantist &lt;em&gt;par excellence&lt;/em&gt;, if I may say so.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>137 THE SAGES OF INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/137_the_sages_of_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/137_the_sages_of_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-sages-of-india&#34;&gt;THE SAGES OF INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In speaking of the sages of India, my mind goes back to those periods of&#xA;which history has no record, and tradition tries in vain to bring the&#xA;secrets out of the gloom of the past. The sages of India have been&#xA;almost innumerable, for what has the Hindu nation been doing for&#xA;thousands of years except producing sages? I will take, therefore, the&#xA;lives of a few of the most brilliant ones, the epoch-makers, and present&#xA;them before you, that is to say, my study of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>138 THE WORK BEFORE US</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/138_the_work_before_us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/138_the_work_before_us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-work-before-us&#34;&gt;THE WORK BEFORE US&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at the Triplicane Literary Society, Madras&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem of life is becoming deeper and broader every day as the&#xA;world moves on. The watchword and the essence have been preached in the&#xA;days of yore when the Vedantic truth was first discovered, the&#xA;solidarity of all life. One atom in this universe cannot move without&#xA;dragging the whole world along with it. There cannot be any progress&#xA;without the whole world following in the wake, and it is becoming every&#xA;day dearer that the solution of any problem can never be attained on&#xA;racial, or national, or narrow grounds. Every idea has to become broad&#xA;till it covers the whole of this world, every aspiration must go on&#xA;increasing till it has engulfed the whole of humanity, nay, the whole of&#xA;life, within its scope. This will explain why our country for the last&#xA;few centuries has not been what she was in the past. We find that one of&#xA;the causes which led to this degeneration was the narrowing of our views&#xA;narrowing the scope of our actions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>139 THE FUTURE OF INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/139_the_future_of_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/139_the_future_of_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-future-of-india&#34;&gt;THE FUTURE OF INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the ancient land where wisdom made its home before it went into&#xA;any other country, the same India whose influx of spirituality is&#xA;represented, as it were, on the material plane, by rolling rivers like&#xA;oceans, where the eternal Himalayas, rising tier above tier with their&#xA;snowcaps, look as it were into the very mysteries of heaven. Here is the&#xA;same India whose soil has been trodden by the feet of the greatest sages&#xA;that ever lived. Here first sprang up inquiries into the nature of man&#xA;and into the internal world. Here first arose the doctrines of the&#xA;immortality of the soul, the existence of a supervising God, an immanent&#xA;God in nature and in man, and here the highest ideals of religion and&#xA;philosophy have attained their culminating points. This is the land from&#xA;whence, like the tidal waves, spirituality and philosophy have again and&#xA;again rushed out and deluged the world, and this is the land from whence&#xA;once more such tides must proceed in order to bring life and vigour into&#xA;the decaying races of mankind. It is the same India which has withstood&#xA;the shocks of centuries, of hundreds of foreign invasions of hundreds of&#xA;upheavals of manners and customs. It is the same land which stands&#xA;firmer than any rock in the world, with its undying vigour,&#xA;indestructible life. Its life is of the same nature as the soul, without&#xA;beginning and without end, immortal; and we are the children of such a&#xA;country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>140 ON CHARITY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/140_on_charity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/140_on_charity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-charity&#34;&gt;ON CHARITY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During his stay in Madras the Swami presided at the annual meeting of&#xA;the Chennapuri Annadāna Samājam, an institution of a charitable nature,&#xA;and in the course of a brief address referred to a remark by a previous&#xA;speaker deprecating special alms-giving to the Brahmin over and above&#xA;the other castes. Swamiji pointed out that this had its good as well as&#xA;its bad side. All the culture, practically which the nation possessed,&#xA;was among the Brahmins, and they also had been the thinkers of the&#xA;nation. Take away the means of living which enabled them to be thinkers,&#xA;and the nation as a whole would suffer. Speaking of the indiscriminate&#xA;charity of India as compared with the legal charity of other nations, he&#xA;said, the outcome of their system of relief was that the vagabond of&#xA;India was contented to receive readily what he was given readily and&#xA;lived a peaceful and contented life: while the vagabond in the West,&#xA;unwilling to go to the poor-house — for man loves liberty more than food&#xA;— turned a robber, the enemy of society, and necessitated the&#xA;organisation of a system of magistracy, police, jails, and other&#xA;establishments. Poverty there must be, so long as the disease known as&#xA;civilisation existed: and hence the need for relief. So that they had to&#xA;choose between the indiscriminate charity of India, which, in the case&#xA;of Sannyāsins at any rate, even if they were not sincere men, at least&#xA;forced them to learn some little of their scriptures before they were&#xA;able to obtain food; and the discriminate charity of Western nations&#xA;which necessitated a costly system of poor-law relief, and in the end&#xA;succeeded only in changing mendicants into criminals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>141 ADDRESS OF WELCOME PRESENTED AT CALCUTTA AND REPLY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/141_address_of_welcome_presented_at_calcutta_and_reply/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/141_address_of_welcome_presented_at_calcutta_and_reply/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;address-of-welcome-presented-at-calcutta-and-reply&#34;&gt;ADDRESS OF WELCOME PRESENTED AT CALCUTTA AND REPLY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On his arrival in Calcutta, the Swami Vivekananda was greeted with&#xA;intense enthusiasm, and the whole of his progress through the decorated&#xA;streets of the city was thronged with an immense crowd waiting to have a&#xA;sight of him. The official reception was held a week later, at the&#xA;residence of the late Raja Radha Kanta Deb Bahadur at Sobha Bazar, when&#xA;Raja Benoy Krishna Deb Bahadur took the chair. After a few brief&#xA;introductory remarks from the Chairman, the following address was read&#xA;and presented to him, enclosed in a silver casket:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>142 THE VEDANTA IN ALL ITS PHASES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/142_the_vedanta_in_all_its_phases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/142_the_vedanta_in_all_its_phases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-vedanta-in-all-its-phases&#34;&gt;THE VEDANTA IN ALL ITS PHASES&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in Calcutta&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Away back, where no recorded history, nay, not even the dim light of&#xA;tradition, can penetrate, has been steadily shining the light, sometimes&#xA;dimmed by external circumstances, at others effulgent, but undying and&#xA;steady, shedding its lustre not only over India, but permeating the&#xA;whole thought-world with its power, silent, unperceived, gentle, yet&#xA;omnipotent, like the dew that falls in the morning, unseen and&#xA;unnoticed, yet bringing into bloom the fairest of roses: this has been&#xA;the thought of the Upanishads, the philosophy of the Vedanta. Nobody&#xA;knows when it first came to flourish on the soil of India. Guesswork has&#xA;been vain. The guesses, especially of Western writers, have been so&#xA;conflicting that no certain date can be ascribed to them. But we Hindus,&#xA;from the spiritual standpoint, do not admit that they had any origin.&#xA;This Vedanta, the philosophy of the Upanishads, I would make bold to&#xA;state, has been the first as well as the final thought on the spiritual&#xA;plane that has ever been vouchsafed to man.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>143 ADDRESS OF WELCOME AT ALMORA AND REPLY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/143_address_of_welcome_at_almora_and_reply/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/143_address_of_welcome_at_almora_and_reply/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;address-of-welcome-at-almora-and-reply&#34;&gt;ADDRESS OF WELCOME AT ALMORA AND REPLY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On his arrival at Almora, Swamiji received an Address of Welcome in&#xA;Hindi from the citizens of Almora, of which the following is a&#xA;translation:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GREAT-SOULED ONE,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the time we heard that, after gaining spiritual conquest in the&#xA;West, you had started from England for your motherland, India, we were&#xA;naturally desirous of having the pleasure of seeing you. By the grace of&#xA;the Almighty, that auspicious moment has at last come. The saying of the&#xA;great poet and the prince of Bhaktas, Tulasidāsa, &amp;ldquo;A person who&#xA;intensely loves another is sure to find him&amp;rdquo;, has been fully realised&#xA;today. We have assembled here to welcome you with sincere devotion. You&#xA;have highly obliged us by your kindly taking so much trouble in paying a&#xA;visit to this town again. We can hardly thank you enough for your&#xA;kindness. Blessed are you! Blessed, blessed is the revered Gurudeva who&#xA;initiated you into Yoga. Blessed is the land of Bhārata where, even in&#xA;this fearful Kali Yuga, there exist leaders of Aryan races like&#xA;yourself. Even at an early period of life, you have by your simplicity,&#xA;sincerity, character, philanthropy, severe discipline, conduct, and the&#xA;preaching of knowledge, acquired that immaculate fame throughout the&#xA;world of which we feel so proud.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>144 VEDIC TEACHING IN THEORY AND PRACTICE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/144_vedic_teaching_in_theory_and_practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/144_vedic_teaching_in_theory_and_practice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vedic-teaching-in-theory-and-practice&#34;&gt;VEDIC TEACHING IN THEORY AND PRACTICE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the Swami&amp;rsquo;s visit was drawing to a close, his friends in Almora&#xA;invited him to give a lecture in Hindi. He consented to make the attempt&#xA;for the first time. He began slowly, and soon warmed to his theme, and&#xA;found himself building his phrases and almost his words as he went&#xA;along. Those best acquainted with the difficulties and limitations of&#xA;the Hindi language, still undeveloped as a medium for oratory, expressed&#xA;their opinion that a personal triumph had been achieved by Swamiji and&#xA;that he had proved by his masterly use of Hindi that the language had in&#xA;it undreamt-of possibilities of development in the direction of oratory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>145 BHAKTI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/145_bhakti_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/145_bhakti_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;bhakti&#34;&gt;BHAKTI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at Sialkote, Punjab&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In response to invitations from the Punjab and Kashmir, the Swami&#xA;Vivekananda travelled through those parts. He stayed in Kashmir for over&#xA;a month and his work there was very much appreciated by the Maharaja and&#xA;his brothers. He then spent a few days in visiting Murree, Rawalpindi,&#xA;and Jammu, and at each of these places he delivered lectures.&#xA;Subsequently he visited Sialkote and lectured twice, once in English and&#xA;once in Hindi. The subject of the Swamiji&amp;rsquo;s Hindi lecture was Bhakti, a&#xA;summary of which, translated into English, is given below:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>146 THE COMMON BASES OF HINDUISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/146_the_common_bases_of_hinduism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/146_the_common_bases_of_hinduism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-common-bases-of-hinduism&#34;&gt;THE COMMON BASES OF HINDUISM&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On his arrival at Lahore the Swamiji was accorded a grand reception by&#xA;the leaders, both of the Ârya Samāj and of the Sanātana Dharma Sabhā.&#xA;During his brief stay in Lahore, Swamiji delivered three lectures. The&#xA;first of these was on &amp;ldquo;The Common Bases of Hinduism&amp;rdquo;, the second on&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;bhakti_2.htm&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bhakti&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; , and the third one was the famous lecture on&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;the_vedanta.htm&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Vedanta&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; . On the first occasion he spoke as&#xA;follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>147 BHAKTI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/147_bhakti_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/147_bhakti_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;bhakti&#34;&gt;BHAKTI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at Lahore on the 9th November, 1897&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a sound which comes to us like a distant echo in the midst of&#xA;the roaring torrents of the Upanishads, at times rising in proportion&#xA;and volume, and yet, throughout the literature of the Vedanta, its&#xA;voice, though clear, is not very strong. The main duty of the Upanishads&#xA;seems to be to present before us the spirit and the aspect of the&#xA;sublime, and yet behind this wonderful sublimity there come to us here&#xA;and there glimpses of poetry as we read; न तत्र सुर्यो भाति न&#xA;चंन्द्रतारकं नेमा विद्युतो भान्ति कुतोऽयमग्निः — &amp;ldquo;There the sun shines&#xA;not, nor the moon, nor the stars, what to speak of this fire?&amp;rdquo; As we&#xA;listen to the heart-stirring poetry of these marvellous lines, we are&#xA;taken, as it were, off from the world of the senses, off even from the&#xA;world of intellect, and brought to that world which can never be&#xA;comprehended, and yet which is always with us. There is behind even this&#xA;sublimity another ideal following as its shadow, one more acceptable to&#xA;mankind, one more of daily use, one that has to enter into every part of&#xA;human life, which assumes proportion and volume later on, and is stated&#xA;in full and determined language in the Purāna, and that is the ideal of&#xA;Bhakti. The germs of Bhakti are there already; the germs are even in the&#xA;Samhitā; the germs a little more developed are in the Upanishads; but&#xA;they are worked out in their details in the Puranas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>148 THE VEDANTA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/148_the_vedanta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/148_the_vedanta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-vedanta&#34;&gt;THE VEDANTA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at Lahore on 12th November, 1897&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two worlds there are in which we live, one the external, the other&#xA;internal. Human progress has been made, from days of yore, almost in&#xA;parallel lines along both these worlds. The search began in the&#xA;external, and man at first wanted to get answers for all the deep&#xA;problems from outside nature. Man wanted to satisfy his thirst for the&#xA;beautiful and the sublime from all that surrounded him; he wanted to&#xA;express himself and all that was within him in the language of the&#xA;concrete; and grand indeed were the answers he got, most marvellous&#xA;ideas of God and worship, and most rapturous expressions of the&#xA;beautiful. Sublime ideas came from the external world indeed. But the&#xA;other, opening out for humanity later, laid out before him a universe&#xA;yet sublimer, yet more beautiful, and infinitely more expansive. In the&#xA;Karma Kānda portion of the Vedas, we find the most wonderful ideas of&#xA;religion inculcated, we find the most wonderful ideas about an&#xA;overruling Creator, Preserver, and Destroyer of the universe presented&#xA;before us in language sometimes the most soul-stirring. Most of you&#xA;perhaps remember that most wonderful Shloka in the Rig-Veda Samhitā&#xA;where you get the description of chaos, perhaps the sublimest that has&#xA;ever been attempted yet. In spite of all this, we find it is only a&#xA;painting of the sublime outside, we find that yet it is gross, that&#xA;something of matter yet clings to it. Yet we find that it is only the&#xA;expression of the Infinite in; the language of matter, in the language&#xA;of the finite, it is,. the infinite of the muscles and not of the mind;&#xA;it is the infinite of space and not of thought. Therefore in the second&#xA;portion of Jnāna Kānda, we find there is altogether a different&#xA;procedure. The first was a search in external nature for the truths of&#xA;the universe; it was an attempt to get the solution of the deep problems&#xA;of life from the material world. यस्यैते हिमवन्तो महित्वा — &amp;ldquo;Whose glory&#xA;these Himalayas declare&amp;rdquo;. This is a grand idea, but yet it was not grand&#xA;enough for India. The Indian mind had to fall back, and the research&#xA;took a different direction altogether; from the external the search came&#xA;to the internal, from matter to mind. There arose the cry, &amp;ldquo;When a man&#xA;dies, what becomes of him?&amp;rdquo; अस्तीत्येके नायमस्तीति चैके — &amp;ldquo;Some say that&#xA;he exists, others that he is gone; say, O king of Death, what is the&#xA;truth?&amp;rdquo; An entirely different procedure we find here. The Indian mind&#xA;got all that could be had from the external world, but it did not feel&#xA;satisfied with that; it wanted to search further, to dive into its own&#xA;soul, and the final answer came.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>149 VEDANTISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/149_vedantism_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/149_vedantism_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vedantism&#34;&gt;VEDANTISM&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At Khetri on 20th December 1897, Swami Vivekananda delivered a lecture&#xA;on Vedantism in the hall of the Maharaja&amp;rsquo;s bungalow in which he lodged&#xA;with his disciples. The Swami was introduced by the Raja, who was the&#xA;president of the meeting; and he spoke for more than an hour and a half.&#xA;The Swami was at his best, and it was a matter of regret that no&#xA;shorthand writer was present to report this interesting lecture at&#xA;length. The following is a summary from notes taken down at the time:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>150 THE INFLUENCE OF INDIAN SPIRITUAL THOUGHT IN ENGLAND</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/150_the_influence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/150_the_influence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-influence-of-indian-spiritual-thought-in-england&#34;&gt;THE INFLUENCE OF INDIAN SPIRITUAL THOUGHT IN ENGLAND&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Swami Vivekananda presided over a meeting at which the Sister&#xA;Nivedita (Miss M. E. Noble) delivered a lecture on &amp;ldquo;The Influence of&#xA;Indian Spiritual Thought in England&amp;rdquo; on 11th March, 1898, at the Star&#xA;Theatre, Calcutta. Swami Vivekananda on rising to introduce Miss Noble&#xA;spoke as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was travelling through the Eastern parts of Asia, one thing&#xA;especially struck me — that is the prevalence of Indian spiritual&#xA;thought in Eastern Asiatic countries. You may imagine the surprise with&#xA;which I noticed written on the walls of Chinese and Japanese temples&#xA;some well-known Sanskrit Mantras, and possibly it will please you all&#xA;the more to know that they were all in old Bengali characters, standing&#xA;even in the present day as a monument of missionary energy and zeal&#xA;displayed by our forefathers of Bengal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>151 SANNYASA: ITS IDEAL AND PRACTICE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/151_sannyasa_its_ideal_and_practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/151_sannyasa_its_ideal_and_practice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;sannyasa-its-ideal-and-practice&#34;&gt;SANNYASA: ITS IDEAL AND PRACTICE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A parting Address was given to Swamiji by the junior Sannyāsins of the&#xA;Math (Belur), on the eve of his leaving for the West for the second&#xA;time. The following is the substance of Swamiji&amp;rsquo;s reply as entered in&#xA;the Math Diary on 19th June 1899:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is not the time for a long lecture. But I shall speak to you in&#xA;brief about a few things which I should like you to carry into practice.&#xA;First, we have to understand the ideal, and then the methods by which we&#xA;can make it practical. Those of you who are Sannyasins must try to do&#xA;good to others, for Sannyasa means that. There is no time to deliver a&#xA;long discourse on &amp;ldquo;Renunciation&amp;rdquo;, but I shall very briefly characterise&#xA;it as &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;the love of death&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. Worldly people love life. The Sannyasin is&#xA;to love death. Are we to commit suicide then? Far from it. For suicides&#xA;are not lovers of death, as it is often seen that when a man trying to&#xA;commit suicide fails, he never attempts it for a second time. What is&#xA;the love of death then? We must die, that is certain; let us die then&#xA;for a good cause. Let all our actions — eating, drinking, and everything&#xA;that we do — tend towards the sacrifice of our self. You nourish your&#xA;body by eating. What good is there in doing that if you do not hold it&#xA;as a sacrifice to the well-being of others? You nourish your minds by&#xA;reading books. There is no good in doing that unless you hold it also as&#xA;a sacrifice to the whole world. For the whole world is one; you are&#xA;rated a very insignificant part of it, and therefore it is right for you&#xA;that you should serve your millions of brothers rather than aggrandise&#xA;this little self.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>152 WHAT HAVE I LEARNT?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/152_what_have_i_learnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/152_what_have_i_learnt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-have-i-learnt&#34;&gt;WHAT HAVE I LEARNT?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at Dacca, 30th March, 1901&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At Dacca Swamiji delivered two lectures in English. The first was on&#xA;&amp;ldquo;What have I learnt?&amp;rdquo; and the second one was &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;the_religion_we_are_born_in.htm&#34;&gt;The Religion we are born&#xA;in&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;. The following is translated from&#xA;a report in Bengali by a disciple, and it contains the substance of the&#xA;first lecture:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First of all, I must express my pleasure at the opportunity afforded me&#xA;of coming to Eastern Bengal to acquire an intimate knowledge of this&#xA;part of the country, which I hitherto lacked in spite of my wanderings&#xA;through many civilised countries of the West, as well as my&#xA;gratification at the sight of majestic rivers, wide fertile plains, and&#xA;picturesque villages in this, my own country of Bengal, which I had not&#xA;the good fortune of seeing for myself before. I did not know that there&#xA;was everywhere in my country of Bengal — on land and water — so much&#xA;beauty and charm. But this much has been my gain that after seeing the&#xA;various countries of the world I can now much more appreciate the&#xA;beauties of my own land.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>153 THE RELIGION WE ARE BORN IN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/153_the_religion_we_are_born_in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_from_colombo_to_almora/153_the_religion_we_are_born_in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-religion-we-are-born-in&#34;&gt;THE RELIGION WE ARE BORN IN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At an open-air meeting convened at Dacca, on the 31st March, 1901, the&#xA;Swamiji spoke in English for two hours on the above subject before a&#xA;vast audience. The following is a translation of the lecture from a&#xA;Bengali report of a disciple:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the remote past, our country made gigantic advances in spiritual&#xA;ideas. Let us, today, bring before our mind&amp;rsquo;s eye that ancient history.&#xA;But the one great danger in meditating over long-past greatness is that&#xA;we cease to exert ourselves for new things, and content ourselves with&#xA;vegetating upon that by-gone ancestral glory and priding ourselves upon&#xA;it. We should guard against that. In ancient times there were, no doubt,&#xA;many Rishis and Maharshis who came face to face with Truth. But if this&#xA;recalling of our ancient greatness is to be of real benefit, we too must&#xA;become Rishis like them. Ay, not only that, but it is my firm conviction&#xA;that we shall be even greater Rishis than any that our history presents&#xA;to us. In the past, signal were our attainments — I glory in them, and I&#xA;feel proud in thinking of them. I am not even in despair at seeing the&#xA;present degradation, and I am full of hope in picturing to my mind what&#xA;is to come in the future. Why? Because I know the seed undergoes a&#xA;complete transformation, ay, the seed as seed is seemingly destroyed&#xA;before it develops into a tree. In the same way, in the midst of our&#xA;present degradation lies, only dormant for a time, the potentiality of&#xA;the future greatness of our religion, ready to spring up again, perhaps&#xA;more mighty and glorious than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
