<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Riots on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Riots on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1714 Holi riot</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/A_Holi_Riot_of_1714_Versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/A_Holi_Riot_of_1714_Versions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A ‘HOLI RIOT&amp;rsquo; OF 1714: VERSIONS FROM AHMEDABAD AND DELHI*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Najaf Haider&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This chapter examines a set of evidence on an event in Ahmedabad in AD 1714. The evidence appears to be the earliest description of a conflict involving Muslims, Jains, and Hindus in Ahmedabad or, for that matter, the whole of India. It offers us an insight into the causes, organization, form, and control of group violence in the capital city of a highly commercialized region. A complete and fresh translation of the descriptions of the incident found in two Persian chronicles is presented here, followed by a schematic reading of both versions. I hope that by adding to our empirical knowledge, and by raising questions and inviting criticisms, some contribution may be made to the study of the tensions and challenges of living together separately in pre-colonial India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delhi Shoe-seller-riot 1729</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/delhi-shoe-seller-riot_1729/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/delhi-shoe-seller-riot_1729/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dharmadispatch.in/history/what-the-deadly-riot-of-delhi-shoe-sellers-in-1729-reveals-about-the-true-character-of-mughal-decline&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The forgotten Delhi Shoe-Sellers&amp;rsquo; Riot of 1729 throws a stark and informative light on the real extent of the decay of the Mughal Empire under Muhammad Shah. It also reveals substantial details of the nature of the Muslim society of that period.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;preface&#34;&gt;Preface&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE REIGN OF MUHAMMAD SHAH, THE 13TH “EMPEROR” of the Mughal dynasty was chiefly notable for two major events. The first was the manner in which the remnants of the Aurangzeb-ravaged Mughal empire were devoured by the ascendant Marathas. Muhammad Shah lost the whole of Malwa and Deccan. The second was the brutal invasion of Nadir Shah which finished off the stubs of pretensions to suzerainty that remained in Muhammad Shah. The “great” Mughal had to literally beg for mercy at Nadir Shah’s feet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>moplah vs Arya samAj</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/moplah_vs_Arya-samAj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/moplah_vs_Arya-samAj/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Excerpted from p.115-120 C Gopalan Nair &amp;lsquo;The Moplah Rebellion, 1921&amp;rsquo; - 12/n (Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1452681793765838857&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1452681793765838857&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When reading through C Gopalan Nair&amp;rsquo;s deeply disturbing &amp;lsquo;The Moplah Rebellion, 1921,&amp;rsquo; I came across this heartening piece in the midst of the stomach-churning account of atrocities perpetrated on Hindus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Zamorin Raja of Calicut met with a council of Nambudiri Vaideekans -  to decide the fate of forced converts during the rebellion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our thanks are mainly due to the Arya Samaj Society for effecting re-conversion of forced converts. When the alarming news of a large number of Hindus forcibly converted to Islam reached Punjab, it shocked the -  Hindu public there, and Mahatma Hans Raj, President of the Arya Pradeshika Pratinidhi Sabha of Punjab, Sind, and Baluchistan was moved to help these unfortunate brethren in Malabar. He sent Arya Missionary Pandit Rishi Ram to Calicut.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xinjiang hindu massacre</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/xinjiang-hindu-massacre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/xinjiang-hindu-massacre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thread on the massacre of Sindhi Hindus in Xinjiang by Uyghur Sunnis by porbotialora&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1933 Sindhi Hindus were trading acriss Central Asia (Bukhara, Khiva) all the way to the Astrakhan Tatars in Russia for ages They managed the finances of Khans, Emirs and were wealthier than the local Muslims. The 1917 Russian revolution ended the long reigning Romanov dynasty, and with them the Emirs and Khans who were their vassals. Afghanistan and Xinjiang weren&amp;rsquo;t touched by the revolution at that point. The Sindhi Hindus in Xinjiang were working as moneylenders. They traced their origin to Shikarpur, Sindh. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/OTkNtecTnU&#34;&gt;https://t.co/OTkNtecTnU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
