<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;karma-yoga on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/karma-yoga/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;karma-yoga on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/karma-yoga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>007 KARMA IN ITS EFFECT ON CHARACTER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/karma-yoga/007_effect_on_character/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/karma-yoga/007_effect_on_character/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;karma-in-its-effect-on-character&#34;&gt;KARMA IN ITS EFFECT ON CHARACTER&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The word Karma is derived from the Sanskrit Kri, to do; all action is&#xA;Karma. Technically, this word also means the effects of actions. In&#xA;connection with metaphysics, it sometimes means the effects, of which&#xA;our past actions were the causes. But in Karma-Yoga we have simply to do&#xA;with the word Karma as meaning work. The goal of mankind is knowledge.&#xA;That is the one ideal placed before us by Eastern philosophy. Pleasure&#xA;is not the goal of man, but knowledge. Pleasure and happiness come to an&#xA;end. It is a mistake to suppose that pleasure is the goal. The cause of&#xA;all the miseries we have in the world is that men foolishly think&#xA;pleasure to be the ideal to strive for. After a time man finds that it&#xA;is not happiness, but knowledge, towards which he is going, and that&#xA;both pleasure and pain are great teachers, and that he learns as much&#xA;from evil as from good. As pleasure and pain pass before his soul they&#xA;have upon it different pictures, and the result of these combined&#xA;impressions is what is called man&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;character&amp;rdquo;. If you take the&#xA;character of any man, it really is but the aggregate of tendencies, the&#xA;sum total of the bent of his mind; you will find that misery and&#xA;happiness are equal factors in the formation of that character. Good and&#xA;evil have an equal share in moulding character, and in some instances&#xA;misery is a greater teacher than happiness. In studying the great&#xA;characters the world has produced, I dare say, in the vast majority of&#xA;cases, it would be found that it was misery that taught more than&#xA;happiness, it was poverty that taught more than wealth, it was blows&#xA;that brought out their inner fire more than praise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>008 EACH
IS GREAT IN HIS OWN PLACE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/karma-yoga/008_each_is_great/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/karma-yoga/008_each_is_great/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER II&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;each-is-great-in-his-own-place&#34;&gt;EACH IS GREAT IN HIS OWN PLACE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to the Sānkhya philosophy, nature is composed of three forces&#xA;called, in Sanskrit, Sattva, Rajas, and Tamas. These as manifested in&#xA;the physical world are what we may call equilibrium, activity, and&#xA;inertness. Tamas is typified as darkness or inactivity; Rajas is&#xA;activity, expressed as attraction or repulsion; and Sattva is the&#xA;equilibrium of the two.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In every man there are these three forces. Sometimes Tamas prevails. We&#xA;become lazy, we cannot move, we are inactive, bound down by certain&#xA;ideas or by mere dullness. At other times activity prevails, and at&#xA;still other times that calm balancing of both. Again, in different men,&#xA;one of these forces is generally predominant. The characteristic of one&#xA;man is inactivity, dullness and laziness; that of another, activity,&#xA;power, manifestation of energy; and in still another we find the&#xA;sweetness, calmness, and gentleness, which are due to the balancing of&#xA;both action and inaction. So in all creation — in animals, plants, and&#xA;men — we find the more or less typical manifestation of all these&#xA;different forces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>009 THE SECRET OF WORK</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/karma-yoga/009_secret_of_work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/karma-yoga/009_secret_of_work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER III&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-secret-of-work&#34;&gt;THE SECRET OF WORK&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Helping others physically, by removing their physical needs, is indeed&#xA;great, but the help is great according as the need is greater and&#xA;according as the help is far reaching. If a man&amp;rsquo;s wants can be removed&#xA;for an hour, it is helping him indeed; if his wants can be removed for a&#xA;year, it will be more help to him; but if his wants can be removed for&#xA;ever, it is surely the greatest help that can be given him. Spiritual&#xA;knowledge is the only thing that can destroy our miseries for ever; any&#xA;other knowledge satisfies wants only for a time. It is only with the&#xA;knowledge of the spirit that the faculty of want is annihilated for&#xA;ever; so helping man spiritually is the highest help that can be given&#xA;to him. He who gives man spiritual knowledge is the greatest benefactor&#xA;of mankind and as such we always find that those were the most powerful&#xA;of men who helped man in his spiritual needs, because spirituality is&#xA;the true basis of all our activities in life. A spiritually strong and&#xA;sound man will be strong in every other respect, if he so wishes. Until&#xA;there is spiritual strength in man even physical needs cannot be well&#xA;satisfied. Next to spiritual comes intellectual help. The gift of&#xA;knowledge is a far higher gift than that of food and clothes; it is even&#xA;higher than giving life to a man, because the real life of man consists&#xA;of knowledge. Ignorance is death, knowledge is life. Life is of very&#xA;little value, if it is a life in the dark, groping through ignorance and&#xA;misery. Next in order comes, of course, helping a man physically.&#xA;Therefore, in considering the question of helping others, we must always&#xA;strive not to commit the mistake of thinking that physical help is the&#xA;only help that can be given. It is not only the last but the least,&#xA;because it cannot bring about permanent satisfaction. The misery that I&#xA;feel when I am hungry is satisfied by eating, but hunger returns; my&#xA;misery can cease only when I am satisfied beyond all want. Then hunger&#xA;will not make me miserable; no distress, no sorrow will be able to move&#xA;me. So, that help which tends to make us strong spiritually is the&#xA;highest, next to it comes intellectual help, and after that physical&#xA;help.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>010 WHAT IS DUTY?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/karma-yoga/010_what_is_duty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/karma-yoga/010_what_is_duty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER IV&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-duty&#34;&gt;WHAT IS DUTY?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is necessary in the study of Karma-Yoga to know what duty is. If I&#xA;have to do something I must first know that it is my duty, and then I&#xA;can do it. The idea of duty again is different in different nations. The&#xA;Mohammedan says what is written in his book, the Koran, is his duty; the&#xA;Hindu says what is in the Vedas is his duty; and the Christian says what&#xA;is in the Bible is his duty. We find that there are varied ideas of&#xA;duty, differing according to different states in life, different&#xA;historical periods and different nations. The term &amp;ldquo;duty&amp;rdquo;, like every&#xA;other universal abstract term, is impossible clearly to define; we can&#xA;only get an idea of it by knowing its practical operations and results.&#xA;When certain things occur before us, we have all a natural or trained&#xA;impulse to act in a certain manner towards them; when this impulse&#xA;comes, the mind begins to think about the situation. Sometimes it thinks&#xA;that it is good to act in a particular manner under the given&#xA;conditions; at other times it thinks that it is wrong to act in the same&#xA;manner even in the very same circumstances. The ordinary idea of duty&#xA;everywhere is that every good man follows the dictates of his&#xA;conscience. But what is it that makes an act a duty? If a Christian&#xA;finds a piece of beef before him and does not eat it to save his own&#xA;life, or will not give it to save the life of another man, he is sure to&#xA;feel that he has not done his duty. But if a Hindu dares to eat that&#xA;piece of beef or to give it to another Hindu, he is equally sure to feel&#xA;that he too has not done his duty; the Hindu&amp;rsquo;s training and education&#xA;make him feel that way. In the last century there were notorious bands&#xA;of robbers in India called thugs; they thought it their duty to kill any&#xA;man they could and take away his money; the larger the number of men&#xA;they killed, the better they thought they were. Ordinarily if a man goes&#xA;out into the street and shoots down another man, he is apt to feel sorry&#xA;for it, thinking that he has done wrong. But if the very same man, as a&#xA;soldier in his regiment, kills not one but twenty, he is certain to feel&#xA;glad and think that he has done his duty remarkably well. Therefore we&#xA;see that it is not the thing done that defines a duty. To give an&#xA;objective definition of duty is thus entirely impossible. Yet there is&#xA;duty from the subjective side. Any action that makes us go Godward is a&#xA;good action, and is our duty; any action that makes us go downward is&#xA;evil, and is not our duty. From the subjective standpoint we may see&#xA;that certain acts have a tendency to exalt and ennoble us, while certain&#xA;other acts have a tendency to degrade and to brutalise us. But it is not&#xA;possible to make out with certainty which acts have which kind of&#xA;tendency in relation to all persons, of all sorts and conditions. There&#xA;is, however, only one idea of duty which has been universally accepted&#xA;by all mankind, of all ages and sects and countries, and that has been&#xA;summed up in a Sanskrit aphorism thus: “Do not injure any being; not&#xA;injuring any being is virtue, injuring any being is sin.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>011 WE HELP OURSELVES, NOT THE WORLD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/karma-yoga/011_we_help_ourselves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/karma-yoga/011_we_help_ourselves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER V&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-help-ourselves-not-the-world&#34;&gt;WE HELP OURSELVES, NOT THE WORLD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before considering further how devotion to duty helps us in our&#xA;spiritual progress, let me place before you in a brief compass another&#xA;aspect of what we in India mean by Karma. In every religion there are&#xA;three parts: philosophy, mythology, and ritual. Philosophy of course is&#xA;the essence of every religion; mythology explains and illustrates it by&#xA;means of the more or less legendary lives of great men, stories and&#xA;fables of wonderful things, and so on; ritual gives to that philosophy a&#xA;still more concrete form, so that every one may grasp it — ritual is in&#xA;fact concretised philosophy. This ritual is Karma; it is necessary in&#xA;every religion, because most of us cannot understand abstract spiritual&#xA;things until we grow much spiritually. It is easy for men to think that&#xA;they can understand anything; but when it comes to practical experience,&#xA;they find that abstract ideas are often very hard to comprehend.&#xA;Therefore symbols are of great help, and we cannot dispense with the&#xA;symbolical method of putting things before us. From time immemorial&#xA;symbols have been used by all kinds of religions. In one sense we cannot&#xA;think but in symbols; words themselves are symbols of thought. In&#xA;another sense everything in the universe may be looked upon as a symbol.&#xA;The whole universe is a symbol, and God is the essence behind. This kind&#xA;of symbology is not simply the creation of man; it is not that certain&#xA;people belonging to a religion sit down together and think out certain&#xA;symbols, and bring them into existence out of their own minds. The&#xA;symbols of religion have a natural growth. Otherwise, why is it that&#xA;certain symbols are associated with certain ideas in the mind of almost&#xA;every one? Certain symbols are universally prevalent. Many of you may&#xA;think that the cross first came into existence as a symbol in connection&#xA;with the Christian religion, but as a matter of fact it existed before&#xA;Christianity was, before Moses was born, before the Vedas were given&#xA;out, before there was any human record of human things. The cross may be&#xA;found to have been in existence among the Aztecs and the Phoenicians;&#xA;every race seems to have had the cross. Again, the symbol of the&#xA;crucified Saviour, of a man crucified upon a cross, appears to have been&#xA;known to almost every nation. The circle has been a great symbol&#xA;throughout the world. Then there is the most universal of all symbols,&#xA;the Swastika. &lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;swastika.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;swastika.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;At one time it was thought that the&#xA;Buddhists carried it all over the world with them, but it has been found&#xA;out that ages before Buddhism it was used among nations. In Old Babylon&#xA;and in Egypt it was to be found. What does this show? All these symbols&#xA;could not have been purely conventional. There must be some reason for&#xA;them; some natural association between them and the human mind. Language&#xA;is not the result of convention; it is not that people ever agreed to&#xA;represent certain ideas by certain words; there never was an idea&#xA;without a corresponding word or a word without a corresponding idea;&#xA;ideas and words are in their nature inseparable. The symbols to&#xA;represent ideas may be sound symbols or colour symbols. Deaf and dumb&#xA;people have to think with other than sound symbols. Every thought in the&#xA;mind has a form as its counterpart. This is called in Sanskrit&#xA;philosophy Nāma-Rupa — name and form. It is as impossible to create by&#xA;convention a system of symbols as it is to create a language. In the&#xA;world&amp;rsquo;s ritualistic symbols we have an expression of the religious&#xA;thought of humanity. It is easy to say that there is no use of rituals&#xA;and temples and all such paraphernalia; every baby says that in modern&#xA;times. But it must be easy for all to see that those who worship inside&#xA;a temple are in many respects different from those who will not worship&#xA;there. Therefore the association of particular temples, rituals, and&#xA;other concrete forms with particular religions has a tendency to bring&#xA;into the minds of the followers of those religions the thoughts for&#xA;which those concrete things stand as symbols; and it is not wise to&#xA;ignore rituals and symbology altogether. The study and practice of these&#xA;things form naturally a part of Karma-Yoga.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>012 NON-ATTACHMENT IS COMPLETE SELF-ABNEGATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/karma-yoga/012_non-attachment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/karma-yoga/012_non-attachment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER VI&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;non-attachment-is-complete-self-abnegation&#34;&gt;NON-ATTACHMENT IS COMPLETE SELF-ABNEGATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just as every action that emanates from us comes back to us as reaction,&#xA;even so our actions may act on other people and theirs on us. Perhaps&#xA;all of you have observed it as a fact that when persons do evil actions,&#xA;they become more and more evil, and when they begin to do good, they&#xA;become stronger and stronger and learn to do good at all times. This&#xA;intensification of the influence of action cannot be explained on any&#xA;other ground than that we can act and react upon each other. To take an&#xA;illustration from physical science, when I am doing a certain action, my&#xA;mind may be said to be in a certain state of vibration; all minds which&#xA;are in similar circumstances will have the tendency to be affected by my&#xA;mind. If there are different musical instruments tuned alike in one&#xA;room, all of you may have noticed that when one is struck, the others&#xA;have the tendency to vibrate so as to give the same note. So all minds&#xA;that have the same tension, so to say, will be equally affected by the&#xA;same thought. Of course, this influence of thought on mind will vary&#xA;according to distance and other causes, but the mind is always open to&#xA;affection. Suppose I am doing an evil act, my mind is in a certain state&#xA;of vibration, and all minds in the universe, which are in a similar&#xA;state, have the possibility of being affected by the vibration of my&#xA;mind. So, when I am doing a good action, my mind is in another state of&#xA;vibration; and all minds similarly strung have the possibility of being&#xA;affected by my mind; and this power of mind upon mind is more or less&#xA;according as the force of the tension is greater or less.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>013 FREEDOM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/karma-yoga/013_freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/karma-yoga/013_freedom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER VII&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;freedom&#34;&gt;FREEDOM&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition to meaning work, we have stated that psychologically the&#xA;word Karma also implies causation. Any work, any action, any thought&#xA;that produces an effect is called a Karma. Thus the law of Karma means&#xA;the law of causation, of inevitable cause and sequence. Wheresoever&#xA;there is a cause, there an effect must be produced; this necessity&#xA;cannot be resisted, and this law of Karma, according to our philosophy,&#xA;is true throughout the whole universe. Whatever we see, or feel, or do,&#xA;whatever action there is anywhere in the universe, while being the&#xA;effect of past work on the one hand, becomes, on the other, a cause in&#xA;its turn, and produces its own effect. It is necessary, together with&#xA;this, to consider what is meant by the word &amp;ldquo;law&amp;rdquo;. By law is meant the&#xA;tendency of a series to repeat itself. When we see one event followed by&#xA;another, or sometimes happening simultaneously with another, we expect&#xA;this sequence or co-existence to recur. Our old logicians and&#xA;philosophers of the Nyāyā school call this law by the name of Vyāpti.&#xA;According to them, all our ideas of law are due to association. A series&#xA;of phenomena becomes associated with things in our mind in a sort of&#xA;invariable order, so that whatever we perceive at any time is&#xA;immediately referred to other facts in the mind. Any one idea or,&#xA;according to our psychology, any one wave that is produced in the&#xA;mind-stuff, Chitta, must always give rise to many similar waves. This is&#xA;the psychological idea of association, and causation is only an aspect&#xA;of this grand pervasive principle of association. This pervasiveness of&#xA;association is what is, in Sanskrit, called Vyāpti. In the external&#xA;world the idea of law is the same as in the internal — the expectation&#xA;that a particular phenomenon will be followed by another, and that the&#xA;series will repeat itself. Really speaking, therefore, law does not&#xA;exist in nature. Practically it is an error to say that gravitation&#xA;exists in the earth, or that there is any law existing objectively&#xA;anywhere in nature. Law is the method, the manner in which our mind&#xA;grasps a series of phenomena; it is all in the mind. Certain phenomena,&#xA;happening one after another or together, and followed by the conviction&#xA;of the regularity of their recurrence — thus enabling our minds to grasp&#xA;the method of the whole series — constitute what we call law.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>014 THE IDEAL OF KARMA-YOGA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/karma-yoga/014_the_ideal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_1/karma-yoga/014_the_ideal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER VIII&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ideal-of-karma-yoga&#34;&gt;THE IDEAL OF KARMA-YOGA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The grandest idea in the religion of the Vedanta is that we may reach&#xA;the same goal by different paths; and these paths I have generalised&#xA;into four, viz those of work, love, psychology, and knowledge. But you&#xA;must, at the same time, remember that these divisions are not very&#xA;marked and quite exclusive of each other. Each blends into the other.&#xA;But according to the type which prevails, we name the divisions. It is&#xA;not that you can find men who have no other faculty than that of work,&#xA;nor that you can find men who are no more than devoted worshippers only,&#xA;nor that there are men who have no more than mere knowledge. These&#xA;divisions are made in accordance with the type or the tendency that may&#xA;be seen to prevail in a man. We have found that, in the end, all these&#xA;four paths converge and become one. All religions and all methods of&#xA;work and worship lead us to one and the same goal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
