<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/crime/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/crime/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Germ murder</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/crime/articles/germ-murder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/crime/articles/germ-murder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Indian &amp;lsquo;germ murder&amp;rsquo; that gripped the world&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Soutik Biswas&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This grainy portrait is possibly the only publicly available picture of Amarendra Pandey. On the afternoon of 26 November 1933, a diminutive man brushed past a young landlord in a crowded railway station in the eastern Indian city of Kolkata (then Calcutta). Amarendra Chandra Pandey, 20, felt a jab of pain in his right arm as the man dressed in khadi, or coarse, homespun cotton, disappeared into the crowd at Howrah station.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Triad oaths</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/crime/articles/triad-oaths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/crime/articles/triad-oaths/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 36 Oaths of China&amp;rsquo;s Triad Societies&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After having entered the Hong Gates I must treat the parents and&#xA;relatives of my sworn brothers as mine own kin. I shall suffer&#xA;death by five thunderbolts if I do not keep this oath.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I shall assist my sworn brothers to bury their parents and brothers&#xA;by offering financial or physical assistance. I shall be killed by five&#xA;thunderbolts if I pretend to have no knowledge of their troubles.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When Hong brothers visit my house I shall provide them with&#xA;board and lodging. I shall be killed by a myriad of swords if I treat&#xA;them as strangers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I will always acknowledge my Hong brothers when they identify&#xA;themselves. If I ignore them I shall be killed by a myriad of swords.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I shall not disclose the secrets of the Hong family, not even to my&#xA;parents, brothers or wife. I shall never disclose the secrets for&#xA;money. I shall be killed by a myriad of swords if I do so.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I shall never betray my sworn brothers. If, through a misunderstanding, I have caused the arrest of one of my brothers, I must&#xA;release him immediately. If I break this oath I will be killed by five&#xA;thunderbolts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I will offer assistance to my sworn brothers who are in trouble, in&#xA;order that they may pay their passage fee. If I break this oath, may&#xA;I be killed by five thunderbolts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I must not cause harm or bring trouble to my sworn brothers or&#xA;Incense Master. If I do so I will be killed by a myriad of swords.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I must never commit an indecent assault on the wives, sisters or&#xA;daughters of my sworn brothers. I shall be killed by five thunderbolts if I break this oath.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I shall never embezzle cash or property from my sworn brothers.&#xA;If I break this oath I will be killed by a myriad of swords.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I will take good care of the wives or children of sworn brothers&#xA;entrusted to my keeping. If I do not do so I will be killed by five&#xA;thunderbolts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If I have supplied false particulars about myself for the purpose of&#xA;joining the Hong family I shall be killed by five thunderbolts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If I should change my mind and deny my membership of the&#xA;Hong family I will be killed by a myriad of swords.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If I rob a sworn brother, or assist an outsider to do so, I will be&#xA;killed by five thunderbolts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If I should take advantage over a sworn brother or force unfair&#xA;business deals upon him I will be killed by a myriad of swords.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If I knowingly convert my sworn brother&amp;rsquo;s cash or property to my&#xA;own use I shall be killed by five thunderbolts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If I have wrongly taken a sworn brother&amp;rsquo;s cash or property during&#xA;a robbery I must return them to him. If I do not I will be killed by&#xA;five thunderbolts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If I am arrested after committing an offence, I must accept my&#xA;punishment, and not try to place the blame on my sworn brothers. If I do so I will be killed by five thunderbolts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If any of my sworn brothers are killed, arrested, or have departed&#xA;to some other place, I will assist their wives and children who may&#xA;be in need. If I pretend to have no knowledge of their difficulties,&#xA;I will be killed by five thunderbolts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When any of my sworn brothers have been assaulted or blamed by&#xA;others, I must come forward and help him if he is in the right, or&#xA;advise him to desist if he is wrong. If he has been repeatedly&#xA;insulted by others I shall inform our other brothers to help him&#xA;physically and financially. If I do not keep this oath, I will be killed&#xA;by five thunderbolts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If it comes to my knowledge that the government is seeking any&#xA;of my sworn brothers who has come from other provinces or from&#xA;overseas, I shall immediately inform him in order that he may&#xA;make his escape. If I break this oath I will be killed by five thunderbolts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I must not conspire with outsiders to cheat my sworn brothers at&#xA;gambling. If I do so I will be killed by a myriad of swords.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I shall not cause discord amongst my sworn brothers by spreading&#xA;false reports about any of them. If I do so I shall be killed by a&#xA;myriad of swords.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I shall not appoint myself Incense Master without authority. After&#xA;entering the Hong Gates for three years, the loyal and faithful&#xA;ones may be promoted by the Incense Master with the support of&#xA;his sworn brothers. I shall be killed by five thunderbolts if I make&#xA;any unauthorised promotions myself.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If my natural brothers are involved in a dispute or lawsuit with my&#xA;sworn brothers, I must not help either party against the other, but&#xA;must attempt to have the matter settled amicably. If I break this&#xA;oath I will be killed by five thunderbolts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After entering the Hong Gates, I must forget any previous&#xA;grudges I may have borne against my sworn brothers. If I do not&#xA;do so I will be killed by five thunderbolts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I must not trespass upon territory occupied by my sworn brothers. I shall be killed by five thunderbolts if I pretend to have no&#xA;knowledge of my brothers&amp;rsquo; rights in such matters.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I must not covet or seek to share in any property or cash obtained&#xA;by my sworn brothers. If I have such ideas I will be killed by five&#xA;thunderbolts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I must not disclose any address where my sworn brothers keep&#xA;their wealth, nor must I conspire to make wrong use of such&#xA;knowledge. If I do so I will be killed by a myriad of swords.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I must not give support to outsiders if so doing is against the interests of any of my sworn brothers. If I do not keep this oath, I will&#xA;be killed by a myriad of swords.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I must not take advantage of the Hong brotherhood, in order to&#xA;oppress or take violent or unreasonable advantage of others. I&#xA;must be content and honest. If I break this oath I will be killed by&#xA;five thunderbolts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I shall be killed by five thunderbolts if I behave indecently towards&#xA;the small children of my sworn brothers&amp;rsquo; families.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If any of my sworn brothers has committed a big offence, I must&#xA;not inform upon them to the government for the purpose of&#xA;obtaining a reward. I shall be killed by five thunderbolts if I break&#xA;this oath.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I must not take to myself the wives and concubines of my sworn&#xA;brothers, nor commit adultery with them. If I do so I will be killed&#xA;by a myriad of swords.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I must never reveal Hong secrets or signs when speaking to outsiders. If I do so I will be killed by a myriad of swords.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After entering the Hong Gates, I shall be loyal and faithful and&#xA;shall endeavour to overthrow the Qing and restore the Ming by&#xA;coordinating my efforts with those of my sworn brothers, even&#xA;though my brothers and I may not be in the same profession. Our&#xA;common aim is to avenge our Five Ancestors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
