<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०२ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०२ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Futures</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/02/2004-02-14_futures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/02/2004-02-14_futures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/02/14/futures/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We wandered on the path by day and decided that we should wander in the&#xA;pitch darkness of night. We set out slowly wending our way through the&#xA;paths. We agreed that either of us would not have done on our own.&#xA;midway there was the four-cross. We sat on the stones there in the&#xA;middle. The black figure of Dollolas suddenly emerged from the thickets.&#xA;I see the past and future with my disc, said the foremost of the&#xA;nishAdas. Why are you here? we asked. The followers of The God shall&#xA;show me the future and the past, right here he said. We asked what does&#xA;the mist of the future hold for us. Ask separately he said. I asked&#xA;first.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kavita’s stone</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/02/2004-02-12_kavitas-stone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/02/2004-02-12_kavitas-stone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/02/12/kavitas-stone/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was a sombre afternoon in the year after dashAnta when Blackie and I&#xA;were wedged in a convenient cleft in the wall that separated the two&#xA;grounds, watching a 3rd rate cricket match played by two second division&#xA;teams. Somehow my mind was not in the match at all for there was hardly&#xA;anything to commend itself in the bowling or batting; nevertheless it&#xA;was better than sitting through the drone of a botany lecture. Blackie&#xA;however was transfixed by the match enjoying even the intended off drive&#xA;of Shri Sandesh Gattaray that flew over thirdman for a six. So when&#xA;Horse-face came by to talk of inversion of matrices and some wierdness&#xA;related to the powers of some x+i*y I found it more worthwhile to&#xA;converse with him. He got a little too carried away and asked if I&#xA;wanted to join him in the library to solve the hottest problems in&#xA;vectors. Heavily disinclined towards such curricular scholarliness&#xA;requested him to seek some other person for his pseudo-intellectual&#xA;pursuits. Blackie was a touch alarmed by the talk of the curriculum but&#xA;another pull from Gattaray that now flew over midoff (!) seemed to erase&#xA;such Samasaric worries. Just then I caught sight of Igul making her way&#xA;along with R and K in our direction. Igul seemed to say something on&#xA;coming close. But I did not perceive that she addressed me because of&#xA;the peculiar shortsightedness in her gaze that came from behind her&#xA;beady spectacles that were acquired as a result of her 15 hour per diem&#xA;study schedules. Igul angrily asked yelled out again with R also saying&#xA;something. I was greatly surprised at the content of Igul’s brisk&#xA;narrative for I never expected Igul to swerve from her path of&#xA;curricular physics and electronics. In any case not being really serious&#xA;about her statement I made some flippant comment. Hearing her repeat her&#xA;case with intensity, and seeing K embellish Igul’s statement, I stated&#xA;that R was as much an expert in such matters as me. I added that R could&#xA;easily answer their question. Both of them looked intently at R: R took&#xA;her time to speak and with a dramatic tone said: “I believe there more&#xA;to this than K and Igul imagine. I believe you must see it yourself.”&#xA;Knowing R well I asked her, using our private code, if she was serious,&#xA;and she said must press for the adventure. Igul and I asked Blackie if&#xA;he wanted to come along, for a burly fellow like him may come of use in&#xA;the event of an adventure beyond our abilities. However, for some reason&#xA;R signaled to me that it would be better to let Blackie remain with his&#xA;cricket. Hence even as Blackie vacillated regarding what to do, we left&#xA;him behind and wended our way in the blazing afternoon heat. R and&#xA;myself being a more acquainted with the outdoors moved ahead with Igul&#xA;and K who were more acquainted with their textbooks than the hills&#xA;following some distance away. We tried to open our classmates to the&#xA;wonders of chrysidid wasps that dwelt in the fig plants dotting the&#xA;ascending slope of dark colored basalt. Igul of course merely smiled&#xA;asking how we told wasps apart from grasshoppers. K while a little more&#xA;discerning was still more interested in finding out the cost of R’s&#xA;dresses and Igul’s bangles than the insects. Soon we walked in two&#xA;groups with R and I talking arthropods and Igul and K talking of their&#xA;next shopping expedition. After about 15 minutes we suddenly realized&#xA;that Igul and K were lagging behind by at least fifteen feet so we sat&#xA;at rock to let them catch up. Even as they neared us K yelled: “We must&#xA;veer left towards the Machi”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ghost</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/02/2004-02-08_the-ghost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/02/2004-02-08_the-ghost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/02/08/the-ghost/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I received a call from him. He sounded much the same rustic fellow as I&#xA;hand last enountered him over 8 years ago. His accent was the same&#xA;rasping one, which sounded like a metal plate rubbing on another. I&#xA;asked what had befallen him. He replied that he had been to the house&#xA;beside the curve on the northward street and was quite sick after his&#xA;stay there. I was shocked, that this could happen. I remembered the old&#xA;words that the place might not be alright. My mind turned to the tale of&#xA;Dildrum and Doldrum.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The dIpAvali vacation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/02/2004-02-02_the-dipavali-vacation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2004/02/2004-02-02_the-dipavali-vacation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/02/02/the-dipavali-vacation/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Never before had I descended to such a low, especially given all the&#xA;show I had made. It was like Tendulkar scoring two zeroes in a row. All&#xA;around us were atirathis and mahArathis (mark that word for it is indeed&#xA;a pun) but still I was a mahArathi too, who had taken on the intense&#xA;heat of battle. Pricked quick by the defeats I had faced, but confident&#xA;about my abilities, I made a charge, even as Prataprao had done in the&#xA;fateful battle of Ahmednagar, and blew away our rival mahArathis in a&#xA;battle that knew no bounds in its fury. After launching myself into this&#xA;fiery battle and emerging victorious, I suddenly felt refreshed at the&#xA;prospect of enjoying a long dIpAvaLI vacation. We met in shady glade at&#xA;the appointed afternoon hour and proceeded to rove the sylvan slopes.&#xA;First there were the 3 bubbles of 65 million year old lava. There the&#xA;sacrificial cock had been butchered and its feathers billowed around.&#xA;Then came the arm chair of the demons; it was wrought in solid basalt.&#xA;Then came flat plateau where the motion of vAta surrounded his&#xA;precocious son. We then descended on the other side where the tower&#xA;arose beside the great basaltic depression of the snake. We saw some&#xA;rival dasyus, I defensively shielded my companion and showed them a sign&#xA;to get lost. We knew we were in control. Then we traversed the extremely&#xA;long path to its end. We peered down the second basaltic depression. We&#xA;saw the turtle again. She said “Batagur baska- We beheld it twice; you&#xA;will experience it at least once more in life. Mark those words and&#xA;think of me when they return to your mind many years later. We shall&#xA;make a profound telepathic connection long after the basaltic&#xA;depressions would have dried. Remember the Oviraptor prancing through&#xA;the Gobi wilderness. “The flash comes home”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
