<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Armies of Islam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/MT/2004-12-30_armies-of-islam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/MT/2004-12-30_armies-of-islam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/12/30/armies-of-islam/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are some striking aspects of the different armies of Islam field in course of the 14 centuries of Jihad against the Kaffrs and Dhimmis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first army of Islam, that of the Arabs, met with rapid somewhat surprising success. It ran through the Sassanian empire in no time and then expanded rapid in the East towards India, in the North East towards Central Asia, the West towards the Christian Roman empire and south towards Africa. The Sassanians fell completely and rather rapidly in Iran to the Islamic Jihad. The campaigns of Abu Muslim and Qutaiba ibn Muslim in central Asia were also widely successful. In the battle of River Talas the Arabs met with a great success against the Chinese army. In Palestine they were successful against the Christian Roman empire (Byzantines). In North Africa they devasted the Christian and pagan states and then invaded Spain and Portugal and conquered huge swaths of Christian southern Europe. Against the Hindus in India they met with considerable success in the Sindh province.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/MT/syria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/MT/syria/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;202412&#34;&gt;202412&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1865839512120648060&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the questions is who are going to make territorial gains from the dismemberment of Syria.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Jews and the Turks seem to have already seized territory: this was probably pre-arranged with the mahAmlechCha.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Kurdistan seems to be in the making &amp;ndash; the question is whether the Turks would move on that. What an how much the mahAmlechCha-allied Al Qaeda will keep is a question. Also we&amp;rsquo;ll have to see how the manage the spill over to Iraq.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
