<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;para-bhakti or supreme devotion on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;para-bhakti or supreme devotion on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>116 THE PREPARATORY RENUNCIATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/116_the_preparatory_renunciation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/116_the_preparatory_renunciation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-preparatory-renunciation&#34;&gt;THE PREPARATORY RENUNCIATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have now finished the consideration of what may be called the&#xA;preparatory Bhakti, and are entering on the study of the Parā-Bhakti or&#xA;supreme devotion. We have to speak of a preparation to the practice of&#xA;this Para-Bhakti. All such preparations are intended only for the&#xA;purification of the soul. The repetition of names, the rituals, the&#xA;forms, and the symbols, all these various things are for the&#xA;purification of the soul. The greatest purifier among all such things, a&#xA;purifier without which no one can enter the regions of this higher&#xA;devotion (Para-Bhakti), is renunciation. This frightens many; yet,&#xA;without it, there cannot be any spiritual growth. In all our Yogas this&#xA;renunciation is necessary. This is the stepping-stone and the real&#xA;centre and the real heart of all spiritual culture — renunciation. This&#xA;is religion — renunciation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>117 THE BHAKTA&#39;S RENUNCIATION RESULTS FROM LOVE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/117_the_bhaktas_renunciation_results_from_love/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/117_the_bhaktas_renunciation_results_from_love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER II&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-bhaktas-renunciation-results-from-love&#34;&gt;THE BHAKTA&amp;rsquo;S RENUNCIATION RESULTS FROM LOVE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We see love everywhere in nature. Whatever in society is good and great&#xA;and sublime is the working out of that love; whatever in society is very&#xA;bad, nay diabolical, is also the ill-directed working out of the same&#xA;emotion of love. It is this same emotion that gives us the pure and holy&#xA;conjugal love between husband and wife as well as the sort of love which&#xA;goes to satisfy the lowest forms of animal passion. The emotion is the&#xA;same, but its manifestation is different in different cases. It is the&#xA;same feeling of love, well or ill directed, that impels one man to do&#xA;good and to give all he has to the poor, while it makes another man cut&#xA;the throats of his brethren and take away all their possessions. The&#xA;former loves others as much as the latter loves himself. The direction&#xA;of the love is bad in the case of the latter, but it is right and proper&#xA;in the other case. The same fire that cooks a meal for us may burn a&#xA;child, and it is no fault of the fire if it does so; the difference lies&#xA;in the way in which it is used. Therefore love, the intense longing for&#xA;association, the strong desire on the part of two to become one — and it&#xA;may be, after all, of all to become merged in one — is being manifested&#xA;everywhere in higher or lower forms as the case may be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>118 THE FORMS OF LOVE — MANIFESTATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/118_the_forms_of_love-manifestation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/118_the_forms_of_love-manifestation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER IV&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-forms-of-love--manifestation&#34;&gt;THE FORMS OF LOVE — MANIFESTATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the forms in which love manifests itself. First there&#xA;is reverence. Why do people show reverence to temples and holy places?&#xA;Because He is worshipped there, and His presence is associated with all&#xA;such places. Why do people in every country pay reverence to teachers of&#xA;religion? It is natural for the human heart to do so, because all such&#xA;teachers preach the Lord. At bottom, reverence is a growth out of love;&#xA;we can none of us revere him whom we do not love. Then comes Priti —&#xA;pleasure in God. What an immense pleasure men take in the objects of the&#xA;senses. They go anywhere, run through any danger, to get the thing which&#xA;they love, the thing which their senses like. What is wanted of the&#xA;Bhakta is this very kind of intense love which has, however, to be&#xA;directed to God. Then there is the sweetest of pains, Viraha, the&#xA;intense misery due to the absence of the beloved. When a man feels&#xA;intense misery because he has not attained to God, has not known that&#xA;which is the only thing worthy to be known, and becomes in consequence&#xA;very dissatisfied and almost mad — then there is Viraha; and this state&#xA;of the mind makes him feel disturbed in the presence of anything other&#xA;than the beloved (Ekarativichikitsā). In earthly love we see how often&#xA;this Viraha comes. Again, when men are really and intensely in love with&#xA;women or women with men, they feel a kind of natural annoyance in the&#xA;presence of all those whom they do not love. Exactly the same state of&#xA;impatience in regard to things that are not loved comes to the mind when&#xA;Para-Bhakti holds sway over it; even to talk about things other than God&#xA;becomes distasteful then. &amp;ldquo;Think of Him, think of Him alone, and give up&#xA;all other vain words&amp;rdquo; अन्या वाचो विमुंचथ। — Those who talk of Him alone,&#xA;the Bhakta finds to be friendly to him; while those who talk of anything&#xA;else appear to him to be unfriendly. A still higher stage of love is&#xA;reached when life itself is maintained for the sake of the one Ideal of&#xA;Love, when life itself is considered beautiful and worth living only on&#xA;account of that Love (तदर्थप्राणसंस्थानं). Without it, such a life would&#xA;not remain even for a moment. Life is sweet, because it thinks of the&#xA;Beloved. Tadiyatā (&lt;em&gt;His-ness&lt;/em&gt;) comes when a man becomes perfect&#xA;according to Bhakti — when he has become blessed, when he has attained&#xA;God, when he has touched the feet of God, as it were. Then his whole&#xA;nature is purified and completely changed. All his purpose in life then&#xA;becomes fulfilled. Yet many such Bhaktas live on just to worship Him.&#xA;That is the bliss, the only pleasure in life which they will not give&#xA;up. &amp;ldquo;O king, such is the blessed quality of Hari that even those who&#xA;have become satisfied with everything, all the knots of whose hearts&#xA;have been cut asunder, even they love the Lord for love&amp;rsquo;s sake&amp;rdquo; — the&#xA;Lord &amp;ldquo;Whom all the gods worship — all the lovers of liberation, and all&#xA;the knowers of the Brahman&amp;rdquo; — यं सर्वे देवा नमन्ति मुमुक्षवो&#xA;ब्रह्मवादिनश्चेति (&lt;em&gt;Nri&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Tap&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Up&lt;/em&gt;.). Such is the power of love. When&#xA;a man has forgotten himself altogether, and does not feel that anything&#xA;belongs to him, then he acquires the state of Tadiyata; everything is&#xA;sacred to him, because it belongs to the Beloved. Even in regard to&#xA;earthly love, the lover thinks that everything belonging to his beloved&#xA;is sacred and so dear to him. He loves even a piece of cloth belonging&#xA;to the darling of his heart In the same way, when a person loves the&#xA;Lord, the whole universe becomes dear to him, because it is all His.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>119 UNIVERSAL LOVE AND HOW IT LEADS TO SELF-SURRENDER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/119_universal_love_and_how_it_leads_to_self-surrender/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/119_universal_love_and_how_it_leads_to_self-surrender/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER V&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;universal-love-and-how-it-leads-to-self-surrender&#34;&gt;UNIVERSAL LOVE AND HOW IT LEADS TO SELF-SURRENDER&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How can we love the Vyashti, the particular, without first loving the&#xA;Samashti, the universal? God is the Samashti, the generalised and the&#xA;abstract universal whole; and the universe that we see is the Vyashti,&#xA;the particularised thing. To love the whole universe is possible only by&#xA;way of loving the Samashti — the universal — which is, as it were, the&#xA;one unity in which are to be found millions and millions of smaller&#xA;unities. The philosophers of India do not stop at the particulars; they&#xA;cast a hurried glance at the particulars and immediately start to find&#xA;the generalised forms which will include all the particulars. The search&#xA;after the universal is the one search of Indian philosophy and religion.&#xA;The Jnāni aims at the wholeness of things, at that one absolute and;&#xA;generalised Being, knowing which he knows everything. The Bhakta wishes&#xA;to realise that one generalised abstract Person, in loving whom he loves&#xA;the whole universe. The Yogi wishes to have possession of that one&#xA;generalised form of power, by controlling which he controls this whole&#xA;universe. The Indian mind, throughout its history, has been directed to&#xA;this kind of singular search after the universal in everything — in&#xA;science, in psychology, in love, in philosophy. So the conclusion to&#xA;which the Bhakta comes is that, if you go on merely loving one, person&#xA;after another, you may go on loving them so for an infinite length of&#xA;time, without being in the least able to love the world as a whole.&#xA;When, at last, the central idea is, however, arrived at that the sum&#xA;total of all love is God, that the sum total of the aspirations of all&#xA;the souls in the universe, whether they be free, or bound, or struggling&#xA;towards liberation, is God, then alone it becomes possible for any one&#xA;to put forth universal love. God is the Samashti, and this visible&#xA;universe is God differentiated and made manifest. If we love this sum&#xA;total, we love everything. Loving the world doing it good will all come&#xA;easily then; we have to obtain this power only by loving God first;&#xA;otherwise it is no joke to do good to the world. &amp;ldquo;Everything is His and&#xA;He is my Lover; I love Him,&amp;rdquo; says the Bhakta. In this way everything&#xA;becomes sacred to the Bhakta, because all things are His. All are His&#xA;children, His body, His manifestation. How then may we hurt any one? How&#xA;then may we not love any one? With the love of God will come, as a sure&#xA;effect, the love of every one in the universe. The nearer we approach&#xA;God, the more do we begin to see that all things are in Him. When the&#xA;soul succeeds in appropriating the bliss of this supreme love, it also&#xA;begins to see Him in everything. Our heart will thus become an eternal&#xA;fountain of love. And when we reach even higher states of this love, all&#xA;the little differences between the things of the world are entirely&#xA;lost; man is seen no more as man, but only as God; the animal is seen no&#xA;more as animal, but as God; even the tiger is no more a tiger, but a&#xA;manifestation of God. Thus in this intense state of Bhakti, worship is&#xA;offered to every one, to every life, and to every being. एवं सर्वेषु&#xA;भूतेषु भक्तिरव्यभिचारिणी। कर्तव्या पण्डितैर्ज्ञात्वा सर्वभूतमयं हरिम्॥ —&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Knowing that Hari, the Lord, is in every being, the wise have thus to&#xA;manifest unswerving love towards all beings.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>120 THE HIGHER KNOWLEDGE AND THE HIGHER LOVE ARE ONE TO THE TRUE
LOVER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/120_the_higher_knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/120_the_higher_knowledge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER VI&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-higher-knowledge-and-the-higher-love-are-one-to-the-true-lover&#34;&gt;THE HIGHER KNOWLEDGE AND THE HIGHER LOVE ARE ONE TO THE TRUE LOVER&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Upanishads distinguish between a higher knowledge and a lower&#xA;knowledge; and to the Bhakta there is really no difference between this&#xA;higher knowledge and his higher love (Parā-Bhakti). The Mundaka&#xA;Upanishad says:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;द्वे विद्ये वेदितव्ये इति ह स्म यद्ब्रह्मविदो वदन्ति। परा चैवापरा च॥&#xA;तत्रापरा ॠग्वेदो यजुर्वदः सामवेदोऽथर्ववेदः शिक्षा कल्पो व्याकरणं&#xA;निरुक्तं छन्दो ज्योतिषमिति। अथ परा यया तदक्षरमधिगम्यते॥&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>121 THE TRIANGLE OF LOVE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/121_the_triangle_of_love/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/121_the_triangle_of_love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER VII&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-triangle-of-love&#34;&gt;THE TRIANGLE OF LOVE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We may represent love as a triangle, each of the angles of which&#xA;corresponds to one of its inseparable characteristics. There can be no&#xA;triangle without all its three angles; and there can be no true love&#xA;without its three following characteristics. The first angle of our&#xA;triangle of love is that love knows no bargaining. Wherever there is any&#xA;seeking for something in return, there can, be no real love; it becomes&#xA;a mere matter of shop-keeping. As long as there is in us any idea of&#xA;deriving this or that favour from God in return for our respect and&#xA;allegiance to Him, so long there can be no true love growing in our&#xA;hearts. Those who worship God because they wish Him to bestow favours on&#xA;them are sure not to worship Him if those favours are not forthcoming.&#xA;The Bhakta loves the Lord because He is lovable, there is no other&#xA;motive originating or directing this divine emotion of the true devotee.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>122 THE GOD OF LOVE IS HIS OWN PROOF</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/122_the_god_of_love_is_his_own_proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/122_the_god_of_love_is_his_own_proof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER VIII&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-god-of-love-is-his-own-proof&#34;&gt;THE GOD OF LOVE IS HIS OWN PROOF&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is the ideal of the lover who has quite passed beyond the idea of&#xA;selfishness, of bartering and bargaining, and who knows no fear? Even to&#xA;the great God such a man will say, &amp;ldquo;I will give You my all, and I do not&#xA;want anything from You; indeed there is nothing that I can call my own.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;When a man has acquired this conviction, his ideal becomes one of&#xA;perfect love, one of perfect fearlessness of love. The highest ideal of&#xA;such a person has no narrowness of particularity about it; it is love&#xA;universal, love without limits and bonds, love itself, absolute love.&#xA;This grand ideal of the religion of love is worshipped and loved&#xA;absolutely as such without the aid of any symbols or suggestions. This&#xA;is the highest form of Para-Bhakti — the worship of such an&#xA;all-comprehending ideal as the ideal; all the other forms of Bhakti are&#xA;only stages on the way to reach it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>123 HUMAN REPRESENTATIONS OF THE DIVINE IDEAL OF LOVE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/123_human_representations_of_the_divine_ideal_of_love/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/123_human_representations_of_the_divine_ideal_of_love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER IX&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;human-representations-of-the-divine-ideal-of-love&#34;&gt;HUMAN REPRESENTATIONS OF THE DIVINE IDEAL OF LOVE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is impossible to express the nature of this supreme and absolute&#xA;ideal of love in human language. Even the highest flight of human&#xA;imagination is incapable of comprehending it in all its infinite&#xA;perfection and beauty. Nevertheless, the followers of the religion of&#xA;love, in its higher as well as its lower forms, in all countries, have&#xA;all along had to use the inadequate human language to comprehend and to&#xA;define their own ideal of love. Nay more, human love itself, in all its&#xA;varied forms has been made to typify this inexpressible divine love. Man&#xA;can think of divine things only in his own human way, to us the Absolute&#xA;can be expressed only in our relative language. The whole universe is to&#xA;us a writing of the Infinite in the language of the finite. Therefore&#xA;Bhaktas make use of all the common terms associated with the common love&#xA;of humanity in relation to God and His worship through love.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>124 CONCLUSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/124_conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/para-bhakti_or_supreme_devotion/124_conclusion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER X&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When this highest ideal of love is reached, philosophy is thrown away;&#xA;who will then care for it? Freedom, Salvation, Nirvāna — all are thrown&#xA;away; who cares to become free while in the enjoyment of divine love?&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Lord, I do not want wealth, nor friends, nor beauty, nor learning, nor&#xA;even freedom; let me be born again and again, and be Thou ever my Love.&#xA;Be Thou ever and ever my Love.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Who cares to become sugar?&amp;rdquo; says the&#xA;Bhakta, &amp;ldquo;I want to taste sugar.&amp;rdquo; Who will then desire to become free and&#xA;one with God? &amp;ldquo;I may know that I am He; yet will I take myself away from&#xA;Him and become different, so that I may enjoy the Beloved.&amp;rdquo; That is what&#xA;the Bhakta says. Love for love&amp;rsquo;s sake is his highest enjoyment. Who will&#xA;not be bound hand and foot a thousand times over to enjoy the Beloved?&#xA;No Bhakta cares for anything except love, except to love and to be&#xA;loved. His unworldly love is like the tide rushing up the river; this&#xA;lover goes up the river against the current. The world calls him mad. I&#xA;know one whom the world used to call mad, and this was his answer: &amp;ldquo;My&#xA;friends, the whole world is a lunatic asylum. Some are mad after worldly&#xA;love, some after name, some after fame, some after money, some after&#xA;salvation and going to heaven. In this big lunatic asylum I am also mad,&#xA;I am mad after God. If you are mad after money, I am mad after God. You&#xA;are mad; so am I. I think my madness is after all the best.&amp;rdquo; The true&#xA;Bhakta&amp;rsquo;s love is this burning madness before which everything else&#xA;vanishes for him. The whole universe is to him full of love and love&#xA;alone; that is how it seems to the lover. So when a man has this love in&#xA;him, he becomes eternally blessed, eternally happy. This blessed madness&#xA;of divine love alone can cure for ever the disease of the world that is&#xA;in us. With desire, selfishness has vanished. He has drawn near to God,&#xA;he has thrown off all those vain desires of which he was full before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
