<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;shAhu on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/shAhu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;shAhu on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/shAhu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Appointment speech to bAjI rAv</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/shAhu/appointment-speech_to_bAjIrAv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/shAhu/appointment-speech_to_bAjIrAv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After Balaji Vishwanath, Baji Rao rendered meritorious services with all unswervine devotion. He was sent to restore the Emperor to the throne after defeating Nadir Shah. The end of his life approached. His object was to bring back the wealth from Iran after defeating the Shab. By God&amp;rsquo;s will this has bappened, though hope was entertained (of defeating the Shah). You are his son and worthy of achieving great successes by faithful service Bajirao&amp;rsquo;s aim remained unfulfilled, so also my resolve to obtain hall of India after protecting the weak Emperor from the Irani. You should now fulfil the resolve by accomplishing the conquest of the whole of Hindasthan without dis pensiog with the emperor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>shAhu to bAji rAv</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/shAhu/shAhu_to_bAji-rAv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/shAhu/shAhu_to_bAji-rAv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That it should be our duty to resuscitate the falling Mughal Empire, that the Chhatrapati, as you are already aware, does not aspire to secure the imperial position for himself, that he considers it a higher merit to renovate an old dilapidated edifice than to build a new one. If we attempt the other course (i.e. a Hindu monarchy) it would involve us in enmity with all our neighbors with the consequence that we would be exposed to unnecessary dangers and court a crop of trouble all round.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>shAhu to nAnAsAheb</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/shAhu/shAhu-to-nAnAsAheb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/peshva-age/docs/shAhu/shAhu-to-nAnAsAheb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After Balaji Vishwanath, Baji Rao rendered meritorious services with all unswerving devotion. He was sent to restore the Emperor to the throne after defeating Nadir Shah. The end of his life approached. His object was to bring back the wealth from Iran after defeating the Shah. By God&amp;rsquo;s will this has happened, though hope was entertained (of defeating the Shah). You are his son and worthy of achieving great successes by faithful service Bajirao&amp;rsquo;s aim remained unfulfilled, so also my resolve to obtain hall of India after protecting the weak Emperor from the Irani. You should now fulfil the resolve by accomplishing the conquest of the whole of Hindasthan without dispensing with the emperor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
