<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Arranged marriage</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/arranged-marriage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/arranged-marriage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If u travel back 40 years from 1960&amp;rsquo;s to Taisho era Japan, u had people having arranged marriages &amp;amp; meeting each other on the day of the wedding&#xA;So we learn from a Guinness World Records video about Kane Tanaka (116 yrs old in 2019)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtube.com/watch?v=FK0-sW95CpA&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>blood-revenge</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/blood-revenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/blood-revenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;rjrasvacomment&#34;&gt;Rjrasvacomment&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Rjrasva/status/1641386214186991616&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not only was it very rare but found out that blood revenge was elaborately regulated, u had to register ur intention to carry out a revenge killing with both ur local daimyo &amp;amp; the Tokugawa authorities, obtain paper approval, peasant women were allowed to kill Samurai men so long as they got gov&amp;rsquo;t approval for the revenge which was only given for murder not mere insults. You also had to only kill the target approved not any1 else in his/her family, the killed person&amp;rsquo;s family members in turn couldn&amp;rsquo;t legally kill u or any1 in ur family because the killed person was a murderer. So no generations long Hatfield-Mccoy style feuding that was common in some societies like Sicily, Corsica etc:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bloodless reorganization</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/bloodless_reorganization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/bloodless_reorganization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Prefectures, Power, and Centralization: Japan’s Abolition of the Feudal Domains&#xA;Aug 27, 2021&#xA;In 1871, Japan abolished the system of feudal domains that had existed for seven centuries - Abolishing 700 yrs in 3 yrs with no bloodshed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Griffis’s account continues:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow Fukui bids farewell to feudalism. On the next day we shall be in a province without a prince. The era of loyalty is passed. The era of patriotism has come &amp;hellip;&#xA;resting upright before him as he sat on his knees, were the three thousand samurai of the Fukui clan . . .&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It was more than a farewell to their feudal lord. It was the solemn burial of the institutions under which their fathers had lived for seven hundred years. &amp;hellip;&#xA;Each face seemed to wear a far-away expression, as if their eyes were looking into the past, or striving to probe an uncertain future. &amp;hellip;&#xA;In conclusion, he adjured all his followers to tranfer their allegiance wholly to the mikado and the imperial house.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kitaro arranged bride</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/kitaro-arranged-bride/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/kitaro-arranged-bride/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Bride of Boneyard Kitaro&#xA;David Greer&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[W]hen Nunoe’s uncle told the family he’d found a match for her in a 39 year-old veteran who’d lost his left arm in the war and wrote comic books in Tokyo, Nunoe’s father rubbed his chin and said “make it happen.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nunoe blinked. Up until now, her father had turned away marriage proposals the way he did unwelcome peddlers. But then again, there just wasn’t a place for her in the house anymore. Her two older sisters had husbands, and her eldest brother’s wife was more than enough help in the family liquor store. Besides, Nunoe was 29, way past the age brides unpack their hope chests, and in Japan in 1960, especially in the village she lived — just a stitch in a quilt of rice fields, really — women married for love as often as they flew to the moon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Late rustic habits</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/late-rustic-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/late-rustic-habits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 70s (Source: @bull_japanese etc..)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;jumping queue was common. People climbed through train windows to get seats.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;People including women pissed on the side of streets. (Continued in 2020, but more discreetly.) &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t piss here&amp;rdquo; signs are still sold.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spitting on streets was common.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Any puddle would soon become a sea of floating cigarette butts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Railroad tracks were covered in feces (&amp;ldquo;dump on tracks&amp;rdquo; toilets). Same in Britain.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ms asada suicide</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/ms-asada-suicide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/ms-asada-suicide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Suicide of an Officer&amp;rsquo;s Wife.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;The Tokyo papers report the suicide of the wife of Lieut. Asada,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;who was killed in the last Manchurian campaign undertaken by Gen. I in order to recover Feughwau.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Mrs. Asada was a daughter of Major Okami, who commanded the third battalion of the Maruyama force. She was brought up. under a rigid system and had only married the lieutenant the year before last. She was very virtuous, and was regarded by all who knew her as the model of a soldier&amp;rsquo;s wife. The lieutenant held his commission in the battalion commanded by his father-in-law, and it was from her father that the young widow received the tidings of her husband&amp;rsquo;s death. After writing an account of the battle, the letter went on to this effect:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nogi suicide</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/nogi-suicide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/articles/nogi-suicide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1694622732850434165.html#google_vignette&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1912, the Newspaper carried a vivid account of the Seppuku of the General Nogi Maresuke(1849 –1912) and his wife Shizuko.&#xA;The head of the Akasaka Police department said there were many false rumors about the Seppuku of Shogun Nogi and his wife,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Incorrect details regarding the Waripuku (Seppuku) of the Shogun Nogi at the eight o’clock in the evening on the 13th of September (the day of the Meiji Emperor’s funeral). For this reason I would like to tell the truth about what happened in his final moments.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
