<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hadza health</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/hadza-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/hadza-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1506996684756193280.html&#34;&gt;Thread by @dranthonygustin on Thread Reader App.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hunted, killed, and ate a wild baboon (brains and all) with the indigenous Hadza tribe in Africa. Here are the 13 things I learned about human health along the way. But why? I&amp;rsquo;ve been fascinated with human health my entire life. Wild humans with their full genetic expression are nearly extinct. We are now zoo inhabitants. So last year @CarnivoreMD and I went to Tanzania, where humans first evolved, to see our species in our natural habitat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marathon mortality</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/marathon-mortality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/marathon-mortality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Marathon running &amp;amp; mortality: Endurance training improves fitness &amp;amp; possibly reduces average long term mortality. However, risk of dying during running itself is marginally higher than average. Of course, marathon running us a rare cause of death. Problems during running:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heart attack: increased shear stress of blood during endurance training can rupture coronary atherosclerotic plaques causing thrombosis &amp;amp; MI. Risk in untrained runners, smokers. Train gradually &amp;amp; stop smoking to prevent.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy: commonly implicated in sudden death during competitive sports. Prevalence of HCM in community is underestimated though not the variants leading to high mortality. Routine echo not advised unless family h/o sudden death or dizziness during runs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hyperthermia: Every hour of running leads to increase in core body temperature by 1 degree C. Adequate cooling by drinking water/dousing oneself with water can prevent hyperthermia related problems.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dehydration/ Hyponatremia: loss of fluid &amp;amp; electrolytes can cause cardiac arrest, if inadequately/inappropriately replaced. Mere free water intake during long distance running can lead to electrolyte imbalance esp low sodium. Electrolyte solutions/tablets advised.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running-knee-health</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/running-knee-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/running-knee-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mdhealth.com.au/does-running-effect-your-knees/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does Running effect your knees?&#xA;Mechanically speaking, how does running affect the knees? What force, for example, does it place on the joints and how does it impact cartilage?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Running increases the load on two specific parts of the knees.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The load on the major tendon of the quadriceps muscles (the patella tendon) is anything from 4.7 to 6.9 times your body weight.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;As you run, the compression forces on the knee cap (patella-femoral joint) can be anywhere from 7 to 11.1 times your body weight.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The issue is that the major source of pain in the knee comes from irritation of the lining of the knee cap. In particular, the synovial sheath. This is a thin layer of cells that have a very rich blood supply and very rich nerve supply. This is what lines the joint capsule. When there is irritation of the knee cap cartilage, small fragments break off and land in this lining. This causes irritation and pain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>strength-standards</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/strength-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/vyAyAmaH/articles/strength-standards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;men&#34;&gt;Men&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Push&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Expected = Bodyweight bench press&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Game-changer = Bodyweight bench press for 15 reps&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pull&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Expected = 5 pullups&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Game-changer = 15 pullups&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hinge&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Expected = Bodyweight to 150% bodyweight deadlift&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Game-changer = Double-bodyweight deadlift&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Squat&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Expected = Bodyweight squat&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Game-changer = Bodyweight squat for 15 reps&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Loaded Carry&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Expected = Farmer walk with total bodyweight (half per hand)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Game-changer =Bodyweight per hand&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Getup&lt;br&gt;&#xA;One left and right, done with a half-filled cup of water&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
