<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v1-origin/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v1-origin/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>bachChe rAv</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v1-origin/articles/bachChe-rAv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v1-origin/articles/bachChe-rAv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Naib Dewan Bachhe Rao : 1744 - 1804 (Living)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Naib Dewan Bachhe Rao (also referred to as Butcherow by Mark Wilks; butcharow by Francis Buchanan; Butche Row by Arthur Wellesley; and Buche Rao by others; the spelling now adopted is based on the way the name is written in Haidar Nama and other Kannada publications) was the son of Khande Rao Banaji (Appendix VI).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although Haidar killed Khande Rao and punished his partisans, he did not harm his family members. Bachhe Rao was born in1744 (?) and was 17 years old when his father, Khande Rao, was killed. He was aware of the misunderstanding between his father and Haidar; the efforts made by Khande Rao to enlist the help of the Marhatta and the English armies to drive Haidar out of Mysore kingdom; the gun fire at Srirangapatna and escape of Haidar; subsequent wars and surrender of his father to Haidar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>khANDe rAv</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v1-origin/articles/khANDe-rAv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v1-origin/articles/khANDe-rAv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Khande Rao Banaji - 1730 - 1762 ( Interpolation - See events )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Khande Rao (also referred to as Kunde Row by Mark Wilks; Canero by the French writer M. M. De La Tour; Conderow by Captain Francis Robson, an English writer; Panderau by Eloy Jose Correa Peixoto, a Portugese writer; Khandi Rao by Ramachandra Rao Punganuri in his memoir on Haider Ali translated from Marathi to English by Charles Philip Brown, and Khande Rao Banaji in the Records of the Peshwa Daftar, Pune), was closely associated with the history of Mysore as a loyal officer who made a valiant effort to restore the Mysore kingdom to Krishnaraja Wodeyar II from Haidar Ali, the usurper.+++(5)+++ Khande Rao was a key figure who could have changed the course of Mysore history if he had succeeded in his effort to drive Haidar Ali out of the kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
