<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;2 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;2 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 HISTORY AND POLITICS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/2/01_HISTORY_AND_POLITICS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/2/01_HISTORY_AND_POLITICS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Historians are sometimes ridiculed for indulging in conjectures about what would have followed in history if some one event had fallen out diflferently. &amp;quot; So gloriously unpractical ! &amp;quot; we exclaim. Now it is not for the sake of practice, but for the sake of theory, that such conjectures are hazarded, and I think historians should deal in them much more than they do. It is an illusion to suppose that great public events, because they are on a grander scale, have something more fatally necessary about them than ordinary private events ; and this illusion enslaves the judgment. To form any opinion or estimate of a great national policy is impossible so long as you refuse even to imagine any other policy pursued. This remark is especially applicable to an event so vast and complex as the Expansion of England. Think for a moment, if there had been no connection of England with the New World ! How utterly different would have been the whole course 190 EXPANSION OF ENGLAND leot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 THE INDIAN EMPIRE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/2/02_THE_INDIAN_EMPIRE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/2/02_THE_INDIAN_EMPIRE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As formerly the Colonial Empire, so now the Indian Empire is to be considered only so far as it illustrates the general law of expansion which prevails in the modern part of English history. It will be considered not in itself, but only in its relation to our own state. It will be considered historically—that is, in the causes which produced it ; but also politically— that is, in regard to its value or stability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 HOW WE CONQUERED INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/2/03_HOW_WE_CONQUERED_INDIA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/2/03_HOW_WE_CONQUERED_INDIA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The question how we conquered India does not at all resemble the questions which I raised in the last course. Our colonists in the new world occupied, to be sure, a vast territory, but it was comparatively an empty territory. The difficulties they encountered arose not so much from the natives, as from the rivalry of other European nations. By what degrees and from what causes we gained the advantage over these rivals, I partly discussed. It was a question to which the answer was not at once obvious, but at the same time not extremely difficult to find. On the other hand it is at first sight extremely perplexing to understand how we could conquer India. Here the population was dense, and its civilisation, though descending along a different stream of tradition, was as real and ancient as our own.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 HOW WE GOVERN INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/2/04_HOW_WE_GOVERN_INDIA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/2/04_HOW_WE_GOVERN_INDIA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I HAVE considered the nature of the relation in which India stands to England, and have tried to explain how this relation could spring up without a miracle. We may now advance a step and form some opinion on the question whether that relation can endure without a miracle, as it was created without one, or whether we ought to regard the government of India by the English as a kind of political tmr de force, a matter of astonishment while it lasts, but certain not to last very long. For the great difficulty which the student has to contend Avith in studying Indian affairs is the dazzling effect of events so strange, so remote, and on a scale so large, by which he is led to think that ordinary causation is not to be expected in India, and that in that region all is miraculous. The rhetorical tone ordinarily adopted in history favours this illusion ; historians are fond of parading all the strange and marvellous features of the Indian Empire, as if it were less their business to account 252 EXPANSION OF ENGLAND LBCT.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 MUTUAL INFLUENCE OF ENGLAND AND INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/2/05_MUTUAL_INFLUENCE_OF_ENGLAND_AND_INDIA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/2/05_MUTUAL_INFLUENCE_OF_ENGLAND_AND_INDIA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last two lectures I was engaged in showing that the conquest of India and the government of it by the English have in a certain sense nothing wonderful about them. We may fairly be proud of many particular deeds done by our countrymen in India, and of many men who in India have shown a rare energy and talent for government, but it is a mistake to suppose that the Empire itself is a stand- ing proof of some vast superiority in the English race over the races of India. Without assuming any such vast superiority we are able to assign causes, which are sufficient to account alike for the growth and for the continuance of that Empire. It is not then wonderful, if by wonderful be meant simply miraculous, or difficult to account for by ordinary causation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 PHASES IN THE CONQUEST OF INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/2/06_PHASES_IN_THE_CONQUEST_OF_INDIA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/2/06_PHASES_IN_THE_CONQUEST_OF_INDIA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The sum of what I have laid before you up to this point is that in India a result has been produced by causes less wonderful than is commonly supposed, which result is in magnitude more wonderful, and in the consequences which may possibly flow from it far more wonderful and great, than is imagined. But in showing how such a result could be produced without a miracle I have laid stress upon another peculiarity of this Empire, which is of fundamental importance, namely the slightness of the machinery which con- nects it with England. Let us now remark that in this respect our Indian Empire resembles our colonies. There is of course this vast difference, that our chief colonies determine in most matters their own policy through Governments which spring up by a constitu tional process out of the colonial assembly, and that India has no such independent initiative, the Viceroy himself being liable to be overruled by the Indian Secretary at home. But at the same time there isLECT. VI PHASES IN THE CONQUEST OF INDIA 295 this great resemblance, that India, like the colonies, has been held at arm&amp;rsquo;s length, that its Government has never been suffered to approach the Home Government so closely as to blend with it, or to modify its character, or to hamper its independent development. India is both constitutionally and financially an independent Empire. If the Empire of the Great Mogul had continued in its original vigour up to the present time, no doubt in foreign affairs the history of England would differ consider- ably from what it is. Several of our wars with France would have taken a different turn, especially that war of which the Egyptian expedition of Bona parte was a main incident. We can imagine too that the Crimean War would not have happened, and that we should not have taken the interest we did in the recent Eusso-Turkish war. But the con stitution of the English state would have been precisely what it is, and our domestic history would have run almost exactly the same course. Only once, I think, namely in 1783, has India come quite into the foreground of parliamentary debate and absorbed the attention of the political world. Even in the Mutiny of 1857, deeply as our feelings were stirred, the course of home politics was not aflFectcd by the affairs of India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 INTERNAL AND EXTERNAL DANGERS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/2/07_INTERNAL_AND_EXTERNAL_DANGERS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/2/07_INTERNAL_AND_EXTERNAL_DANGERS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For estimating the stability of an Empire there are certain plain tests which the political student ought to have at his fingers&amp;rsquo; ends. Of these some are applied to its internal organisation, and some to its external conditions, just as an insurance company in estimating the value of a life will take the opinion of the medical oflBcer, who will feel the candidate&amp;rsquo;s pulse and listen to his heart, but they will also inquire how and where the candidate lives, and whether his pursuits or habits expose him to any peculiar risks from without. Now I have partly applied the internal test. The internal test of the vitality of a state consists in ascertaining whether or no the Government rests upon a solid basis. For in every state besides the two things which are obvious to all, viz. the Government and the governed, there is a third thing, which is overlooked by most of us, and yet is usually not difficult to distinguish, — mean the power outside the Government which holds the Government up. This power may be slight or&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 RECAPITULATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/2/08_RECAPITULATION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/2/08_RECAPITULATION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have now dwelt for a long time on that extra- ordinary expansion which has had the effect that, considered as a state, England has left Europe altogether behind it and become a world-state, while, considered purely as a nation—that is, as speaking a certain language—she has furnished out two world states, which vie with each other in vigour, influence, and rapidity of growth. We have inquired into the causes, traced the process, and considered some of the results of this expansion. It remains then in this closing lecture to gather up the impressions we have received into a general conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
