<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Cochran Gregory on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/articles/cochran-gregory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Cochran Gregory on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/articles/cochran-gregory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deaths with covid - cochran</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/articles/cochran-gregory/deaths_with_covid_cochran/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/articles/cochran-gregory/deaths_with_covid_cochran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/gcochran99/status/1894836502586368070&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thread by @gcochran99 on Thread Reader App – Thread Reader App&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Deaths 𝙬𝙞𝙩𝙝 Covid&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Grok):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Misclassifications don’t change the raw count of bodies. The total number of deaths is what it is, whether we label them COVID, heart disease, or something else. That’s why excess deaths are such a useful yardstick here: they sidestep the whole “what’s on the certificate” debate and just show how many more people died than we’d expect based on pre-pandemic norms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Medicine efficacy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/articles/cochran-gregory/medicine-efficacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/articles/cochran-gregory/medicine-efficacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Claude: &amp;quot; A CDC report found that receiving 2 or 3 doses of an mRNA COVID-19 vaccine was associated with a 90% reduction in risk for COVID-19–associated invasive mechanical ventilation or death. Protection was even higher (94%) during the Omicron period for those who received 3 doses.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;chatgpt: &amp;ldquo;COVID-19 mRNA vaccines have significantly reduced the risk of death associated with the virus. For instance, a study in New South Wales, Australia, found that unvaccinated individuals were more than 16 times more likely to experience severe illness or death compared to those who were vaccinated. Additionally, the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) reported that unvaccinated people were 11 times more likely to die from COVID-19 than those fully vaccinated. These findings underscore the substantial protective effect of mRNA vaccines against COVID-19 mortality.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vs flu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/articles/cochran-gregory/vs_flu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/virus/ribo/ortho-rna/corona/wuhan_epidemic/articles/cochran-gregory/vs_flu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 control measures (masking, distancing, reduced gatherings, etc.) created what epidemiologists might call a &amp;ldquo;transmission bottleneck&amp;rdquo; that affected different respiratory viruses differently:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For influenza (R0 ~1.3-1.5): The interventions reduced transmission potential below the critical threshold of R0=1, causing cases to plummet globally&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For SARS-CoV-2 (starting R0 ~2-3, increasing over time): The same interventions reduced transmission but often not below the critical threshold, especially as more transmissible variants emerged.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Influenza got hit so hard by the control measures it looks like one of the 4 big strains of it &lt;em&gt;went extinct&lt;/em&gt;.  COVID is just a different beast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
