<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;6 India under Jahangir and Shah Jahan, 1605–1658 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/6_India_under_Jahangir_and_Shah_Jahan_16051658/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;6 India under Jahangir and Shah Jahan, 1605–1658 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/6_India_under_Jahangir_and_Shah_Jahan_16051658/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 JAHANGIR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/6_India_under_Jahangir_and_Shah_Jahan_16051658/01_JAHANGIR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/6_India_under_Jahangir_and_Shah_Jahan_16051658/01_JAHANGIR/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Of his three sons, Akbar favoured his firstborn, Salim, to succeed him. Yet Salim, even while being groomed for the throne, felt excluded from what he deemed his proper share of royal authority. He was especially jealous of the attention that his father showered on his principal adviser and friend, Abu’l-fazl. Already in the early 1590s, he began showing signs of impatience for full sovereign power, picking fights with his younger brothers and engaging in excesses and follies that Abu’l-fazl would bring to Akbar’s attention. This only created tensions between father and son, while intensifying the prince’s hostility towards Abu’l-fazl. Matters came to a head in 1599 when, while his father was campaigning in the Deccan, Salim gathered supporters and made an impetuous strike on Agra, where the imperial treasure was stored. When Akbar’s mother scolded the wayward prince, Salim, ashamed and unable to challenge his dear grandmother, dashed back to his base in Allahabad. In 1601, after Akbar had returned to Agra, he again marched towards the capital, pretending to pay respects to his father. But he turned away, intimidated by the prospect of actually confronting him. Yet when he returned to Allahabad, he followed the urgings of his advisers and set up his own court. He even assumied imperial titles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 THE VIEW FROM THE FRONTIER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/6_India_under_Jahangir_and_Shah_Jahan_16051658/02_THE_VIEW_FROM_THE_FRONTIER/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/6_India_under_Jahangir_and_Shah_Jahan_16051658/02_THE_VIEW_FROM_THE_FRONTIER/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jahangir’s India amounted to much more than the palace intrigues and battles that fill the pages of contemporary chronicles, or the courtly gossip that so fascinated contemporary European visitors. A very different picture emerges if one steps away from the courtly centre and considers the empire’s political margins. In these porous frontier zones, the imperial presence was but a shadow of its imposing profile in Agra or Lahore. In the first place, such zones were hardly empty spaces that the empire simply occupied. Rather, they were filled with peoples of varied cultural backgrounds who had their own political traditions and leaders. Many of them, moreover, participated in India’s vast military labour market. Armed villagers might sell their martial services to the highest bidder, but would remain in service only as long as their salaries were forthcoming. How, then, did the Mughals integrate such politically fluid, often volatile, zones into their cultural and political system? With what success? We get glimpses from a detailed memoir left by Mirza Nathan, a junior imperial officer who was posted on the Mughals’ eastern frontier between 1607 and 1624, spanning most of Jahangir’s reign.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 THE DECCAN: AFRICANS AND MARATHAS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/6_India_under_Jahangir_and_Shah_Jahan_16051658/03_THE_DECCAN_AFRICANS_AND_MARATHAS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/6_India_under_Jahangir_and_Shah_Jahan_16051658/03_THE_DECCAN_AFRICANS_AND_MARATHAS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most arresting portraits commissioned by Jahangir is the deeply allegorical painting of himself standing on a globe that rests on the horns of a bull, which in turn stands on a great fish – symbols of kingship drawn from Hindu lore [see Fig. 14]. All around the emperor are seen images representing his highest aspirations. Cherubs in the sky offer him a sword and arrows. To one side is an elaborate crown above a roundel in which is inscribed his own name and those of each of his royal ancestors reaching back to Timur. Above the crown flutters a bird of paradise. To the emperor’s other side is a golden scale of justice hanging from a chain with golden bells. The chain is suspended between the globe and a javelin, against which rests a musket. In the centre of the painting, wearing a white turban, a crimson gown and impeccably white slippers, is Jahangir himself, drawing a reverse-curved bow and aiming his arrow at the severed head of his most hated enemy, Malik Ambar (d. 1626), which rests on the tip of the javelin. Perched on Ambar’s bare head is an owl, a symbol of darkness. All around the head are inscriptions that speak of the emperor’s contempt for Malik Ambar – ‘The head of the night-coloured servant has become the house of the owl’; ‘Ambar the owl, which fled the light, has been driven from the world by your [Jahangir’s] enemy-smiting arrow.’31&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 EMERGING IDENTITIES: THE IDEA OF ‘SIKH’</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/6_India_under_Jahangir_and_Shah_Jahan_16051658/04_EMERGING_IDENTITIES_THE_IDEA_OF_SIKH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/6_India_under_Jahangir_and_Shah_Jahan_16051658/04_EMERGING_IDENTITIES_THE_IDEA_OF_SIKH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Especially between the fourteenth and seventeenth centuries, poets across India, writing in the spoken languages of the people, aspired for direct experience of ultimate reality unmediated by liturgy, elaborate rituals, book learning or intercession by institutionalized specialists such as Brahmin priests or Muslim clerics. Some poets focused on fervent devotion – &lt;em&gt;bhakti&lt;/em&gt; – to a loving, personal deity who possessed attributes that were manifested in visible form. Such devotion was expressed by outward forms of piety such as reciting or singing verses of adoration addressed directly to the deity, or making pilgrimages to a temple in which the deity’s image was enshrined. Other poets conceived of the deity as a formless, eternal, all-pervading consciousness that both created and inhabited reality, but which was not manifested with attributes and could not be represented in images. Both kinds of devotion were animated by the promise of liberation for all sincere devotees, regardless of caste or gender, meaning that the verses of &lt;em&gt;bhakti&lt;/em&gt; poet-saints often carried, at least implicitly, a message of protest against socio-religious inequality. From at least the late nineteenth century on, it was common to refer to the collective aspirations and deeds of these poets as constituting a ‘&lt;em&gt;bhakti&lt;/em&gt; movement’. This phrase, however, suggests a monolithic and self-conscious historical phenomenon possessing a well-considered goal, such as a ‘nationalist movement’. An alternative model is the notion of a ‘&lt;em&gt;bhakti&lt;/em&gt; network’, in which the voices of disparate poets echoed or resonated with one another across time and space, but without there ever having been a coherent or collectively organized ‘movement’.37&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 ASSESSING JAHANGIR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/6_India_under_Jahangir_and_Shah_Jahan_16051658/05_ASSESSING_JAHANGIR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/6_India_under_Jahangir_and_Shah_Jahan_16051658/05_ASSESSING_JAHANGIR/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jahangir’s reign falls into two distinct phases. From his coronation to 1622, the emperor remained active in the state’s administrative and military affairs, ruling after 1611 in virtual partnership with Nur Jahan. The latter issued land grants to women under her own seal, struck coins in her own name and sat in the &lt;em&gt;jharokha&lt;/em&gt; of her palace, while below her nobles presented themselves and received her orders. Her name and title were jointly attached on all imperial documents receiving Jahangir’s signature.53 But in the last five years of his life, from 1622 to his death in 1627, the emperor became so incapacitated by drink and opium that Nur Jahan took many administrative matters into her own hands. The extent of her influence in this latter phase of Jahangir’s reign is suggested by Francisco Pelsaert, a Dutch East Company commercial officer serving in Agra from 1621 to 1627. ‘When the King comes home in the evening from hunting,’ he wrote:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 SHAH JAHAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/6_India_under_Jahangir_and_Shah_Jahan_16051658/06_SHAH_JAHAN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/6_India_under_Jahangir_and_Shah_Jahan_16051658/06_SHAH_JAHAN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jahangir died in late October 1627 while en route from Kashmir to Lahore. Nur Jahan’s brother Asaf Khan, who all along had backed the cause of the late emperor’s third son, Khurram, now took matters into his own hands, swiftly putting his sister under detention while, as a precautionary measure, removing Khurram’s young sons Dara Shukoh and Aurangzeb from her custody. He also sent a courier down to the Deccan to fetch Khurram to north India. While marching to Agra, the prince sent a return courier ordering the execution of other princes who might contest his claim to the throne: his younger brother Shahryar, the two sons of his late brother Khusrau, and two sons of his late uncle Danyal. Khurram was doubtless determined to avoid the sort of messy succession conflict experienced by his father, for which he himself had been responsible. In January 1628 his grisly order was carried out, and soon he triumphantly entered Agra where he was hailed with the title that his father had earlier given him – Shah Jahan. On 4 February 1628, at an hour precisely fixed by his astrologers, he was formally crowned emperor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 CONCLUSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/6_India_under_Jahangir_and_Shah_Jahan_16051658/07_CONCLUSION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/6_India_under_Jahangir_and_Shah_Jahan_16051658/07_CONCLUSION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;India and the Mughals experienced important changes under Jahangir and Shah Jahan. First, the empire grew in both territorial extent and wealth: between 1580 and 1646 its revenue demand more than doubled, growing from 90.7 to 222.3 million rupees, owing largely to territorial annexations, especially in Bengal and the northern Deccan.80 When Shah Jahan came to power, however, he found a treasury that had been nearly depleted. To remedy this, he increased the amount of the empire’s &lt;em&gt;khalisa&lt;/em&gt; land, or land whose revenues went directly to the central treasury, and decreased its total &lt;em&gt;jagir&lt;/em&gt; land, whose revenues were allocated to imperial &lt;em&gt;mansabdar&lt;/em&gt;s. Between 1631 and 1646, &lt;em&gt;khalisa&lt;/em&gt; land increased from 6.6 per cent to 14.3 per cent of the empire’s total assessed revenue.81 Both &lt;em&gt;khalisa&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;jagir&lt;/em&gt; lands were administered under Akbar’s regulation system (&lt;em&gt;zabt&lt;/em&gt;), according to which government officials made periodic surveys and revenue assessments by measuring land areas and by determining the quality of the fields and their potential crop value. Detailed records of such surveys and assessments were kept in both local and central revenue offices – information that was critical for running the army, since the number of troops a &lt;em&gt;mansabdar&lt;/em&gt; was expected to maintain had to match the amount of revenue his &lt;em&gt;jagir&lt;/em&gt;s were expected to produce.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
