<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/subversion/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/subversion/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ambedkar - Mahar and Matki</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/subversion/articles/ambedkar_mAhar_maTki/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/subversion/articles/ambedkar_mAhar_maTki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/0jvgOAZG9w&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thread on the myth of Ambedkar Mahar and Matki :&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whatever sources I provide are true to my knowledge and from contemporary sources. Story revolves around the year 1936. Ambedkar was to give a speech at Lahore session organized by Jaatpat Todak Mandal, but due to differences on his speech to be given the session was cancelled by the mandal so Ambedkar went on to publish his speech independently where he stated that during the rule of the Peshwas Mahars &amp;amp; other lower jaatis were forced to wear Matka (pot) in their neck &amp;amp; broom (jhadu) on the back of their waist. Wear a black band on their wrist. Broom was tied at the back so the path on which lower jaatis walk should get wiped. The pot was used as spittoon so others won&amp;rsquo;t get polluted by he spitting on the side of the road. To which YN Kelkar son of Sahityasamrat Narsinha Kelkar who was writer asked him for clarification stating that recently more than 50 diaries of peshwa time are out like वाडकृत peshwa diary, peshwa daftar diaries and many other documents gathered by the British none of them mention even one of incidents. He further says:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>eLavas and communism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/subversion/articles/eLavas_and_communism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/subversion/articles/eLavas_and_communism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Bias warnings - akShay nair&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Take it with a bucket of salt. Many things are errenous. He had earlier written that Kerala was mainly a Buddhist society before Nambuthiris came in.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s wrong that Avarnas weren&amp;rsquo;t considered as Hindus&amp;hellip;they had their own rituals and worship. For instance many rites related to Theyyam are done by them, Even in important temples like at Kottiyoor, they have special rights to perform abhisheka with tender coconut water. Also most of the early commie leaders were Nairs and Brahmins, not Avarnas. When AK Gopalan, a Nair commie leader tried to preach equal rights for all Hindus, a group of Thiyyas (OP&amp;rsquo;s caste) actually beat him up.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why Kerala Hindus vote for communism?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nehru on EVR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/subversion/articles/nehru_on_evr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/subversion/articles/nehru_on_evr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STATES AND CENTRALLY ADMINISTERED AREAS&lt;br&gt;&#xA;V. MADRAS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To K. Kamaraj Nadar&lt;br&gt;&#xA;New Delhi&lt;br&gt;&#xA;November 5, 1957&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My Dear Kamaraj.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am much distressed by the anti-Brahmin campaign continuously carried on by E. Ramaswami Naicker.&amp;rsquo; I wrote to you I think about this some time ago, and I was told that this matter was under consideration. I find that Ramaswami Naicker is going on saying the same thing again and calling upon people at the right time to start stabbing and killing. What he says can only be said by a criminal or a lunatic. I do not know him adequately to be able to decide what he is, but one thing is clear to me that this kind of thing has a very demoralizing effect on the country. All the anti-social and criminal elements imagine that they can act in this way also. I suggest, therefore, to you that there should be no delay in dealing with this matter. Let him be put in a lunatic asylum and his perverted mind treated there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
