<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;epistles third series on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;epistles third series on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>741 volume 7/epistles third seriesnote</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/741_note/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/741_note/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NOTE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before leaving for the USA, Swamiji used to change his name very often.&#xA;In earlier years he signed as Narendra or Naren; then for some time as&#xA;Vividishananda or Sachchidananda. But for the convenience of the&#xA;readers, these volumes use the more familiar name Vivekananda.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PUBLISHER&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>742 I</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/742_01_sir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/742_01_sir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Addressee &lt;a href=&#34;02_sir.htm&#34;&gt;»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;i&#34;&gt;I&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Translated from &lt;a href=&#34;b6017e7001.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Glory to Ramakrishna!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BAIDYANATH,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;25th December, 1889&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR SIR (Shri Balaram Bose),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have been staying for the last few days at Baidyanath in Purna Babu&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;Lodge. It is not so cold, and my health too is indifferent. I am&#xA;suffering from indigestion, probably due to excess of iron in the water.&#xA;I have found nothing agreeable here — neither the place, nor the season,&#xA;nor the company. I leave for Varanasi tomorrow. Achyutananda stopped at&#xA;Govinda Chaudhury&amp;rsquo;s place at Deoghar, and the latter, as soon as he got&#xA;news of us, earnestly insisted on our becoming his guests. Finally, he&#xA;met us once again and prevailed on us to accede to his request. The man&#xA;is a great worker, but has a number of women with him — old women most&#xA;of them, of the ordinary Vaishnava type. . . . His clerks too revere us&#xA;much; some of them are very much ill-disposed towards him, and they&#xA;spoke of his misdeeds. Incidentally, I raised the topic of __. You&#xA;have many wrong ideas or doubts about her; hence I write all this after&#xA;particular investigation. Even the aged clerks of this establishment&#xA;highly respect and revere her. She came to stop with __ while she was&#xA;a mere child, and ever lived as his wife. . . . Everyone admits in one&#xA;voice that her character is spotless. She was all along a perfectly&#xA;chaste woman and never behaved with __ in any relation but that of&#xA;wife to husband, and she was absolutely faithful. She came at too early&#xA;an age to have incurred any moral taint. After she had separated from&#xA;__, she wrote to him to say that she had never treated him as anything&#xA;but her husband, but that it was impossible for her to live with a man&#xA;with a loose character. His old office-bearers too believe him to be&#xA;satanic in character; but they consider __ a Devi (angel), and remark&#xA;that it was following her departure that __ lost all sense of shame.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>743 II</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/743_02_sir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/743_02_sir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii&#34;&gt;II&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Translated from &lt;a href=&#34;b6019e7002.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Glory to Ramakrishna!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ALLAHABAD,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;30th December, 1889&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR SIR (Shri Balaram Bose),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gupta left a slip when coming and the next day a letter from Yogananda&#xA;gave me all the news and I immediately started for Allahabad which I&#xA;reached the day after, to find that Yogananda had completely recovered.&#xA;He had chicken-pox (with one or two smallpox rashes also). The doctor is&#xA;a noble soul, and they have got a brotherhood, who are all great pious&#xA;men and highly devoted to the service of Sādhus. They are particularly&#xA;anxious that I pass the month of Māgh here, but I am leaving for&#xA;Varanasi. . . . How are you? I pray to God for the welfare of yourself&#xA;and your family. Please convey my compliments to Tulasiram, Chuni Babu,&#xA;and the rest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>744 III</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/744_03_sir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/744_03_sir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii&#34;&gt;III&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Translated from &lt;a href=&#34;b6025e7003.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GHAZIPUR,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;30th January, 1890&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;REVERED SIR (Shri Balaram Bose),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am now stopping with Satish Babu at Ghazipur. Of the few places I have&#xA;recently visited, this is the healthiest. The water of Baidyanath is&#xA;very bad — it leads to indigestion. Allahabad is very congested. The few&#xA;days I passed at Varanasi, I suffered from fever day and night — the&#xA;place is so malarious! Ghazipur has a very salubrious climate —&#xA;specially the quarter I am living in. I have visited Pavhari Baba&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;house — there are high walls all round, and it is fashioned like an&#xA;English bungalow. There is a garden inside and big rooms and chimneys,&#xA;etc. He allows nobody to enter. If he is so inclined, he comes up to the&#xA;door and speaks from inside — that is all. One day I went and waited and&#xA;waited in the cold and had to return. I shall go to Varanasi on Sunday&#xA;next. If the meeting with the Babaji takes place in the meantime, all&#xA;right, otherwise I bid him good-bye. About Pramada Babu&amp;rsquo;s place I shall&#xA;write definitely from Varanasi. If Kali Bhattacharya is determined to&#xA;come, let him do so after I leave for Varanasi on Sunday, but he should&#xA;rather not. After a few days&amp;rsquo; stay at Varanasi, I shall start for&#xA;Hrishikesh. Pramada Babu may accompany me. Please accept all of you my&#xA;cordial greetings — and blessing to Fakir, Ram, Krishnamayi, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>745 IV</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/745_04_sir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/745_04_sir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;iv&#34;&gt;IV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Translated from &lt;a href=&#34;b6031e7004.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Salutation to Bhagavan Ramakrishna!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C/O Satish Mukherji,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;GORABAZAR, GHAZIPUR.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;14th February, 1890&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;REVERED SIR (Shri Balaram Bose),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am in receipt of your letter of contrition. I am not leaving this&#xA;place soon — it is impossible to avoid the Babaji&amp;rsquo;s request. You have&#xA;expressed remorse at not having reaped any appreciable results by&#xA;serving the Sadhus. It is true, and yet not true; it is true if you look&#xA;towards ideal bliss; but if you look behind to the place from which you&#xA;started, you will find that before you were an animal, now you are a&#xA;man, and will be a god or God Himself in future. Moreover, that sort of&#xA;regret and dissatisfaction is very good; it is the prelude to&#xA;improvement. Without this none can rise. He who puts on a turban and&#xA;immediately sees the Lord, progresses thus far and no farther. You are&#xA;blessed indeed to have that constant dissatisfaction preying upon your&#xA;mind — rest assured that there is no danger for you. . . . You are a&#xA;keenly intelligent man, and know full well that patience is the best&#xA;means of success. In this respect I have no doubt that we light-headed&#xA;boys have much to learn from you. . . . You are a considerate man, and I&#xA;need not add anything. Man has two ears but one mouth. You specially are&#xA;given to plain-speaking and are chary of making large promises — things&#xA;that sometimes make me cross with you, but upon reflection I find that&#xA;it is you who have acted with discretion. &amp;ldquo;Slow but sure.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;What is lost&#xA;in power is gained in speed.&amp;rdquo; However, in this world everything depends&#xA;upon one&amp;rsquo;s words. To get an insight behind the words (specially, with&#xA;your economical spirit masking all) is not given to all, and one must&#xA;associate long with a man to be able to understand him. . . . Religion&#xA;is not in sects, nor in making a fuss — why do you forget these&#xA;teachings of our revered Master? Please help as far as it lies in you,&#xA;but to judge what came of it, whether it was turned to good or evil&#xA;account, is perhaps beyond our jurisdiction. . . . Considering the great&#xA;shock which Girish Babu has received, it will give him immense peace to&#xA;serve Mother at this moment. He is a very keen-witted person. And our&#xA;beloved Master had perfect confidence in you, used to dine nowhere else&#xA;except at your place, and, I have heard, Mother too has the fullest&#xA;confidence in you. In view of these, you will please bear and forbear&#xA;all shortcomings of us fickle boys, treating them as if they were done&#xA;by your own boy. This is all I have got to say. Please let me know by&#xA;return of post when the Anniversary is to take place. A pain in the&#xA;loins is giving me much trouble. In a few days the place will look&#xA;exceedingly beautiful, with miles and miles of rose-banks all in flower.&#xA;Satish says he will then send some fresh roses and cuttings for the&#xA;Festival. . . . May the Lord ordain that your son becomes a man, and&#xA;never a coward!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>746 V</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/746_05_gupta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/746_05_gupta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;v&#34;&gt;V&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Translated from &lt;a href=&#34;b6032e7005.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GHAZIPUR,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;14th Feb&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;em&gt;,1890&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MY DEAR GUPTA (Swami Sadananda),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hope you are doing well. Do your own spiritual exercises, and knowing&#xA;yourself to be the humblest servant of all, serve them. Those with whom&#xA;you are staying are such that even I am not worthy to call myself their&#xA;humblest servant and take the dust of their feet. Knowing this, serve&#xA;them and have devotion for them. Don&amp;rsquo;t be angry even if they abuse or&#xA;even hurt you grievously. Never mix with women. Try to be hardy little&#xA;by little, and gradually accustom yourself to maintaining the body out&#xA;of the proceeds of begging. Whoever takes the name of Ramakrishna, know&#xA;him to be your Guru. Everyone can play the role of a master, but it is&#xA;very difficult to be a servant. Specially you should follow Shashi. Know&#xA;it for certain that without steady devotion for the Guru and unflinching&#xA;patience and perseverance, nothing is to be achieved. You must have&#xA;strict morality. Deviate an inch from this, and you are gone forever.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>747 VI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/747_06_sir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/747_06_sir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Received your kind note yesterday. I am very sorry to learn that Suresh&#xA;Babu&amp;rsquo;s illness is extremely serious. What is destined will surely&#xA;happen. It is a matter of great regret that you too have fallen ill. So&#xA;long as egoism lasts, any shortcoming in adopting remedial measures is&#xA;to be considered as idleness — it is a fault and a guilt. For one who&#xA;has not that egoistic idea, the best course is to forbear. The&#xA;dwelling-place of the Jivātman, this body, is a veritable means of work,&#xA;and he who converts this into an infernal den is guilty, and he who&#xA;neglects it is also to blame. Please act according to circumstances as&#xA;they present themselves, without the least hesitation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>748 VII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/748_07_atul_babu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/748_07_atul_babu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vii&#34;&gt;VII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Translated from &lt;a href=&#34;b6041e7007.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GHAZIPUR,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;15th March, 1890&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR ATUL BABU (Atul Chandra Ghosh.),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am extremely sorry to hear that you are passing through mental&#xA;afflictions. Please do only what is agreeable to you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;यावज्जननं तावन्मरणं&lt;br&gt;&#xA;तावज्जननीजठरे शयनम्।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;इति संसारे स्फुटतरदोषः&lt;br&gt;&#xA;कथमिह मानव तव सन्तोषः॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;— &amp;ldquo;While there is birth there is death, and again entering the mother&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;womb. This is the manifest evil of transmigration. How, O man, dost thou&#xA;want satisfaction in such a world!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>749 VIII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/749_08_adhyapakji/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/749_08_adhyapakji/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Addressee &lt;a href=&#34;09_adhyapakji.htm&#34;&gt;»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;viii&#34;&gt;VIII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SALEM (U.S.A.),&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;30th Aug., 1893&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR ADHYAPAKJI (HONOURABLE PROFESSOR) (Prof. John Henry Wright),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am going off from here today. I hope you have received some reply from&#xA;Chicago. I have received an invitation with full directions from Mr.&#xA;Sanborn. So I am going to Saratoga on Monday. My respects to your wife.&#xA;And my love to Austin and all the children. You are a real Mahātmā (a&#xA;great soul) and Mrs. Wright is nonpareil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>750 IX</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/750_09_adhyapakji/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/750_09_adhyapakji/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ix&#34;&gt;IX&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SALEM,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Saturday, 4th Sept&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;em&gt;, 1893&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR ADHYAPAKJI (Prof. John Henry Wright),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hasten to tender my heartfelt gratitude to you for your letters of&#xA;introduction. I have received a letter from Mr. Theles of Chicago giving&#xA;me the names of some of the delegates and other things about the&#xA;Congress.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your professor of Sanskrit in his note to Miss Sanborn mistakes me for&#xA;Purushottama Joshi and states that there is a Sanskrit library in Boston&#xA;the like of which can scarcely be met with in India. I would be so happy&#xA;to see it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>751 X</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/751_10_adhyapakji/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/751_10_adhyapakji/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;x&#34;&gt;X&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CHICAGO,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;2nd October, 1893&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR ADHYAPAKJI (Prof. John Henry Wright),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do not know what you are thinking of my long silence. In the first&#xA;place I dropped in on the Congress in the eleventh hour, and quite&#xA;unprepared; and that kept me very very busy for some time. Secondly, I&#xA;was speaking almost every day in the Congress and had no time to write;&#xA;and last and greatest of all — my kind friend, I owe so much to you that&#xA;it would have been an insult to your &lt;em&gt;ahetuka&lt;/em&gt; (unselfish) friendship to&#xA;have written you business-like letters in a hurry. The Congress is now&#xA;over.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>752 XI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/752_11_mrs_tannatt_woods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/752_11_mrs_tannatt_woods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Addressee &lt;a href=&#34;13_mrs_woods.htm&#34;&gt;»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;xi&#34;&gt;XI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CHICAGO,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;10th October, 1893&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR MRS. TANNATT WOODS,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I received your letter yesterday. Just now I am lecturing about Chicago&#xA;— and am doing as I think very well; it is ranging from 30 to 80 dollars&#xA;a lecture, and just now I have been so well advertised in Chicago gratis&#xA;by the Parliament of Religions that it is not advisable to give up this&#xA;field now. To which &lt;em&gt;I am sure you will agree&lt;/em&gt;. However I may come soon&#xA;to Boston, but when I cannot say. Yesterday I returned from Streator&#xA;where I got 87 dollars for a lecture. I have engagements every day this&#xA;week. And hope more will come by the end of the week. My love to Mr.&#xA;Woods and compliments to all our friends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>753 XII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/753_12_adhyapakji/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/753_12_adhyapakji/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xii&#34;&gt;XII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C/O J. LYON,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;262 MICHIGAN AVENUE, CHICAGO,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;26th October, 1893&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR ADHYAPAKJI (Prof. John Henry Wright),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You would be glad to know that I am doing well here and that almost&#xA;everybody has been very kind to me, except of course the very orthodox.&#xA;Many of the men brought together here from far-off lands have got&#xA;projects and ideas and missions to carry out, and America is the only&#xA;place where there is a chance of success for everything. But I thought&#xA;better and have given up speaking about my project entirely — because I&#xA;am sure now — the heathen draws more than his project. So I want to go&#xA;to work earnestly for my own project only keeping the project in the&#xA;background and working like any other lecturer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>754 XIII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/754_13_mrs_woods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/754_13_mrs_woods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Addressee&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;xiii&#34;&gt;XIII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;541 DEARBORN AVENUE, CHICAGO,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;19th November, 1893&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR MRS. WOODS,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Excuse my delay in answering your letter. I do not know when I will be&#xA;able to see you again. I am starting tomorrow for Madison and&#xA;Minneapolis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The English gentleman you speak of is Dr. Momerie of London. He is a&#xA;well-known worker amongst the poor of London and is a very sweet man.&#xA;You perhaps do not know that the English church was the only religious&#xA;denomination in the world who did not send to us a representative, and&#xA;Dr. Momerie came to the Parliament in spite of the Archbishop of&#xA;Canterbury&amp;rsquo;s denouncing of the Parliament of Religions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>755 XIV</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/755_14_sister/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/755_14_sister/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xiv&#34;&gt;XIV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DETROIT,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;17th March, 1894&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR SISTER (Miss Harriet McKindley of Chicago.),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Got your package yesterday. Sorry that you send those stockings — I&#xA;could have got some myself here. Glad that it shows your love. After&#xA;all, the satchel has become more than a thoroughly stuffed sausage. I do&#xA;not know how to carry it along.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have returned today to Mrs. Bagley&amp;rsquo;s as she was sorry that I would&#xA;remain so long with Mr. Palmer. Of course in Palmer&amp;rsquo;s house there was&#xA;real &amp;ldquo;good time&amp;rdquo;. He is a real jovial heartwhole fellow, and likes &amp;ldquo;good&#xA;time&amp;rdquo; a little too much and his &amp;ldquo;hot Scotch&amp;rdquo;. But he is right along&#xA;innocent and childlike in his simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>756 XV</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/756_15_brother/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/756_15_brother/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xv&#34;&gt;XV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DETROIT,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;29th March, 1894&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR BROTHER,&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your letter just reached me here. I am in a hurry, so excuse a few&#xA;points which I would take the liberty of correcting you in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the first place, I have not one word to say against any religion or&#xA;founder of religion in the world — whatever you may think of our&#xA;religion. All religions are sacred to me. Secondly, it is a misstatement&#xA;that I said that missionaries do not learn our vernaculars. I still&#xA;stick to my statement that few, if any, of them pay any attention to&#xA;Sanskrit; nor is it true that I said anything against any religious body&#xA;— except that I do insist on my statement that India can never be&#xA;converted to Christianity, and further I deny that the conditions of the&#xA;lower classes are made any better by Christianity, and add that the&#xA;majority of southern Indian Christians are not only Catholics, but what&#xA;they call themselves, caste Christians, that is, they stick close to&#xA;their castes, and I am thoroughly persuaded that if the Hindu society&#xA;gives up its exclusive policy, ninety per cent of them would rush back&#xA;to Hinduism with all its defects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>757 XVI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/757_16_professor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/757_16_professor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xvi&#34;&gt;XVI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NEW YORK,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;25th April, 1894&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR PROFESSOR (Prof. John Henry Wright),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am very very grateful for your invitation. And will come on May 7th.&#xA;As for the bed — my friend, your love and noble heart can convert the&#xA;stone into down.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am sorry I am not going to the authors&amp;rsquo; breakfast at Salem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am coming home by May 7th.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yours truly,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VIVEKANANDA.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>758 XVII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/758_17_sister/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/758_17_sister/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Addressee &lt;a href=&#34;18_sister.htm&#34;&gt;»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;xvii&#34;&gt;XVII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NEW YORK,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;26th April, 1894&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR SISTER (Miss Isabelle McKindley.),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your letter reached me yesterday. You were perfectly right — I enjoyed&#xA;the fun of the lunatic Interior, (&lt;em&gt;Chicago Interior&lt;/em&gt;, a Presbyterian&#xA;newspaper which opposed Swamiji. — Ed.) but the mail you sent yesterday&#xA;from India was really, as Mother Church says in her letter, a good news&#xA;after a long interval. There is a beautiful letter from Dewanji. The old&#xA;man — Lord bless him — offers as usual to help me. Then there was a&#xA;little pamphlet published in Calcutta about me — revealing that once at&#xA;least in my life the prophet has been honoured in his own country. There&#xA;are extracts from American and Indian papers and magazines about me. The&#xA;extracts printed from Calcutta papers were especially gratifying,&#xA;although the strain is so fulsome that I refuse to send the pamphlet&#xA;over to you. They call me illustrious, wonderful, and all sorts of&#xA;nonsense, but they forward me the gratitude of the whole nation. Now I&#xA;do not care what they even of my own people say about me — except for&#xA;one thing. I have an old mother. She has suffered much all her life and&#xA;in the midst of all she could bear to give me up for the service of God&#xA;and man; but to have given up the most beloved of her children — her&#xA;hope — to live a beastly immoral life in a far distant country, as&#xA;Mazoomdar was telling in Calcutta, would have simply killed her. But the&#xA;Lord is great, none can injure His children.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>759 XVIII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/759_18_sister/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/759_18_sister/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xviii&#34;&gt;XVIII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NEW YORK,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;2nd&lt;/em&gt; [&lt;em&gt;actually 1st&lt;/em&gt;] &lt;em&gt;May, 1894&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR SISTER (Miss Isabelle McKindley.),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am afraid I cannot send you the pamphlet just now. But I got a little&#xA;bit of a newspaper cutting from India yesterday which I send you up.&#xA;After you have read it kindly send it over to Mrs. Bagley. The editor of&#xA;this paper is a relative of Mr. Mazoomdar. I am now sorry for poor&#xA;Mazoomdar!! (The last two sentences were written crosswise on the left&#xA;margin.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>760 XIX</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/760_19_adhyapakji/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/760_19_adhyapakji/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xix&#34;&gt;XIX&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NEW YORK,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;4th May, 1894&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR ADHYAPAKJI (Prof. John Henry Wright),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have received your kind note just now. And it is unnecessary for me to&#xA;say that I will be very happy to do as you say.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have also received Col. Higginson&amp;rsquo;s letter. I will reply to him.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I will be in Boston on Sunday [May 6]. On Monday I lecture at the&#xA;Women&amp;rsquo;s Club of Mrs. Howe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>761 XX</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/761_20_adhyapakji/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/761_20_adhyapakji/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xx&#34;&gt;XX&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;17 BEACON STREET, BOSTON,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;May, 1894&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR ADHYAPAKJI (Prof. John Henry Wright),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By this time you have got the pamphlet and the letters. If you like, I&#xA;would send you over from Chicago some letters from Indian Princes and&#xA;ministers — one of these ministers was one of the Commissioners of the&#xA;late opium commission that sat under Royal Commission in India. If you&#xA;like, I will have them write to you to convince you of my not being a&#xA;cheat. But, my brother, our ideal of life is to hide, to suppress, and&#xA;to deny.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>762 XXI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/762_21_adhyapakji/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/762_21_adhyapakji/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xxi&#34;&gt;XXI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;541 DEARBORN AVE.,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;CHICAGO,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;24th May, 1894&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR ADHYAPAKJI (Prof. John Henry Wright),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Herewith I forward to you a letter from one of our ruling princes of&#xA;Rajputana, His Highness the Maharaja of Khetri, and another from the&#xA;opium commissioner, late minister of Junagad, one of the largest states&#xA;in India, and a man who is called the Gladstone of India. These I hope&#xA;would convince you of my being no fraud.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>763 XXII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/763_22_adhyapakji/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/763_22_adhyapakji/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xxii&#34;&gt;XXII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;541 DEARBORN AVENUE,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;18th June, 1894&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR ADHYAPAKJI (Prof. John Henry Wright),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Excuse my delay in sending the other letters; I could not find them&#xA;earlier. I am going to New York in a week.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do not know whether I will come to Annisquam or not. The letters need&#xA;not be sent over to me until I write you again. Mrs. Bagley seems to be&#xA;unsettled by that article in the Boston paper against me.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; She&#xA;sent me over a copy from Detroit and has ceased correspondence with me.&#xA;Lord bless her. She has been very kind to me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>764 XXIII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/764_23_mr_bhattacharya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/764_23_mr_bhattacharya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xxiii&#34;&gt;XXIII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Translated from &lt;a href=&#34;b6111ae7023.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;U.S.A.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;5th September, 1894&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR MR. BHATTACHARYA (Mr. Manmatha Nath Bhattacharya),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was much pleased to read your affectionate letter. I shall make&#xA;inquiries about the weaving machine as soon as I can, and let you know.&#xA;Now I am resting at Annisquam, a village on the seacoast; soon I shall&#xA;go to the city and attend to the matter of the machine. These seaside&#xA;places are filled with people during the summer; some come to bathe in&#xA;the sea, some to take rest, and some to catch husbands.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>765 XXIV</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/765_24_kali/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/765_24_kali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xxiv&#34;&gt;XXIV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Translated from &lt;a href=&#34;b7148e7024.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;U.S.A.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(&lt;em&gt;November&lt;/em&gt; ?) &lt;em&gt;1894&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR KALI [ABHEDANANDA],&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks for all that I come to know from your letter. I had no news of&#xA;the telegram in question having appeared in the &lt;em&gt;Tribune&lt;/em&gt;. It is six&#xA;months since I left Chicago, and I have not been yet free to return. So&#xA;I could not keep myself well posted. You have taken great pains indeed!&#xA;And for this how can I thank you adequately? You have all evinced a&#xA;wonderful capacity for work. And how can Shri Ramakrishna&amp;rsquo;s words prove&#xA;false? — You have got wonderful spirit in you. About Shashi Sanyal, I&#xA;have already written. Nothing remains undetected, through the grace of&#xA;Shri Ramakrishna. But let him found a sect or whatever he will, what&#xA;harm? &amp;ldquo;शिवा वः सन्तु पन्थानः — May blessings attend your path!&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Secondly, I could not catch the drift of your letter. I shall collect my&#xA;own funds to build a monastery for ourselves, and if people criticise me&#xA;for it, I see nothing in this to affect us either way. You have your&#xA;minds pitched high and steady, it will do you no harm. May you have&#xA;exceeding love for one another among yourselves, and it would be enough&#xA;to have an attitude of indifference towards public criticisms.&#xA;Kalikrishna Babu has deep love for the cause and is a great man. Please&#xA;convey my special love to him. So long as there is no feeling of&#xA;disunion amongst you, through the grace of the Lord, I assure you, there&#xA;is no danger for you, &amp;ldquo;रणे वने पर्वतमस्तके वा — be it in battle, in the&#xA;forest, or on the top of mountains&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;श्रेयांसि बहुविघ्नानि — All noble&#xA;undertakings are fraught with obstacles&amp;rdquo;. It is quite in the nature of&#xA;things. Keep up the deepest mental poise. Take not even the slightest&#xA;notice of what puerile creatures may be saying against you.&#xA;Indifference, indifference, indifference! I have already written to&#xA;Shashi (Ramakrishnananda) in detail. Please do not send newspapers and&#xA;tracts any more. &amp;ldquo;Take the husking hammer to heaven, and there it will&#xA;do its husking&amp;rdquo;, as the Bengali saying goes. The same trudging about&#xA;here as it was in India, only with the carrying of others&amp;rsquo; loads added!&#xA;How can I procure customers for people&amp;rsquo;s books in this land? I am only&#xA;one amongst the many here and nothing more. Whatever the papers and&#xA;things of that sort in this country write about me, I make an offering&#xA;of to the Fire-God. You also do the same. That is the proper course.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>766 XXV</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/766_25_brother_shivananda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/766_25_brother_shivananda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Addressee &lt;a href=&#34;../../volume_9/letters_fifth_series/114_shivananda.htm&#34;&gt;»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;xxv&#34;&gt;XXV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Translated from &lt;a href=&#34;b7149e7025.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;U. S.A.,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;1894&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR BROTHER SHIVANANDA,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your letter just reached me. Perhaps by this time you have received my&#xA;other letters and learnt that it is not necessary to send anything to&#xA;America any more. Too much of everything is bad. This newspaper booming&#xA;has given me popularity no doubt, but its effect is more in India than&#xA;here. Here, on the other hand, constant booming creates a distaste in&#xA;the minds of the higher class people; so enough. Now try to organise&#xA;yourselves in India on the lines of these meetings. You need not send&#xA;anything more in this country. As to money, I have determined first to&#xA;build some place for Mother, (Holy Mother, Shri Sarada Devi.) for women&#xA;require it first. . . . I can send nearly Rs. 7,000 for a place for&#xA;Mother. If the place is first secured, then I do not care for anything&#xA;else. I hope to be able to get Rs. 1,600 a year from this country even&#xA;when I am gone. That sum I will make over to the support of the Women&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;place, and then it will grow. I have written to you already to secure a&#xA;place. . . .&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>767 XXVI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/767_26_brahmananda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/767_26_brahmananda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Addressee &lt;a href=&#34;30_rakhal.htm&#34;&gt;»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;xxvi&#34;&gt;XXVI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Translated from &lt;a href=&#34;b7151e7026.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Salutation to Bhagavan Ramakrishna!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1894&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR AND BELOVED (Swami Brahmananda.),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;. . . Well, do you think there is any religion left in India! The paths&#xA;of knowledge, devotion, and Yoga — all have gone, and now there remains&#xA;only that of Don&amp;rsquo;t touchism — &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t touch me! Don&amp;rsquo;t touch me!&amp;rdquo; The&#xA;whole world is impure, and I alone am pure. Lucid Brahmajnāna! Bravo!&#xA;Great God! Nowadays Brahman is neither in the recesses of the heart, nor&#xA;in the highest heaven, nor in all beings — now He is in the cooking-pot.&#xA;Formerly the characteristic of a noble-minded man was&#xA;&amp;ldquo;त्रिभुवनमुपकारश्रेणिभिः प्रीणयन्तः — Pleasing the whole universe by&#xA;one&amp;rsquo;s numerous acts of service&amp;rdquo; but now it is — I am pure and the whole&#xA;world is impure — go and get money and set it at my feet. . . . Tell the&#xA;sapient sage who writes to me to finish my preaching work here and&#xA;return home, . . . that this country is more my home. What is there in&#xA;Hindusthan? Who appreciates religion? Who appreciates learning?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>768 XXVII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/768_27_alasinga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/768_27_alasinga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xxvii&#34;&gt;XXVII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1895&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR ALASINGA,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have no organisation, nor want to build any. Each one is quite&#xA;independent to teach, quite free to preach whatever he or she likes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have the spirit within, you will never fail to attract others.&#xA;Theosophists&amp;rsquo; method can never be ours, for the very simple reason that&#xA;they are an organised sect, we are not.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Individuality is my motto. I have no ambition beyond training&#xA;individuals up. I know very little; that little I teach without reserve;&#xA;where I am ignorant, I confess it as such, and never am I so glad as&#xA;when I find people being helped by Theosophists, Christians,&#xA;Mohammedans, or anybody in the world. I am a Sannyasin; as such I&#xA;consider myself as a servant, not as a master in the world. . . . If&#xA;people love me, they are welcome, if they hate, they are also welcome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>769 XXVIII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/769_28_brother/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/769_28_brother/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Addressee &lt;a href=&#34;37_friend.htm&#34;&gt;»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;xxviii&#34;&gt;XXVIII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;54 W. 33 NEW YORK,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;25th April, 1895&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR BROTHER (To Dr. I. Janes.),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was away in the Catskill mountains and it was almost impossible to get&#xA;a letter regularly posted from where I was — so accept my apology for&#xA;the delay in offering you my most heartfelt thanks for your letter in&#xA;the &amp;ldquo;Eagle&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was so scholarly, truthful and noble and withal so permeated with&#xA;your natural universal love for the good and true everywhere. It is a&#xA;great work to bring this world into a spirit of sympathy with each other&#xA;but it should be done no doubt when such brave souls as you still hold&#xA;your own. Lord help you ever and ever my brother and may you live long&#xA;to carry on the mighty work you and your society has undertaken.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>770 XXIX</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/770_29_dear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/770_29_dear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xxix&#34;&gt;XXIX&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;54 W. 33 NEW YORK,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;May, 1895&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR __,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since writing to you my pupils have come round me with help, and the&#xA;classes will go on nicely now no doubt.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was so glad at it because teaching has become a part of my life, as&#xA;necessary to my life as eating or breathing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yours,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VIVEKANANDA.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PS. I saw a lot of things about __ in an English paper, the&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Borderland&lt;/em&gt;. __ is doing good work in India, making the Hindus, very&#xA;much to appreciate their own religion. . . . I do not find any&#xA;scholarship in __&amp;rsquo;s writing, . . . nor do I find any spirituality&#xA;whatever. However Godspeed to anyone who wants to do good to the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>771 XXX</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/771_30_rakhal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/771_30_rakhal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xxx&#34;&gt;XXX&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Translated from &lt;a href=&#34;b7207e7030.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;19 WEST 38th STREET,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;NEW YORK, &lt;em&gt;August&lt;/em&gt;, 1895.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BELOVED RAKHAL,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;. . . I am now in New York City. The city is hot in summer, exactly like&#xA;Calcutta. You perspire profusely, and there is not a breath of air. I&#xA;made a tour in the north for a couple of months. Please answer this&#xA;letter by return of post to England, for which I shall start before this&#xA;will have reached you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>772 XXXI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/772_31_alasinga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/772_31_alasinga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xxxi&#34;&gt;XXXI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;U.S.A.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;March, 1896&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR ALASINGA,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last week I wrote you about the &lt;em&gt;Brahmavādin&lt;/em&gt;. I forgot to write about&#xA;the Bhakti lectures. They ought to be published in a book all together.&#xA;A few hundreds may be sent to America to Goodyear in New York. Within&#xA;twenty days I sail for England. I have other big books on Karma, Jnana,&#xA;and Raja Yogas — the Karma is out already, the Raja will be a very big&#xA;book and is already in the Press. The Jnana will have to be published, I&#xA;think, in England.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>773 XXXII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/773_32_dear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/773_32_dear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xxxii&#34;&gt;XXXII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Translated from &lt;a href=&#34;b7273e7032.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HIGH VIEW, CAVERSHAM,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;READING,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;27th April, 1896&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR (Members of the Alambazar Math),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;. . . Let me write something for you all. It is not for gaining personal&#xA;authority that I do this, but for your good and for fulfilling the&#xA;purpose for which the Lord came. He gave me the charge of you all, and&#xA;you shall contribute to the great well-being of the world — though most&#xA;of you are not yet aware of it — this is the special reason of my&#xA;writing to you. It will be a great pity if any feeling of jealousy or&#xA;egotism gain ground amongst you. Is it possible for those to establish&#xA;cordial relations on earth who cannot cordially live with one another&#xA;for any length of time? No doubt it is an evil to be bound by laws, but&#xA;it is necessary at the immature stage to be guided by rules; in other&#xA;words, as the Master used to say that the sapling must be hedged round,&#xA;and so on. Secondly, it is quite natural for idle minds to indulge in&#xA;gossip, and faction-mongering, and so forth. Hence I jot down the&#xA;following hints. If you follow them, you will undoubtedly prosper, but&#xA;if you don&amp;rsquo;t do so, then there is a danger of all our labours coming to&#xA;naught.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>774 XXXIII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/774_33_sister/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/774_33_sister/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xxxiii&#34;&gt;XXXIII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;63 ST. GEORGE&amp;rsquo;S ROAD, LONDON,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;May, 1896&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR SISTER,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In London once more. The climate now in England is nice and cool. We&#xA;have fire in the grate. We have a whole house to ourselves, you know,&#xA;this time. It is small but convenient, and in London they do not cost so&#xA;much as in America. Don&amp;rsquo;t you know what I was thinking — about your&#xA;mother! I just wrote her a letter and duly posted it to her, care of&#xA;Monroe &amp;amp; Co., 7 Rue Scribe, Paris. Some old friends are here, and Miss&#xA;MacLeod came over from the Continent. She is good as gold, and as kind&#xA;as ever. We have a nice little family, in the house, with another monk&#xA;from India. Poor man! — a typical Hindu with nothing of that pluck and&#xA;go which I have, he is always dreamy and gentle and sweet! That won&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;do. I will try to put a little activity into him. I have had two classes&#xA;already — they will go on for four or five months and after that to&#xA;India I go. But it is to Amerique — there where the heart is. I love the&#xA;Yankee land. I like to see new things. I do not care a fig to loaf about&#xA;old ruins and mope a life out about old histories and keep sighing about&#xA;the ancients. I have too much vigour in my blood for that. In America is&#xA;the place, the people, the opportunity for everything. I have become&#xA;horribly radical. I am just going to India to see what I can do in that&#xA;awful mass of conservative jelly-fish, and start a new thing, entirely&#xA;new — simple, strong, new and fresh as the first born baby. The eternal,&#xA;the infinite, the omnipresent, the omniscient is a principle, not a&#xA;person. You, I, and everyone are but embodiments of that principle, and&#xA;the more of this infinite principle is embodied in a person, the greater&#xA;is he, and all in the end will be the perfect embodiment of that and&#xA;thus all will be one as they are now essentially. This is all there is&#xA;of religion, and the practice is through this feeling of oneness that is&#xA;love. All old fogy forms are mere old superstitions. Now, why struggle&#xA;to keep them alive? Why give thirsty people ditch-water to drink whilst&#xA;the river of life and truth flows by? This is only human selfishness,&#xA;nothing else. Life is short — time is flying — that place and people&#xA;where one&amp;rsquo;s ideas work best should be the country and the people for&#xA;everyone. Ay, for a dozen bold hearts, large, noble, and sincere!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>775 XXXIV</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/775_34_shashi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/775_34_shashi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xxxiv&#34;&gt;XXXIV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Translated from &lt;a href=&#34;b7279e7034.pdf&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C/O E. T. STURDY, ESQ.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;HIGH VIEW, CAVERSHAM, READING,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;May&lt;/em&gt; (?) &lt;em&gt;1896&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR SHASHI (RAMAKRISHNANANDA),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;. . . This City of London is a sea of human heads — ten or fifteen&#xA;Calcuttas put together. One is apt to be lost in the mazes unless he&#xA;arranges for somebody to meet him on arrival. . . . However, let Kali&#xA;start at once. If he be late in starting like Sharat, better let no one&#xA;come. It won&amp;rsquo;t do to loiter and procrastinate like that. It is a task&#xA;that requires the height of Rajas (activity). . . . Our whole country is&#xA;steeped in Tamas, and nothing but that. We want Rajas first, and Sattva&#xA;will come afterwards — a thing far, far removed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>776 XXXV</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/776_35_adhyapakji/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/776_35_adhyapakji/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last mail brought the very very sad news of the blow that has fallen on&#xA;you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the world my brother — this illusion of Māyā — the Lord alone is&#xA;true. The forms are evanescent; but the spirit, being in the Lord and of&#xA;the Lord, is immortal and omnipresent. All that we ever had are round us&#xA;this minute, for the spirit can neither come nor go, it only changes its&#xA;plane of manifestation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>777 XXXVI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/777_36_miss_noble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/777_36_miss_noble/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xxxvi&#34;&gt;XXXVI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;63 ST. GEORGE&amp;rsquo;S ROAD, LONDON,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;7th June, 1896&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR MISS NOBLE,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My ideal indeed can be put into a few words and that is: to preach unto&#xA;mankind their divinity, and how to make it manifest in every movement of&#xA;life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This world is in chain of superstition. I pity the oppressed, whether&#xA;man or woman, and I pity more the oppressors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One idea that I see clear as daylight is that misery is caused by&#xA;ignorance and nothing else. Who will give the world light? Sacrifice in&#xA;the past has been the Law, it will be, alas, for ages to come. The&#xA;earth&amp;rsquo;s bravest and best will have to sacrifice themselves for the good&#xA;of many, for the welfare of all. Buddhas by the hundred are necessary&#xA;with eternal love and pity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>778 XXXVII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/778_37_friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/778_37_friend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yours of the 25th June has duly reached and gave me great pleasure. I am&#xA;so glad to see the noble work progressing. I had learnt with the&#xA;greatest delight from Mrs. Bull of the work that is going to be done in&#xA;Cambridge this winter and no better person could have been selected to&#xA;direct it as yourself. May all power attend you. I will be only too glad&#xA;to write for the magazine from time to time and my first instalment was&#xA;to be in a few weeks, when I hope to get some leisure. Certainly it goes&#xA;without saying that no one of the types we call religious ought to die —&#xA;they like races require fresh infusion of blood in the form of ideas. It&#xA;is wonderful to be able to sympathise with others from their standpoints&#xA;of view.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>779 XXXVIII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/779_38_sharat_chandra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/779_38_sharat_chandra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Addressee&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;../../volume_5/epistles_first_series/077_sharat_chandra.htm&#34;&gt;»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;xxxviii&#34;&gt;XXXVIII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Written to Sj. Sharat Chandra Chakravarti, B.A&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ॐ नमो भगवते रामकृष्णाय!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;शुभमस्तु! आशीर्वादप्रेमालिङ्गनपूर्वकमिदं भवतु तव प्रीतये। पाञ्चभौतिकं मे&#xA;पिञ्जरमधुना किञ्चिद् सुस्थतरम्। अचलगुरोर्हिमानिमण्डितशिखराणि&#xA;पुनरुज्जीवयन्ति मृतप्रायानपि जनानिति मन्ये। श्रमबाधापि कथश्चित्&#xA;दूरीभूतेत्यनुभवामि। यत्ते हृदयोद्वेगकरं मुमुक्षुत्वं लिपिभंङ्गया&#xA;व्यञ्जितं तन्मया अनुभूतं पूर्वम्। तदेव शाश्वते ब्रह्मणि मनः समधातुं&#xA;प्रसरति। &amp;ldquo;नान्यः पन्थाः विद्यतेऽनाय।&amp;rdquo; ज्वलतु सा भावना अधिकमधिकं&#xA;यावन्नधिगत एकान्तक्षयः कृताकृतानाम्। तदनु सहसैव ब्रह्मप्रकाशः सह&#xA;समस्तविषयप्रध्वंसेन। आगामिनी सा जीवन्मुक्तिस्तव हिताय&#xA;तवानुरागदाढर्येणैवानुमेया। याचे पुनस्तं लोकगुरुं महासमन्वयाचार्य श्री&#xA;१०८ रामकृष्णं आविर्भवितुम् तव हृदयोद्देशे येन वै कृतकृतर्थस्त्वं&#xA;आविष्कृतमहाशौर्यः लोकान् समुद्धर्तुं महामोहसागरात् सम्यक् यतिष्यसे। भव&#xA;चिराधिष्ठित ओजसि। वीराणामेव करतलगता मुक्तिः न कापुरुषाणाम्। हे वीरा,&#xA;बद्धपरिकरा भवत, सम्मुखे शत्रवः महामोहरूपाः। &amp;ldquo;श्रेयांसि बहुविघ्नानि&amp;rdquo; इति&#xA;निश्चितेऽपि समधिकतरं कुरुत यत्नम्। पश्यत इमान् लोकान् मोहग्राहग्रस्तान्।&#xA;शृणुत अहो तेषां हृदयभेदकरं कारुण्यपूर्णं शोकनादम्। अग्रगा भवत, अग्रगा,&#xA;हे वीरा, मोचयितुं पाशं बद्धानां श्लथयितुं क्लेशभारं दीनानां, द्योतयितुं&#xA;हृदयान्धकूपं अज्ञानाम्। अभीरभीरिति घोषयति वेदान्तडिण्डिमः। भूयात् स&#xA;भेदाय हृदग्रन्थेः सर्वेषां जगन्निवासिनामिति।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>780 XXXIX</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/780_39_mrs_bull/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/780_39_mrs_bull/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xxxix&#34;&gt;XXXIX&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ALAMBAZAR MATH, CALCUTTA,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;May 5th, 1897&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR MRS. BULL,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have been to Darjeeling for a month to recuperate my shattered health.&#xA;I am very much better now. The disease disappeared altogether in&#xA;Darjeeling. I am going tomorrow to Almora, another hill station, to&#xA;perfect this improvement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Things are looking not very hopeful here as I have already written you —&#xA;though the whole nation has risen as one man to honour me and people&#xA;went almost mad over me! The practical part cannot be had in India.&#xA;Again, the price of the land has gone up very much near Calcutta. My&#xA;idea at present is to start three centres at three capitals. These would&#xA;be my normal schools, from thence I want to invade India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>781 XL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/781_40_shuddhananda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/781_40_shuddhananda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xl&#34;&gt;XL&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ALMORA,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;11th July, 1897&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My dear Shuddhananda,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was very glad to receive your last report. I have very little&#xA;criticism to make except that you ought to write a bit more legibly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am quite satisfied with the work done so far, but it must be pushed&#xA;forward. I have not learnt as yet of the suggestion I made before as to&#xA;getting a set of chemical and physical apparatus and starting classes in&#xA;elementary and experimental Chemistry and Physics, especially in&#xA;Physiology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>782 XLI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/782_41_miss_noble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/782_41_miss_noble/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xli&#34;&gt;XLI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ALMORA,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;23rd July, 1897&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MY DEAR MISS NOBLE,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Excuse these few lines. I shall write more fully as soon as I reach some&#xA;place. I am on my way from the hills to the plains.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do not understand what you mean by frankness without familiarity — I&#xA;for one will give anything to get rid of the last lingering bit of&#xA;Oriental formality in me and speak out like a child of nature. Oh, to&#xA;live even for a day in the full light of freedom, to breathe the free&#xA;air of simplicity! Is not that the highest purity?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>783 XLII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/783_42_miss_noble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/783_42_miss_noble/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xlii&#34;&gt;XLII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ALMORA,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;29th July, 1897&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MY DEAR MISS NOBLE,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A letter from Sturdy reached me yesterday, informing me that you are&#xA;determined to come to India and see things with your own eyes. I replied&#xA;to that yesterday, but what I learnt from Miss Muller about your plans&#xA;makes this further note necessary, and it is better that it should be&#xA;direct.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you frankly that I am now convinced that you have a great&#xA;future in the work for India. What was wanted was not a man, but a woman&#xA;— a real lioness — to work for the Indians, women specially.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>784 XLIII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/784_43_madam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/784_43_madam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Very glad to receive your kind note. If by the sacrifice of some&#xA;specially cherished object of either myself or my brother-disciples many&#xA;pure and genuinely patriotic souls come forward to help our cause, rest&#xA;assured, we will not hesitate in the least to make that sacrifice nor&#xA;shed a tear-drop — you will see this verified in action. But up till now&#xA;I have seen nobody coming forward to assist in this way. Only some have&#xA;wished to put their own hobby in place of ours — that is all. If it&#xA;really help our country or humanity — not to speak of giving up&#xA;Guru-worship — believe me, we are prepared to commit any dire iniquity&#xA;and suffer the eternal damnation of the Christians. But my hairs have&#xA;turned grey since I began the study of man. This world is a most trying&#xA;place, and it is long since I have taken to wandering with the lantern&#xA;of the Grecian Philosopher in hand. A popular song my Master often used&#xA;to sing comes to my mind:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>785 XLIV</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/785_44_sturdy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/785_44_sturdy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xliv&#34;&gt;XLIV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C/O F. H. LEGGETT,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;21 WEST THIRTY-FOURTH STREET&lt;br&gt;&#xA;NEW YORK&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Nov&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;em&gt;, 1899&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MY DEAR STURDY,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is not to defend my conduct. Words cannot wipe off the evils I have&#xA;done, nor any censor stop from working the good deeds, if any.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the last few months I have been hearing so much of the luxuries I&#xA;was given to enjoy by the people of the West — luxuries which the&#xA;hypocrite myself has been enjoying, although preaching renunciation all&#xA;the while: luxuries, the enjoyment of which has been the great&#xA;stumbling-block in my way, in England at least. I nearly hypnotised&#xA;myself into the belief that there has at least been a little oasis in&#xA;the dreary desert of my life, a little spot of light in one whole life&#xA;of misery and gloom; one moment of relaxation in a life of hard work and&#xA;harder curses — even that oasis, that spot, that moment was only one of&#xA;sense-enjoyment!!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>786 XLV</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/786_45_mrs_leggett/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/786_45_mrs_leggett/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xlv&#34;&gt;XLV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CHICAGO,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;26th Nov&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;em&gt;, 1899&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MY DEAR MRS. LEGGETT,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many, many thanks for all your kindness and especially the kind note. I&#xA;am going to start from Chicago on Thursday next, and got the ticket and&#xA;berth ready for that day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Miss Noble is doing very well here, and working her way out. I saw&#xA;Alberta the other day. She is enjoying every minute of her stay here and&#xA;is very happy. Miss Adams (Jane Adams), as ever is an angel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>787 XLVI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/787_46_mother/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/787_46_mother/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xlvi&#34;&gt;XLVI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CHICAGO,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;30th Nov&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;em&gt;, 1899&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MY DEAR MOTHER, (Mrs. Leggett.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nothing new — except Madame Calvé&amp;rsquo;s visit. She is a great woman. I wish&#xA;I saw more of her. It is a grand sight to see a giant pine struggling&#xA;against a cyclone. Is it not?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I leave here tonight. These lines in haste as A__ is waiting. Mrs.&#xA;Adams is kind as usual. Margot doing splendidly. Will write more from&#xA;California.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>788 XLVII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/788_47_margot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/788_47_margot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xlvii&#34;&gt;XLVII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LOS ANGELES,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;6th Dec&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;em&gt;, 1899&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR MARGOT,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your sixth has arrived, but with it yet no change in my fortune. Would&#xA;change be any good, do you think? Some people are made that way, to love&#xA;being miserable. If I did not break my heart over people I was born&#xA;amongst, I would do it for somebody else. I am sure of that. This is the&#xA;way of some, I am coming to see it. We are all after happiness, true,&#xA;but that some are only happy in being unhappy — queer, is it not? There&#xA;is no harm in it either, except that happiness and unhappiness are both&#xA;infectious. Ingersoll said once that if he were God, he would make&#xA;health catching, instead of disease, little dreaming that health is&#xA;quite as catching as disease, if not more! That is the only danger. No&#xA;harm in the world in my being happy, in being miserable, but others must&#xA;not catch it. This is the great fact. No sooner a prophet feels&#xA;miserable for the state of man than he sours his face, beats his breast,&#xA;and calls upon everyone to drink tartaric acid, munch charcoal, sit upon&#xA;a dung-heap covered with ashes, and speak only in groans and tears! — I&#xA;find they all have been wanting. Yes, they have. If you are really ready&#xA;to take the world&amp;rsquo;s burden, take it by all means. But do not let us hear&#xA;your groans and curses. Do not frighten us with your sufferings, so that&#xA;we came to feel we were better off with our own burdens. The man who&#xA;really takes the burden blesses the world and goes his own way. He has&#xA;not a word of condemnation, a word of criticism, not because there was&#xA;no evil but that he has taken it on his own shoulders willingly,&#xA;voluntarily. It is the Saviour who should &amp;ldquo;go his way rejoicing, and not&#xA;the saved&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>789 XLVIII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/789_48_mother/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/789_48_mother/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;xlviii&#34;&gt;XLVIII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1719 TURK STREET,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;SAN FRANCISCO,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;17th March, 1900&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MY DEAR MOTHER (Mrs. Leggett.),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So glad to get your nice letter. Well, you may be sure I am keeping in&#xA;touch with my friends. Yet a delay may sometimes cause nervousness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. and Mrs. Hiller returned to the city, much benefited, as they&#xA;declare, by Mrs. Melton&amp;rsquo;s rubbings. As for me, I have got several huge&#xA;red patches on my chest. What materialises later on as to complete&#xA;recovery, I will let you know. Of course, my case is such that it will&#xA;take time to come round by itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>790 IL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/790_49_mother/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/790_49_mother/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;il&#34;&gt;IL&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1719 TURK STREET,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;SAN FRANCISCO,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;17th March, 1900&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR MOTHER (Mrs. Leggett.),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had a letter from Joe asking me to send my signature on four slips of&#xA;paper, so that Mr. Leggett may put my money in the bank for me. As I&#xA;cannot possibly reach her in time, I send the slips to you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am getting better in health and doing financially something. I am&#xA;quite satisfied. I am not at all sorry that more people did not respond&#xA;to your call. I knew they would not. But I am eternally thankful to you&#xA;for all your kindness. May all blessings follow you and yours for ever.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>791 L</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/791_50_mother/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/791_50_mother/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;l&#34;&gt;L&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1719 TURK STREET,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;SAN FRANCISCO,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;7th April, 1900&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR MOTHER (Mrs. Leggett.),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Accept my congratulations for the news of the cause of the wound being&#xA;completely removed. I have no doubt of your being perfectly cured this&#xA;time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your very kind note cheered me a good deal. I do not mind at all whether&#xA;people come round to help me or not; I am becoming calm and less&#xA;worried.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>792 LI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/792_51_mr_leggett/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/792_51_mr_leggett/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Addressee&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;li&#34;&gt;LI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;17th April, 1900&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MY DEAR MR. LEGGETT,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Herewith I send the executed Will to you. It has been executed as&#xA;desired by her, and of course, as usual, I am requesting you for the&#xA;trouble of taking charge of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You and yours have been so uniformly kind to me. But you know, dear&#xA;friend, it is human nature to ask for more favours (now that they have&#xA;come) where it gets from.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>793 LII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/793_52_aunt_roxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/793_52_aunt_roxy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;lii&#34;&gt;LII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2nd May, 1900&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DEAR AUNT ROXY, (Mrs. Blodgett of Los Angeles),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your very, very kind letter came. I am down again with nerves and fever,&#xA;after six months of hard work. However, I found out that my kidneys and&#xA;heart are as good as ever. I am going to take a few days&amp;rsquo; rest in the&#xA;country and then start for Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have just written to Mrs. Milward Adams and also have given an&#xA;introduction to my daughter, Miss Noble, to go and call upon Mrs. Adams&#xA;and give her all information she wants about the work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>794 LIII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/794_53_alberta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_7/epistles_third_series/794_53_alberta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;liii&#34;&gt;LIII&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PERROS GUIREC&lt;br&gt;&#xA;BERTAGNE,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;22nd September, 1900&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To Miss Alberta Sturges&lt;br&gt;&#xA;on her 23rd birthday&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The mother&amp;rsquo;s heart, the hero&amp;rsquo;s will,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The softest flower&amp;rsquo;s sweetest feel;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The charm and force that ever sway&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The altar fire&amp;rsquo;s flaming play;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The strength that leads, in love obeys;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Far-reaching dreams, and patient ways,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Eternal faith in Self, in all&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The sight Divine in great in small;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;All these, and more than I could see&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Today may &amp;ldquo;Mother&amp;rdquo; grant to thee.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
