<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Indian elections 2024</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/2024-06-08_indian-elections-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/2024-06-08_indian-elections-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2024/06/08/indian-elections-2024/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Indian elections 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ways of the fierce gods are not easy for men to comprehend with their finite lives. A course of five years might seem like nothing in historical time, but the dice rolled by the gods in that window could change both the life of a man and the history of a nation. Five years ago, little did we know the Wuhan disease was on the horizon to irreversibly change the lives of many. Some who were seemingly well then were consumed by the disease, and their very existence was entirely forgotten. There were going to be other casts of the dice that would irrevocably afflict some while elevating others to great heights. The elections of 2019 and 2024 bracketed these events. The former saw the unmistakable triumph of the Lāṭapuruṣa, while the latter saw his fortunes wobble. In the same time frame, among the mahāmleccha-s, &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2021/10/31/the-rise-of-navyonmada-the-subversion-of-the-mahamleccha-s-cinanusara-and-beyond/&#34;&gt;Picchilaka was overthrown by the Sora-śaṇḍa-conjoined Deep State and replaced by the pliable Piṇḍaka&lt;/a&gt;. By plying his rubber stamp, the Deep State, for the first time adhering to the new religion of Navyonmāda, could now turn the still formidable mleccha war machine against the Rūs while undermining their own people who back Picchilaka. While we normally do not expend thought and words on the minutiae of electoral politics, we believe the current events are worth some general comments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Anglosphere and India: new events</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/2005-03-21_the-anglosphere-and-india-new-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/2005-03-21_the-anglosphere-and-india-new-events/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/03/21/the-anglosphere-and-india-new-events/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;complex-ploy&#34;&gt;Complex ploy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One cannot rule out a complex ploy by the US decision-makers (the inner circle). Note the following carefully:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Many of the people on these “human rights” organizations have ties with neocons (ironic but true).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The core neocons have this remarkable love for Pakistan as evidenced by their deft use of 9-11 to prop up TSP, ignore its blazing role in 9-11, and go Eye-raq.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The neocons are closely allied with or plainly rule the major media outlets, which have revved-up a concerted anti-Hindu campaign in the past year or so with sepoys or their own hachetmen.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They say that the cold war is over, but Russia is persistantly targetted for down-sizing by the US. Note the consistent pro-Chechen stance of US, despite their awful atrocities in Russia.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Given that the cold war is not really over India is treated exactly the way it was during the cold war.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hindus have a problem- they are very gullible and talk in terms of “friends” rather than interests while refering to international politics. Hindus have low level of unity in addition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Box India</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/2004-10-03_box-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/2004-10-03_box-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/10/03/box-india/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If we look at this carefully I see a pattern (may be I am a conspiracy theorist, but I believe I am right):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;india&#34;&gt;India&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;BJP comes to power&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bombs are bursted and India finally shows its muscle.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pakistan trashed at Kargil by Indian army followed by ignomious retreat of TSP. Signal sent to the world that India is no longer shackled by the terrorist state in the open battle field.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;TSP steps up terrorism, Nepal plane hijacking etc&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;9-11: USA learns first hand what terrorism is all about and losses some enthusiasm in covertly supporting Islamic terrorism&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Op-Parakram, India sends the signal to the world that it is not afraid of nuclear war with Pakistan. Nuclear war unlikely destroy India, but TSP will be gone.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hindu consciousness rising in the Indian masses and historical memories of Islamic atrocities are building up.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Indian economy shows some improvement, signaling additions to its military muscle.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;usa&#34;&gt;USA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Issues sanctions for the bombs, but notes that they cannot curb India.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The complex of events mentioned above make Pakistan less likely to balance India on its own on the battlefield. US 0-sum game is in peril with India threatening to become a regional power.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;us-foreign-policy&#34;&gt;US foreign policy&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There has always been a gulf between the way American people act and the way their governments’ foreign policy plays out.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The American people are largely inward-looking and prefer going about their lives in a private way, often evincing little interest in geopolitics&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They can be easily swayed by the mass media and easily accept demonizations of distant peoples by the mass media.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;observations&#34;&gt;Observations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;USA will go to any length to protect Pakistan&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watch out! Democracy(Marxism) is for all!</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/2004-10-03_watch-out-democracymarxism-is-for-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/2004-10-03_watch-out-democracymarxism-is-for-all/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/10/03/watch-out-democracymarxism-is-for-all/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;gifts-of-the-west&#34;&gt;Gifts of the west&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The West (in particular US of America) has endlessly spun tales of the glory of democracy. One day they are calling for democracy amongst Soviets, the next they want democracy in Latin America and on yet another day they want to bring this golden democracy to the Moslems. They bring the light of democracy and disperse the darkness of autocracy via invasions (typically termed liberations) or subversions (catalyzed by the omnipresent, omniscient CIA). Normally it comes tastefully gift-wrapped under various covers, termed “human rights”, “equality of humans”, “social justice” bla bla bla…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 canada-khAlistAn</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/2023_canada-khAlistAn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/2023_canada-khAlistAn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1705403294519120133.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Seeing related posts too, but those who have followed the khAlistAn issue for a while know that it is not a purely (probably not even primarily) TSPian project. It is a mahAmlechCha deepstate project contracted out in main to its pa~nchanetraka subsidiaries like laNDapura &amp;amp; karNATa.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The deeper roots go back to 1857 CE when an H coalition under marahaTTa leadership with the Mogol remnants made one last attempt to rid the subcontinent of Abrahamo-anglo dominance gained via the Anglo-marahaTTa &amp;amp; sikh wars. It was part of the larger global series of events for Abrahamo-anglo world conquest. The Crimean war against the rUs, featuring the well-known mlechCha-marUnmattAbhisaMdhi, the opium wars on the Ching, the Boer war, the world wars 1 &amp;amp; 2 were all part of the same system of their quest for world dominance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 election</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/2024-election/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/2024-election/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;सोरश् चोपसोराश् च&lt;br&gt;&#xA;कृष्णाद्रि-फुकोऽपि च ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;गुग्गुलुश् च द्वारश् च&lt;br&gt;&#xA;वनानाम् अधिपस्+++(=??)+++ तथा ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;अग्रभटश् च पृष्ठकश्&lt;br&gt;&#xA;चार्ध-कृष्णस् तथापरः ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;षिड्गश् च पौर-पुत्रश् च&lt;br&gt;&#xA;म्लेच्छानाम् प्रणिध्यस् तथा ।&#xA;इमे दिल्लीश्वरस्याग्र्या&lt;br&gt;&#xA;निर्वाचन-प्रदूषकाः ॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1740966848513052793&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While some believe that IQ could be the issue, the spoiled-soybeans mlechCha forces have relied more on what their predecessors also did: they could always purchase people throughout the chain of leadership to go contrary to national interests. That why the desperately want sorAdi-duShTAH to bring kAngress, kejarin and the like back on the gaddi. The advantages of these would be immense for them! It incidentally also resonates with their Galtonism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>75 years Republic</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/75-years-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/75-years-state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rattibha.com/thread/1559033772183588865?lang=en&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The latest Indian empire has survived 75 years &amp;ndash; against the hopes and wishes of the mlechCha and marUnmatta potentates. But it is quite possible that the ultimate reckoning will be forced on the H in the coming years. I suspect we have already seen the forward floaters of that I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to be wrong because by this reading we could see a superposition of bad times &amp;ndash; not something the H seem to be prepared for. The ancient system of father manu that found a way to stabilize  fundamental structural problems was rent asunder by the mlechCha conquest. This will resonate with navyonmAda, the latest of the diseases from the west, something lATeshvara&amp;rsquo;s court doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem too clued in to. This then will be superimposed on the ultimate civilizational clash with the ekarAkShasa who wears visible and invisible cloaks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bipin Rawat Death</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/rawat-bipin-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/rawat-bipin-death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1468788257806815233&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1468788257806815233&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The death of the CDS definitely seems puzzling. If it was an accident it is surprising for lesser nations ensure better transport safety for their leadership. If it was a deliberate foreign attack then it speaks for v.poor military intelligence, which is again surprising at this level. That leaves out activation of a deeply lodged internal agent, aka a Herpes zoster like &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;sleeper cell&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, there might have been indications of some threat that the national leadership was aware of. They may have even misread it. The reason to consider this is the craven retreat of the Lāṭapati in the confrontation with the sora-backed tool-kitties. One way to look at it is they had some intelligence of a bigger attack and decide to tactically retreat on that front as the resources might be needed for the bigger one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emigration</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/emigration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/emigration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1973630569134113149&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From personal inquiries, I have learnt that people leave India to work &amp;amp; live abroad for various reasons.  Some of the major ones are salary, ease of living, lower ambient disease load, clean air/water/drainage, access to the outdoors, and opportunities for descendants. Even if there is growing animus towards H, they are unlikely to easily drop these and return to the desh. If the government wants to bring back its foreign-based talent, it needs to think about these factors. Unless it expects to flee back as refugees when things get too hot, like it happened before in Fiji or Uganda.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/europe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;pivot&#34;&gt;Pivot&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/2016368369759342753&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The A&lt;del&gt;Nglamleccha/pa&lt;/del&gt;nchanetraka confederation has tried its best to throw sand in the gears of the H to thwart their restoration since independence: the tacit military support for TSP immediately after independence; the refusal to support large steel plants etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the internal social, biological and political issues of the H have repeatedly provided them with handles to do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The current pivot towards &amp;ldquo;Europe&amp;rdquo; is the return of an old cycle vis-a-vis the A~NglamlechCha. That has to be played carefully, with a realization of how it failed in the previous major historical cycle of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India Rus parallels</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/2022-06-12_vikirNaH-viShayaH-india-and-the-rus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/2022-06-12_vikirNaH-viShayaH-india-and-the-rus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;js_include&#34; url=&#34;https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/balto-slavic/slavic/rus/articles/MT/2022-06-12_vikirNaH-viShayaH-india-and-the-rus.md&#34;  newLevelForH1=&#34;5&#34; includeTitle=&#34;false&#34;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reckoning forecasts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/reckoning-forecasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/reckoning-forecasts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2025&#34;&gt;2025&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;h-danger&#34;&gt;H Danger&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1922087206975336725&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;H have to get used to a dangerous world where they walk by themselves like the evil Kipling&amp;rsquo;s proverbial cat.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The mAhamlechCha and their array of vassals will fear any demonstration of power, much like they fear and loathe the same from rUs and chIna.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The chIna-s with ambitions of not just Asian but world hegemony, will try their best to demolish the H.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The marUnmatta-s will tend to go with their coreligionist.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sundry pretasAdhaka powers will have a natural hostility towards H and, despite intra-Abrahamistic rivalry, be more comfortable with u3s.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Indic counter-religions have a natural counterreligious antipathy towards their parent.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We saw how in the west, despite the marUnmatta-s being the clear and brutal aggressors, a large section of public opinion turned against the u1s. This is despite the u2 deriving their identity from u1s and their desha. H should be prepared for the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Street veto</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/street-veto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/street-veto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: [TW]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the Indian media we encounter the peculiar term &amp;ldquo;street veto&amp;rdquo;. It is a good coinage. It is used effectively by both tR^ityonmatta-s &amp;amp; nayvonmatta-s. The former have been using it since they came into being while the latter more recently. It was most effectively used in mahAmlechCha-land in the uchchATana of the nAri&lt;del&gt;Nga-puruSha. It is a strategy that would be used both in India &amp;amp; the occident going forward unless put down ruthlessly. In India, it will be aided &amp;amp; abetted by the mlechCha navyonmatta-s. In both places it will be provided full cover by the sora-ShaNDa-bejhAdi-backed MSM &amp;amp; the likes of mukhagiri, reNugiri, guggulu &amp;amp; talcum powder. This cover will be aimed at dampening/heading off counter-mobilization through electronic warfare &amp;amp; hiding the dahana &amp;amp; bha&lt;/del&gt;njana used in the street veto.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US actions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/us_actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/MT/us_actions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2026&#34;&gt;2026&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;challenges&#34;&gt;Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;H will probably face challenging times in the relatively near future from the A~NglamlechCha directly or more likely via their marUnmatta allies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/2007985238765449457&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As 2026 proceeds, it seems like everything is shaping in the direction for the H to face major challenges from their mlechCha-marUnmatta-saMyoga.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are some who think that the pichChilaka&amp;rsquo;s support base are the main enemies of the H. They are, but if one thinks the liberals of the other pakSha are friends, open your eyes &amp;ndash; they are as much for the overthrow of H as the piciChilu~Nga&amp;rsquo;s men.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
