<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Yemen on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/yemen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Yemen on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/yemen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Uae retreat</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/yemen/uae-retreat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/yemen/uae-retreat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/Salansar1/status/2012895742633934970&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Around ten years ago, I had the pleasure of moderating a panel in Riyadh with @nytimes columnist @TomFriedman, where he said that the world was no longer divided between East and West, but between order and disorder. That framing captures the essence of what is unfolding today between Riyadh and Abu Dhabi.&#xA;In recent days, many western analysts and journalists have struggled to explain the growing rift between Saudi Arabia and the UAE. Much of the commentary is contradictory or superficial. This piece aims to briefly and objectively outline the key phases that led to this rupture.&#xA;Historically, Saudi Arabia took pride in being the only GCC country that was never occupied and in challenging British dominance in the Middle East. Before its formation, the UAE existed as the Trucial States under British protection, with London controlling defense and foreign affairs while local rulers governed internally. Riyadh consistently encouraged independence and self-rule, as it did across much of the Arab world. Ultimately, the British decided to end their presence, and Saudi Arabia played a central role in supporting the newly formed UAE. King Faisal was among the first to recognize the UAE and provided substantial political and financial backing in the early 1970s.&#xA;As the UAE developed rapidly, Saudis viewed its progress with pride, particularly Dubai’s economic transformation in the 1990s, which offered a successful non-oil model. Many Saudis of my generation spoke positively and with pride of Dubai in the 2000s as a modern Arab success story. That pride was genuine.&#xA;Saudi Arabia has long been seen be serious analysts within the GCC as the region’s strategic depth and security backbone. This was evident in the liberation of Kuwait and later in the rapid deployment of Gulf Shield forces to protect Bahrain from Iranian interference. Diplomatically, the same approach applied to the UAE. When Iran began provoking the Emirates militarily, Saudi Arabia, through Foreign Minister Prince Saud Al Faisal, issued a strong statement on 9 September 2008 affirming Saudi determination to liberate the three Emirati islands occupied by Iran.&#xA;Less than a month later, on 30 October 2008, Abu Dhabi surprised Riyadh by sending its foreign minister to Tehran to sign a comprehensive cooperation agreement. It was as if Abu Dhabi was apologizing to Tehran for Riyadh’s statement. While Saudi Arabia did not publicly object, the timing and style raised serious concerns in Riyadh, Washington, and beyond. Over time, those concerns deepened. Today, the UAE is Iran’s second-largest trading partner, and U.S. Treasury sanctions have repeatedly highlighted UAE-based networks used for money laundering and terror financing, most recently on 16 January 2026.&#xA;In 2015, Saudi Arabia formed a coalition to uphold the UN Charter, counter the Iranian-backed Houthi militia, and restore Yemen’s legitimate government. The UAE initially appeared fully aligned. Riyadh rewarded this cooperation by establishing a bilateral strategic council and integrating the UAE deeply into Vision 2030 projects and Saudi mega initiatives. The two countries projected an image of inseparability.&#xA;That trust was not reciprocated. Abu Dhabi increasingly used joint mechanisms to understand Saudi economic plans, then pursued parallel and competing deals independently. Riyadh eventually concluded that the UAE was not an economically reliable partner and scaled back cooperation.&#xA;The decisive break came in Yemen. Abu Dhabi’s actions revealed that its participation in the coalition was not primarily about restoring Yemeni unity, but about supporting separatist forces and securing influence over strategic ports, including Aden and areas near the Bab al-Mandab Strait, through which around 20 percent of global trade passes.&#xA;By that stage, the Saudi-led coalition had liberated nearly 80 percent of Yemen, and government forces were less than 20 kilometers from Sana’a. Then came the shock. Abu Dhabi split the Yemeni army, turned its factions against one another, and created the Southern Transitional Council, exploiting legitimate southern grievances for geopolitical gain. That was the moment Riyadh concluded the UAE was no longer a trustworthy partner economically, politically, or in security terms. Even then, Saudi Arabia exercised restraint, often shielding Abu Dhabi from Yemeni government criticism.&#xA;In September 2020, the UAE joined the Abraham Accords and normalized relations with Israel. Riyadh did not object to this decision, at least publicly. However, senior Emirati voices, including Minister Anwar Gargash, publicly framed normalization as a tool to increase the UAE’s regional competitiveness. Other Emirati figures went further, presenting it as the foundation of a new coalition designed to challenge existing regional alignments. Abu Dhabi appeared to believe that alignment with Israel would shield it while it intensified support for non-state actors across the region. This was a serious miscalculation.&#xA;Despite everything, Riyadh again accommodated Abu Dhabi by persuading the Yemeni government to integrate the STC into the cabinet, hoping to preserve unity. Abu Dhabi instead empowered figures such as Hani bin Buraik, a former al-Qaeda affiliate who became vice president of the STC, and Aidarous Al Zubaidi, the STC leader, who has a controversial past, including alleged training by Hezbollah two decades ago. Both were granted UAE citizenship. It empowered them not to be statesmen but as militia leaders. Abu Dhabi used these two figures as its major pawns and viewed southern Yemen as a chessboard.&#xA;Notably, in 2015, Iranian parliamentary speaker Ali Larijani reportedly told Yemeni separatist figures that &amp;ldquo;Iran does not mind two Yemens, a Shiite one in the north and a friendly one in the south.&amp;rdquo; This statement, taken alongside Abu Dhabi’s actions on the ground, raised serious concerns about overlapping objectives between separatist projects and Iranian regional strategy. It is therefore unsurprising that the Houthis later condemned Saudi strikes against STC militia forces.&#xA;In 2018, the Associated Press exposed a further layer of this contradiction, reporting that the UAE’s claimed war on terrorism in Yemen was largely a farce. The investigation documented how Emirati-backed forces recruited, financed, and empowered some of the most dangerous al-Qaeda operatives in Yemen in exchange for loyalty and territorial control, directly undermining the stated objectives of the coalition.&#xA;Beyond Yemen, Abu Dhabi faced one of its gravest reputational crises I argue on all its history on 26 October after its proxy in Sudan, the RSF militia, was implicated in genocide, mass killings, and widespread rape. Two weeks later, amid intense global outrage directed at the UAE, Abu Dhabi announced, for the first time ever, three days of nationwide federal military training across all emirates on 11 November 2025 and warned citizens and residents not to take photos. This show of force could easily be interpreted as a message directed inward, signaling who ultimately holds power and that internal dissent over Abu Dhabi’s foreign policy would not be tolerated.&#xA;Shortly thereafter, on 29 November, the Abu Dhabi government rolled out large-scale loan forgiveness, a classic combination of coercion and patronage, or a sword-and-gold tactic. Many within the UAE, including in Dubai, are deeply uneasy with Abu Dhabi’s overall trajectory and its increasingly immature regional adventures, which have significantly damaged the reputation of all the Emirates. This is especially the case since the other six emirates do not rely on oil like Abu Dhabi and instead largely depend on their reputations as hubs of tourism, business, and finance.&#xA;At this stage, Abu Dhabi entered a state of political paranoia. Senior circles in Abu Dhabi became convinced that the Crown Prince of Saudi Arabia had personally lobbied Washington to impose sanctions on the UAE over its support for the RSF militia in Sudan. This allegation was entirely false. No such request was ever made. Nevertheless, this mistaken belief heavily influenced Abu Dhabi’s subsequent behavior and contributed to a series of reckless decisions.&#xA;The biggest misstep by Abu Dhabi came when it directed its STC proxy to attempt further territorial seizures during a GCC summit in Bahrain, particularly in Hadramout. These operations resulted in civilian killings, forced displacement, and widespread intimidation, all of which were documented and raised serious alarm. Riyadh issued a 72-hour ultimatum for the STC to withdraw from the newly seized areas. Multiple STC defectors later confirmed that Abu Dhabi instructed its agent, Aidarous Al Zubaidi, not to comply. Saudi Arabia then acted decisively, striking new UAE military tanks and weapons at the port of Mukalla that were intended to be given to its STC militia, despite Abu Dhabi’s commitment not to export arms anymore. Riyadh also helped the legitimate government of Yemen dismantle the STC militia within five days, collapsing what had been a decade-long chaotic Abu Dhabi project.&#xA;It is important to note that Riyadh has not taken any decision yet regarding its bilateral relations with Abu Dhabi. There has been no official diplomatic rupture, no economic boycott, no border closures, no air embargo, and nothing of that nature so far. All Riyadh did was put an end to Abu Dhabi’s Yemen adventure for good and allow its official media outlets to become critical and revealing of Abu Dhabi’s recklessness and crimes in Yemen, Sudan, and other regions.&#xA;With widespread criticism now coming from Arab and Muslim countries’ media, and some official condemnations, Abu Dhabi may have realized, albeit too late, that its real cover had been Riyadh. Many of these countries view any GCC state through the lens of the Council, whose head is Riyadh, and had refrained from being vocal against Abu Dhabi due to the Saudi cover. Riyadh merely lifted that cover slightly, not fully, at least for now. It is also important to note that Saudi Arabia has never been more determined to help its neighbors secure their countries and combat non-state actors and extremists. Serious analysts and observers should attentively watch Riyadh’s next steps. Managing to finish a ten-year destabilizing project in just five days in Yemen can be replicated elsewhere, which would benefit the region and the wider world.&#xA;Returning to Friedman’s framework, this rift is ultimately about order versus disorder. Abu Dhabi backstabbed Riyadh, and Riyadh responded decisively, restoring limits. Abu Dhabi has also backstabbed Egypt in Sudan and the Horn of Africa. That will be the focus of my next piece.&#xA;Salman Al-Ansari&#xA;Saudi geopolitical researcher&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
