<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The enigma of ash mounds</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/2007-01-09_the-enigma-of-ash-mounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/2007-01-09_the-enigma-of-ash-mounds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2007/01/09/the-enigma-of-ash-mounds/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These thoughts sprung in course of one of those extended conversations&#xA;that we had. As we passed by train to the city of our birth we saw the&#xA;typical landscape of the southern Deccan plains: The clusters of&#xA;castellated granite hills and rock spurs of granite. These granite&#xA;landscapes immensely fascinated us, and in our early days we spent a&#xA;great deal of effort investigating their geology. We then had our&#xA;encounter with their archaeology which we never fathomed till we ran&#xA;into Allchin’s work. Allchin, a British archaeologist, spent decades&#xA;studying Indian dung and this is precisely what caught our attention. We&#xA;had seen the little hills of ash and where various villages dotted the&#xA;Kanada and Telugu countryside known as Budihalli-s or ash villages (bUdi&#xA;as is vibhUti or ash). Sadly, these remarkable sites are vanishing&#xA;rapidly these days under the action of both local and the government&#xA;development schemes and we may lose our as it is tenuous link to the&#xA;past. The Budihal itself was a center of great archaeological&#xA;investigation by the Indian successors of Allchin, and have produced&#xA;much new data. We summarize below some data and speculations on the&#xA;archaeology and history of the ash mounds and associated peninsular&#xA;prehistoric sites:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The end of the era of Tamil warlords</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-08-26_the-end-of-the-era-of-tamil-warlords/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-08-26_the-end-of-the-era-of-tamil-warlords/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/08/26/the-end-of-the-era-of-tamil-warlords/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The puranAnuru and related puraM texts of early Tamil literature mark the end era of the Tamil warlords. The violent, grandiose and impractically generous Tamil warlords were passing out of vogue with the solidification of the 3 great Tamil kingdoms- the choLan, the cheran and the pANDiyan. The great reign of the 3 Tamil polities lasted till the external kalabhra rule ended the sangam phase of tamil literature.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They were followed by the more Sanskritized Pallavas and finally by the revival of the big 3 till the days of pan-India tripartite struggle between, north, middle and south India, all alternately contending for supremacy over the land. But the image of the tamil warlords still inspires the modern tamil world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indus iconography and its parallels</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-11-22_indus-iconography-and-its-parallels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/2004-11-22_indus-iconography-and-its-parallels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/11/22/indus-iconography-and-its-parallels/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As Thomas McEvilley pointed out there are numerous connections between Indus Valley (IVC) Iconography and those in the Middle East. The real significance of these clear connections have hardly been understood.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Central strongman figure wrestling lions on either side symmetrically.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is seen in period 2000-3000 BC in the Sumerian seals. There are two IVC seals with the same image, one with the Indus script and one without from around the same time. Much later around 500 BC it is seen amongst the Achaemenid Iranians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dravidian theory problems</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/dravidian-theory-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/dravidian-theory-problems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One strong argument in that direction has been Brahui a Dravidian language in lands with high Iranian farmer contribution. However, we argue that Dr was not the Harappan language because:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There is a common substratum including for agricultural terms and plants that is shared by both Dravidian and Indo-Aryan languages. This implies there was once a third language in the picture and unique to the subcontinent.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t find Dr as the earliest distinctly Indian substrate in IA but Dr loans appear later. The earliest available Dr text show evidence in contrast for a long contact with IA and IA literary and cultural conventions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If we look at the &lt;a href=&#34;../../../images/dravidian-language-tree.png&#34;&gt;recently constructed tree&lt;/a&gt; for Dr based on linguistic data Brahui is lodged quite deep in the tree with no indication of a root-ward position that would be expected if it were the relict of a Harappan Dr presence in the NW.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Now with genetic data we can constraint ages. The clearly defined language families like IE, DR, AA are unlikely to be much older than 6000 YBP. That offers a kind of bound that suggests that Pr-DR was not very old &amp;ndash; at best around Mature Harappan suggesting that it might not have had deep history which also inconsistent with the loans from another language.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hence, together we surmise that the Iranian farmers brought a now lost language that was the primary Harappan. In their southern borderlands were DR speakers who admixed with them and acquired some of the Harappan cultural elements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kRShNamUrti proto-dravidian</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/kRShNamUrti_proto-dravidian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/kRShNamUrti_proto-dravidian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;spreadsheet&#34; src=&#34;../kRShNamUrti_proto-dravidian.tsv.toml&#34; fullHeightWithRowsPerScreen=8&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kurunga</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/kurunga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/kurunga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On a separate note, one “Kuruṅga” occurs as the name of a Turvāsava prince in the Rgveda. In light of Paurāņika memory of Turvāsu-s/Turvāsava settling to southeast of Madhyadeśa i.e. Near Rewa, MP &amp;amp; given the historic tribal presence in MP &amp;amp; JH, one may be tempted to infer that Ārya clans like the Turvāsu had perhaps mixed with the local non-Ārya population as they expanded from Madhyadeśa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The origin of kuru&lt;del&gt;Nga is not as trivial as modern linguists think it to be. Different hypotheses connect it to words like kora&lt;/del&gt;Ngu (monkey) from Dr or an Austrasiatic word for antelope/deer or a tribal ethnonym name (kuruMga community &amp;ndash; an &amp;ldquo;AASI&amp;rdquo; enriched caste in Odisha).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>nIram</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/nIra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/nIra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1883571064753828048&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;sadA-nIrA is a river name appearing in the shatapatha brAhmaNa and texts coming after it (e.g., itihAsa-purANa). It is not found in any early layer of Vedic. Hence, it does seem the nIrA suffix is derived from a Dravidian word for water.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By most reckonings it is an Eastern river and indicates that the Indo-Aryans were already moving eastwards across the Gangetic doab. This, taken with the absence of reliable Harappan loans indicative of a Dravidian language, suggests that&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Possibilities</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/possibilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/possibilities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1990949887119413338&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are 3 possible hypothesis for the origin of the core Dravidians:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They were Harappans (I reject this hypothesis);&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;they were a near West Asian group (perhaps close to the Elamites; possible);&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;they were a peninsular Indian group (possible).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I posit that in the closing days of the Harappan civilization the ancestral Dravidian group (either #2 or #3) admixed with Harappans moving south&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and subsequently adopted (and admixed to a smaller degree with) the incoming Indo-Aryans&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and moved south as culturally Indo-Aryanized folks (the earliest Dr language text the Tam. puranAnuru supports such a scenario).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tajik outpost</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/tajik-outpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/articles/MT_lekhAH/tajik-outpost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2024.02.15.580575v1.supplementary-material&#34;&gt;new preprint&lt;/a&gt; on Indian genomics from Moorjani et al. Some figures and statements are a bit shoddy, but overall, it has good material.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 notable result: only 22 out of 2126 from core Indian cline lack Aryan ancestry! They don&amp;rsquo;t tell us which part of or which jAti-s these hail from. That is only ~1% of the core India cline population has a purely pre-Aryan heritage &amp;ndash; this illustrates the sheer magnitude of the genetic impact of the AI &amp;ndash; something many of us have known for more than 2 decades. Yet is something the India pseudointellectuals constantly deny till they go blue in the face. It is hard to see a nation so disconnected from its ethnogenesis which stares at its face.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
