<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;GuruAnaerobic on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/articles/guruAnaerobic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;GuruAnaerobic on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/articles/guruAnaerobic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CV-life</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/articles/guruAnaerobic/cv-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/articles/guruAnaerobic/cv-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GuruAnaerobic/status/1673016289638400004&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Never Had A CV&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s a CV? It&amp;rsquo;s the acronym for Curriculum Vitae, which means, &amp;lsquo;I need a job, in Latin. When I left school I was pretty clueless. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been taught there were ways to live other than being a full-time employee. I&amp;rsquo;d been brainwashed into conformity. I put on my only suit and went to an employment agency who told me I needed a CV to help me get a job. I had no idea what a CV was, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t know Latin because I went to a modern school where it was regarded as an unnecessary, dead language. [Note: All the top private schools teach Latin, so they must know something that shit schools don&amp;rsquo;t. If you&amp;rsquo;re a normal street kid in a gang, and you teach yourself Latin, it will confuse the hell out of the people you meet they won&amp;rsquo;t be able to bracket you. This one thing can help alter your life, not necessarily because you can read Latin shit, but that any preconceived notions that people have about you will change].&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money vs Freedom: GangFit</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/articles/guruAnaerobic/gang_fit_quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/articles/guruAnaerobic/gang_fit_quote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From GangFit 3 by Mark Baker/ GuruAnaerobic:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;state-of-freedom&#34;&gt;State of freedom&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;trading-freedom-for-money&#34;&gt;Trading freedom for money&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are 2 types of individual who trade freedom for money.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 The employed (millions of these). They spend all their weekdays working for money. They earn money so they can pay bills and feel free at the weekend&lt;br&gt;&#xA;2 The individual who is never satisfied - they want more money. The business owner/megarich, entrepreneur, wanker, etc. They are boring show-offs and even more boring company; they only talk about making money. Men like this surround themselves with plastic women and sports cars. Women like this are childless, depressed, and drink too much wine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
