<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Iranian Farmer on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Iranian Farmer on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Iranian farmer influx</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/iranian-farmer-invasion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/iranian-farmer-invasion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;../images/Arya-iranian-farmers-asi-service-castes-pca.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;../images/Arya-iranian-farmers-asi-service-castes-pca.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;        Arya-iranian-farmers-asi-service-castes-pca&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1109307670866075649&#34;&gt;MT_TW19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;iranian-farmers&#34;&gt;Iranian farmers&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Iranian farmers are a population emerging from the vicinity of the Zagros mountains and are related to the Caucasian hunter-gather shown as CHG in the Arya-iranian-farmers-asi-service-castes-pca figure. &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;rise-of-harappa&#34;&gt;Rise of Harappa&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Indus Valley civilization (IVC) area were settled by a people heavy in Iranian Farmer input (over a prior IHG substrate).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A Bronze Age civilisation lasting from 3300 BCE to 1300 BCE, and in its mature form from 2600 BCE to 1900 BCE.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3200-2600 BC Kot Dijian tradition emerged as unified pottery type across Indus River Valley &amp;amp; into Haryana &amp;amp; Rajasthan. They built walls around their settlements that were 6 m thick &amp;amp; 5 m tall. They had carts, bull figurines, &amp;amp; large brick platforms. Bricks were uniform in size.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2800-2600 BC several Indus River Valley Civilization settlements were burned, &amp;amp; almost all were abandoned. Invaders from Baluchistan mixed with their predecessors &amp;amp; kept much of their material culture. After invasion, almost all settlements were built in virgin lands, not ruins.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;noted for their urban planning, baked brick houses, elaborate drainage systems, water supply systems, clusters of large non-residential buildings, and new techniques in handicraft (carnelian products, seal carving) and metallurgy (copper, bronze, lead, and tin)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Indus Valley Civilization built even their small settlements with drains.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;meluḫḫa&#34;&gt;Meluḫḫa&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A prominent theory was that these people were referred to by neighboring civilizations as Meluḫḫa or Melukhkha (later giving rise to sanskrit mlecCha) [&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meluhha&#34;&gt;W&lt;/a&gt;]. After the decline of the Indus civilization, the toponym Meluḫḫa was preserved in the cuneiform tradition as the designation for a distant exotic country. The knowledge of its location, however, was permanently lost. In the first half of the first millennium BCE, the kings of the Neo-Assyrian empire identified far-away Nubia, situated in Africa, as Meluḫḫa.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ahar-banas&#34;&gt;Ahar Banas&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ahar-Banas Culture in Rajasthan was near a major copper deposit 3000-1500 BC. Some sites worked copper. They had a cultural change around 2000 BC &amp;amp; outlasted the IVC by centuries. They were connected to IVC by trade routes as well as the northern Deccan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Dravidian bloom</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/dravidian-bloom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/dravidian-bloom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;../images/dravidian-distro.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;../images/dravidian-distro.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;        Dravidian language distribution&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;../images/dravidian-language-tree.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;../images/dravidian-language-tree.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;        dravidian-language-tree&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;harappan-times&#34;&gt;Harappan times&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Harappans spoke a now lost/ subsumed language. In their southern borderlands were DR speakers who admixed with them and acquired some of the Harappan cultural elements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ia-interactions&#34;&gt;IA interactions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;IA met, and culturally influenced Dravidian language speakers, leading to acquisition of beneficial meme-plexes. They, as a consequence, expanded in to peninsular India, mixing and linguistically dominating the proto-Indian tribes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This is indicated  [&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/725906932431613952/photo/1&#34;&gt;TW16&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nature.com.ucsf.idm.oclc.org/ng/journal/vaop/ncurrent/full/ng.3559.html&#34;&gt;N16&lt;/a&gt;] by estimated time of L1 haplotype&amp;rsquo;s blooming after the blooming of the R1a haplotype.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SE Asian examples&lt;/strong&gt;-  See &lt;a href=&#34;../mon-khmer/khmer/&#34;&gt;Khmer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;bronze-age&#34;&gt;Bronze age&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;karnataka&#34;&gt;karNATaka&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Karnataka by 2300-2200 BC had domesticated several local plants for farming. Then numerous sites there were abandoned in that period, many cattle stockades were burned in enormous fires, &amp;amp; new pastoral practices appeared in Karnataka with new settlements. Copper and bronze introduced to Karnataka between 2100-1700 BC.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kulli culture</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/kulli-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/iranian-farmer/kulli-culture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gradual rather than sudden development of urban societies in Indian Subcontinent 6000 - 2000 BC. Some pottery shards show graffiti from proto-writing which was very different from the Indus Valley Civilization script.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Baluchistan 4300-3500 BC had growing settlements made of mud bricks, &amp;amp; featured granaries &amp;amp; stores. Lapis lazuli, steatite, turquoise, carnelian, &amp;amp; seashells were all worked with pottery in specialized workshops. Glass was made at same time as Egypt &amp;amp; Mesopotamia.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Baluchistan 3500-3000 shows signs of earliest irrigation channels in subcontinent, though debated. 3000-2600 population seems to have grown &amp;amp; social complexity increased. Monumental platforms (pyramids?) were built, &amp;amp; trade as far as Afghanistan &amp;amp; western India was conducted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Baluchistan coast under under influence of Indus Valley Civilization, but rest of Baluchistan remained culturally distinctive as the Kulli Culture 2500-2000 BC.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Baluchistan was overrun by invaders from Central Asia or Iran around 2000 BC. Settlements were burned &amp;amp; abandoned, walls were destroyed, &amp;amp; many objects were smashed. Horse bones are found in subsequent layers. Continuity in axes &amp;amp; cylinder seals though.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
