<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nair Akshay on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/nAyar-akShaya/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nair Akshay on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/nAyar-akShaya/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brit lynching</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/nAyar-akShaya/brit-lynching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/nAyar-akShaya/brit-lynching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(A British officer from Anjengo factory in 18th century Travancore nearly lost his life for overlooking at a temple out of his curiosity &amp;amp; saw a Nair lady. The local Nairs chased him and  almost lynched him until he ran &amp;amp; hid himself in a village under moplahs)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These ignorant and bigotted priests seem to hold strangers in abhorrence, and detest every intrusion into their holy retreats: I nearly lost my life by indulging an innocent curiosity near Quilone, a Dutch settlement, twenty miles to the northward of Anjengo. Strolling one evening through a wild scenery of woods and forests, I accidentally saw a Hindoo temple, almost concealed by banyan trees. Pleased with the scenery, I ascended a rising ground within the grove, to take a sketch; and in an adjoining tank saw a Nair girl performing her ablutions: she instantly snatched up her garment, and ran to an inner court; aware of her high caste, I did not attempt to speak to her; but seating myself on the bank, finished my drawing. In the grove was a Nair at his devotions, who, on the female speaking to him with earnestness, looked stedfastly at me, and departed with her to the temple. Thinking no more of either, I returned leisurely towards Quilone; when hearing a noise, I looked round, and perceived the same man, joined by several others, armed with sticks and stones, hastily following, and alarming the forest with their cries. I had neither time for deliberation, nor any weapon to defend myself; but, with a little distance in my favour, ran to the nearest village, and claimed the protection of some Moplals, having received a few stones in my flight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cladwell poem</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/nAyar-akShaya/cladwell-poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/nAyar-akShaya/cladwell-poem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Father of Dravidianism, the dangerous 18th century christian missionary Robert Caldwell describes about Travancore in one of his satirical poems (mocks as Coconutcore). He says it was a prosperous &amp;lsquo;model state&amp;rsquo;, where &amp;lsquo;Brahminical superiority&amp;rsquo; prevailed &amp;amp; as heaven on earth. GAMMON Row refers to mAdhav rAv.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WHO has not heard of that wonderful man,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;SIR GAMMON Row, the great Dewan,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Who has ruled for the last ten years, or more,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The Protected State of Cocoanutcore ?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This State, if judged from &amp;ldquo;Reports&amp;rdquo; you read,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Is a very wonderful State indeed;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A &amp;ldquo;Model State,&amp;rdquo; in which you may see&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Every thing is just as it should be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Travencore court and mlechChas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/nAyar-akShaya/travencore-court_and_mlechChas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/2_euro-assault/articles/nAyar-akShaya/travencore-court_and_mlechChas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Though Travancore Maharajas &amp;amp; court Brahmins maintained good alliance with Europeans, they built special place to meet them. They would change sacred thread &amp;amp; take bath to purify themselves after meeting Europeans whom they still considered as mlechchas. Only later this changed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
