<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/vasiShThaH/kauNDinyaH/gomaTha-kulam/manavALa-mAmuni/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/vasiShThaH/kauNDinyaH/gomaTha-kulam/manavALa-mAmuni/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ALagiya manavALa mAmuni</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/vasiShThaH/kauNDinyaH/gomaTha-kulam/manavALa-mAmuni/articles/aLagiya-manavALa-mAmuni/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/vasiShThaH/kauNDinyaH/gomaTha-kulam/manavALa-mAmuni/articles/aLagiya-manavALa-mAmuni/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;azhagiya maNavALa mAmunigaL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;sri:&#xA;srimathE rAmAnujAya nama:&#xA;srimadh varavaramunayE nama:&#xA;sri vAnAchala mahAmunayE nama:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the previous article (&lt;a href=&#34;https://guruparamparai.wordpress.com/2012/09/19/thiruvaimozhi-pillai/&#34;&gt;https://guruparamparai.wordpress.com/2012/09/19/thiruvaimozhi-pillai/&lt;/a&gt;) we discussed about thiruvAimozhi piLLai. Now we will move on to the next AchAryan in the OrAN vazhi guru paramparai.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;mamuni-ktpt&#xA;Thirunakshathram: ippasi, thirumUlam&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;avathAra sthalam: AzhwAr thirunagari&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AchAryan: thiruvAimozhi piLLai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sishyas: ashta dhik gajangaL – ponnadikkAl jIyar, kOil aNNan, pathangi paravasthu pattarpirAn jIyar, thiruvEnkata jIyar, eRumbiappA, prathivAdhi bhayankaram aNNan, appiLLai, appiLLAr. nava rathnangaL – sEnai muthaliAndAn nAyanAr, satagOpa dhAsar (nAlUr siRRAththAn), kanthAdai pOrERRu nAyan, yEttUr singarAchAryar, kanthAdai aNNappan, kanthAdai thirukkOpurathu nAyanAr, kanthAdai nAraNappai, kanthAdai thOzhapparappai, kanthAdai azhaiththu vAzhviththa perumAL. He had many other sishyas from various thiruvamsams, thirumALigais and dhivya dhEsams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Satyam Urti H</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/vasiShThaH/kauNDinyaH/gomaTha-kulam/manavALa-mAmuni/articles/satyamUrtiH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/vasiShThaH/kauNDinyaH/gomaTha-kulam/manavALa-mAmuni/articles/satyamUrtiH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SRI RAMANUJA&#xA;A BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH OF&#xA;MANAVALA MAMUNIGAL&#xA;BY&#xA;SRI S. SATYAMURTHI IYENGAR, GWALIAR&#xA;ADAPTED FROM&#xA;THE TAMIL TEXT OF&#xA;JAGADACHARYA. P. B. ANNANGARACHARYA SWAMI&#xA;SRI RAMANUJAN PUBLICATION&#xA;Printed at&#xA;Granthamala Office,&#xA;L. KANCHEEPURAM.&#xA;[Price: 0-30&#xA;SREE&#xA;A BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH OF&#xA;MANAVALA MAMUNIGAL&#xA;[An English version of Srl P. B. Anangaracharya Swami&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;love-laden and awe-inspiring Tamil biography, published in&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Sri Ramanujan-190,” by Sri S. Satyamurthi lyengar, Gwalior.]&#xA;INTRODUCTION&#xA;Of the two distinct realms emprised in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s kingdom, namely,&#xA;&amp;lsquo;Nityavibhuthi&amp;rsquo;and Leclavibhuthi&amp;rsquo;, the latter is looked upon by the&#xA;realised souls (gnanis) as the land of darkness or nescience. The darkness&#xA;alluded to here is not its physical aspect, which can be dispelled by&#xA;luminous bodies like fire, Sun, Moon etc., but the darkness within, the&#xA;impenetrable age-long mental stupor, which could be blotted out only by&#xA;that extraordinary Sun, which appeared on the spiritual firmament, in the&#xA;person of Sri Ramanuja. After vanquishing the athiests, agnostics and&#xA;heretics, who had brought about a sort of moral paralysis unto the soulelevating doctrines of the Vedas, through his all-conquering erudition and&#xA;enlightenment, and resuscitating the Vedas and putting them on their true&#xA;and legitimate Pedestal, he completed the mission of his Avatar (descent),&#xA;by ensuring the schenmatic propagation of the great hymns of the Azhwars&#xA;and the happy preservation of the Divya Desams (pilgrim centres) hallowed&#xA;by their songs, before returning to the Supreme Realn, whence he had come.&#xA;It is against this background, that Sri Ramanuja is extolled as the fostermother of the Divya Prabandhams, yielded by the Azhwars, but nourished&#xA;and stabilised by him. However, after some time, the fate, which had&#xA;earlier befallen the Sanskrit Vedas leading to the advent of Sri Ramanuja,&#xA;overtook Dramida Vedas (Divya Prabandhams) also. At the Lords&amp;rsquo;s behest,&#xA;Sri Ramanuja re-incarnated as Manavala Mamunigal and excelled his previous&#xA;record in many ways and performed the great miracle of transforming this&#xA;abode, notorious for its ignorance, into one of enlightenment and faith in the&#xA;Supreme. His unique qualities of hend and heart would baffle description&#xA;even by the thousand-headed&amp;rsquo;Adi Sesha&amp;rsquo;, who, incidentally, is but another&#xA;manifestation of himself,&#xA;The illustrious hierarchy of the Vaishnavite preceptors, known in&#xA;Vaishnavite Parlance as &amp;ldquo;poorvacharyas&amp;rdquo; has its happy culmination in&#xA;2 SRI RAMANUJAN—195&#xA;Manavala Mamunigal and none, after him, could join that great panel, however exalted. The personification of sweetness, it was in the fitness of things&#xA;that Mamunigal completed the great galaxy. This only redounds to the&#xA;wisdom of the Omniscient Lord. c.f. the dictum. [&lt;em&gt;மதுரேணஸமாபயேத்&lt;/em&gt;)&#xA;During His many incarnations, the Lord had the most unenviable&#xA;experience. As Dasaratha-Rama, he bowed before sage Viswamitra and served&#xA;him, ever ready to serve still more, and it was only some time later,&#xA;he came to,know from sage Sadanand, in the wake of Ahalya&amp;rsquo;s reclamation&#xA;from her terrific curse, the life history of Viswamitra, marking him out as a&#xA;combination of the Rajasic and Tamasic traits. Rama sought refuge in&#xA;Sugreeva, the monkey king, but was soon driven to the necessity of&#xA;admonishing him severely through Lakshmana. And then, failure on the&#xA;part of the king of the ocean to respond to Rama&amp;rsquo;s entreaty to open up&#xA;a causeway in the sea, chagrined Rama to the extent of threatening complete&#xA;dehydration of the whole brine.&#xA;In the next Avatar as Krishna, He fared no better. He went&#xA;through the rigours of learning, studying under Sandipani. At the conclusion&#xA;of the course, the disciple solicited the Guru&amp;rsquo;s choice in regard to the&#xA;reward (fee) payable by the former for the lessons imparted to him, only&#xA;to be called upon to regrant his son, swept off by the sea long back.&#xA;The great Lord in the garb of a human disciple was indeed stung by&#xA;the remorseful thought of a Guru, longing for such ephemeral wordly gains.&#xA;Having met with disappointment, at every turn, during the ‘Vibhava&#xA;Avatars&amp;rsquo;, the Lord was bent upon retrieving the position in &amp;lsquo;Archa Avatar&amp;rsquo;, as&#xA;Ranganatha (enshrined in the temple at Srirangam), through a Guru of the&#xA;pre-eminence of Mamunigal. A brief sketch of the life-history of Mamunigal&#xA;of such unique excellence, the stead-fast pillar of Vaishnavism, has been&#xA;attempted below.&#xA;THE BIRTH OF MAMUNIGAL&#xA;The line of succession in the hierarchy of the &amp;lsquo;Poorvacharyas&amp;rsquo; from&#xA;and after Sri Ramanuja runs as follows :-&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
