<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hindutva ko fek do</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/2003-11-18_hindutva-ko-fek-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/2003-11-18_hindutva-ko-fek-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/11/18/hindutva-ko-fek-do/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some years ago, VS Naipaul correctly saw that Hindutva as a real and potent revival of the soul of India. It is a movement of the teeming Indian masses, the plebeians finding their long lost identity. In a sense it goes hand in hand with the identity of the country itself. Yet many an educated member of the Indian elite finds a deep fear in associating with Hindutva. For example in this forum we see Rajiv Malhotra and his cohorts trying to adopt a holier than thou stance where they try to identify themselves with some thing they term “Indic traditions” while trying to pooh-pooh Hindutva as the dirty “danDavAlAs”. It is true that the danDavAlA approach of Hindutvavadins is deficient in several ways: for example, it has a very poor intrinsic understanding of the Hindu dharma, it is not intellectual in its outlook and fails to define major problems currently, its abrasive responses can turn off the Indian elite and lastly it revels in floating lost or flawed causes such as mad cows, astrology training and pseudoscholastic Out of India theories for the origin of Indo-Aryans.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jinnah and Huntington</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/2003-09-11_jinnah-and-huntington/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/2003-09-11_jinnah-and-huntington/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/09/11/jinnah-and-huntington/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Often, certain Hindus labor under the belief that they have a superior understanding of Christianism and Mohammedanism than the Christians and Mohammedans themselves. This was never more clear than in the case of Jinnah the founder of the Terrorist State of Pakistan. Eventhough Jinnah was pretty lucid in explaining how the Two nation theory worked, the Hindus completely failed to understand it. Even today many Hindus, both secularvaadi and otherwise, believe that the two nation theory is incorrect. What has been shown to be incorrect is the ridiculous “martial races” theory that was mainly an European invention. The crux of the issue is that, in the two nation theory, the person who who proposes it, is the one controls the dialog. So when Mr. Jinnah told Gandhi and Chachaji that there were two nations: Dar-ul-Momeen and Dar-ul-Harb, he was in control of the dialog right from the begining. So irrespective of whatever our Chacha or the Mahatma thought there were going to be two nations. The response of the Nehru-Gandhi clique was of course no different from the manner in which Hindus deal with contentious issues amidst themselves. This made no sense in the context of Jinnah because he was a part of Dar-ul-Momeen and idiots from Dar-ul-Harb have no say in the matter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1994-2024 outlook</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/1994-2024_outlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/1994-2024_outlook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1753837293335453862.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wish I could answer this with numbers, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to dig up such. Hence, this answer is based on feelings. I feel approximately the same. In the thread below I&amp;rsquo;ll elaborate a bit: It might arouse disagreement in some readers. In 1989 we had the disastrous ascent of VP Singh, the Mandal affair, then by 1991 the collapse of our main ally the Sov-rUs empire, the assassination of Rajiv, the unstable brief rule of Chandrashekhar. Coeval with this the mlechCha-marUnmatta attempt to grab our head &amp;ndash; Kashmir was initiated with full violence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apathy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/apathy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/apathy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1821408589774274758&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;+++(In the aftermath of 2024 BD coup + anti-hindu atrocities)+++&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If one looks at life in general in India&lt;br&gt;&#xA;there are a lot of immediate concerns:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;disease from infection, dietary extravagance &amp;amp; pollution;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;local issues like finding water;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;long commutes often through traffic;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;sapping work schedules.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So most people cannot really think about big geopolitical H issues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People without historical religious awareness seek hedonistic objectives when they have some time/money.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>English role</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/english-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/english-role/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1006392925004206080&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do think that religiosity has deeper biological(broadly including para-genetic transmission) roots and the expression of religiousity is monophyletic among extant humans. That said natural religions (e.g. H dharma), as opposed to counter-religions e.g. Abrahamisms, are slow in defining themselves in clearly demarcated terms or giving themselves a name. They have certain sense of universality in that they see the religiosity of the other as just a manifestation of their own (even if an inferior one). Often they develop the sharp demarcation when confronted by a counter-religion. Thus, the narrow sense H boundary developed when confronted with jaina &amp;amp; bauddha. It was amplified in the conflicts with the 3rd &amp;amp; 2nd Abrahamism. If anything the English played a role in that sense rather than anything else. One place where they did seem to have created a schism by definition was with the abrahamized H cult of the sikhs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Euro interest</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/euro-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/euro-interest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1829715551318315297&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;m not a social person, over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve a noticed a continuing interest in certain western circles which comes in different (sometimes non-interacting flavors):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There is a large contingent seeking &amp;ldquo;meaning in life&amp;rdquo; via making sense of the subjective realm. Most of them try to explore it via the American state religion of Judeo-Christanity but often find it falling short. Some of that type discovers Indian religious streams and gets interested.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are academic white indologists who might be interested in anthropology, linguistics, philology and (pre)history. Some of them may begin as #1.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are industrial and political types which see an opportunity in making a profit or playing 0-sum games for Occidental foreign policy. They get interested in contemporary India without much of an understanding of its religious traditions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many of these begin positive&lt;br&gt;&#xA;but turn negative as they mature &amp;ndash;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;a part of this phenomenon of the malhotran U-turn&lt;br&gt;&#xA;which is facilitated by a frustration with &amp;ldquo;the other&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;that develops over time&lt;br&gt;&#xA;along with rediscovery of their undercurrent (even if secularized) Judeo-Christianity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genetics</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/genetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1719546040758460616.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Boy raised by traditional, devout parents; taught traditional arts; went to a famous, hallowed maṭha during summer holidays to do Guruseva &amp;amp; was quite involved in such Dhārmikas things. Grew up, married a Marūnmatta-strī, changed name &amp;amp; started eating meat. Svabhāva.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I mostly concur. Over the years I have realized that genetic determinism is a much bigger factor that abrahamo-occidentally conditioned minds like to admit. I see two vectors that might have an angle of up to 30 degs between them:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meme Gene balance</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/meme-gene-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/meme-gene-balance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1465099817055576073&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;+++(Consider)+++ The growing Cases of people of European/West Asian ancestry claiming to be First Americans or of African descent. This seems to illustrate one of the contradictions of liberal (mostly North American) identity crisis. The simultaneous insistence &amp;amp; denial of the centrality of race. It laterally impinges on an oft discussed (heatedly) modern identity problem in the Hindu world too &amp;ndash; i.e. that of varNa by birth vs temperament. In our opinion (as mentioned before) it is good to not go the whole hog along either branch of the decision tree but accept a bit of a superposition.+++(5)+++ The genetics of tribes, lineages etc keep changing with admixture &amp;ndash; a reality of human existence &amp;ndash; hence, hanging your identity purely on a &amp;ldquo;mine is bigger&amp;rdquo; attitude is not the best thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Same DNA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/race-language_vs_religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/articles/MT/race-language_vs_religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1457941507353284609&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a topic I have commented a lot on, nevertheless: &amp;ldquo;same DNA&amp;rdquo; thing +++(Mohan Bhagawat of RSS: &amp;ldquo;Muslims have same DNA as Hindus&amp;rdquo;)+++ is what in America goes under the name racism. Race &amp;amp; religion are topics that evoke great passion &amp;amp; there is nothing surprising about it. But people need to have an objective look at it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Theory accurately predicts that organisms will favor kin. In visual animals like humans this will involve looking for people who appear similar. They are likely to be kin &amp;ndash; nothing peculiar. Hence, there is an innate tendency to favor those who look like you against those who dont.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
