<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;vembu-shrIdharaH on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;vembu-shrIdharaH on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Boeing crash</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/boeing-crash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/boeing-crash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vifindia.org/article/2019/july/22/a-look-at-the-boeing-bloomberg-s-bloomer-on-737-max-aircraft%20&#34;&gt;URL&lt;/a&gt; (retrieved on Sep 6 2021 - 06:06)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Look at the Boeing-Bloomberg’s Bloomer on 737 Max Aircraft&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sridhar Vembu Sridhar Vembu [^3]&lt;br&gt;&#xA;July 22 , 2019&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-bloomer&#34;&gt;A Bloomer!&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In claiming that cheap Indian coders brought down the plane, here is the actual Bloomberg headline: ‘Boeing’s 737 Max Software Out-sourced to $9-an-Hour Engineers’(&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-06-28/boeing-s-737-max-software-outsourced-to-9-an-hour-engineers&#34;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-06-28/boeing-s-737-max-software-outsourced-to-9-an-hour-engineers&lt;/a&gt; [^4]). The article goes on to strongly imply that the reason the 737 Max crashed was cheap Indian coders. This section below is in the first part of the article:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Employee retention</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/employee-retention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/employee-retention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Startup founders often ask me about how to reduce employee attrition. At Zoho, I ask our managers &amp;ldquo;What have we done to deserve the loyalty and commitment of our employees?&amp;rdquo; This reverses the question from &amp;ldquo;why do people leave us&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;why should they stay with us?&amp;quot;+++(5)+++&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we truly internalize the question &amp;ldquo;what have I done to deserve loyalty and commitment&amp;rdquo; everything changes. We stop worrying about people leaving. Instead we start to feel profound gratitude for people who choose to stay with us and we don&amp;rsquo;t ever take them for granted.+++(5)+++ That&amp;rsquo;s important. In too many organizations, the committed and loyal employees are taken for granted. It often feels the company has no gratitude. Expressing gratitude in a variety of ways is a very important part of asking &amp;ldquo;what have we done to deserve commitment&amp;rdquo;. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fungible person Rot</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/fungible-person-rot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/fungible-person-rot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In our 25+ experience in business, we have seen companies come and go, companies that looked very powerful externally that stagnate and crumble. Reason? Cultural decay within. How does that happen to seemingly very successful companies? There is a startup religion that preaches ultra-fast growth, growth measured weekly(!), a religion pushed by people who have never built long term durable companies themselves and VCs who love that model. Such extreme growth obsession exacts a long term toll. Excessive growth addiction hides the fact that there is only so far you can push people before they break. The damage can be subtle. It is easy to paper over the damage by &amp;ldquo;professionalizing&amp;rdquo; the environment under the theory that one professional is substitutable by another. When a crisis comes or simply when growth slows, the growth obsessed company that cycled through people finds itself stranded and lost because the people that are there now have no shared experience or institutional memory of facing challenges and overcoming them. The external world may still be in awe of this growth darling but internally the rot has set in and becomes very hard to reverse because of the by now established culture of cycling through people. This has almost become a pattern with hyper growth VC funded companies. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GE fall</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/GE_fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/GE_fall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/svembu/status/1747750062380425253&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The man who did the most damage to American industry was Jack Welch, as the CEO of GE. The Boeing engineering disaster had roots in Welch&amp;rsquo;s deeply flawed management doctrines which were spread across American industry by his acolytes. This has to be understood in India too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He sacrificed sound engineering at the altar of finance and created debt fueled phantom profits at GE Capital that nearly destroyed GE during the Great Financial Crisis. He destroyed morale, culture and loyalty at GE with his brutal layoffs-as-strategy and took pride in it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Handling uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/handling-uncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/handling-uncertainty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1279922267925835781&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1279922267925835781&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In building any know-how intensive product, you face an essential uncertainty in project schedule and cost. Know-how intensive product, new team that has not built the exact product before and precise schedule are an impossible trinity. That drives CFOs and planners crazy! This is a major reason India has lagged behind in know-how intensive industry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best of Indian industry is largely driven by a project management discipline that values precise schedules and cost estimates.+++(5)+++ That&amp;rsquo;s normally a good thing. Except when it is not. Knowing when that project management discipline does not apply is wisdom. Even when we know it, applying it in a real world context is hard. &amp;ldquo;Why are we slipping&amp;rdquo; comes too readily!+++(5)+++&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Land price</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/land-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/land-price/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most important price that determines almost every other price and the cost of living is the price of land. Land prices increase very rapidly with population density. People collaborating with other and the resulting value added justifies higher land prices at first. Over time, as a location becomes too popular, land prices go up faster than local economic value added (local GDP).+++(5)+++&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Late arrivals to the hot location in effect work to provide an outsized return to lucky early residents who &amp;ldquo;got in&amp;rdquo; at the right time and the right price. This has the effect of increasing local inequality as more and more of wage income goes to rent or mortgage. Some people simply get priced out of the market altogether. We can see this in almost all the &amp;ldquo;desirable&amp;rdquo; big cities around the world. The problem has a solution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Management doctrine</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/management-doctrine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/management-doctrine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1306047987613745152&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1306047987613745152&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I want to talk about the topic of &amp;ldquo;modern management doctrine&amp;rdquo;, what is taught in business schools around the world. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at core tenets:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a) Metrics: you can only manage what you can measure&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b) Specialize: focus on your core competence and outsource all the rest&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;c) Shareholder value: the sole purpose of a company is to increase shareholder value (this from Milton Friedman).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now my take on these.I often joke that a major purpose of my life is to refute Milton Friedman, who I actually admire as a person!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marketing</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/marketing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/marketing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1437170940207517698&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1437170940207517698&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Building a business needs two basics, both of which are equally important:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a) the ability to come up with a product that people want&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b) the ability to make a sale.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Both are hard and are only rarely found in the same person and when they are, you have a great entrepreneur. Since I was not born with either skill (in particular I had no sales skill to speak of), I am going to present an approach on how to train yourself in both skills.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Org culture</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/org-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/org-culture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Salesforce - Slack acquisition demonstrates the &amp;ldquo;operating system&amp;rdquo; of the technology industry. The assumption is that professionals in Slack and professionals in Salesforce can nicely blend together to produce awesome results for customers and shareholders. Culture!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Slack and Salesforce grew up totally differently. The org cultures cannot be more different. &amp;ldquo;Culture eats strategy for breakfast&amp;rdquo; as the saying goes. Yet somehow in the romantic excitement of the deal, all that is forgotten. Money is blind after all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Production scale</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/production-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/production-scale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: https://threader. app/thread/1310005310510170112)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Concentration of activity in industry and agriculture (even coffee shops!) is justified by economic theory on the grounds of economies of scale. That&amp;rsquo;s the idea that the per unit cost of a product drops with rising scale of production.  It is true to a point but oversold.+++(5)+++ Per unit cost of production does drop with rising scale but here are a few key caveats. The costs drop rapidly with scale at first but beyond a certain scale (let&amp;rsquo;s call it &amp;ldquo;optimal scale&amp;rdquo;), stop dropping or even start increasing as dis-economies of scale kick in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R&amp;D</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/R_and_D/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/R_and_D/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1304273443983065088&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1304273443983065088&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One idea I would push hard among the industrial ecosystem is &amp;ldquo;Please invest in R and D, please create room for engineers and inventors to imagine and refine ideas, nurture R and D projects with patience, perseverance and endurance&amp;rdquo;. I will explain this in some depth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First my definition of R and D is far different from &amp;ldquo;what wins a Nobel prize&amp;rdquo;. In the rural India context, figuring out how to make a humble nail clipper is an R and D project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R&amp;D Projects</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/R_and_D_projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/R_and_D_projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If an R&amp;amp;D project ever goes smoothly according to a schedule, by definition it is not an R&amp;amp;D project! Such projects are characterized by &amp;ldquo;unknown unknowns&amp;rdquo;, things we don&amp;rsquo;t know that we don&amp;rsquo;t know.  We have to find ways to deal with that essential, irreducible uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My definition of R&amp;amp;D here is not just fundamental scientific or technological breakthroughs.  It includes doing things a particular team has not done and has no access to people who have done it before.  A lot of advanced industrial know how is in that category for India.  A new industry coming up in a rural area, where no one with previous expertise will move, has to accept the task of figuring many things out on their own, supplemented by online learning.  I call that the &amp;ldquo;Eklayvya Strategy&amp;rdquo; and the Dronacharya here is the online learning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rural advantages</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/rural-advantages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/rural-advantages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: https://threader. app/thread/1371279804914274305)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We tend to think only in terms of &amp;ldquo;what disadvantages to poor rural areas have&amp;rdquo;.  As an optimist, I look at the advantages instead.  To be an entrepreneur requires you to be an optimist and have a kind of faith that can only be termed religious. Let me list the advantages. 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The biggest advantage is the availability of people who are willing and eager for an opportunity and are grateful to anyone who extend it.+++(5)+++  Entrepreneurship is primarily about creating that opportunity, serving the unserved.  That is deeply satisfying and is also sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small scale business</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/small-scale-biz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/small-scale-biz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1266568560190447616&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1266568560190447616&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I talked about the thought experiment of building Boeing 747 from scratch in Bihar.Let me now talk about the other end: making nail clippers in a village. Nail clipper, hair trimmer, cell phone charger - these are the kinds of products that are doable in small villages. Today an Indian village grows food and buys everything else from outside. What they sell has low value compared to all the things they need to buy. That&amp;rsquo;s a fancy way of saying the &amp;ldquo;terms of trade&amp;rdquo; are stacked against them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting a business</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/starting-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/starting-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: https://threader. app/thread/1309287202480746496)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One young man approached me recently to ask for advice to start a small manufacturing business in a rural area.  He had arranged financing from his family. I told him I am not an expert in manufacturing (still learning the basics) so talked to him about business in general.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I asked him &amp;ldquo;First, are you mentally prepared to lose your entire initial investment? Have you prepared your family for that possibility?&amp;rdquo; This is not negative thinking.  I always ask: &amp;ldquo;Am I prepared to lose it?&amp;rdquo; I actually did lose all my savings in my first attempt!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong conviction</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/strong-conviction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/strong-conviction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the corporate world, there is a quest for &amp;ldquo;repeatable process&amp;rdquo;, done under the rubric of &amp;ldquo;scientific management&amp;rdquo;. Another related slogan is &amp;ldquo;data driven&amp;rdquo; decision making. What I have found is that the most important decisions are not easily formalized this way. In reality, the question &amp;ldquo;What should be our course of action?&amp;rdquo; on some issue, if we probe it further, goes like this. It first transforms into &amp;ldquo;What do we &lt;em&gt;believe&lt;/em&gt; we ought to do?&amp;rdquo; and then it becomes &amp;ldquo;What is our core conviction?&amp;rdquo; and that leads to the eventual &amp;ldquo;Who am I?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trend chasing</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/trend-chasing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/trend-chasing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: TW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of us in business are &amp;ldquo;trend following&amp;rdquo; in the sense that we implicitly project the immediate past forward. If we grew 30% for the past 2 years, we project 30% growth forward. We are usually right, except when we are not. Let us explore this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Trends exhaust themselves. As an example, the movement of software to the cloud is a major trend and one day that trend will exhaust itself. That is when growth slows. Late entrants are the most vulnerable to trend exhaustion because they projected the growth trend forward.Over-clouding, sorry over-crowding 🤣 is the next big reason projections go bad. Too many people jump in to a sector believing that the growth trend will continue and even an otherwise healthy market gets over-crowded and that impacts company performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>valuation-sanity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/valuation-sanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/valuation-sanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Startups that got hyper-inflated valuations in the bubble now face the prospect of having to &amp;ldquo;defend&amp;rdquo; those valuations. This translates to price increases for customers &amp;amp; cost cutting for employees, resulting in poor customer satisfaction &amp;amp; employee morale.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bubbles do damage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vision commitment</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/vision-commitment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/vision-commitment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1294432613151551490&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1294432613151551490&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are timeless business truths like &amp;ldquo;take care of customers well&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are also transient or contextual truths like &amp;ldquo;it is easy to make money in X&amp;rdquo; and this &amp;ldquo;truth&amp;rdquo; becomes untrue by being too widely believed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Then there is another category of business truth. The third category of business truth is the &amp;ldquo;what ought to be&amp;rdquo; - you imagine a new state of the world and you drive your actions towards achieving that goal.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the present moment, the new state may look like a distant dream. Yet that dream becomes our companion and lover. Only words like love, passion, soul can capture the essence of this. Those are not words you find in a business presentation or an MBA curriculum. It cannot be taught, any more than romantic love can be taught.It is commitment to that love that drives our greatest efforts. The person in thrall to that idea seems exactly as crazy as the person deeply in love. Your friends will roll their eyes.Yet the idea won&amp;rsquo;t leave you. It is the constant companion and a delightful tormenter.A lifetime of pursuit is the price that love commands.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wrong assumptions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/wrong-assumptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/svembu/wrong-assumptions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we begin a new project, we often have doubts. People offer caution. Early troubles may increase our self-doubt and may also generate &amp;ldquo;I told you so&amp;rdquo;. Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to lose face! I have lost so much face over the years that I wonder how I still have a face😅 One mental attitude I try to carry is &amp;ldquo;Yes some of my assumptions could be wrong. Yet if my core conviction is valid, we will figure a way out. We will learn from mistakes and failures, while acknowledging them.&amp;rdquo; Taking failures too personally is an ego trap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
