<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;vembu-shrIdharaH on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;vembu-shrIdharaH on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>$ creation - debt, turbulence</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/dollar-creation_debt_turbulence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/dollar-creation_debt_turbulence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1466389240342736904&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1466389240342736904&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;money-as-debt&#34;&gt;Money as debt&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The US Fed unleashed a massive round of dollar creation post pandemic. That has led to a dollar deluge in some places and industries - the startup ecosystem in India, for example. At the same time, there is a serious shortage of dollars in other places - Turkey is an example. The world faces a dollar deluge and a dollar shortage at the same time. How is that possible?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big city infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/big-city-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/big-city-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/svembu/status/1567293105979953154&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The infrastructure woes of Bengaluru &amp;amp; mega cities point to an important issue: cost of urban infrastructure goes up as a square of the population and &lt;em&gt;cost per person&lt;/em&gt; goes up linearly with population. A lot of the extra GDP enabled by cities is consumed by infrastructure. This is why cities like Hong Kong have very high GDP per capita but average incomes and consumer living standards are not as high as the GDP would suggest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big tech and bubble</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/big-tech_and_bubble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/big-tech_and_bubble/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I disagree with Aaron&amp;rsquo;s thesis, which flies in the face of the fact that no alternative to Big Tech has emerged in the last 15 years in spite of (because of!) extraordinary levels of VC funding that relied on selling to Big Tech and valuations pushed up by that prospect. In reality, both the high valuations of Big Tech as well as the derivative valuations that startups achieved counting on being acquired by Big Tech depended on the monetary fuel of the big bubble. The net result is concentration of monopoly power by Big Tech.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building vs using</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/building_vs_using/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/building_vs_using/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1289055212192202752&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1289055212192202752&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just because I drive a car and have driven it for a long time does not give me any particular insight on how to build one.+++(5)+++ Building requires a conscious process of learning and mastery and takes years, decades. This is a fundamental difference that economists often ignore. Just because India consumes hundreds of millions of smart phones does not by itself create the know-how on how to build the phones or the networks. At best, it is a &lt;em&gt;signal&lt;/em&gt; that demand exists but that signal does not magically transform into know-how and capability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Central bank vendor financing</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/central-bank-vendor-financing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/central-bank-vendor-financing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1232171665502752769&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1232171665502752769&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Globalization has become a sophisticated and central bank enabled form of vendor financing. Countries import goods they have no means to pay for except debt.+++(4)+++ Result? Countries like Sri Lanka in a serious debt trap. There is no alternative to building skills and know-how.Academic economists see that debt fueled consumption and mistake it for prosperity. The unemployment that arises from a population not having the skills and know-how to produce the very goods we consume with debt is seen as a separate problem. They are the same problem. As countries drown under debt, even the countries that vendor financed on a large scale face a severe crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China wage suppression</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/china-wage-suppression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/china-wage-suppression/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In China, one would imagine that fewer babies &amp;amp; declining working age population = higher wages and job prospects for the young, but there&amp;rsquo;s a disconnect b/n supply &amp;amp; demand.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Demand = manufacturing jobs&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Supply = University grads not wanting manu jobs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;China has plenty of manufacturing jobs but Chinese youth with college degrees want office jobs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This came about because China suppressed manufacturing wages (wage growth well below productivity growth) to encourage exports and that has made those jobs unappealing to youth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debt</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/debt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a Tamil sign we used to see in shops: கடன் உறவைக் கெடுக்கும் (debt destroys relationships). It means &amp;ldquo;Please pay for your goods, don&amp;rsquo;t ask us to postpone your payment&amp;rdquo;. That quaint sign of course is against modern practice where we are encouraged to charge it up!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The entire global trading system, in fact much of the global economy, now runs on the &amp;ldquo;charge it up&amp;rdquo; principle. Countries are encouraged to become &amp;ldquo;prosperous&amp;rdquo; by promoting consumption without local production. It does feel prosperous because we got all these goods. Here is the problem: global free trade is fundamentally incompatible with ever-expanding global debt (as measured by global debt to GDP ratio). The old Tamil saw is right after all - debt does destroy relationships, and that&amp;rsquo;s true in the village and true across nations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demand inflation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/demand-inflation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/demand-inflation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;America is running a trade deficit of nearly $100 billion a month. This is the consequence of &amp;ldquo;boost aggregate demand to avert a serious downturn&amp;rdquo; policy long advocated by economists like Paul Krugman. This is a good illustration of the bankruptcy of academic macro economics. Inflating aggregate demand (&amp;ldquo;priming the pump&amp;rdquo;) does not create new capability.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inflation rewards existing capability, and it also degrades that capability.+++(5)+++ It does so by creating a short term &amp;ldquo;make hay while the sun shines&amp;rdquo; mindset. We can clearly see that mindset right now. By running such &amp;ldquo;inflate demand&amp;rdquo; policy repeatedly for the past 20 years, America has eroded its real capability across a wide range of manufacturing industries and hence the trillion dollar trade deficit. The semiconductor industry is the latest one where this is seen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Develop poor districts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/develop-poor-districts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/develop-poor-districts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is the kind of problem I often think about: Take a very poor district in India. What does it take for it to become one of the rich places in the world? How does per capita GDP go from $1K to $25K-50K? What is &amp;ldquo;catch up&amp;rdquo;? How long would it take?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It comes down to having skills and know-how in the workforce and developing those skills require employers who will invest in that workforce to develop those skills and know-how. So going from $1K to $25K is the process of employers and the workforce advancing together. Employers and workforce advancing together to develop skills and know-how needs commitment to the cause, discipline to stay the course, curiosity to learn new things and ultimately the faith that it can be done. We have to find these within ourselves. An inner journey first.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development-patters</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/development-patters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/development-patters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threads-web.vercel.app/threads/1597652601507827712&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is there a difference between the pattern of development of South Korea vs that of Mexico? Taiwan vs Thailand? There is a distinct difference and broad-brushing such diverse countries as examples of &amp;ldquo;free trade&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;open to FDI&amp;rdquo; does not offer much insight.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Japan, South Korea and Taiwan followed what can only be termed their Swadeshi model, emphasizing domestic savings and investment, mercantalist export policy, with consumer goods imports restricted. To this day, you will not find many foreign owned factories in these countries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>End USD driven trade</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/end-usd-driven-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/end-usd-driven-trade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1255411817221931010&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1255411817221931010&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Risks to the global trading system. The US Fed is trapped between two contradictory objectives:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;a) keep the sputtering globalization model alive&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;b) save American society from even more division and conflict&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a) Globalization demands the US Fed has to serve the bottomless demand for dollar funds in the &amp;ldquo;offshore&amp;rdquo; market or the so-called Eurodollar market as @JeffSnider_AIP has explained before.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b) serving the needs of people who lost jobs and poor communities needs domestic funds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Export obsession</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/export-obsession/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/export-obsession/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1469817150302867460&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1469817150302867460&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;India runs a trade deficit and so India needs to export more. We need to learn from East Asia. With that said, I will explore the consequences of export obsession (also known as mercantalism). First, I want to thank @michaelxpettis and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/52009042-trade-wars-are-class-wars&#34;&gt;the book&lt;/a&gt; …&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A developing country starts exporting manufactured goods when its workers are able to produce more than they consume. In the early stages when there is a labor surplus, that excess productivity does not lead to higher wages for workers but higher profit for companies.+++(4)+++ The higher profit results in higher capital investment, funded by profits from exports, which leads to capital-goods imports from abroad. That fuels further increases in worker productivity.Normally wages rise to catch up with productivity and consumption and imports go up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free trade criticism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/free-trade-criticism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/free-trade-criticism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a critic of Prof Panagariya&amp;rsquo;s free trade theory for development, I will present the opposing case here. My critique has 3 parts:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;a) debt driven trade is not free trade&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;b) technology &amp;amp; production know-how are not tradable&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;c) cross-border migration&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lets start with debt. The present regime of &amp;ldquo;free trade&amp;rdquo; is more accurately described as &amp;ldquo;trade that causes extreme debt imbalances due to infinitely stretchable monetary instruments&amp;rdquo;. In no sane monetary regime would Sri Lanka have been able to accumulate over $50 billion of net foreign debt.+++(5)+++ Sri Lanka&amp;rsquo;s debt is totally out of proportion to its annual exports of about $1.1 B, which means prospects of repayment are very bleak. The question is how did Sri Lanka get into such a deep hole in the first place? Our regime of debt-driven trade dressed up as &amp;ldquo;free trade&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global-finance-fragility</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/global-finance-fragility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/global-finance-fragility/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Import-credits</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/import-credits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/import-credits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1587975418824384514.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;India imported 31% more from China so far in 2022 while exporting 36% less. Chinese economy is so structurally distorted, it can only produce and not consume. As a recent example, they ran factories during lockdowns but closed shopping malls.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What can India do? If India passively accepts China&amp;rsquo;s structural distortion, we risk heavily distorting our own economy to consume without producing and that would change our jobs mix towards token distribution jobs whose purpose is to create income to consume imported goods. We must resist. Economists like Prof Panagariya believe in what I call &amp;ldquo;naive free trade theory&amp;rdquo; that simply is not even aware that there is such a thing called structural distortion because it is not part of their toy models.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indian google-apple</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/indian-google-apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/indian-google-apple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threads-web.vercel.app/threads/1608243432535003136&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How can India produce globally competitive companies like Apple, Google, Pfizer, Samsung, Honda, Boeing, Siemens, TSMC or Huawei? Why are these companies so important to their host nations? Is India on a path to producing these companies? I will explore these quesrions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First let me answer the &amp;ldquo;Why&amp;rdquo; question. These companies are extremely important to their host nations because they embody within themselves the advanced know-how and R &amp;amp; D capabilities essential for modern life and nationhood. Most critical R &amp;amp; D happens within such companies. These companies enjoy a disproportionate share of economic value added as well as profits (compared to their direct effect on employment) and also pay heavy taxes to their host nations both through their well-compensated employees and directly as corporations. That&amp;rsquo;s the why.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Industrial policy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/industrial-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/industrial-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: svembu at DT, 2021&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The need of the hour is to promote strong domestic investment in skilling, building know-how in workforce, and nurturing a tradition of industrial R&amp;amp;D&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The budget season is an appropriate time to discuss a question that dominates my mind. I come at this question from the vantage point of a predominantly rural district like Tenkasi in Tamil Nadu: how could we make Tenkasi as wealthy as the nation of Estonia, which happens to have a slightly lower population compared to the Tenkasi district, both in the range of 13 to 15 lakh people. Estonia has a per-capita GDP of about $23,000, while Tenkasi is at about $1,500. A 15-fold growth is required for Tenkasi to catch up with Estonia. How does Tenkasi get there? Our economic policy must become an industrial policy. We need to promote strong domestic investment in skill and building know-how in our workforce, and we need to build and nurture a tradition of industrial R&amp;amp;D.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine tools</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/machine-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/machine-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: https://threader. app/thread/1313996801402306560)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently visited a textile spinning mill, one that converts raw cotton to yarn.  The yarn goes to weaving mills which weave the yarn to fabric.  The fabric eventually becomes clothing - that last part is where most textile jobs are, with the earlier parts highly automated.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The spinning mills and the weaving mills have highly sophisticated machinery, most of which are made in Germany, Switzerland and Japan.  These countries have had a long tradition of engineering focus and excellence. India has a lot to learn and catch up in this area. We need to revive our tool making culture and build a strong machine building focus in India. The economic impact of tool making and machine building is enormous.  I will discuss that now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Macro models</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/macro-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/macro-models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1567304169782124544.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I talk about the toy models of macro economists. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/paulkrugman/status/1566056460315942912&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is an illustration. This toy model of inflation vs unemployment does not capture demographics, does not capture the effect of foreign trade on inflation (US inflation was kept low for decades by China suppressing wages) and many more such parameters that influence inflation. Krugman himself failed to see &amp;ldquo;supply chain constraints&amp;rdquo; as a parameter (not part of his toy model!) so missed the 2021-22 inflationary surge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paying for trade-deficits</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/paying_for_trade-deficits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/paying_for_trade-deficits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threads-web.vercel.app/threads/1590830142099968001&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Warren Buffett proposed balancing US external trade by introducing the idea of freely tradable import credits whose total quantity is tied to export volume, economists dismissed it. That was in 2003. The US runs a far bigger trade deficit today &amp;amp; is in worse shape now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let us review the primary argument the economists made and often still make: the trade deficit is merely a reflection of the fact that foreigners have a huge demand for US assets, and that reflects the strength, safety and liquidity of US financial markets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poverty productivity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/poverty-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/poverty-productivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2001, Prof C K Prahalad published &amp;ldquo;Fortune at the Bottom of the Pyramid&amp;rdquo; i.e poor people as untapped markets for corporations. His idea became a big hit. I was not persuaded. Thanks to @AnandaramSanjay I found this counter from 2006. I agree with this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prof CKP preached a comforting illusion: selling to the poor makes them prosperous. This is also the economics idea &amp;ldquo;demand makes us rich&amp;rdquo;, forgetting how the supply comes to be. Demand does not make us rich, only by enabling people to be productive, we enable real consumption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trade deficits and bad debt</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/trade-deficits_and_bad-debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/trade-deficits_and_bad-debt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1304580991172845568&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1304580991172845568&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s NPA (bad debt) problem arose because India has run massive trade deficits which were funded with debt, very often dollar-denominated debt at the corporate sector. We don&amp;rsquo;t have the know-how to export to earn the dollars to pay back that debt. Trade policy ignored debt. The NPA problem, contrary to Prof Panagariya&amp;rsquo;s assertion is deep and structural and is directly linked to our persistent trade deficits.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We cannot fix our economy without fixing our trade policy (the absurdity of a massive labour surplus nation importing nail clippers). Alas Prof Panagariya demonstrates how economists obsess about GDP and essentially ignore debt. The NPA problem is not a technical issue with bank or corporate balance sheets. It is a vital sign of structural problems with trade policy. We have to get trade policy right.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trade value parity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/trade-value-parity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/trade-value-parity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1260707343710339072&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1260707343710339072&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When a country imports high-value and know-how intensive goods, it is worth asking &amp;ldquo;what do we provide in return&amp;rdquo;. If the answer is &amp;ldquo;low value goods&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;we export labour&amp;rdquo; or worse of all &amp;ldquo;we go into debt&amp;rdquo;, it is time to reexamine policy. Such imbalances tend to end badly. Both observation and theory support this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Witness the hard times developing world commodity exporters go through periodically, both the coffee and the oil exporters. Advanced nations export the same &lt;em&gt;kind of goods&lt;/em&gt; they import with other advanced nations - Japan and Germany. Global trade needs principles of balance and symmetry. Balance is the short term notion &amp;ldquo;we won&amp;rsquo;t go into debt&amp;rdquo;.+++(5)+++ Symmetry is the longer term notion of &amp;ldquo;similarity of capabilities&amp;rdquo;.+++(5)+++ Both are important for harmony among nations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Trade deficit effects</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/US-trade-deficit-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/US-trade-deficit-effects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1461122633198542848&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1461122633198542848&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The US imports $1 trillion more than it exports and &amp;ldquo;pays&amp;rdquo; for that with debt. At the same time, there are massive labor shortages. This is telling us the labor is not allocated correctly, a huge structural distortion in the economy.+++(5)+++ This issue is also relevant for India.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you import so much more than you export, jobs essentially become &amp;ldquo;token distribution jobs&amp;rdquo; - the actual work is not relevant and the purpose of the job is to allocate tokens to claim the imported goods. People figure that out, hence the &amp;ldquo;bullshit job&amp;rdquo; phenomenon. The longer you run this system, the more serious the erosion in real productive capability because if you don&amp;rsquo;t use the skills, you lose them. The US has suffered a serious erosion in capability. That appears to be accelerating now along with the trade deficit.+++(5)+++&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USA-inflation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/usa-inflation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/svembu/usa-inflation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/svembu/status/1637625235355897856&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Commenting on &lt;a href=&#34;../../alden-lyn/usa-inflation/&#34;&gt;Lyn Alden inflation metrics&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In America, housing, medical care and education have all been going up in price faster than CPI inflation for 20+ years. Those are 3 big categories of spending. This reflects a real erosion in living standards and economists have not even acknowledged there is a problem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The models academic macro economists use to describe the world do not have much to do with reality. As a perfect textbook illustration(!), Paul Krugman writes that Silicon Valley Bank episode is an isolated one just as a global banking crisis erupts, leading to a panicked Fed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
