<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chinese policy of kushANas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/MT/2005-11-26_chinese-policy-of-kushanas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/MT/2005-11-26_chinese-policy-of-kushanas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/11/26/chinese-policy-of-kushanas/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Under the Kushanas, unlike in the days of later Indian rulers, the Indians followed an active policy of supporting the central Asian oasis civilization in the Tarim region. This forward policy was adopted by Vima Taktu, furthered by Vima Khadphises and Kanishka. The most important victory was that of Kanishka in central Asia was against the Chinese, when he came to the aid of the Tarim chiefs, who had been severely oppressed by the Chinese warriors like Pan Cha’o. Having routed them, he brought four Chinese princes as hostages to India and detained them in fort near what is now Amritsar. The village interestingly bears the name Chiniyari, as a distant echo of the long past days. These Chinas are supposed to have introduced the pear to India. This is one of the few defeats of the China army at the hands of the Indians that even the chronicle of Huan Tsang records. Kanishka to convey his international status to all concerned adopted 4 titles simultaneously: mahArajAdhiraja (Emperor of India), Kaisara (for the romans), Kshatriya-tama (for the Persians), and deva-putra (for the Chinese). So firmly was Sogdiana, brought under the Indian sphere of influence that the Chinas referred to it as utto-lo-pa-do: uttarApatha or the northern frontier of India. Of course Kanishka’s entry in to Central Asia, other that its economic benefits, resulted in a tremendous injection of sanskrit literature into China many of whose original were lost in India. This process to a certain extant actually improved Sino-Indian relations and facilitated technological exchange between the then superpowers: the Parthian empire, India and China. Kanishka’s domain stretched from the Tarim regions to Central India. His southern capital was Mathura where some statues of his vandalized by the Moslems can still be found. From a Hindu standpoint the Kushana regime was critical for the rise of Kaumarism in India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indic names</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/MT/indic-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/MT/indic-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Commenting on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.asor.org/anetoday/2021/07/contacts-cuneiform-cultures-india&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are some issues that article raises that need further thought. For example, the so called Indians in Babylon have clearly Iranic names. baga-ina is part of a large number of theophorous names associated with the cult of the Indo-Iranian god bhaga: baga-dAta; baga-denu; baga-mithra (probably devatA dvandva with Iranic mithra, one such is son of mithra-dAta); baga-vIra; baga-pAna; baga-pAda to list some from hAkamAnashiya Iranic document. This suggests that there was an active cult of baga (c.f. bhaga-sUkta of vasiShTha on our side of the divide). The baga-ina in the said document is the son of a certain zimaka. The z initial again strongly indicates his Iranic identity. Hence, these so called hindu-s of Babylon were in all likelihood eastern Iranians from the Indo-Iranian borderlands rathern than Indians proper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kansihka religion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/MT/kanishka-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/MT/kanishka-religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;kaniShka&amp;rsquo;s own Rabatak inscription is plainly suffused with his religious identity. He is a worshipper of  the goddesses nAnA ~ Iranic: aredvi shUrA AnahitA; goddess ummA = umA; ahura mazdha, muzhduwan= Iranic rudra; sraosha, mithra. He also indicates the identity of sraosha with kumAra &amp;amp; vishAkha &amp;ndash; evidently for this Indian subjects.  Thus we can see he was a votary of the non-Zoroastrian Iranic religion with Hindu elements. Thus, calling him H is not far from the mark.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>khwarizmi on Kama river</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/MT/khwarizmi_on_kama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/MT/khwarizmi_on_kama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rattibha.com/thread/1514115042349834241?lang=en&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inner Eurasia ~ 565-580 CE: The most remarkable is that little-known culture in the Kama river region. Far up north several silver bowls have been found that contain images of the goddess durgA-nAnA with at least one having an Eastern Iranian inscription. Who were they? One of the durgA-nAnA images on a bowl from Bartym in the Kama region. Was a high north Iranic outpost? (&amp;ldquo;Koryakova says it was Sarmatians.&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steppe vs sedentary</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/MT/steppe-sedentary-tension/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/MT/steppe-sedentary-tension/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we look at our own early tradition we see that even after &amp;ldquo;settling&amp;rdquo; in India, the Arya-s were not comfortable with large-scale urbanity &amp;ndash; this is reflected even in the rAmAyaNa &amp;amp; mahAbhArata &amp;ndash; eventually the Arya-s of India came around to go urban. I think the evidence is strongly in favor of the Iranics as a group being even less inclined to total urbanity. The nature of their &amp;ldquo;post-invasion&amp;rdquo; domain retained the straddling of the steppe-land on 1 side and West Asian urbanity on the other. It does seem that even the foundation of their first major empire &amp;ndash; the hAkamAnashiya, was based on a steppe military core &amp;ndash; the kuru-kamboja &amp;ndash; which was likely related to the eponymous military core that led to the Arya unified empire in India that is remembered in the late veda &amp;amp; emulated subsequently by the pANDu-s of the mahAbhArata.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Western scholarship critique</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/MT/western-scholarship-critique/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/iranic/articles/MT/western-scholarship-critique/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Unfortunately, even these more unified accounts there are lacunae: This one tries to place Rome &amp;amp; Iran in proper balance. Other western works engage in Chinese boosterism (a successor sentiment of Galtono-Needhamism). Like the author here says the chIna-s might have been a comparably rich state as Rome &amp;amp; Iran. However, the chIna-s overlapping with quite a bit of that period were fragmented and defeated by steppe powers. The real powers of note were the Eastern Iranic empire of the kuShANa followed by Indian gupta. One of the notable Sassanian shAh-s was even married to an Indian princess. Clearly, in purely economic terms, the Indian gupta empire was probably on top. What has not been written is placing the Hindu empire of the age in the world setting with the Iranic, Roman and steppe ones. samudragupta&amp;rsquo;s conquest of the Sassanian clients and emergence of the greater H domain is something that you would never find written by a mlechCha author &amp;ndash; perhaps reflective of the fact that a dead civilization is a safe thing. A living one clearly incompatible with your own is not.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the western accounts there is a tendency to treat Rome in a unitary manner. However, we hold that 2 empires should be distinguished. The Roman empire proper &amp;amp; the Xtian empire that conquered the former from within &amp;ndash; complexion of the wars in Augustan period with the Parthians &amp;amp; the post-preta wars with Sassan&amp;rsquo;s broad were ideologically different.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
