<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1 THE WAY THINGS WERE on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1 THE WAY THINGS WERE on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 A COUNTRY OF SAVAGES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/01_A_COUNTRY_OF_SAVAGES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/01_A_COUNTRY_OF_SAVAGES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;savages&#34;&gt;Savages&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Il y aurait de bons courriers à faire de France et de pays que nous croyons connus; l&amp;rsquo;étrange n&amp;rsquo;est pas toujours au pays étranger; on ferait d&amp;rsquo;immenses découvertes chez soi; on obtiendrait de singuliers résultats si l&amp;rsquo;on savait regarder le pays habituel d&amp;rsquo;un regard inhabitué; regarder la France comme si on n&amp;rsquo;en était pas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CHARLES PÉGUY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;YOU DON&amp;rsquo;T NEED to go to America to see savages,&amp;rdquo; mused a Parisian as he strolled through the Burgundian countryside of the 1840&amp;rsquo;s. &amp;ldquo;Here are the Redskins of Fenimore Cooper.&amp;rdquo; Thus Balzac, in his Paysans (1844). Indeed, there is a great deal of evidence to suggest that vast parts of nineteenthcentury France were inhabited by savages. Louis Chevalier has told us how this label was pinned on the urban poor-classe laborieuse, classe dangereuse -around mid-century. But it can as readily be applied, and for a longer period of time, to sections of the rural population-equally strange and little known, equally hard-working though perhaps less dangerous for being less concentrated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 THE MAD BELIEFS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/02_THE_MAD_BELIEFS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/02_THE_MAD_BELIEFS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a Superstition in avoiding Superstition.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-FRANCIS BACON&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;DO NOT BELIEVE in witches,&amp;rdquo; warned a widely used elementary textbook of 1895. &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; People who say they can steal or work harm by muttering certain words, those who claim to know the future, are madmen or thieves. Do not believe in ghosts, in specters, in spirits, in phantoms&amp;hellip;. Do not imagine one can avoid harm or accidents with&amp;hellip; amulets, talismans, fetishes, such as&amp;hellip; herbs gathered on St. John&amp;rsquo;s Eve.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 THE KING&#39;S FOOT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/03_THE_KINGS_FOOT/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/03_THE_KINGS_FOOT/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The invention of a barbarous age, to set off wretched matter with lame meter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-JOHN MILTON&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IN THE mid-nineteenth century one Charles Gille wrote a carpenter&amp;rsquo;s song, &amp;ldquo;My Plane,&amp;rdquo; whose last verse alluded to the metric system that the Revolution had introduced:1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Challenging routine and hatred, Taking its stand on useful things, The measure of the Republic&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Has overthrown the foot of kings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Actually kings proved easier to overthrow than the measures associated with them. A law of 1837 had made the metric system the only legal measure of the land, effective January 1, 1840. But its fate, like that of the franc germinal introduced in 1803, remained uncertain for several generations. Public archives and private transactions alike bear witness that ancient measures survived and thrived into the twentieth century, above all in the poorest and most isolated areas, where life and work were slow to enter the broader national market.2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 ALONE WITH ONE&#39;S FELLOWS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/04_ALONE_WITH_ONES_FELLOWS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/04_ALONE_WITH_ONES_FELLOWS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;C&amp;rsquo;est donc à bon droit que les Anciens tenaient l&amp;rsquo;étranger à distance. C&amp;rsquo;est celui qui a d&amp;rsquo;autres mocurs, et dont on ne peut savoir ce qu&amp;rsquo;il va faire.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-BERTRAND DE JOUVENEL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AT THE END of the eighteenth century, when the intendant of Gascony wanted to have roads constructed so as to connect the area with neighboring provinces, the people of Auch, bourgeois and common folk alike, protested: &amp;ldquo;We have all we need to live well. Our neighbors will come to take what they lack, and we have no need of what they can offer us.&amp;rdquo; This sort of attitude lasted through much of the nineteenth century. But not all of it. As a country doctor observed shortly before the First World War, &amp;ldquo;a profound moral evolution&amp;rsquo; had taken place over the past 25 years: &amp;ldquo;The race [was] becoming separated from this land it loved so much.&amp;ldquo;1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 FROM JUSTICE, LORD, DELIVER US!</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/05_FROM_JUSTICE_LORD_DELIVER_US/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/05_FROM_JUSTICE_LORD_DELIVER_US/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;La jhustic&amp;rsquo;, moun amit, é coum&amp;rsquo; les arentèles: O prend reinq&amp;rsquo; les mussets, le tuon peurc&amp;rsquo; la toèle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SAINTONGE PROVERB&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ONE SOLID REASON for the peasant&amp;rsquo;s abiding suspicion of all comers lay in the devastating intrusions of the alien law and its representatives into his world. Adolphe Blanqui, very far from a radical, called lawmen the true scourge of rural populations. The rural populations evidently agreed. In the Limousin the farmer&amp;rsquo;s evening prayers would long include the tag line &amp;ldquo;Deliver us from all evil and from justice.&amp;rdquo; The same formula survived in Charente into the 1930&amp;rsquo;s: &amp;ldquo;My God, deliver us from all ill and from justice!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 A WEALTH OF TONGUES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/06_A_WEALTH_OF_TONGUES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/06_A_WEALTH_OF_TONGUES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Parlez français,&amp;rdquo; says the master to the pupil. &amp;ldquo;Monsieur, je parle comme je save et comme je poude.&amp;rdquo; The villager forgets a little of his mother tongue at school, and learns only a parody of French.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-ABBÉ M. M. GORSE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IN 1863, ACCORDING to official figures, 8,381 of France&amp;rsquo;s 37,510 communes spoke no French: about a quarter of the country&amp;rsquo;s population. The Ministry of Public Instruction found that 448,328 of the 4,018,427 schoolchildren (ages seven to thirteen) spoke no French at all, and that another 1,490,269 spoke or understood it but could not write it, suggesting an indifferent grasp of the tongue. In 24 of the country&amp;rsquo;s 89 departments, more than half the communes did not speak French, and in six others a significant proportion of the communes were in the same position (see Map 3). In short, French was a foreign language for a substantial number of Frenchmen, including almost half the children who would reach adulthood in the last quarter of the century.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 FRANCE, ONE AND INDIVISIBLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/07_FRANCE_ONE_AND_INDIVISIBLE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/07_FRANCE_ONE_AND_INDIVISIBLE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Le grand précepte qu&amp;rsquo;il faut donner aux historiens, c&amp;rsquo;est de distinguer au lieu de confondre; car, à moins d&amp;rsquo;être varié, l&amp;rsquo;on n&amp;rsquo;est point vrai. Mais malheureusement les esprits médiocres ont le goût de l&amp;rsquo;uniformité.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AUGUSTIN THIERRY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WHEN DID FRANCE become one? Surely we know that. Forty kings worked hard at the task, but it was the Revolution that finished the work in the end: abolished local particularisms, perfected a national unity stronger and more compact than any other nation ever knew. By 1808, as Hippolyte Taine asserted in his preface to The Origins of the Revolution in France, &amp;ldquo;all of France&amp;rsquo;s traits&amp;rdquo; were &amp;ldquo;set and definitive.&amp;rdquo; This is pretty much what the schoolbooks of the Third Republic taught: one people, one country, one government, one nation, one fatherland. This is what historical studies expounded and still expound, an axiom most recently repeated by Albert Soboul: &amp;ldquo;The French Revolution completed the nation which became one and indivisible.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 THE WORKING OF THE LAND</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/08_THE_WORKING_OF_THE_LAND/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/08_THE_WORKING_OF_THE_LAND/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Il ne faut pas regretter les choses, même les plus jolies, quand un peu de misère et de fatigue humaine disparaît avec elles. RENÉ BAZIN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;popu-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ALL THROUGH THE nineteenth century and into the first decades of the twentieth the rural and agricultural populations were a majority in France. On that everyone agrees. But the figures vary depending on how such populations are defined. The data most often cited are also the least enlightening. Official definition classes as urban any locality with 2,000 or more inhabitants, and on this standard, estimates that in 1851 three-quarters of the French lation lived in rural areas, that by 1901 the proportion of rural to urban inhabitants had shifted to about 3 to 2, and that between 1921 and 1929 the urban population gained a slight edge over the rural.1 The difficulty, of course, is that some localities with fewer than 2,000 inhabitants were essentially small towns, and some with more than 2,000 remained largely rural. A bourg of Provence or Languedoc, for example, would have had more urban characteristics than a bourg of the same size in Lorraine. For this reason, such figures are useful only in indicating and to some extent charting a general trend.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 GIVE US THIS DAY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/09_GIVE_US_THIS_DAY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/09_GIVE_US_THIS_DAY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ce n&amp;rsquo;est pas le malheur, c&amp;rsquo;est le bonheur qui est contre nature. La condition naturelle d&amp;rsquo;un homme comme d&amp;rsquo;un animal c&amp;rsquo;est d&amp;rsquo;être assommé ou de mourir de faim.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HIPPOLYTE TAINE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;AS FA! mandja ta ma, garda l&amp;rsquo;aoutro per dema!&amp;rdquo; Many&amp;rsquo;s the snuffling child or the pinched adult who must have heard it: &amp;ldquo;You are hungry! Eat your hand, keep the other for tomorrow!&amp;rdquo; We have already seen how hunger had its place at the peasant&amp;rsquo;s board well into the nineteenth century. To pass from&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 FROM &#39;SUBSISTANCE&#39; TO &#39;HABITAT&#39;</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/10_FROM_SUBSISTANCE_TO_HABITAT/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/10_FROM_SUBSISTANCE_TO_HABITAT/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh happy, if he knew his happy State!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Swain, who, free from Business and Debate; Receives his easy Food from Nature&amp;rsquo;s Hand, And just Returns of cultivated Land!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unvex&amp;rsquo;d with Quarrel, undisturb&amp;rsquo;d with Noise, The Country King his peaceful Realm enjoys.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-VIRGIL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AT THE TIME of the French Revolution the great socioeconomic issue had been subsistance-how to feed the poor. By the 1840&amp;rsquo;s, however, the focus of interest had begun to shift to habitat, their miserable quarters. Physical misery still flourished on all fronts, but with the food problem near solution, priorities could be readjusted in terms of relative need.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 THE FAMILY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/11_THE_FAMILY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/french/articles/weber-peasants_1900/1_WAY_THINGS_WERE/11_THE_FAMILY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;marriage&#34;&gt;Marriage&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Marie-toi, ne te marie pas,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Pour sur, tu t&amp;rsquo;en repentiras.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Will you marry, yea or nay?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;You&amp;rsquo;ll regret it either way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;family-primacy&#34;&gt;Family primacy&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MARRIAGE WAS ONE of the great social occasions of traditional French society, a vast feast, with as many as 500 guests, for all of them one of the rare breaks in a routine of hard and weary work and frequent privation. But marriage was not just an occasion for socializing, for reaffirming bonds of friendship, kinship, and social obligation. It was an alliance that concerned far more than two individuals-two clans and the whole of the society they lived in were affected by their arrangements.+++(4)+++&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
