<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/dattakAngIrasAH/hAritaH/rAmAnujaH/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/dattakAngIrasAH/hAritaH/rAmAnujaH/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AyI-jananyAchArya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/dattakAngIrasAH/hAritaH/rAmAnujaH/articles/AyI-jananyAchArya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/dattakAngIrasAH/hAritaH/rAmAnujaH/articles/AyI-jananyAchArya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ayee Jananyacharya or Devaraja Perumal (1341–1445 CE) was a Hindu Sri Vaishnava religious leader, great saint, and one of the important propagator of the Sri Vaishnavism tradition. Sri Jananyacharya Swami was Seventh in the lineage of Sri Ramanujacharya. He was a scholar in ubhaya vedanta who took Vishishtadvaita school of vedanta to the next level and widely popularized and propagated the Sri Vaishnava tradition.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;birth-and-early-life&#34;&gt;Birth and early life&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ayee Jananyacharya Swamy was born in 1341 at Melukote in Karnataka to Asuri Lakshmanacharya in the month of Tula Karthika and belongs to the lineage of Harita gotra. As per few hagiographies, the life period is placed as 1341–1445 CE thereby yielding a lifespan of almost 105 years. Ayee swamy got his sacred thread ceremony and pancha samskaram at a very early age and started his education of Veda, vedanga and Divya Prabhandam from his father.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>govindAchArya-granthaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/dattakAngIrasAH/hAritaH/rAmAnujaH/articles/govindAchArya-granthaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/dattakAngIrasAH/hAritaH/rAmAnujaH/articles/govindAchArya-granthaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[4]] This is an edited version of the original work by “Alkondaville Govindacharya” which was first published in 1906. We thank all the JET Volunteers who have contributed and helped in the Editing process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ramanujacharya.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/the_life_of_ramanujacharya.pdf&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[1]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;0&#34;&gt;0&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[2]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;chinna-jeeyar-message&#34;&gt;Chinna Jeeyar message&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Message from HH Sri Chinna Jeeyar Swamiji! “If my act of revealing the Manthra, redeems the whole world, from the horrendous clutches of karma, and for that Infernal Hell will be the result, I have absolutely no objection to go to that Hell” Who else can show such a convivial concern other than Acharya Ramanuja? Nearly a thousand years ago, a savior, a marvelous philosopher- saint appeared on this Earth, announcing to this world, the advent of a scintillating era in the world of philosophy and spirituality. His vibrant philosophy “tri-une Monism”, Visishtadwaitham, raised curtain for ushering an era of social, as well as, philosophic revolution. Bhagavad Ramanuja was instrumental for the revival, growth, amplification and vivification of “Visishtadwaitha school of thought” which had been in existence from time immemorial. Humanity all over the globe, barring religion, caste, creed, territory etc. should be indebted to this ‘great savior’ whose philosophy penetrated and enlightened millions and millions of Truth Seekers Bhagavad Ramanuja, was the beloved son of the couple Sri Asuri Keswava Yajvi &amp;amp; Kanthimathi. He sanctified this Earth with his appearance, in Sri Perumbudur, near Chennai in the state of Tamil Nadu, during 1017 AD. Being a precocious and brilliant child, he gave out beautiful and true explanations to the Vedic texts even as a lad. His studies were profound and his thinking was deep. He turned out to be a great learner under the tutelage of several Acharyas. In the process of learning, he suffered several privations and indignities and he withstood them all with a burning zeal for studies and reverence to his preceptors. In fulfilment of untold 3 wishes and mandate of his great grand guru Sri Yamunacharya, another equally illustrious savant, Sri Ramanuja spread the concept of Visishtadwaitham, dynamically far and wide,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rAmAnuja-darshana-bio</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/dattakAngIrasAH/hAritaH/rAmAnujaH/articles/rAmAnuja-darshana-bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/dattakAngIrasAH/hAritaH/rAmAnujaH/articles/rAmAnuja-darshana-bio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;mAmunigaL states in upadesha raththina mAlai that our sath sampradhAyam is named as emperumAnAr dharisanam (rAmAnuja dharsanam) by SrI ranganAthan himself so that everyone will forever remember the contributions of emperumAnAr towards this eternal sampradhAyam. SrI rAmAnuja was neither the founder of this sath sampradhAyam nor the only AchArya of this sampradhAyam. But he anchored the sampradhAyam so firmly that it will remain afloat forever which is why he is greatly glorified. If attempted, one can some how try to comprehend and speak the glories of emperumAn. But emperumAnAr’s glories are so limitless that, it is difficult for any one to fully comprehend and speak about them too. But we are blessed to have his sambandham through our glorious guru paramparai and with that strength let us enjoy emperumAnAr’s glories, little by little.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sources</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/dattakAngIrasAH/hAritaH/rAmAnujaH/articles/sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/dattakAngIrasAH/hAritaH/rAmAnujaH/articles/sources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://hinduism.stackexchange.com/questions/33201/complete-biography-hagiography-of-ramanujacharya&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t a single comprehensive work outlining the complete biography of Sri Ramanuja. These are some of the more well known somewhat older works that describe his life:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yatiraja Vaibhavam of Vaduga Nambi, a student of Sri Ramanuja is a biographical poem in 114 Sanskrit verses. You can read an English translation here. This is the oldest known biography.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The 6000-padi Guruparampara Prabhavam of Pinbazagiya Perumal Jiyar is a Manipravala Biography of the Srivaishnava Guru Parampara. The Tengalai tradition subscribes to this version of events. It is supposed to be written in the 14th century but there is a doubt as to the period of the author as some portions of later texts appear verbatim in it. It is the earliest extant (in print) elaborate discussion of Ramanuja&amp;rsquo;s life. You can can read it here: Tamil script&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The 3000-padi Guruparampara Prabhavam of the 3rd Brahmatantra Svatantra Svami is a Manipravala Biography of the Srivaishnava Guru Parampara. The Vadagalai tradition subscribes to this version of events. It was written in the late 15th/ early 16th centuries. The author says that the first Brahmatantra Svatantra Svami wrote a biography in 12000 verses that was abridged by the second Svami in 6000 verses that was further abridged to the present form. You can read it here: Tamil script, Telugu script&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prapannamritam of Anantacharya. Sanskrit version here. It has been observed to be almost a literal translation of the 6000-padi GPP. It is considered to be written in the second half of the 17th century.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Divyasuri Caritam of Garudavahana Pandita. This is a Sanskrit poem biography of the Sri Vaishnava Guru Parampara from the Azvars through Ramanuja. It is unclear if the author is the same Garudavahana Pandita who was a contemporary of Ramanuja or not. There is a verse in it that suggests that it was written when Ramanuja was still alive but modern historians opine that it is written in the 15th or 16th centuries. You can read the Sanskrit text and Hindi translation &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/Divyasuri-Charitam-Garudavahana-Pandita/page/n3&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Koil Olugu - A Tamil chronicle of the Srirangam Temple shines some light on Ramnuja&amp;rsquo;s influence. It was fully translated to English. You can read an abridged English translation &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/Divyasuri-Charitam-Garudavahana-Pandita/page/n3&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yatiraja Saptati of Vedanta Desika is a poem praising Ramanuja in Sanskrit. It shines some light on certain aspects of Ramanuja&amp;rsquo;s life. You can read and English translation here -&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Periya Tirumudi Adaivu - supposed to be written by Kandadai Nayan of the 15th century is clearly a later work as it details the life of people known to have lived a century after the author died.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ramanujarya Divya Charithai - Don&amp;rsquo;t know much about it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Besides these, there are several English biographies of Ramanuja that sample bits and pieces from these above texts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>गद्य-त्रय-यदुगिरि-प्रस्तावात्</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/dattakAngIrasAH/hAritaH/rAmAnujaH/articles/gadya-traya-yadugiri-prastAvAt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/dattakAngIrasAH/hAritaH/rAmAnujaH/articles/gadya-traya-yadugiri-prastAvAt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;जनम&#34;&gt;जन्म&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;एते च भाष्यकाराः भगवद्रामानुजाचार्याः&lt;br&gt;&#xA;तमिल्नाडु-प्रान्तीये श्रीमति भूत-पुरी-नाम्न्य् अग्रहारे कृतावताराः ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;lsquo;श्रीपेरुम्बुदूर्&amp;rsquo; इति द्राविडभाषानाम ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;क्रिस्ताब्दः १०१७ तः, ११३७ पर्यन्तः एषां जीवितकालः&lt;br&gt;&#xA;इति गुरुपरम्परा-वैभवाद् अवगम्यते ।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;चैत्रा(मेषा)र्द्रासम्भवं, विष्णोः&lt;br&gt;&#xA;दर्शन-स्थापनोत्सुकम् ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;तुण्डीरमण्डले शेष-&lt;br&gt;&#xA;मूर्तिं रामानुजं भजे&amp;rsquo; ॥&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;इति च जन्मादि-विषयकः श्लोकः ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;आदिशेषावतार-रूपा एते हारीत-गोत्र-लब्ध-जन्मानः ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;तात-पादा एतेषां केशव-सोमयाजि-नामानः ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;प्रख्यातं वंश-नामापि आसूरीति ।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;एतेषां मातृ-भावेन पुण्यवती कान्तिमती-नाम्नी ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;भूदेवीत्य् अपि +एनां जनाः व्यवहरन्ति स्म ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;एषा शठमर्षण-गोत्रसम्भवस्य श्रीमन्-नाथ-मुनि-वंश्यस्य श्रीशैल-पूर्णाख्यस्य गुरोः सोदरी ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;तद्वंशीयाः &amp;lsquo;ताताचार्य&amp;rsquo;-सञ्ज्ञया लोके व्यवह्रियमाणाः विलसन्ति ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;अभिजन-माता-पितृ-वर्णन-परोऽयं श्लोकः&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
