<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;१० on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/10/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;१० on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New wave</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/10/2006-10-23_new-wave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/10/2006-10-23_new-wave/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/10/23/new-wave/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The jAnashruteya birds flew by and said: “The spider has run around the&#xA;web twice since that fateful night of the 3-front war. 2 bow-shots away&#xA;from your seat you saw the deadly one. It was the same place where your&#xA;then senAnI immersed in sorrow narrated his defeat against the vaiShNava&#xA;on the Northern plain. The kR^ityA-s were kept aside from reaching you&#xA;by the eye of mitra and varuNa. Now the kAla of vR^itra has begun. The&#xA;front called kosha could be weakened. You thought your defenses were&#xA;firm, but you are not seeing the agent of dhUmAvatI in your midst!”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Of the past</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/10/2006-10-20_of-the-past/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/10/2006-10-20_of-the-past/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/10/20/of-the-past/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was relatively late when we were sort of startled by R’s call. She&#xA;said we had a visitor from really ancient times- Igul. One forgets most&#xA;males, at such a distance in time, but then some women are much harder&#xA;to forget (the male brain seems to be wired so). I must be careful of&#xA;what I say here for yudhiShThira cursed women that they will not keep&#xA;their mouth shut. Anyhow I do not want to make it private as we do want&#xA;to our pakSha and the jAnashruteya pakShI-s to see it. Anyhow, we say so&#xA;little of the rest. We had great fun picking on R for calling us “native&#xA;Indians”, a term she can never give up. Our collective memories somehow&#xA;wandered to that day when there was a certain competition in school&#xA;where R was defending the varNa system. Igul was supposed to be her&#xA;partner but she was clueless of everything and after all the debate was&#xA;supposed to be about the evils of varNa. But now as all of us grow old&#xA;and are no longer the youths we were the pratikriya changes one’s&#xA;perspectives. Igul we were pleased to note was consciously Hindu than&#xA;ever before. Igul wondered, why me and R tend to yarn so much about the&#xA;past — school and college days as though neither of us ever grew up to&#xA;be adults (in some cases even parents). This view of our juvenile freeze&#xA;is shared with Igul by strI, but our one other friend yarns like us&#xA;endlessly on these days. I realized something really remarkably&#xA;paradoxical at that point.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Igul: School and college were great nice days, a faint nice blur to be&#xA;forgotten now.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;strI: Same&lt;br&gt;&#xA;R: They were bad days but should be talked about endlessly.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Marc: Same&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Me: Same&lt;br&gt;&#xA;amAvasu: same&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The said women diagnosed us as suffering from a disease “juvenile&#xA;freezure”…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The encounter with the pAShaNDa-s of the nAstIka mata</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/10/2006-10-05_the-encounter-with-the-pashanda-s-of-the-nastika-mata/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2006/10/2006-10-05_the-encounter-with-the-pashanda-s-of-the-nastika-mata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/10/05/the-encounter-with-the-pashanda-s-of-the-nastika-mata/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the due assent I decided to narrate the account of&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://manollasa.blogspot.com/2006/07/some-notes-of-shatsahasra-tradition.html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;‘s&#xA;father encounter with the vile pAShaNDa-s of the nAstIka mata- this is&#xA;an illustrative example of some technicalities for the complete&#xA;uchChATana of paShaNDa mantras. The other learned vR^iddhA had also&#xA;demolished the prayoga-s of such a pAShaNDa from the vanga country. The&#xA;old R1F had journeyed deep into the were the practitioners of the fallen&#xA;ways of mahAchInAchAra and upachInAchAra still wandered. In their midst&#xA;he saw their mantra-s that are are thefts from savants the first varNa&#xA;or gifts from patita-sAvitra-s of the bygone eras. Over the ages these&#xA;chInAchAryas and other pAShaNDa-s who practice their vile para-tantras&#xA;have mellowed down as though due to the delusion of nArAyaNa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
