<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;The Hindu-Muslim Problem (1924) on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;The Hindu-Muslim Problem (1924) on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>84 UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/01part/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/01part/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*&lt;a href=&#34;txt_lajpatrai_1924.html&#34;&gt;THE HINDU-MUSLIM PROBLEM (1924)&lt;/a&gt;*&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Lala Lajpat Rai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART 1 &amp;ndash; [The Hindu-Muslim problem is the problem of India]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[A]&lt;/strong&gt; THE HINDU-MUSLIM PROBLEM is the problem of India. We have&#xA;heard and read much of Hindu-Muslim unity. It is always a matter of&#xA;controversy between the Anglo-Indian [=British person in India] and&#xA;the Nationalist. The former asserts, and the latter denies, the&#xA;impossibility of Hindus and Muslims uniting together to form one nation.&#xA;The amount of unity or disunity existing at a particular moment is also&#xA;always an issue. Yet it is a fact that from 1919 to the end of 1921&#xA;Hindus and Muslims of India were fairly united. It was during this&#xA;period that for the first time in the history of India a &lt;em&gt;Kafir&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;preached from the pulpit of the biggest and historically the most&#xA;important and the most magnificent mosque of Northern&#xA;India.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#n01&#34;&gt;/1/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; It was during the same period that the &lt;em&gt;Malechhas&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;fraternised with the Hindus on the occasion of their religious&#xA;festivals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>85 UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/02part/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/02part/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*&lt;a href=&#34;txt_lajpatrai_1924.html&#34;&gt;THE HINDU-MUSLIM PROBLEM (1924)&lt;/a&gt;*&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Lala Lajpat Rai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART 2 &amp;ndash; [The Unity Conference and the relativity of rights]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[A]&lt;/strong&gt; In the discussions at tbe Unity Conference held at Delhi, one&#xA;thing struck me very forcibly. That was the fact that so many of the&#xA;ablest and most patriotic Muhammadan young men, as well as a few Hindus,&#xA;were obsessed with the idea of &amp;ldquo;absolute rights.&amp;rdquo; Time after time it was&#xA;said that the Muhammadans had an inherent right to slaughter cows, and&#xA;that that right could only be curtailed by their own voluntary&#xA;sacrifice. It was on the basis of absolute right that draft resolutions&#xA;had actually been prepared by a number of young men who counted among&#xA;them some of the most brilliant and self-sacrificing workers in the&#xA;Congress organization. And yet, as I have pointed out more than once,&#xA;the idea of absolute rights is a fallacious one, and has really no&#xA;foundation in law. Pandit Motilal Nehru, the President, also took pains&#xA;to explain the same point of view. I am not quite sure, however, that&#xA;the explanations were quite satisfactory; and as the idea seems to me to&#xA;be shared by a large number of men, I would like to deal with it at some&#xA;length.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>86 UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/03part/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/03part/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*&lt;a href=&#34;txt_lajpatrai_1924.html&#34;&gt;THE HINDU-MUSLIM PROBLEM (1924)&lt;/a&gt;*&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Lala Lajpat Rai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART 3 &amp;ndash; [Religions must be rationalised as much as possible]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[A]&lt;/strong&gt; All those who aim at creating a United India, should remember&#xA;that India is a land of many faiths and many religions; that these&#xA;faiths and religions, again, are divided into sections and sub-sections;&#xA;that these sections and sub-sections practise numerous religious&#xA;observances ceremonials and rituals; and that some of these rituals and&#xA;observances conflict with one another. It is impossible for any&#xA;Government to guarantee to all these religions, sections, and&#xA;sub­sections, full and complete freedom in the matter of the observance&#xA;of all their rituals and ceremonials, especially when they are in&#xA;conflict with one another. Some of these ceremonials and observances,&#xA;moreover, are inhuman, cruel, and immoral. To insist upon, and to&#xA;emphasise, the right of every community, small or large, to a strict and&#xA;full observance of all their religious rituals and cermonials is,&#xA;therefore, a clear impossibility, besides being directly opposed to the&#xA;idea of a United India. The British Government, in spite of its&#xA;professions of religious neutrality, have, from time to time, interfered&#xA;in the matter of religious practices; for example, they stopped by&#xA;legislation the inhuman practices of &lt;em&gt;Sati&lt;/em&gt; and infanticide which Hindu&#xA;orthodoxy contended was a part of its religion.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#n07&#34;&gt;/7/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>87 UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/04part/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/04part/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*&lt;a href=&#34;txt_lajpatrai_1924.html&#34;&gt;THE HINDU-MUSLIM PROBLEM (1924)&lt;/a&gt;*&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Lala Lajpat Rai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART 4 &amp;ndash; [Narrow sectarianism holds us back from obtaining Swaraj]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[A]&lt;/strong&gt; The observations made in the last article raise several&#xA;cognate questions, which may profitably be discussed before we come to&#xA;the political and economic aspects of the problem. Are the Hindu and&#xA;Muhammadan religions and cultures so fundamentally different, or to be&#xA;more exact, so antagonistic, as to make their followers naturally and&#xA;instinctively hostile to each other? If so, what chances are there of&#xA;our being able to bring about a unity between the two? It is said that&#xA;Hinduism is not a dogma, that it is almost impossible to define it, that&#xA;it is a system of life of which caste is an essential feature; and that&#xA;as long as caste is there, it is impossible to make it sufficiently&#xA;tolerant and progressive, so as to make unity and co-operation with&#xA;other religious communities either easy or even possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>88 UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/05part/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/05part/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*&lt;a href=&#34;txt_lajpatrai_1924.html&#34;&gt;THE HINDU-MUSLIM PROBLEM (1924)&lt;/a&gt;*&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Lala Lajpat Rai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART 5 &amp;ndash; [&amp;ldquo;Untouchables&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Kafirs&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[A]&lt;/strong&gt; The considerations urged in the last article are so important&#xA;.and relevant that I will not apologise for laying further emphasis upon&#xA;them. Every possible effort should be made (a) to integrate the&#xA;different religions as much as possible by emphasizing the points&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;[[189]]&lt;/strong&gt; on which they agree, by eliminating non-essentials, and&#xA;by restricting essential differences within the narrowest limits; (b) to&#xA;remove all barriers to free social intercourse between the communities,&#xA;which do not go to the root of anyone&amp;rsquo;s faith.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>89 UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/06part/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/06part/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*&lt;a href=&#34;txt_lajpatrai_1924.html&#34;&gt;THE HINDU-MUSLIM PROBLEM (1924)&lt;/a&gt;*&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Lala Lajpat Rai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART 6 &amp;ndash; [The history of communal representation]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[A]&lt;/strong&gt; In this article I propose to trace the history of the&#xA;evolution of the idea of Communal Representation and separate communal&#xA;interests. It was in the seventies of the 19th century that the movement&#xA;for the establishment of the M. A. O. College at Aligarh &lt;strong&gt;[[193]]&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;was started, and it was about the same time that the Arya Samaj was&#xA;founded. The idea of a united India was present to the minds of the&#xA;founders of both when they met at Delhi on the occasion of the Imperial&#xA;Durbar of 1877. But they soon found out that it was impossible to unite&#xA;India on the basis of a common faith. The Indian National Congress had&#xA;not then come into existence, and the idea at back of Sir Syed&amp;rsquo;s mind&#xA;was to found an institution which would enable Indian Muhammadans to&#xA;make up for lost time in the acquisition of that Western knowledge which&#xA;was, in his eyes, [a] &lt;em&gt;sine qua non&lt;/em&gt; of worldly prosperity both under&#xA;the Government and otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>90 UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/07part/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/07part/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*&lt;a href=&#34;txt_lajpatrai_1924.html&#34;&gt;THE HINDU-MUSLIM PROBLEM (1924)&lt;/a&gt;*&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Lala Lajpat Rai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART 7 &amp;ndash; [From Sir Syed Ahmed Khan to Iqbal]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[A]&lt;/strong&gt; Sir Syed Ahmed Khan was unquestionably a great man. He was&#xA;highminded, unselfish, and devoted to the interests of his community. He&#xA;lived and died for it. His political creed consisted of three articles:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(a) Non-interference in the affairs of outside Muslim states.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(b) Concentration of all efforts on the betterment of the Muslims&#39;&#xA;condition at home, and&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(c) Alliance with the British Government.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>91 UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/08part/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/08part/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*&lt;a href=&#34;txt_lajpatrai_1924.html&#34;&gt;THE HINDU-MUSLIM PROBLEM (1924)&lt;/a&gt;*&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Lala Lajpat Rai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART 8 &amp;ndash; [Pan-Islamism and its bankruptcy]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[A]&lt;/strong&gt; Add to this the &lt;em&gt;Fatwa&lt;/em&gt; of the Ulemas that India being a&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Dar­ul-Harab&amp;rdquo; (a place of war), every good Muslim ought to leave it and&#xA;migrate to a Muslim country. We know by this time how the &lt;em&gt;Hijrat&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;movement ended; how much money was wasted over it and how much misery&#xA;was wrought thereby. The best commentary on it was witnessed by me at&#xA;Constantinople.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#n17&#34;&gt;/17/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; On the third or fourth day of my stay&#xA;there, I met two young Indian Muslims walking in the street. They&#xA;accosted me first. When I asked them how they fared in Constantinople,&#xA;one of them burst out almost in tears and said that if he ever returned&#xA;to India, he would give out a bit of his mind to tell his Muslim&#xA;countrymen how mischievous was the teaching that India was&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Dar-ul-Harab&amp;rdquo; (a place of war) and how false the idea that the whole&#xA;world was the home of the Muslims. That boy was one of the Mahajarins of&#xA;1921. He had travelled all over Muslim Asia from Afghanistan through&#xA;Turkistan to Russia, and then back to Angora and Constantinople. His&#xA;experience was so bitter, and his condition was so pitiable, that he&#xA;denounced Pan-Islamism in rather strong terms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>92 UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/09part/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/09part/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*&lt;a href=&#34;txt_lajpatrai_1924.html&#34;&gt;THE HINDU-MUSLIM PROBLEM (1924)&lt;/a&gt;*&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Lala Lajpat Rai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART 9 &amp;ndash; [Hindu revivalism and other communalist trends]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[A]&lt;/strong&gt; What I have said about Pan-Islamism and the excess of&#xA;communalism among the Mussalmans, should not be understood to imply that&#xA;Hindus on their side have been quite inactive and innocent. One thing,&#xA;of course, is patent. Hindus cannot be anything but Indians. They have&#xA;no other country and no other nation to look to. They cannot, therefore,&#xA;be accused of any kind of Pan­Hinduism, in the sense in which the term&#xA;is used in relation to Islam. Hinduism and Indianism are, in their case,&#xA;synonymous terms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>93 UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/10part/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/10part/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*&lt;a href=&#34;txt_lajpatrai_1924.html&#34;&gt;THE HINDU-MUSLIM PROBLEM (1924)&lt;/a&gt;*&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Lala Lajpat Rai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART 10 &amp;ndash; [The Shuddhi, Sanghathan, and Tanzim movements]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[A]&lt;/strong&gt; The aggressive Hinduism preached by the Arya Samaj was not&#xA;political in its conception. That it has been strengthened by political&#xA;considerations cannot, however, be denied.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[B]&lt;/strong&gt; This is an appropriate place for examining the origin and&#xA;bearings of the &lt;em&gt;Shuddhi&lt;/em&gt; movement of which we have heard so much of&#xA;late. The movement is as old as the Arya Samaj or even the Sikh&#xA;religion. The Arya Samaj claims that the religion preached by it is&#xA;universal religion, and aims at bringing the whole world under its&#xA;banner. In this respect its claims are as ambitious and wide as those of&#xA;Christianity and Islam. There was a time when the more orthodox section&#xA;of the Arya Samaj used to proclaim from the housetops that they were&#xA;non-Hindus; and that they were free to eat and drink and marry with&#xA;non-Hindus; and that even Hindus should undergo a certain amount of&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Shuddhi&lt;/em&gt; before they could be admitted into the Arya Samaj.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>94 UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/11part/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/11part/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*&lt;a href=&#34;txt_lajpatrai_1924.html&#34;&gt;THE HINDU-MUSLIM PROBLEM (1924)&lt;/a&gt;*&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Lala Lajpat Rai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART 11 &amp;ndash; [Some suggestions for political improvements]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[A]&lt;/strong&gt; I have so far touched [on] the past history of Hindu-Muslim&#xA;relations and given a picture of how matters stand at present. I will&#xA;now offer a few observations on how the present situation can be&#xA;improved, in the political field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[B]&lt;/strong&gt; It is suggested on behalf of Muslim leaders that–&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(a) Communal representation with separate electorates in all the&#xA;legislatures, local bodies, Universities, and other official or&#xA;semi-official bodies should be provided.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>95 UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/12part/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/12part/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*&lt;a href=&#34;txt_lajpatrai_1924.html&#34;&gt;THE HINDU-MUSLIM PROBLEM (1924)&lt;/a&gt;*&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Lala Lajpat Rai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART 12 &amp;ndash; [A summary of my conclusions and advice]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[A]&lt;/strong&gt; In the last article I observed that Mian Fazl-i-Husain&#xA;embodied, in his person, a real grievance. But a grievance against whom?&#xA;Certainly not against the Hindu community. If the Hindus occupy a larger&#xA;number of posts under the Government than they would be entitled to on a&#xA;purely numerical basis, they are not to be blamed for it. The Muslim&#xA;community ought to recognise that the fault is principally their own.&#xA;They did not take sufficient advantage of &lt;strong&gt;[[215]]&lt;/strong&gt; the&#xA;educational facilities provided by the Government in the early days of&#xA;the British rule, and it is that fact which is responsible for the&#xA;present condition of things. For the last fifty years the Government&#xA;have been giving them special facilities for making up for lost time,&#xA;with the gratifying result that they are now in a position to hold their&#xA;own against every other community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>96 UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/13part/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/lAjpat-rAi/hindu_muslim_problem_1924/13part/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*&lt;a href=&#34;txt_lajpatrai_1924.html&#34;&gt;THE HINDU-MUSLIM PROBLEM (1924)&lt;/a&gt;*&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Lala Lajpat Rai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART 13 &amp;ndash; [A plea for mutual co-operation]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[A]&lt;/strong&gt; No Indian who loves his country can look upon the prevailing&#xA;state of things except with the most excrutiating pain and anguish.&#xA;There are men in the public life of the country, who have given their&#xA;all in the hope that before they die they may see the Goddess of Liberty&#xA;ruling over their beloved native land. They have put up with all kinds&#xA;of humiliations, sufferings, and losses, and sacrificed every comfort&#xA;and convenience, and even neglected their children for &lt;strong&gt;[[219]]&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;the sake of this, the one single object of their life. Absorbed in this&#xA;their one passion, they have treated with supreme contempt all kinds of&#xA;calumnies, libels, and slanders, that have been heaped on their devoted&#xA;heads by the foreign rulers of the land, and also by some among their&#xA;own countrymen. They have seen their juniors rise over their heads to&#xA;the highest offices under the State and to the most alluring positions&#xA;in life. They have suffered insults and rebukes at the hands of men who&#xA;were not leven worthy of unloosening the strings of their shoes. They&#xA;have been followed like criminals, imprisoned and banished like common&#xA;felons, but have never lost hope.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
