<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;xatra v2 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;xatra v2 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>kali-age presence</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/kali-age-presence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/kali-age-presence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See theory page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;support&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;It would appear that &lt;strong&gt;Gāgābhaṭṭa&lt;/strong&gt; accepted the first argument about the seed-presence of the Kṣatriyas in the Kali age, and tried to remedy their loss of dharma with purificatory vrātya-stoma rite. &amp;hellip; The opinion of Nārāyaṇabhaṭṭa&amp;rsquo;s Dharmapravr̥tti is echoed verbatim by &lt;strong&gt;Anantadeva&lt;/strong&gt; in his Samskāra-kaustubha (pp. 114-115, litho graphic edition, Bombay, 1861). Anantadeva was a close associate of Gāgābhaṭṭa in making decisions regarding the CKPs and Kṣatriyas. &amp;hellip; It seems quite clear that Gāgābhaṭṭa was no modern reformist, out to abolish the caste system, in the image of Jotiba Phule or B.R. Ambedkar. The dispute was not over the legitimacy of the caste system as such, but about whether the traditional Dharmaśāstra could be tweaked to find just enough space to recognize a de facto Rājā as a legitimate Kṣatriya.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;A counter argument supporting the expiatory rights to purify the impure Kṣatriyas is offered in the text of Vrātyatā-śuddhi-saṅgraha produced by the &lt;strong&gt;pandits at the court of Jayasiṁha&lt;/strong&gt; in Rajasthan.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;disagreement&#34;&gt;Disagreement&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The most extensive argumentation against admitting the presence of pure Kṣatriyas in the Kali age, and the ineligibility of the impure Kṣatriya to purify themselves by undergoing an expiatory rite is offered in two nirṇaya texts that are attributed to &lt;strong&gt;Nāgeśabhaṭṭa&lt;/strong&gt;: Vrātyatā-prāyascitta-nirṇaya (in Mahā- and Laghu- versions).&amp;rdquo; He says: &amp;ldquo;From the birth of Pariksit to the coronation of Nanda, these were the first fifteen hundred years of the Kali age, and there were genuine Kṣatriyas on earth only for this duration. On the basis of this statement in the ViṣṇuPurāṇa, the absence of genuine Kṣatriyas, worthy of Upanayana, in the rest of the Kali age is indicated.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;A convenient summary of the main arguments is provided by the editor of these texts, &lt;strong&gt;NārāyaṇaśāstrI Khiste&lt;/strong&gt;, in his preface&amp;hellip; He claims that those pandits who were dependent upon Jayasiṁha for their livelihood produced the Vrātyatāśuddhisaṅgraha, having forgotten the true intent of the ancient Smrtis under the influence of wealth. On the other hand, wealth did not mean anything to Nāgeśabhaṭṭa, whose sole concern was to protect the proper domain of the śāstras, and he produced the Vrātyatāprāyascittanirṇaya, following solely the path of the śāstras, and disregarding the pressure from Jayasiṁha. &amp;ldquo;This is what we have heard from the older generations of Banaras.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; Nārāyaṇaśāstri Khiste&amp;rsquo;s statements in the preface show us how Nāgeśabhaṭṭa&amp;rsquo;s views were considered authoritative by the Maharashtrian Brahmins of Banaras, even after more than a century.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vaidyanatha Pāyagunde (1690-1780AD)&lt;/strong&gt; in his Chāyā on Nāgeśabhaṭṭa&amp;rsquo;s Uddyota on Kaiyata&amp;rsquo;s Pradipa on Patañjali&amp;rsquo;s Mahābhāsya commenting on &amp;ldquo;brāhmanena niskārano dharmah sadango vedo &amp;lsquo;dhyeyo jheyas ca&amp;rdquo; says that in fact there are no Kṣatriyas and Vaisyas in the Kali age, and to suggest this Patanjali says that (only) Brahmins should study the Veda (vastutas tu kalau Kṣatriya-vaisyayor abhāvaṁ sūcayitum tathoktam iti yathāsrutam eva tat sādhu).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;P.V. Kane (1975: 971) cites &lt;strong&gt;Bālambhaṭṭa&lt;/strong&gt; on the views of his father, Vaidyanitha, on the question of Kṣatriyas in the Kali age: tathā ugrādi-rūpa-Kṣatriya-sattve &amp;lsquo;pi- tesām na Kṣatriyatvam kim tu śūdratvam eveti guru-caraṇa-kr̥ta-vrātya-prāyascitta-nirṇaye spaṣṭam / tata eva bodhyam / sphuṭīkrtam caitat pitr-caranaih kāyastha-nirṇaye.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Pandit Nīlakaṇṭha Shastri Thatte (1750-1834AD)&lt;/strong&gt; of the late Peshwa and early British period in Maharashtra opposed it. He was a great grammarian, who is said to have studied with the great grammarian Vaidyanātha Pāyagunde (1690-1780AD), who was himself a direct disciple of the illustrious grammarian Nāgeśabhaṭṭa (1650- 1730AD), a junior contemporary of the great Gāgābhaṭṭa.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kerala case</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/kerala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/kerala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the place of kShatriya-s, for example, we had Samanta Kshatriya-s in keraLa ( &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samantha_Kshatriya&#34;&gt;W&lt;/a&gt;, ie. shUdra-s who function like kShatriya-s for most practical, if not ceremonial, purposes ).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In traditional texts and treatises on Kerala such as the Kerala Mahatmayam and Keralolpathi the nair rulers are referred to as &amp;ldquo;sAmanta kShatriyas&amp;rdquo; (Kshatriyas only in function, not jAti). This was because swaroopams/royal families had political and social power but were Kshatriya only in profession and were not recognized as Kshatriya within the Vedic tradition per se.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The first ascension of these Nairs to Kshatriya status was begun by the Kolathiri Raja, Udayavarman, who wished to wear the Yajnopaveetham (Poonool or sacred thread) and become an officially recognized Kshatriya. Since the Nambudiris were not prepared, Udayavarman brought 237 families (Saagara Brahmins) of Illams from Gokarnam in 1617 AD (792 ME) and settled them in five Desams, Cheruthazham, Kunniriyam, Arathil, Kulappuram and Vararuchimangalam of Perinchelloor Graamam.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Raja of Cochin, who was elevated to the Suryavanshi clan of the Kshatriya caste by the Namboothiri openly insulted the Zamorin, who belonged to the Eradi subdivision of Samantan Nair caste, calling him a cowherd. Zamorin tried to elevate himself to the Samanta Kshatriya status by performing the Hiranyagarbha Yagna, but fierce opposition by his opponents (Most notable of whom were the Maharaja of Cochin) forced the Namboothiris of Malabar to abandon the plan. Instead the Zamorin, who was an ordinary Nair was elevated to the Samantan Nair caste by performing the Padmagarbha Yagna.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Raja of Travancore, however used to perform an extraordinary ceremony known as Hiranyagarbha. The essential feature of this ceremony was the casting of a hollow golden vessel through which the Raja passed. On emerging from the vessel, the Raja&amp;rsquo;s caste status rose from Samanthan Nair to Samanta Kshatriya. Unfortunately for the royal family, the Samanta Kshatriya status so acquired was not hereditary, and thus the ceremony had to be performed for each new Raja. The Samanta Kshatriya and Samanthan Nair subdivision were minute. For example, In Travancore in 1931, the Samanta Kshatriya population was 3,673 (0.07% of the total population), and the Samanthan NairSamanta Kshatriya population was recorded as less than 0.1% of the total population; for 1921, the Samanthan Nair population was given as 4,663 (0.15%). - &lt;a href=&#34;http://malayalakshatriya.blogspot.com/2011/10/nair-sub-castes.html#sthash.Ti4qrMe4.dpuf&#34;&gt;MK&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>North East</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/ne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/ne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;J. Johnstone has revealed the historical truth that towards the middle of the 18th century a Hindu revivalist movement took place in the East of India. The conversion to Hinduism on the Eastern Frontier from Sadiya down to Chittagong was daily taking place. To quote him “A man belonging to Hill tribes, if the Raja chose at any time, received the sacred thread of twice born castes, and on payment of small sum of money was admitted as a Hindu and was thenceforth called Khetree (probably a corruption of Khatri). This privilege was not accorded to Mussulmans. I once asked a Manipuri why they received hill-men and not Mussalman, both being Mlecchas according to Hindu theory, he said it was because the hill-men had sinned in ignorance whereas Musulmans knew the evil of their ways.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Provenance</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/provenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/provenance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Before the muslim invasion, the kShatriya varNa was widespread - even in south India.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;vIra ballALa the hoysala, famously told malik kafur that he is willing to give up everything except his sacred thread.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;chulavamsha clearly describes the buddhist sinhalese king parAkrama bAhu of lanka undergoing upanayanam (&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2012/05/30/some-inquiries-into-the-shrilankan-past/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=RvuDlhpvvHwC&amp;amp;pg=PA37&amp;amp;lpg=PA37&amp;amp;dq=parakramabahu+upanayana&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=b1ZnfUhpYj&amp;amp;sig=qrqioDBgT8uwLOa0r3fSlLdGNfk&amp;amp;hl=sa&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0CB0Q6AEwAGoVChMIwOD90rn5xgIViTOICh1PkwWv#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=parakramabahu%20upanayana&amp;amp;f=false&#34;&gt;GB&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the kadamba-s of karNATaka were famously brAhmaNa-s converted to kShatriya-s.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Many dynasties of India, including south Indian ones such as chAlukya, pANDya and choLa kings conducted vedic yAga-s allowed for kShatriya-s such as rAjasUya and ashvamedha.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some images, supposedly of these kings, show a yajJNOpavIta (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.frontline.in/static/html/fl2819/stories/20110923281908400.htm&#34;&gt;NVP_F&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/Fk8LeLT.jpg&#34;&gt;IMG&lt;/a&gt;), while others don&amp;rsquo;t (simhaviShNu-pallava &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/OJZIvJ8.jpg&#34;&gt;IMG&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/IHak7fl.jpg&#34;&gt;IMG2&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is quite possible that the vijayanagara kings were not invested with the yajnopavIta - they&amp;rsquo;re not known to have performed the vedic sacrifices. (This despite their great scholarship in sanskrit, patronage of temples etc..)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Names ending with &amp;ldquo;varma&amp;rdquo; try to claim ceremonial (not just de-facto) kShatriya status - that suffix is prescribed by the dharmashAstra-s for kShatriya-s. mArtANDa-varma, narasimhavarma pallava etc..&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shivaji</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/shivAji/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/shivAji/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The CKP dispute at Shivāji&amp;rsquo;s court appears to have arisen before the dispute regarding Shivāji&amp;rsquo;s own eligibility for royal coronation.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;It was Balāji Avaji Chitnis,[4] a CKP, who assisted Shivāji&amp;rsquo;s search for his Rajput Kṣatriya roots by sending investigators to the north (cf. Shejwalkar 1964: 477; Sriśivadigvijaya, pp. 249 ff.), and, according to the Chitnis-Bakhar, it was Balāji Avaji who suggested to Shivāji that he invite Gāgābhaṭṭa in connection with the coronation. .. In the CKP documents, including the Citnis Bakhar, the role of Bālājī āvaji is somewhat exaggerated. It is not clear how much convincing Gāgābhaṭṭa needed from Bālāji Avaji.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Sabhāsad Bakhar attributes the initiative regarding coronation to Gāgābhaṭṭa himself.  If the date of the śyēnavi-jāti-dharma-nirṇaya of 1664 AD is valid, then Shivāji was already in touch with Gāgābhaṭṭa in such Dharmaśāstric matters. &amp;hellip; According to Sabhāsad (pp. 78) Gāgābhaṭṭa said that in his opinion, the Muslim kings sat on their throne and ruled with a royal umbrella. Shivāji on the other hand, who had defeated four sultans, had seventy-five thousand troops and had forts, had no throne. He stated that the Maratha Raja should become a Chattrapati &amp;ldquo;holder of the umbrella.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;bhaṭ gosāvī yāmce mateṁ, musalmān pādsahā takti basavūn, chatra dharūn, pātasāhī karitāt, āni sivājīrāje yāṁṇīṁhi cār pātaśāhī dabāvilyā āni pāūn lākh ghoḍā laṣkar gaḍ koṭ aseṁ asatām, tyāms takta nāhim̐. yākaritām marhāṭhā rājā chatrapati vhāvā aseṁ cittāṁt āṇileṁ.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;From the time of Shivāji to Pratapasiṁha of Satara, the constant effort of the Maratha lineages was to establish their ancestry from the Rajput lineages of Rajasthan, and this was assumed to be a sufficient proof of Kṣatriyahood.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;gagabhattas-decision&#34;&gt;GagabhaTTa&amp;rsquo;s decision&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;From his preamble to the śyēnavi-jāti-dharma-nirṇaya, composed ten years before Shivāji&amp;rsquo;s coronation in 1674AD, it is clear that Gāgābhaṭṭa accepts Shivāji&amp;rsquo;s father Shahāji as someone born in a pure royal family [vimala-rāja-kula], and he glorifies Shivāji&amp;rsquo;s achievements against the Mughals of Delhi, and addresses him as Shivāji-Rājā. While this does not touch the Dharmaśāstric question, it shows Gāgābhaṭṭa&amp;rsquo;s acceptance of Shivāji both as a person born in a &amp;ldquo;pure royal family&amp;rdquo; and as a de facto Rājā &amp;ldquo;king&amp;rdquo;, ten years before the question of his eligibility for the consecration ceremony was raised.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Given his own Dharmaśāstric views (regarding whether a shUdra king can be served), Gāgābhaṭṭa was most likely as anxious about having Shivāji properly consecrated, as Shivāji himself may have been about his own consecration. &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;While none of the texts composed by Gāgābhaṭṭa that are available to us explicitly discuss the issues involved in how he decided the question of Shivāji&amp;rsquo;s authentic Kṣatriyahood, the surviving text of the Rājyābhiśeka-paddhati &amp;ldquo;Procedure for the Royal Consecration&amp;rdquo; composed by Gāgābhaṭṭa on the occasion of Shivāji&amp;rsquo;s royal consecration includes Vedic mantras, and hence one must conclude that by the time of the actual royal consecration, Shivāji was deemed to be completely eligible to be treated as a full Kṣatriya. While the text of the Rājyābhiśekapaddhati does not tell us that Gāgābhaṭṭa made Shivāji to undergo a purificatory rite, the received reports from other sources do indicate this purificatory rite, and the fact that Shivāji underwent the ceremony of Upanayana, and then his queens were dharmically remarried to him.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;later-disputes&#34;&gt;Later disputes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The anti-CKP document dating to Sake 1671 (1749 ad) openly criticizes Gāgābhaṭṭa and says that his decision on performing upanayana for Shivāji was a mistake, and it calls it amārga: pahile veda-śāstra-sampanna kailāsa-vāsī gāgābhaṭṭayāmni kṣetrīśarmāms adhikāra rājyās vr̥tabandha karūn, gāitrī-upadesa karūn sthāpile. te karma siddhīs gele nāhi - donahī vaṁśāne nirmūla jāhāle. he pratyaksa jānūn āmārgāne vartalyās sādhya śrīkr̥pā nāhi. (P.N. Patwardhan 1912: 96) &amp;ldquo;This statement from the Brahmins of the Peshwa period claims that Gāgābhaṭṭa was mistaken in treating Shivāji as a Kṣatriya and offering upanayana to him with the teaching of the Vedic Gāyatri mantra, and that the non dharmic coronation eventually resulted in both the branches of Shivāji&amp;rsquo;s line drying up without (non-adopted) descendants.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gupte (1919: 99) reports that the Brahmins of Maharashtra had excomunicated Gāgābhaṭṭa for approving the Kṣatriya status of Shivāji.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;In opposition to Gāgābhaṭṭas opinion, Nānā Phadnavis, the Kārbhāri of the Peshwas allowed only a Paurānika Upanayana for the king of Satara (Gupte, 1919: 95-96).&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;maratha-gramanya-s-of-1800s&#34;&gt;marATha grAmaNya-s of 1800s&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Gramaṇya between the Brahmins and the Marathas evolved out of the Prabhu Gramaṇya of 1826. The brahmins were not ready to accept the Chhatrapati of Satara and other maratha families as Kshatriyas. According to the brahmins, Parshuram eradicated the Kshatriyas twenty-one times and there fore no Kshatriyas were left on earth. So the present Marathas were Kunbis and not the Kshatriyas.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The jagirdars of Satara in their letters addressed to Pratapsinha only as Chhatrapati and not Kshatriya Kulwantansa as we find in the original title of the founder of the Maratha power—Shivāji. We do find a reference in the Rojnishi of Raja Pratapsinha that he refused to reply to Chintamanrao Patwardhan of Sangli as he did not address him as Kshatriya Kulwantansa.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;This dispute, briefly outlined here, resulted into a full blown dispute in subsequent times and spread to Kolhapur, Baroda, and Pune, and under the general title of &amp;ldquo;Vedokta Dispute,&amp;rdquo; this conflict between the Brahmins and the Kshatriyas has been richly documented by Copland (1973), Wagle (1987), O&amp;rsquo;Hanlon (1983 and 1985) and Pawar (1985). &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
