<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Fogel - china &amp; japan on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Fogel - china &amp; japan on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>“Shanghai-Japan”: The Japanese Residents’ Association of Shanghai</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Shanghai-Japan_The_Japanese_Residents_Association_of_Shanghai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Shanghai-Japan_The_Japanese_Residents_Association_of_Shanghai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At noon on December 3, 1937, a Japanese military parade—perhaps in ironic imitation of other processions by foreigners in Shanghai—began marching down Nanjing Road through the foreign concessions in Shanghai and along the Bund. In the lead was a military police (kenpeitai) car escorted by mounted troops bearing sabres at the hilt. They were followed by a large infantry detach-ment, machine-gunners, and finally by artillerymen. Japanese aircraft flew by overhead, and Japanese civilians lined the route along the way and shouted out choruses of banzai.  When they arrived at Jessfield Park, they were met by a contingent of Italian ladies—allies in the anti-Comintern pact—waving Japanese flags. The event lasted until 3 p.m. and involved all 6000 Japanese troops stationed in the city. The next day a smaller contingent of troops marched in orderly fashion from Garden Bridge south to the Bund and through the concessions ( Tokyo asahi shinbun, December 4, 1937, and December 5, 1937; cited in Muramatsu 1991, 308–9). Lest there be any doubt about it, this was clearly intended as a victory march, an effort to demonstrate the new reality of Japan’s preeminence in Shanghai. However much this display may have been directed at the Chinese, with whom Japan had now been at war for five months, the Western residents of the concessions—with whom the resident Japanese had been at loggerheads for many years—were the primary targets. No such event ever took place in any of the other centers of Japanese residence in China, only in Shanghai, where all the Western powers were present in full force.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>00</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/00/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/00/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;document-outline&#34;&gt;Document Outline&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Contents&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Introduction: My Route into Asian Studies&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Art History and Sino-Japanese Relations&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Miyazaki Tōten and the 1911 Revolution&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;New Thoughts on an Old Controversy: Shina as a Toponym for China&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Gold Seal of 57 CE and the Afterlife of an Inanimate Object&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Japanese Views of China in Historical Perspective&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Translator’s Preface to Books and Boats (Ōba Osamu)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Recent Boom in Shanghai Studies&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chinggis on the Japanese Mind&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A Decisive Turning Point in Sino-Japanese Relations: The Senzaimaru Voyage to Shanghai of 1862&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lust for Still Life: Chinese Painters in Japan and Japanese Painters in China in the 1860s and 1870s&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Nanking Atrocity and Chinese Historical Memory&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prostitutes and Painters&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On Translating Shiba Ryōtarō into English&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tackling the Translation of an Invaluable Primary Source that No One Person Would Dare Face Alone&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Introduction: Liang Qichao and Japan&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Response to Herbert P. Bix, “Remembering the Nanking Massacre”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Naitō Konan and Naitō’s Historiography: A Reconsideration in the Early Twenty-First Century&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Japanese Travelers to Shanghai in the 1860s&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An Important Japanese Source for Chinese Business History&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chinese Understanding of the Japanese Language from Ming to Qing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;“Shanghai-Japan”: The Japanese Residents’ Association of Shanghai&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Introduction: Masuda Wataru and the Study of Modern China&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Japanese and the Jews: A Comparative Analysis of Their Communities in Harbin, 1898–1930&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Controversy over Iris Chang’s Rape of Nanking&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Nanjing Massacre in History&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Integrating into Chinese Society: A Comparison of the Japanese Communities of Shanghai and Harbin&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Other Japanese Community: Leftwing Japanese Activities in Wartime Shanghai&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Akutagawa Ryūnosuke and China&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Confucian Pilgrim: Uno Tetsuto’s Travels in China&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Japanese Travelers in Wartime China&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nationalism, the Rise of the Vernacular, and the Conceptualization of Modernization in East Asian Comparative Perspective&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Recent Translation Theory and Linguistic Borrowing in the Modern Sino-Chinese Cultural Context&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Japanese Literary Travelers in Prewar China&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Japanese Approaches to the Cultural Revolution: A Review of Kokubun Ryōsei’s Survey of the Literature&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Debates over the Asiatic Mode of Production in Soviet Russia, China, and Japan&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Introduction: Itō Takeo and the Research Work of the South Manchurian Railway Company&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A New Direction in Japanese Sinology&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the “Rediscovery” of the Chinese Past: Cui Shu and Related Cases&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Index&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;**Introduction: My Route into Asian Studies **1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Decisive Turning Point in Sino-Japanese Relations: The Senzaimaru Voyage to Shanghai of 1862</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/A_Decisive_Turning_Point_in_Sino-Japanese_Relations_The_Senzaimaru_Voyage_to_Shanghai_of_1862/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/A_Decisive_Turning_Point_in_Sino-Japanese_Relations_The_Senzaimaru_Voyage_to_Shanghai_of_1862/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Western scholarship on East Asia has taken note of the Japanese group voyage to the United States in 1860, most prominently in Masao Miyoshi’s study of that mission, to officially ratify the treaty imposed upon their country by Townsend Harris (1804–78) and the government of the United States.1 Considerably less well known are the Japanese missions to Shanghai of 1862 and 1864, both domestically inspired and both frank admissions in their respective forms that there was a brave new world out there confronting Japan, that Commodore Perry (1794–1863), Townsend Harris, and the United States were only the beginning of an imperialist onslaught, and that as a result Japan had to take a more activist role in its own future by going out to examine the outside world. The future belonged to international trade and diplomacy, and, in a metaphor of a few years later, Japan could join the table at dinner or be served up with the main course.2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Direction in Japanese Sinology</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/A_New_Direction_in_Japanese_Sinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/A_New_Direction_in_Japanese_Sinology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chūgoku shitaifu kaikyū to chiiki shakai to no kankei ni tsuite no sōgōteki&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;kenkyū&lt;/strong&gt; 中国士大夫階級と地域社会との関係についての総合的研究&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[ Studies on the Relationship Between the Literati Class and Local Society in China], Tanigawa Michio 谷川道雄, ed. Kyoto: Kyoto University Press, 1983.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Historical materialism has dominated postwar Japanese historiography on China, but its great influence is now crumbling or, rather, in the process of being overcome. The noble postwar task of rescuing China from theorists of stagnation by giving her a history, making her historical development resemble that of any European country or Japan, and thus bringing her into the course of world history foundered ultimately when more facts proved exceptions than regularities to the “basic laws of world history.” One could point to traits in Chinese society over time which indicated developmental stages in modes of production. The next step of claiming thereby the unity of the universality of world history with the particularity of the Chinese experience proved considerably more problematic. The distinctiveness of Chinese society could never simply be generated by the “mode of production.” For example, large-scale land management (as a mode of production) and a despotic state structure did coexist in time but should not have, for theory dictated that small peasant management accompany the despotic state.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Important Japanese Source for Chinese Business History</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/An_Important_Japanese_Source_for_Chinese_Business_History/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/An_Important_Japanese_Source_for_Chinese_Business_History/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the course of recent research on the early history of the Japanese community of Shanghai, I came across a source of prospective interest to anyone concerned with Chinese business history in the nineteenth century. It was a monthly publication entitled Shanhai shōgyō zappō (Shanghai commercial reports), published in Shanghai by the “Shanhai shōdōkai” (Shanghai commercial association) between July 1882 and October 1883. Initially it appeared monthly, with the last few issues coming less frequently. Little is known about the publishing group or about the editor, Oka Masayasu, who was also the sec-retary of the “Shanhai shōdōkai.” Offices were first listed at Number 7 Jiangxi Road in the British Concession but soon moved to the grounds of the Mitsui Bussan Company at Number 11 Sichuan Road. This was, significantly, the first serial published by the Japanese community of Shanghai.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Art History and Sino-Japanese Relations</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Art_History_and_Sino-Japanese_Relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Art_History_and_Sino-Japanese_Relations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the reforms put in place by Deng Xiaoping (1904–97) and the opening up of China, the first cinematic Sino-Japanese joint venture was a movie entitled &lt;em&gt;The Go-Masters&lt;/em&gt; (1982).1 It covers in sweeping, colossal fashion several decades in the lives a Chinese and a Japanese, both renowned &lt;em&gt;go&lt;/em&gt; (Chinese, *weiqi) * masters whose bond forged through a shared passion for this ancient game transcends politics, war, family safety, and just about everything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Understanding of the Japanese Language from Ming to Qing</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Chinese_Understanding_of_the_Japanese_Language_from_Ming_to_Qing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Chinese_Understanding_of_the_Japanese_Language_from_Ming_to_Qing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, there have been four periods in which heightened Chinese interest in Japan has led to the development of scholarship concerning Japan: the late Ming (principally the Jiajing and Wanli eras); roughly the decade between the first Sino-Japanese War (1894–95) and the Russo-Japanese War (1904–05); the 1930s and early 1940s, from the Manchurian Incident until the&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;end of World War Two; and the present, post-Mao era.1 Concerning the first period it has been argued that, while the Ming years witnessed the compilation of hallmark Chinese texts on Japan, in the Qing period, by contrast, there was a decline in Chinese learning about Japan. This essay will examine this phenomenon by focusing on the specific issue of changing Chinese perceptions of the Japanese language from the Ming to the Qing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinggis on the Japanese Mind</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Chinggis_on_the_Japanese_Mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Chinggis_on_the_Japanese_Mind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A specialist on neither Mongolian nor Inner Asian history, my discussion of Chinggis Khan centers on the uses to which his perceived heroic stature was put in late-nineteenth- and early-twentieth-century Japan. I came across the stories that will unfold in this essay twice in the process of other, tangential research. Most recently, I completed the translation of a novel about the life of Chinggis Khan by the great historical novelist Inoue Yasushi 井上靖 (1907–91), entitled *Aoki ōkami * 蒼き狼 (The Blue Wolf), which appeared in 2008 from Columbia University Press. It was made into a blockbuster movie released in&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contents</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Contents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Contents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;**Introduction: My Route into Asian Studies **1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;**1 Art History and Sino-Japanese Relations **4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;**2 Miyazaki Tōten and the 1911 Revolution **14&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 New Thoughts on an Old Controversy: &lt;em&gt;Shina&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;** as a Toponym for** **China **24&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;**4 The Gold Seal of 57 CE and the Afterlife of an Inanimate Object **47&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;**5 Japanese Views of China in Historical Perspective **65&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 Translator’s Preface to &lt;em&gt;Books and Boats&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;** (Ōba Osamu) **77&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Document Outline</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Document_Outline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Document_Outline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Contents&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Introduction: My Route into Asian Studies&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Art History and Sino-Japanese Relations&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Miyazaki Tōten and the 1911 Revolution&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;New Thoughts on an Old Controversy: Shina as a Toponym for China&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Gold Seal of 57 CE and the Afterlife of an Inanimate Object&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Japanese Views of China in Historical Perspective&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Translator’s Preface to Books and Boats (Ōba Osamu)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Recent Boom in Shanghai Studies&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chinggis on the Japanese Mind&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A Decisive Turning Point in Sino-Japanese Relations: The Senzaimaru Voyage to Shanghai of 1862&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lust for Still Life: Chinese Painters in Japan and Japanese Painters in China in the 1860s and 1870s&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Nanking Atrocity and Chinese Historical Memory&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prostitutes and Painters&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On Translating Shiba Ryōtarō into English&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tackling the Translation of an Invaluable Primary Source that No One Person Would Dare Face Alone&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Introduction: Liang Qichao and Japan&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Response to Herbert P. Bix, “Remembering the Nanking Massacre”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Naitō Konan and Naitō’s Historiography: A Reconsideration in the Early Twenty-First Century&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Japanese Travelers to Shanghai in the 1860s&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An Important Japanese Source for Chinese Business History&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chinese Understanding of the Japanese Language from Ming to Qing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;“Shanghai-Japan”: The Japanese Residents’ Association of Shanghai&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Introduction: Masuda Wataru and the Study of Modern China&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Japanese and the Jews: A Comparative Analysis of Their Communities in Harbin, 1898–1930&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Controversy over Iris Chang’s Rape of Nanking&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Nanjing Massacre in History&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Integrating into Chinese Society: A Comparison of the Japanese Communities of Shanghai and Harbin&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Other Japanese Community: Leftwing Japanese Activities in Wartime Shanghai&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Akutagawa Ryūnosuke and China&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Confucian Pilgrim: Uno Tetsuto’s Travels in China&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Japanese Travelers in Wartime China&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nationalism, the Rise of the Vernacular, and the Conceptualization of Modernization in East Asian Comparative Perspective&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Recent Translation Theory and Linguistic Borrowing in the Modern Sino-Chinese Cultural Context&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Japanese Literary Travelers in Prewar China&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Japanese Approaches to the Cultural Revolution: A Review of Kokubun Ryōsei’s Survey of the Literature&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Debates over the Asiatic Mode of Production in Soviet Russia, China, and Japan&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Introduction: Itō Takeo and the Research Work of the South Manchurian Railway Company&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A New Direction in Japanese Sinology&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the “Rediscovery” of the Chinese Past: Cui Shu and Related Cases&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Index&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating into Chinese Society: A Comparison of the Japanese Communities of Shanghai and Harbin</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Integrating_into_Chinese_Society_A_Comparison_of_the_Japanese_Communities_of_Shanghai_and_Harbin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Integrating_into_Chinese_Society_A_Comparison_of_the_Japanese_Communities_of_Shanghai_and_Harbin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries, Japanese began settling in what were to become famous as the two most “international” cities in East Asia, Shanghai and Harbin. The Japanese communities that formed in these multicultural metropolises varied widely as they faced different issues and developed within different contexts. Writing in 1933 and 1934, the renowned journalist Edgar Snow cut through the “internationalist” hyperbole and inadvertently shed light on the question of ethnic integration within Shanghai and Harbin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction: Itō Takeo and the Research Work of the South Manchurian Railway Company</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Introduction_It_Takeo_and_the_Research_Work_of_the_South_Manchurian_Railway_Company/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Introduction_It_Takeo_and_the_Research_Work_of_the_South_Manchurian_Railway_Company/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In November 1906, following the Russo-Japanese War, Japan acquired the South Manchurian Railway (SMR). Gotō Shimpei was named its first president and he immediately made plans for inaugurating a Research Department.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Research” was something Gotō considered utterly essential to colonial management. Tokutomi Sohō once said of Gotō: “Everyone has his own peculiarities. ‘Research’ is something that always hung close to Gotō like a briefcase.”1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Research Department began in April 1907 as a small agency and changed its name many times, at its height, around 1940, encompassing a total of 2,354&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction: Masuda Wataru and the Study of Modern China</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Introduction_Masuda_Wataru_and_the_Study_of_Modern_China/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Introduction_Masuda_Wataru_and_the_Study_of_Modern_China/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Masuda Wataru, the author of the text that follows was born in a small fishing village in Shimane prefecture in 1903, the only son of a medical doctor.1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Excelling at school, he entered Tokyo Imperial University’s Department of Chinese Literature in 1926. It was not a particularly happy time to study there in the immediate aftermath of the Great Kantō Earthquake, and Masuda frequently made use of the Ueno Library at the time. The Faculty of Letters had been completely destroyed, and lectures were often held in makeshift bar-racks or in the operating rooms of the Medical School. He especially recalled enjoying the lectures of Shionoya On on the history of Chinese fiction and Taki Seiichi on East Asian art. He also studied with the great poet Satō Haruo and helped with his translations of Chinese fiction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japanese Approaches to the Cultural Revolution: A Review of Kokubun Ryōsei’s Survey of the Literature</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Japanese_Approaches_to_the_Cultural_Revolution_A_Review_of_Kokubun_Ryseis_Survey_of_the_Literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Japanese_Approaches_to_the_Cultural_Revolution_A_Review_of_Kokubun_Ryseis_Survey_of_the_Literature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What follows is an extended review of an excellent summary of Japanese writings on the Great Proletarian Cultural Revolution in China and the changes in China since the death of Mao Zedong and the purge of the “Gang of Four” in Kokubun Ryōsei’s “The Present State of Japanese Research on the Chinese Cultural Revolution and Problems Areas.”1 Professor Kokubun of Keio University is one of the few genuinely recognizable political scientists of China in Japan. Although still young, he has already amassed an impressive list of publications, including two articles in English. This piece appeared in a Keio University publication.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japanese Literary Travelers in Prewar China</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Japanese_Literary_Travelers_in_Prewar_China/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Japanese_Literary_Travelers_in_Prewar_China/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like the epic, like history, like the novel, the literature of travel has evolved through the centuries. Like them it has existed since the beginnings of oral and written literature. As with them some of its authors have been bad, others have delighted and informed their readers, and many, from the earliest times, have been popular, influential, even brilliant. As with other forms of literature its quantity and nature have varied because of political, religious, economic, and other social and human factors. And like them it includes countless subtypes that continually approach each other, separate, join, overlap, and consistently defy neat classification.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japanese Travelers in Wartime China</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Japanese_Travelers_in_Wartime_China/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Japanese_Travelers_in_Wartime_China/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper grows out of a much longer study of Japanese travel writing about China from 1862, when the first legal voyage set off in over two centuries, through the end of WWII.1 I have collected 500 book-length Japanese travelogues for this period, specifically excluding diaries, most newspaper accounts, and guidebooks. This paper will be a first effort to address those travelogues produced during the war, 1937–45.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are at least two approaches one may take with these 500 accounts: they may be seen as a mass of primary material on China at the time, or they may be used as a mirror of changing Japanese views of China. This essay is most interested in the latter approach and will examine this body of writing as providing mountains of new evidence on the changing nature of Sino-Japanese cultural interactions over a crucial century. Thus, the larger study is of how East meets East.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japanese Views of China in Historical Perspective</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Japanese_Views_of_China_in_Historical_Perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Japanese_Views_of_China_in_Historical_Perspective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have given many talks over the past thirty-five years here at the &lt;em&gt;Jinbun kagaku&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;kenkyūjo&lt;/em&gt; 人文科学研究所 (Research Institute for the Humanities) of Kyoto University and over in the *Bungakubu * 文学部 * *(Faculty of Letters), but never have I had the leisure to do so in English. For that alone I would owe the organizers of this conference, the Australian Centre on China in the World at The Australian National University and our hosts here at Kyoto University, an immense debt of gratitude. But, even beyond that, I want to thank all of the organizers for inviting me to take part in this event. I must say, though, that as a Westerner coming to the Temple of modern Sinology here at Kyoto University and lecturing on that topic bespeaks a little more *chutzpah * הפצוח than even I am usually prepared to utter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lust for Still Life: Chinese Painters in Japan and Japanese Painters in China in the 1860s and 1870s</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Lust_for_Still_Life_Chinese_Painters_in_Japan_and_Japanese_Painters_in_China_in_the_1860s_and_1870s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Lust_for_Still_Life_Chinese_Painters_in_Japan_and_Japanese_Painters_in_China_in_the_1860s_and_1870s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the Edo period (1600–1868), Sino-Japanese cultural contacts were mediated through Nagasaki, to which Chinese ships brought quantities of paintings, books, and everyday objects. Nagasaki was the only city in Japan where foreigners lived; it had a Dutch settlement and a Chinese community, which included a number of important Chinese painters. Japanese artists working in the “Southern School” manner (Nanga), an old tradition rooted in China, frequently traveled to Nagasaki to study with Chinese émigré artists and to learn about China. Only in the early Meiji period (1868–1912)—when Japan opened its doors to the outside world—did Japanese artists begin making the trip to China, at long last able to see the true landscapes of Southern School painting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Miyazaki Tōten and the 1911 Revolution</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Miyazaki_Tten_and_the_1911_Revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Miyazaki_Tten_and_the_1911_Revolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Joshua Fogel, and I teach East Asian history, in particular the history of Sino-Japanese relations, at York University in Toronto, Canada. Let me begin by thanking the organizers of this symposium for inviting me and allowing me to offer some thoughts at this forum. I have another reason to be thankful for this invitation to Fukuoka which I shall mention at the end of my talk today. Many people, especially those living in warm climates like Fukuoka, believe that because Canada is so far north, it is always freezing cold. In the winter, yes, Canada can be very cold, but Canada is a big place—in fact, it’s the second largest country in the world. East of the Rocky Mountains, Toronto has one of the nicer climates—much milder than nearby Buffalo, New York or even Detroit, Michigan. Please come visit us some time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Naitō Konan and Naitō’s Historiography: A Reconsideration in the Early Twenty-First Century</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Nait_Konan_and_Naits_Historiography_A_Reconsideration_in_the_Early_Twenty-First_Century/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Nait_Konan_and_Naits_Historiography_A_Reconsideration_in_the_Early_Twenty-First_Century/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In English the term “Japanese Sinology” might be translated into Chinese as either 日本漢學 or 日本的中國硏究, and it covers as much or even more&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;than the Chinese expressions. It can mean Japanese studies of Chinese history and culture, or Japanese exegeses of the Chinese classics throughout the ages, or in fact any instance in which one examines Japanese approaches to or responses to Chinese civilization from antiquity through the present. My own work has tended to fall within the first category: Japanese studies of Chinese history, and it is to this general subject that I shall address my remarks today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nationalism, the Rise of the Vernacular, and the Conceptualization of Modernization in East Asian</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Nationalism_the_Rise_of_the_Vernacular_and_the_Conceptualization_of_Modernization_in_East_Asian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Nationalism_the_Rise_of_the_Vernacular_and_the_Conceptualization_of_Modernization_in_East_Asian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comparative Perspective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since coming to Santa Barbara, my job description has been “comparative East Asianist,” rather than historian of China or Japan; as a result, I have had to do a great deal of reading in the histories of the other countries in the region.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Among the many things that have struck me in this connection over the past few years are not only how so much of what I initially learned in Chinese history classes has startling resonances with the other major areas influenced by Chinese culture (everybody knows that), but also how remarkably similar was the conceptualization of pressing issues in those countries with China as well as how much less extraordinary China’s historical experience becomes through comparison. The differences as well as the similarities are thrown in a fascinating relief and potentially tell us much about not only high Chinese culture but also the social and economic systems in which it found a home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Thoughts on an Old Controversy: *Shina**** ***as a** **Toponym for China</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/New_Thoughts_on_an_Old_Controversy_Shina_as_a_Toponym_for_China/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/New_Thoughts_on_an_Old_Controversy_Shina_as_a_Toponym_for_China/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zhina dizi wu yanyu&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;支那弟子無言語&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chuan’er huseng xiao diantou 穿耳胡僧笑點頭&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Chinese youngsters stood there speechless, *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*While foreign monks wearing earrings smiled and nodded. *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(From “Ti fan shu” 題梵書** &lt;strong&gt;[inscription to a Sanskrit work], a poem by Tang Emperor Xuanzong 玄宗&lt;/strong&gt;, ** r. 712–756, describing young Chinese looking at a piece of writing in Sanskrit).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do toponyms provide an index of the position a nation, state, or country occupies on the evolutionary scale? Scanning the world in which we now live, we can see that only a relatively small number of states have more than one name (aside from official vs. popular names), usually the result—as in the case of “China” vs. Taiwan or the two “Koreas” (although England, Great Britain, Albion, etc. would be an obvious exception)—of a heightened or strained political consciousness. By the same token, the only places such concerns are obviously operative are at the United Nations and the Olympics, and in official state documents. Journalists, writers, ordinary citizens, and others usually could not care less—usually.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the “Rediscovery” of the Chinese Past: Cui Shu and Related Cases</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/On_the_Rediscovery_of_the_Chinese_Past_Cui_Shu_and_Related_Cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/On_the_Rediscovery_of_the_Chinese_Past_Cui_Shu_and_Related_Cases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is meant by the “rediscovery” of some old text, ancient heritage, or person from another era? A whole range of differing circumstances surrounds each of the various entities that we include under this rubric. For instance, the rediscovery par excellence was Dunhuang, where for centuries texts had been preserved in a cave in Gansu Province, apparently without a soul ever having seen them. A less perfect although still exemplary case involved the works of Wang Fuzhi (1619–1692), the brilliant protonationalist and anti-Manchu her-mit from Hunan, whose writings were supposedly unknown for 150 years until Zeng Guofan (1811–1872) sponsored their republication. Wang’s works were not totally unknown during the eighteenth and early nineteenth centuries; in fact, from the research of Chinese scholars in the late 1950s and early 1960s, we know that more than a handful of Chinese scholars saw Wang’s writings in manuscript form and commented on them in their own essays throughout this lengthy hiatus. As one eminent sinologist explained to me, “It took a big shot like Zeng Guofan to sponsor the publication of so sensitive a writer as Wang.”1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prostitutes and Painters Early Japanese Migrants to Shanghai</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Prostitutes_and_Painters_Early_Japanese_Migrants_to_Shanghai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Prostitutes_and_Painters_Early_Japanese_Migrants_to_Shanghai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That the Chinese port of Shanghai was opened by British gunboats in the Opium War (1839–42) is so well known now that it scarcely requires mention.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It has recently been brought once again to the big screen in Xie Jin’s panoramic 1997 movie Yapian zhanzheng (Opium War). That inglorious history aside, it would be two decades following the Treaty of Nanjing (1842) before the first Japanese made the trip to Shanghai in 1862, not counting the handful of fascinating cases of earlier shipwreck victims whose unfortunate peregrinations landed them in Shanghai for shorter or longer periods of time.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Translation Theory and Linguistic Borrowing in the Modern Sino-Chinese Cultural</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Recent_Translation_Theory_and_Linguistic_Borrowing_in_the_Modern_Sino-Chinese_Cultural/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Recent_Translation_Theory_and_Linguistic_Borrowing_in_the_Modern_Sino-Chinese_Cultural/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Context&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fascinating developments in the new field of translation studies may help us advance our understanding of the evolving vocabulary of the Chinese Revolution in the twentieth century. Indeed, there has been an unconscious theoretical convergence between translation studies outside the China field and modern Chinese cultural history. The key concept is “culture” writ large in both cases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Translation theory has been virtually unknown in China until recent times.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is not that the Chinese historically have never been forced to confront the issue; on the whole, however, until the later decades of the nineteenth century, most of those who came to China were prepared to communicate in Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Response to Herbert P Bix, “Remembering the Nanking Massacre”</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Response_to_Herbert_P_Bix_Remembering_the_Nanking_Massacre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Response_to_Herbert_P_Bix_Remembering_the_Nanking_Massacre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have just read Herbert Bix’s long and thoughtful Japan Focus review essay of a new contribution to the recent spate of books and articles concerned with the Nanjing Massacre (also known as the Nanjing Atrocity or Incident). I found much food for thought there and much that I would like to have seen fleshed out more fully. There were as well a number of points that I found more questionable or even irresponsible. For these reasons, I have chosen to air several points of agreement and disagreement in the interest of widening an important debate. Let me note from the outset, however, that this is not meant as another review of the book discussed by Bix, but of the issues he raised in his review.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tackling the Translation of an Invaluable Primary Source that No One Person Would Dare Face Alone</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Tackling_the_Translation_of_an_Invaluable_Primary_Source_that_No_One_Person_Would_Dare_Face_Alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Tackling_the_Translation_of_an_Invaluable_Primary_Source_that_No_One_Person_Would_Dare_Face_Alone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ding Wenjiang 丁文江 and Zhao Fengtian 趙豐田, original compilers; translation by Shimada Kenji 島田虔次 et al. Ryō Keichō nenpu chōhen  梁啟超&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;年譜長編 ([annotated Japanese translation of] Liang Qichao nianpu chang-bian = Chronological biography of Liang Qichao, full edition). Five volumes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tokyo: Iwanami Shoten, 2004. 426, 57 pp. ¥8600, isbn 4000270613 (vol. 1). 477&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;pp. ¥8600, isbn 4000270621 (vol. 2). 522 pp. ¥8600, isbn 400027063x (vol. 3).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;541 pp. ¥8600, isbn 4000270648 (vol. 4). 478, 89 pp. ¥9000, isbn 4000270656&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Controversy over Iris Chang’s Rape of Nanking</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/The_Controversy_over_Iris_Changs_Rape_of_Nanking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/The_Controversy_over_Iris_Changs_Rape_of_Nanking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1997 when Iris Chang, an independent journalist, published her book on the Nanjing Massacre of 1937–38, many people felt that an important story from World War II in East Asia would now be told for the first time in English.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That is, until they actually read the book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book, entitled The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II (New York: Basic Books), appeared with gushing proclamations on the back cover from an assortment of China scholars and journalists (Frederic Wakeman, Beatrice Bartlett, and Ross Terrill among them) lauding the merits of the book and carried a preface by a Harvard University professor of modern Chinese history (William Kirby). The early reviews in such esteemed places as the New York Times  continued to gush praise. Yet, anyone who has ever studied modern Sino-Japanese relations should be able to clearly discern that the book is grievously flawed in many ways. And, sadly, it plays right into the hands of the right-wing extremists in Japan who still deny or strongly downplay the massacre itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Debates over the Asiatic Mode of Production in Soviet Russia, China, and Japan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/The_Debates_over_the_Asiatic_Mode_of_Production_in_Soviet_Russia_China_and_Japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/The_Debates_over_the_Asiatic_Mode_of_Production_in_Soviet_Russia_China_and_Japan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A great deal has been written** **about the “Asiatic mode of production,” most of it the work of Marxists around the world, as they tried to establish what Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels meant by the expression and what it signified for the contemporary “Orient.” Over the past decade, several scholars less involved in the Marxist discussions have addressed the debates that emerged over the Asiatic mode of production as topics in the intellectual history of Russia, China, and Japan of the 1920s and 1930s.1 More recently, a flurry of some thirty or more articles appeared in the People’s Republic of China on the issue, but the topic disappeared from scholarly journals as quickly and mysteriously as it had arisen, only to be revived again in 1985 and 1986. None of the writings on the Asiatic mode of production has yet attempted an examination of the issues raised in all the major countries in which there was debate—primarily, the Soviet Union, China, and Japan—and of the important interrelationships between them from the late 1920s through the late 1930s. Without appreciating the transnational context in which the debate took place at that time, we cannot fully understand it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gold Seal of 57 ce and the Afterlife of an **Inanimate Object**</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/The_Gold_Seal_of_57_ce_and_the_Afterlife_of_an_Inanimate_Object/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/The_Gold_Seal_of_57_ce_and_the_Afterlife_of_an_Inanimate_Object/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This essay operates on the assumption that objects can inspire thought, and thought can generate debate, and the consequences of that debate can be of ontological importance. Thus, the inanimate object plays no “conscious” role in engendering ideas, but humans invest in it a range of meanings which can reach levels of great cultural and historical significance. The object in question is a golden seal, presently on display in the Fukuoka City Museum in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Japanese and the Jews: A Comparative Analysis of Their Communities in Harbin, 1898–1930</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/The_Japanese_and_the_Jews_A_Comparative_Analysis_of_Their_Communities_in_Harbin_18981930/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/The_Japanese_and_the_Jews_A_Comparative_Analysis_of_Their_Communities_in_Harbin_18981930/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One effective way to reach an understanding of the experiences of a given foreign community or colonial (or semi-colonial) situation in a given city is to compare it with another foreign community or colonial situation in the same city. This enables us to contrast degrees of assimilation, integration, interaction with the surrounding indigenous community and other foreign communities, and the like. Indeed, this volume, as a whole, will move us a large step forward in that direction. This chapter examines the experiences of the Jewish and the Japanese communities of Harbin in the three decades before the Manchurian Incident.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Nanking Atrocity and Chinese Historical Memory</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/The_Nanking_Atrocity_and_Chinese_Historical_Memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/The_Nanking_Atrocity_and_Chinese_Historical_Memory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Serious scholars will continue to debate many aspects of the Nanking Atrocity perpetrated by the Japanese military from mid-December 1937 to early-February 1938. Why did it take place? How did Japanese military discipline break down? How many Chinese were massacred and raped? These and other questions remain open to scholarly debate. But no serious historian of any nationality doubts or denies that the Atrocity &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; take place. I stress this point at the outset because of, among other things, the grossly uninformed treatment this issue has received over the past decade in the American news media. The Atrocity has not achieved its full place in the catalog of world atrocities despite the great suffering that took place during those terrible weeks in Nanking, the Chinese capital city. Of course, the same can be said for other great acts of mass murder in the twentieth century, such as massacres of Armenians under the regime of the Young Turks during World War I, or the Porrajmos or Gypsy genocide by the Nazis during World War Two. But this hardly stanches the pain felt by survivors of Nanking and by their descendants. Over the past decade, there has been a dramatic surge of interest in Nanking and other atrocities committed by the Japanese in wartime China. This has taken place both in the People’s Republic of China (PRC) and in Chinese diaspora communities, especially in North America. There is even a journal published in Chinese in the United States expressly devoted to the topic, the &lt;em&gt;Jih-pen ch’in-Hua yen-chiu&lt;/em&gt; (Studies of Japanese Aggression against China), and there are now many websites focused on Nanking and similar Japanese wartime atrocities.1 Organizations sponsoring the journal and websites have held many conferences and other commemorative events, such as a major symposium at Princeton University in November 1997, and a number of recent books by young Chinese nationalists 1  See, for example, the following websites: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.Nanking1937.org/;&#34;&gt;www.Nanking1937.org/;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.smn.co.jp/gallery/&#34;&gt;www.smn.co.jp/gallery/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Other Japanese Community: Leftwing Japanese Activities in Wartime Shanghai</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/The_Other_Japanese_Community_Leftwing_Japanese_Activities_in_Wartime_Shanghai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/The_Other_Japanese_Community_Leftwing_Japanese_Activities_in_Wartime_Shanghai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To speak of the Japanese community of wartime Shanghai as a monolith would be to misrepresent its internal complexity. To the extent that we know of the Japanese in Shanghai in the 1930s and 1940s, we understand them to be a group closely self-protective and dependent on the home government and military for its security. The great majority of the Japanese in Shanghai in those tense years were most concerned with ensuring their government’s active involvement in protecting their community and its interests against the Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Recent Boom in Shanghai Studies</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/The_Recent_Boom_in_Shanghai_Studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/The_Recent_Boom_in_Shanghai_Studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past two decades have witnessed a surge of scholarly interest within the field of China studies in Shanghai’s modern history and culture. As if in replication of China’s exploding economy, this attraction to China’s largest city has by no means been limited to the Anglophone world (most non-native Anglophone westerners who work on China now publish much of their scholarship in English), but has been equally matched if not surpassed in quantity by work in Chinese and Japanese. After examining why Shanghai has become so popular to researchers, I will look at the kinds of work that have been done on the city’s history, examine a few recent works of cultural and intellectual history more closely, and suggest a number of avenues for future scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Translator’s Preface to *Books and Boats***** \(Ōba Osamu\)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Translators_Preface_to_Books_and_Boats_ba_Osamu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/fogel_china_japan/Translators_Preface_to_Books_and_Boats_ba_Osamu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ōba Osamu was born in Kyoto in 1927. Three months later his family moved to Osaka, where he grew up. Virtually his entire academic life has been tied to the Kansai region, which generally refers to that area in central Japan encompassing Kyoto, Osaka, and Kobe. He received both undergraduate and graduate training in East Asian history at Ryūkoku University in Kyoto.1 After serving in several teaching positions in the 1950s, he moved to Kansai University in Osaka, where he taught for most of his career. Retiring in 1997, Ōba followed the Japanese practice of teaching elsewhere in post-retirement, in this case, at Kōgakkan University in Mie Prefecture.2 There, he served as its president until his death in 2002. During his distinguished career, he lectured at countless venues around the world, and he was a visiting professor at numerous Chinese universities as well as at Princeton University in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
