<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/timur/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/timur/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The death of Timur-i-leng</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/timur/articles/MT/2005-10-05_the-death-of-timur-i-leng/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/timur/articles/MT/2005-10-05_the-death-of-timur-i-leng/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/10/05/the-death-of-timur-i-leng/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This year marks the 600th anniversary of the death of the great Islamic hero Timur-i-leng. I had long wanted to prepare a document regarding his death, because it led to the most profound inequities of Asia. Many people these days are in the business of comparing the old civilizational powers of Asia: Iran, India and China. But they typically forget the most important normalization factor in these comparisons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Invasion of India</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/timur/articles/MT/2003-03-02_the-invasion-of-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/timur/articles/MT/2003-03-02_the-invasion-of-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/03/02/the-invasion-of-india/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tughlaq-decline&#34;&gt;Tughlaq decline&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1397 Timur-i-lang obtained the intelligence that the Tughlaq Sultanate in India was on the decline. After the destruction the Southern Alliance of Mir Hussain (whose grandfather, Amir Qazaghan of Balkh was a great backer of Mohamed bin Tughlaq and Firoz Shah Tughlaq) and the conquest of Balkh by Timur, the Tughlaqs lost the backing of the Southern Alliance and the buffer provided by this alliance against the Central Asian Khanates. As a consequence the Kokhars of the Salt Range under Raja Jasrat led a massive rebellion against Mahmud Shah Tughlaq. In South India too, the Tughlaq armies were repulsed by the Hindu revival, and the local Islamic governors of Bijapur, Golconda and Ahmednagar broke free from Delhi. Turkic chieftains in Bengal, Gujarat and Avadh also crowned themselves local Sultans. The Rajput chief Rai Dalachandra liberated himself from the Tughlaqs and took the forts of Bhatnair and Loni on the road from Multan to Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The struggle against the Khan Toqtamish</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/timur/articles/MT/2003-02-27_the-struggle-against-the-khan-toqtamish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/timur/articles/MT/2003-02-27_the-struggle-against-the-khan-toqtamish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/02/27/the-struggle-against-the-khan-toqtamish/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing-toqtamish&#34;&gt;Installing Toqtamish&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The land North of the Syr Darya delta and the Little Aral Sea was the domain of the White Horde Khanate. In 1373 the powerful Urus Khan, a descendant of Chingiz Khan, through his eldest son Jöchi, was crowned ruler of the Horde. He was sixth in line from Orda the son of sutaJöchi and the brother of Batu. His nephew Toqtamish was in conflict with him and fled to Samarqand to seek aid from Timur-i-lang in 1376. Timur was delighted beyond words to have a descendant of Chingiz as a client and gifted him the territory around the cities of Utrar, Sabran and Sighnakhi, which his ancestor Jöchi had conquered in course of the westward thrust of the Kha’Khan. Toqtamish was attacked twice in his new ulus by Urus Khan, beaten badly and driven to Samarqand. However, Timur-i-lang reinstated him on each occasion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The annihilation of Iraq</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/timur/articles/MT/2003-02-25_the-annihilation-of-iraq/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/timur/articles/MT/2003-02-25_the-annihilation-of-iraq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/02/25/the-annihilation-of-iraq/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;jelairs&#34;&gt;Jelairs&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Iraq and Azerbaijan had towards the end of the 1300s came under the rule of the Islamized Mongol Chiefs of the Jelair clan who had descended from Jelme, the great general of Chingiz Ka’khan. The Jelair converts to Islam, Ahmed Jelair ibn Uweis and his brother Husain were engaged in a deadly struggle in which Ahmed, described as a vicious despot, brave warrior and protector of scholars triumphed. He executed his brothers and moved victoriously to Sultaniyeh one of the principal cities of Iraq, when Timur-i-lang, who had just smothered Iran marched against him. Timur easily captured Sultaniyeh and Ahmed fled to Tabriz. Timur decided not to campaign any further and returned to Samarqand to rest for about a year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The invasion of Afghanistan and Iran</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/timur/articles/MT/2003-02-20_the-invasion-of-afghanistan-and-iran/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/timur/articles/MT/2003-02-20_the-invasion-of-afghanistan-and-iran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/02/20/the-invasion-of-afghanistan-and-iran/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Timur-i-lang had campaigned in Afghanistan and Eastern Iran with Mir Hussain in his earlier days and subsequently Timur had wrested Balkh and the neighboring regions of Ghor from Hussain. However the rest of Afghanistan with the surrounding regions of Iran were far from being under the conqueror’s control. Hussain before him, and even before Amir Qazaghan had failed in the total conquest of these regions. Timur felt his glory lay in the conquest of these regions just has Chingiz and his grandson Hulegu had done. He conducted his famous campaign of Iran in between the last Qamar-ad Din wars but is considered here for due geographic coherence in the narrative.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The struggle against Qamar-ad-din.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/timur/articles/MT/2003-02-17_the-struggle-against-qamar-ad-din/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/timur/articles/MT/2003-02-17_the-struggle-against-qamar-ad-din/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/02/17/the-struggle-against-qamar-ad-din/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The heartland of the Chagadai khanate- Mogholistan lay in the land bounded by the Ili River that drains into the Balkhash lake in the north and the many branched Tarim river that drains into the Lob Nor lake. On the Ili in its middle course was the important city of Almalik that was once founded by the Uighur ka’Khans and was the center of their power. While just north of the Tarim river in a diagonal towards the Balkhash lay the 3 cities of Kucha, Sairam and Alma-Ata that was just beyond the Issyk Kul lake. These cities were all that remained of once prolific Indic colonies on the Silk route founded by the great Maharaja Vima Taktu and his successors.+++(4)+++&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The rise of Timur-i-Leng</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/timur/articles/MT/2003-02-15_the-rise-of-timur-i-leng/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/timur/articles/MT/2003-02-15_the-rise-of-timur-i-leng/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/02/15/the-rise-of-timur-i-leng/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I stated before I have begun my compilation of the history of the Turko-Mongol conqueror Timur i lang from a variety of scholarly sources. Understanding Timur has several dimensions for the connoisseurs of history that include grasping the complexity of modern day Asia’s fate, the spread of Islamic terror and culture and even a lesson for all the many mere mortals trying to reenact Timur’s tumultuous passage through Asia on their own small scales in their own spheres.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mogolification</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/timur/articles/MT/mogolification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/turks/timur/articles/MT/mogolification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1634054253378453506.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Timur, the founder of the so-called Mogol dynasty of India, was originally not from Mogholistan. He was a descendent of Qarachar Barlas a bek in the army of Chingiz Khan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The core Mogholistan was the Eastern Chagadai ulus. After one of their Khans Temur converted to marUnmAda, he launched into fury of jihads &amp;amp; in the end they probably controlled the whole of Uighuristan converting the Uighurs in toto. The prominent clan of Mongol beks of Mogholistan, Dughlats also conquered the southern regions shown as their possessions which at some point encompassed the &amp;ldquo;oases&amp;rdquo; cities of Khotan, Yarkhand and Kashgar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
