<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Hindoo History on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/usa/articles/hindoo-history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Hindoo History on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/usa/articles/hindoo-history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bhagat singh thind</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/usa/articles/hindoo-history/bhagat-singh-thind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/usa/articles/hindoo-history/bhagat-singh-thind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/HindooHistory/status/1834796029851648361&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Omaha morning bee, February 08, 1925&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Bhagat Singh Thind to Talk on Divine Realization of Kingdom of Heaven.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By WILL M. MAUPIN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Bhagat Singh Thind, native of India, once a naturalized American citizen and then not, soldier in the American army during the world war, member of the American Legion, psychologist, metaphysician and divine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sounds like a lot, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A cultured, learned gentleman is Dr. Thind. Born and reared in India, a Hindu of the Brahmin caste, he is intensely interested in India&amp;rsquo;s social and political affairs. He looks forward with confidence to the time when India will again be an independent nation, again a leader among the nations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BrahmachArI tail</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/usa/articles/hindoo-history/brahmachArI-tail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/usa/articles/hindoo-history/brahmachArI-tail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The San Francisco call, May 03, 1897&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DON&amp;rsquo;T TREAD ON HIS COAT TAILS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Hindoo Brahmacharin Considers It a Grave Discourtesy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He Gives His Version of the Rumpus at the Woman&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;Congress.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mrs. John F. Swift Says the Man Is a Lunatic and Is Sorry That He Came.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In future, should you chance to come into contact with a Brahmin, don&amp;rsquo;t pass up close to his back, or touch, or brush whatever he wears. He&amp;rsquo;ll resent it, as you do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curse of India</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/usa/articles/hindoo-history/curse_of_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/usa/articles/hindoo-history/curse_of_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1531342950382260224.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Elmore County Republican, 1913&lt;br&gt;&#xA;CURSE OF INDIA GETS FOOTHOLD IN AMERICA&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Reverend Trawin of Baptist Church Issues a Stern Warning to Women of Country&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rev. C. L. Trawin, pastor of the Baptist church, preached a strong sermon Sunday, warning the women of the United States against the religions brought to the country by Yogis and Swamis from India under the guise of philosophy, reincarnation, and the so-called higher life. He said, taking the text from II. Timothy 3:6, 7 &amp;lsquo;Of this sort are they which creep into houses, and lead captive silly women laden with sins, led away with diverse lusts, never learning and never able to come to the knowledge of the truth&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helena lover</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/usa/articles/hindoo-history/helena-lover/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/usa/articles/hindoo-history/helena-lover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Omaha daily bee, December 16, 1900&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Helena’s First Lover&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Hindoo Swami&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The recent marriage of Miss Helena Zimmerman of Cincinnati to the duke of Manchester has revived the story of a former love affair of the heiress. Miss Zimmerman, it is stated, was on her way to India to become a life disciple of Hindoo philosophy, Raja Yoga, when she met the duke of Manchester in London. But desire for knowledge of the mysticism of the east led almost directly to the beginning of the romance which culminated in the wealthy American girl secretly becoming the wife of the financially barren British duke.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russel calls out fiction</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/usa/articles/hindoo-history/russel_calls_out_fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/usa/articles/hindoo-history/russel_calls_out_fiction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Washington Times, 1902&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Bit of India in Washington&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Edmund Russell, an Indian Traveler and Student, Describes &amp;lsquo;Land of the Lotus&amp;rsquo; and its Inhabitants&amp;ndash; Severely Scores Kipling and His Work&amp;ndash; Calls the Realist &amp;lsquo;Incarnation of Journalistic Impudence&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If a man who lived his whole life in Washington were put under the influence of a powerful opiate and carried, unaware, to the apartments of Mr. Edmund Russell, in the northwestern section of this city he would, on regaining consciousness, rub his eyes, stare about him and come to the conclusion that he had been transported by some occult power to the sleeping room of a rajah in India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sara bull - vedAnta society</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/usa/articles/hindoo-history/sara-bull_vedAnta-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/usa/articles/hindoo-history/sara-bull_vedAnta-society/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/HindooHistory/status/1835403518041354243&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Hinduism was put on Trial: The Case of Mrs. Sara Bull&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After Swami Vivekananda delivered his now famous speech at World&amp;rsquo;s Parliament of Religions in 1893, he would go on to found the Vedanta Society in America, establishing centers in New York City, Washington D.C., Chicago, and San Francisco. Vedanta quickly gained a following among the urban elite, particularly well-heeled women. The reasons for Vedanta&amp;rsquo;s sudden success were manifold. One cannot discount the importance of Vivekananda&amp;rsquo;s personal charisma, which helped draw in a dedicated set of volunteers and devotees who would help establish and grow chapters across the country. More importantly, however, Vivekananda did not present Vedanta as a distinctly &amp;ldquo;Indian religion&amp;rdquo;, but rather a universal one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop hindu immigration</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/usa/articles/hindoo-history/hindu-immigration-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/usa/articles/hindoo-history/hindu-immigration-stop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1533896927900667904.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An editorial from the San Francisco Call, 1910&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hindu Immigration Must Stop&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The present rate of importation of Hindu laborers runs about 300 a month and is increasing&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If not checked the influx will exceed 5,000 a year, and these figures are moderate if we consider the virtually unlimited cooly population from which the supples are drawn and the pernicious activity of the steamship companies engaged in this profitable trade. These Hindus are by far the most objectionable call of Asiatic immigrants arriving in this country. They are unfitted by constitution to withstand the rigors and variations of the American climate and as laborers they are distressingly inferior.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
