<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/lankA/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/lankA/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Culture pfaffenberger 81</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/lankA/articles/culture-pfaffenberger81/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/lankA/articles/culture-pfaffenberger81/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/2643999?read-now=1&amp;amp;seq=13#page_scan_tab_contents&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The author wishes to express his gratitude to the Foreign Area Fellowship Program of the Social Science Research Council of Learned&#xA;Societies for supporting field research in Sri Lanka during 1974-1975, to Burton Benedict, Gerald Berreman, and George L. Hart, III, of the University of California, Berkeley, for the encouragement they gave to my studies, and to the anonymous reader whose helpful comments were passed on to me by the Editor.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE CULTURAL DIMENSION OF TAMIL SEPARATISM IN SRI LANKA&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Bryan Pfaffenberger*&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human rights 2020</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/lankA/articles/human-rights_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/lankA/articles/human-rights_2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hinduamerican.org/projects/human-rights-report/sri-lanka&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2019-2020 was marked by political turmoil, terrorism, riots, and religiously motivated violence. Government authorities continued to discriminate against religious minorities and did not adequately respond to or prevent religious violence or harassment by non-state actors. (U.S. Department of State, 2020) The government also failed to address alleged war crimes stemming from the civil war between the Sinhalese dominated government and the Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam (LTTE), an ethnic Tamil separatist group, that ended in 2009.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mullivakkal 2022</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/lankA/articles/mullivakkal_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/non-india/lankA/articles/mullivakkal_2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hindustudentscouncil.org/2022/remembering-the-mullivaikkal-massacre-in-sri-lanka/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Remembering the Mullivaikkal Massacre in Sri Lanka&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hindustudentscouncil.org/author/hindu-students-council/&#34; title=&#34;Posts by Hindu Students Council&#34;&gt;Hindu Students Council&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;May 18, 2022  March 9, 2025&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At a remembrance event in Mullivaikkal on May 18, 2022, Tamils mourned their loved ones who were killed or disappeared 13 years ago. (Source: IBC Tamil)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By: Dhivyan Karunakaran – College Chapter Relations Coordinator (Mid-Atlantic)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On May 18, 2009, Sri Lanka’s 26-year civil war ended with a bloodbath in a village called Mullivaikkal in the northern part of the island. During the final few months of the war alone, tens of thousands of Tamil civilians, who are mostly Hindu, were massacred by the Sri Lankan military, which is dominated by the island’s Sinhala-Buddhist majority. As a 10-year-old Hindu American of Sri Lankan Tamil heritage living in Maryland, I spent my weekends in May 2009 in front of the White House desperately demanding international intervention to stop the mass killings of Tamils in northern Sri Lanka. At each protest, I carried a placard I made that said, “President Obama, help suffering Tamil children!” The catastrophic humanitarian crisis in northern Sri Lanka received almost no attention from the American media. A couple days after the war ended on May 18, 2009, I finally saw a couple national evening news broadcasts briefly reporting that a civil war in Sri Lanka had come to an end with a government victory. However, they only showed videos of men dancing on the streets of Sri Lanka’s capital Colombo, lighting firecrackers, and proudly waving Sri Lankan flags. There was no mention of the massive loss of life that was taking place in northern Sri Lanka, almost as if those lives didn’t really matter. Watching those men celebrating as their fellow citizens were being slaughtered was heartbreaking and painful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
