<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some musings on chimpanzee hunting</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/articles/MT/2005-11-10_some-musings-on-chimpanzee-hunting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/articles/MT/2005-11-10_some-musings-on-chimpanzee-hunting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/11/10/some-musings-on-chimpanzee-hunting/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like the human ape the chimpanzee is a predatory great ape. We saw a remarkable footage on the “Predators” documentary of a band of 5 chimps hunt the colobus monkeys. It leaves a tremendous impact on any one who watches it. Observations have shown that chimpanzee may hunt in bands ranging from 1 to 35 individuals, but the most common tendency is to hunt with about a handful of individuals. The most important point to note is that most of the hunting bands are composed of adult and adolescent males from and the majority of kills are registered by males only, even if females and juveniles do participate in the hunt. While the colobus monkey is the main prey for the chimpanzee, it also hunts pigs, small antelopes and other small mammals and reptiles. Sometimes chimps go on major hunting binges (especially with the climate is dry) to kill many victims over a period of days or weeks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orang-utan behavior</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/articles/MT/2003-08-09_orang-utan-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/articles/MT/2003-08-09_orang-utan-behavior/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/08/09/orang-utan-behavior/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The great ape of East , the Orang was until recently thought to be rather limited in its behavioral complexity. The lineage of the Orangutan is an ancient one, including Sivapithecus, which inhabited the subcontinent under 16 Million years. Given its time of divergence from the rest of the anthropoid apes the matter of its behavioral complexity has been one of great interest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In captivity the orang shows much dexterity and capability of tool use, much like the chimp or Bonobo which are closer to Homo. The summation of several years of work has shown that the Orang has many of the behavioral traits that are commonly associated with Homo and Pan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ardipethicus</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/articles/MT/ardipethicus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/articles/MT/ardipethicus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1654354287797981185.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The solid black represents the current range where our closest living cousins the 2 Pan species are found. The * shows the site where the only known fossil chimp from ~545 KYA was found. Here it overlapped in space &amp;amp; time with an extinct grade of Homo, probably erectus. Thus, Image Pan and Homo lived in close proximity as recently 545 KYA. But the paradox is, where are the fossils of the Pan lineage then? While Sahelanthropus &amp;amp; Orrorin were probably close to the Homo-Pan common ancestor, most apes after that, Ardipithecus, Australopithecus, Paranthropus are are seen as closer to Homo than Pan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Denisovan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/articles/MT/denisovan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/articles/MT/denisovan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;papuan-negritos&#34;&gt;Papuan, Negritos&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interesting &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2021.07.022&#34;&gt;new work&lt;/a&gt; on the Negritos of the Philippines. The Aeta or the Ayta include groups that have the highest Denisovan admixture to date. The authors suggest that Papuans and Negritos had separate admixtures with Denisovans after ~53KY. The Papuans had their admixture around 25–30 Kyr suggesting that Denisovans were widely distributed from Siberia, to the far reaches of Asia-Pacific. Thus, they go on to suggest that various pygmy Homos like Homo luzonensis&amp;amp; H.floresiensis might have all been Denisovans. had their admixture around 25–30 Kyr suggesting that Denisovans were widely distributed from Siberia, to the far reaches of Asia-Pacific. Thus, they go on to suggest that various pygmy Homos like Homo luzonensis&amp;amp; H.floresiensis might have all been Denisovans. It makes sense that there were multiple races of Denisovans even as there is of sapiens today over that vast area &amp;amp; some of them on the islands were pygmy morphs just as we seen in sapiens. The paper is also notable for the entry of the new Euro-American religion into scientific publications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neanderthal contribution</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/articles/MT/neanderthal-contribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/articles/MT/neanderthal-contribution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1577093484237885440.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;genetic&#34;&gt;Genetic&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reasonable review on the impact of Neanderthal introgression on modern sapiens. A big factor in the survival of N alleles is the selective pressure from infections. Interestingly, a study found that E.Asian came under strong selection from coronavirus(es) within the last 900 generations. Think about what the implication of that is for the so-called lab-leak hypothesis for SARS-CoV-2.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, several genes that might play a role in viral immunity show introgressed Neanderthal variants. Interestingly, the chemokine receptor CCR9 N variant has increased susceptibility for SARS-CoV-2 in places like the Indian subcontinent; see &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2020/10/12/pandemic-days-6-genetic-risk-factors/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; . This suggests that in the past, the CCR9 N variant might have provided protection against some other virus that became a liability with Wuhan. On the other hand the N variant associated with the OAS1 which codes for synthetase generating an immunity signaling oligonucleotide  increases SARS-CoV-2 resistance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulawesi animal drawing</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/articles/MT/sulawesi-animal-drawing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/articles/MT/sulawesi-animal-drawing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1969638976249049338&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recent studies suggest that non-Africans have descended from a common ancestor who admixed with Neanderthals 49-45K years ago. Thus, the spread of non-African sapiens around the rest of the world began then.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Neanderthals are currently not known to have drawn animals, though they made abstract art and hand stencils. It is believed that only sapiens had this capability.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rock art dated to 51200 years from Sulawesi (below) has so far been attributed to sapiens. However, that is too old for sapiens as they started outside-Africa radiation only 49-45K years ago. Before sapiens, in Southeast Asia, there were Denisovans, Indonesian erectus (last seen 108-117Kya) and floresiensis (190-50 Kya). Homo erectus was probably gone by then (why is a question), and the hand stencils suggest it was not H. floresiensis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surroundings</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/articles/MT/surroundings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/eukaryota/animal/bilatera/dutero-stome/chordata/vertebrata/osteichthyes/sarco-pterygia/tetrapoda/amniota/mammal/primate/hominidae/articles/MT/surroundings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/with_replies&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Humans had their origins as an ape in an incredibly rich fauna. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S1040618225004215&#34;&gt;recent monograph&lt;/a&gt; studies the fauna cooccurring with the primitive member of the human lineage Kenyanthropus platyops: pythons, Varanus lizards, gigantic crocodiles, several species of pigs, hippos, rhinos and elephants, an array of antelopes and bovids and several large cats.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The primitive members of the human lineage appear to have lived in bands in close association with troops of the monkey Theropithecus. This gigantic baboon probably had a complex vocalization convergent on a primitive language comparable to what was developing among human-like apes. It is possible that the only living member of this lineage, the gelada, has something like a language, representing a stage close to what might have been seen in early human-like apes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
