<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indo-china border on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/indo-china-border/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Indo-china border on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/indo-china-border/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1950 paTel to nehru</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/indo-china-border/1950_paTel_to_nehru/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/indo-china-border/1950_paTel_to_nehru/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My dear Jawaharlal,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;D.O. No. 821-DPM/50 New Delhi, 7th Nov. 1950&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ever since my return from Ahmedabad and after the Cabinet meeting the same day which I had to attend at practically fifteen minutes&amp;rsquo; notice and for which I regret I was not able to read all the papers, I have been anxiously thinking over the problem of Tibet and I thought I should share with you what is passing through my mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1961 withdrawal</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/indo-china-border/1961-withdrawal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/indo-china-border/1961-withdrawal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;China Captured Almost Half Of Arunachal Pradesh In 1962, So Why Did It Decide To Back Off?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;February 15, 2021&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the war broke out between China and India in 1962, the former declared a unilateral ceasefire after 32 days of fighting on November 21, and its army returned behind the McMahon Line. If China wanted, it could have continued to occupy the territory it had gained after capturing almost half of Arunachal Pradesh, but it didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2017 chumbi valley</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/indo-china-border/2017-chumbi-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/indo-china-border/2017-chumbi-valley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;China&amp;rsquo;s Chumbi Valley Shenanigans India Must Act Tough&#xA;By Brig Arun Bajpai | Date : 04 Jul , 2017&#xA;￼&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Against China’s objections when India  allowed Dalai Lama to visit Arunachal Pradesh a few months back, China was all balloons and blunderbuss, shouting and ranting but did not go beyond that. However when India repeated this slight to China by not participating in Chinese summit in the month of May this year on the issue of sovereignty  in Chinese most ambitious project of One Belt One Road (OBOR), it was expected that China will do something to cut India to size. This China has done now by its shenanigans in Chumbi Valley commencing on 16 Jun, ostensibly against Bhutan, well knowing that it is India’s protectorate and this valley is just 50 Kms from India’s Achilles heel the Siliguri corridor, which connects Indian North Eastern States with rest of India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2020 kailAsh range vacation blunder</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/indo-china-border/2020-kailash-range-vacation-blunder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/indo-china-border/2020-kailash-range-vacation-blunder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If India loses grip on Kailash Range, PLA will make sure we never get it back&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1962, the actual objective of the Chinese was Kailash Range and that is where they halted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lt Gen H S Panag (retd) 12 November, 2020 1:08 pm IST&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Lt Gen H S Panag PVSM, AVSM (R) served in the Indian Army for 40 years. He was GOC in C Northern Command and Central Command. Post retirement, he was Member of Armed Forces Tribunal. Views are personal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2020 land grab solidificatin</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/indo-china-border/2020-land-grab_solidification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/4_post-brit/geopolitics/articles/indo-china-border/2020-land-grab_solidification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How China Turned the Tables on India and Converted 1993 Agreement into a Land Grab&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As is evident from the present Ladakh crisis, Indian diplomacy, to put it politely, has fallen short.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How China Turned the Tables on India and Converted 1993 Agreement into a Land Grab&#xA;Indian army trucks move along a highway leading to Ladakh, at Gagangeer in Kashmir&amp;rsquo;s Ganderbal district June 17, 2020. REUTERS/Danish Ismail&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Describing China’s approach to border disputes, a foreign diplomat who has had several years of experience negotiating with China, said, “A Chinese stands on the border and takes a broad sweep of the neighbour’s land. Then he takes off his hat and throws it across the border. A while later, he points to the hat on the neighbour’s land and says, ‘that hat has been there since antiquity. It proves that this has historically been my land’.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
