<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Ambedkar on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/persons/articles/ambedkar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Ambedkar on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/persons/articles/ambedkar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ambedkar sponsors Sanskrit: PTI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/persons/articles/ambedkar/ambedkar_sponsors_sanskrit_PTI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/persons/articles/ambedkar/ambedkar_sponsors_sanskrit_PTI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/h6N5vQ2.jpg&#34;&gt;https://i.imgur.com/h6N5vQ2.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SANSKRIT PROPOSED AS OFFICIAL LANGUAGE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Idia&amp;rsquo;s Law Minister. Dr 8. R Ambedkar, is among those who have sponsored Sanskrit as the Micial: language of the Indian Union. One of This sipporters is Dr B. Keskar, India Deputy Minister for External Affairs, another Mr Naziruddin Ahmad.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Questioned about this move, Dr Ambedkar asked a PTI correspondent &amp;ldquo;What is wrong with Sanskrit&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The amendment will be taken up by the Constituent Assembly when the aliestion of official language is considered.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arun Shourie Excerpt</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/persons/articles/ambedkar/arun-shourie-excerpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/persons/articles/ambedkar/arun-shourie-excerpt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Excerpted from Worshipping False Gods by Arun Shourie, ASA Publishers, 1997, Rs 450. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rediff.com/freedom/29ambed1.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.rediff.com/freedom/29ambed1.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ambedkar and his patrons were dealt a humiliating blow by the elections of 1937. There were a total of 1,585 seats in the 11 assemblies in &amp;lsquo;British India&amp;rsquo;. Of these 777 were &amp;rsquo;tied&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash; in the sense that they were to be filled by communal or special representation from Chambers of Commerce, plantations, labour etc. Of the 808 &amp;lsquo;general&amp;rsquo; seats, the Congress, which Ambedkar, Jinnah and others denounced from the house tops, won 456. It secured absolute majorities in 5 assemblies &amp;ndash; those of Madras, United Provinces, Central Provinces, Bihar and Orissa. And was the largest single party in 4 others&amp;ndash; Bombay, Bengal, Assam and the NWFP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bodhi sattva&#39;s hindutva</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/persons/articles/ambedkar/bodhi-sattvas_hindutva/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/persons/articles/ambedkar/bodhi-sattvas_hindutva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Author - Aravindan Neelakandan 2012 on CRI&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Terming Baba Saheb Ambedkar as a Hindu nationalist would be the ultimate blasphemy in ‘secular’ India. But if there is an ideology that can resonate with Dr.Ambedkar’s mindscape it is Hindutva – the much maligned Hindu nationalism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr.Ambedkar always struggled for justice and liberty. He naturally knew that the caste system was inherently unjust and anti-democratic. He wanted Hindu society to be free of this malaise. But to remove it one should understand the problem in its socio-historic context. In quest for such an understanding the good doctor arrived at a cardinal truth. It became a fundamental truth all his life. It is the ‘indubitable cultural unity’ of India. As early as 1916, in his famed paper presented at an anthropology seminar of Columbia University, Dr.Ambedkar made an observation that may well become the definition of what is today called the ‘cultural nationalism’ in Indian context:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wavell on Ambedkar 39</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/persons/articles/ambedkar/wavell_on_ambedkar_39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/persons/articles/ambedkar/wavell_on_ambedkar_39/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;7 October 1939&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He (Ambedkar) and I had seen something of one another in 1934-35: but he had had time to think since then, and the general conclusion which he had in the result reached was that the parliamentary system would not do in India.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I asked him whether he would say that in public, to which he replied that he would be perfectly ready to do so, whith the utmost emphasis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wavell on Ambedkar 39</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/persons/articles/ambedkar/wavell_on_ambedkar_46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v4/persons/articles/ambedkar/wavell_on_ambedkar_46/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;5 April 1946&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ambedkar called on the Cabinet Delegation and the new Viceroy, Field Marshal Viscount Wavell. Wavell recorded a &amp;ldquo;Secret&amp;rdquo; memorandum about the discussion. Here too Ambedkar urged his case in the same words:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Scheduled Castes had beeen the earleist source of man-power for the East India Company&amp;rsquo;s army, and so it was with their help that the British had conquered India,&amp;rdquo; the Viceroy recorded Ambedkar as arguing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
