<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;4 Becoming a God on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/4_Becoming_a_God/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;4 Becoming a God on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/4_Becoming_a_God/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>14 The Last Campaign</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/4_Becoming_a_God/14_The_Last_Campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/4_Becoming_a_God/14_The_Last_Campaign/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1224, at sixty-two years of age, Genghis Khan decided to head home, so that he could spend his final years along the Tuul River that ran down from Burkhan Khaldun. Unlike the lightning-strike speed with which he had begun his invasion of Central Asia, his trip home from Afghanistan was slow and leisurely, and included a long pause for one of the largest hunts known in history. During the four-year campaign, his army had conquered land from the Indus to the Volga, including what are today Kazakhstan, Afghanistan, Turkmenistan, Tajikistan, Kyrgyzstan, Uzbekistan, Azerbaijan, Iran, Georgia, Armenia, southern Russia, and part of Pakistan. His army had grown weary of fighting and plundering. They wanted to go home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 War, Inside and Out</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/4_Becoming_a_God/15_War_Inside_and_Out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/4_Becoming_a_God/15_War_Inside_and_Out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;**A **life cannot properly be measured until it ends. One could argue that the greatest achievements of Buddha, Jesus, and Muhammad, or political figures such as Alexander, Caesar, and Cleopatra, lie less in what they themselves did, but in their legacies, in what they inspired their followers to do. Genghis Khan’s most enduring impact came from the laws he created and the dynamic energy he infused into his large and ever-growing state. His empire continued to expand for more than sixty years after his death, and it survived another century after that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Burning the Books</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/4_Becoming_a_God/16_Burning_the_Books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/4_Becoming_a_God/16_Burning_the_Books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Of all the religious scholars who had met with Genghis Khan, the young Taoist disciple Li Zhichang had benefited the most, lived the longest, and was destined to die in the cruelest manner. His sect had prospered after the meeting in Afghanistan and Li Zhichang had become an honored figure among the Taoists. He published a book on his discussions with Genghis Khan and, because of his intimate connection to the conqueror, he was revered by many younger Mongols.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Life After Death</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/4_Becoming_a_God/17_Life_After_Death/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/4_Becoming_a_God/17_Life_After_Death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Genghis Khan built his empire with lightning speed, and it continued to expand until the death of his grandson Khubilai Khan in 1294. Then it began a prolonged period of decay, like a beached whale slowly rotting in the sun. Khubilai Khan, who united China and founded the Yuan dynasty in 1271, claimed to be the new Great Khan, whose empire extended to Russia and included everything between Korea and modern-day Turkey. Yet in truth he only controlled China and he had to struggle to keep a hold of his Mongolian homeland. He embraced a Confucian style of ancestor worship and honored his grandfather as the founder of the Yuan dynasty. In 1286, Khubilai assigned his grandson Kammala to administer Mongolia and build a temple on Burkhan Khaldun, and in 1292 he gave Kammala the new title of Jinong, or Golden Prince. Kammala assumed responsibility for the sacred area around Burkhan Khaldun and for control of the &lt;em&gt;Keshig&lt;/em&gt;. He gathered the old &lt;em&gt;gers&lt;/em&gt; of Genghis Khan’s queens and made them into portable shrines. He also built a small brick and tile temple in the Chinese architectural style. He kept one thousand of the old guard, mostly Uriyankhai men, and instructed them to keep everyone out. The area became the official burial grounds for the Yuan emperors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 The Unfulfilled Law</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/4_Becoming_a_God/18_The_Unfulfilled_Law/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/quest_for_god/4_Becoming_a_God/18_The_Unfulfilled_Law/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As Europe progressed from the Renaissance toward the Enlightenment, consensus among intellectuals grew toward favoring some degree of religious tolerance, which mostly meant tolerance between Catholics and Protestants, and occasionally extended to Jews. Genghis Khan and the Mongol model were not mentioned in this context; no one seemed to have an interest in him. If Dante’s views were truly inspired by Genghis Khan, that connection was lost on his audience, and the Mongols seemed to be fading from history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
