<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Bengaluru on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/maisUru-saMsthAnam/bengaLUru/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Bengaluru on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/maisUru-saMsthAnam/bengaLUru/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cremation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/maisUru-saMsthAnam/bengaLUru/cremation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/maisUru-saMsthAnam/bengaLUru/cremation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;eye-donation&#34;&gt;Eye donation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dial the Eye Bank within 6 hours of death.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;nArAyaNa netrAlaya - (+91-9741685555, +91-80-66121641)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Close eyes of the donor and place wet cotton swab on closed eyes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Switch off the fans and keep the air-conditioner or cooler on.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Raise the head with the help of a pillow.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Benefits&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The corneal tissue extracted from a pair of eyes can restore vision of up to four blind persons. Success rate of the transplant is 98-99 per cent.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;India requires 1 lakh cornea donations a year. Due to a shortage of donated corneas, young children or persons with blindness in one eye are given priority for transplants.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Give a missed call to 88840 18800 and get a certificate for pledging your eyes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eligibility&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornea must be donated within 6 hours of a person’s death and transplanted at the earliest.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Age and blood group no bar to donate. Cataract, diabetes and blood pressure patients can pledge, and also blind persons with intact cornea. “People with above-neck cancers or infections like HIV/AIDS are exceptions,”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;body-donation&#34;&gt;Body donation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Anatomy students in medical institutes benefit.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;rAmAiah medical college.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vydehi Institute of Medical Sciences &amp;amp; Research Centre #82, EPIP area, Nallurahalli, Whitefield Bangalore – 560 066.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rajarajeshwari medical college  74112 41640&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After death body has to reach our department within 6-8 hours after death. If 12 hours have passed after the death of the person or if the body has a foul smell, it will not be accepted.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If informed to the hospital number. Institute will provide the transport to bring the body to the institute.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If the death occurs on holiday or Sunday also transport is possible as hospital services are 24×7.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Certification of death is must to avoid Legal complications.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;organ-donation&#34;&gt;Organ donation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brain dead patients donate. Anyone aged between 5 to 60 years can donate. HIV, Cancer or Junior Diabetic patients deprecated.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;you have to register yourselves as donors with the Zonal Coordination Committee of Karnataka for Transplantation (ZCCK).&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Online. A pledge card will be sent to you through post&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;or you can also call them on 9845006768 and soon they will be at your doorstep, with a registration form.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While registering for donation, two witnesses are required, of which at least one should be a family member.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brain death test&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The patient is kept on life supporting system till the test is carried out. This also helps keep the organs like heart, pancreas, kidney etc. alive while removing it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;According to the THO-1994, four licensed doctors are required to carry out these tests within 24 hours.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A set of four tests – Cornea reflex test, Ear reflex test, Gag reflex test and Aphena reflex test – is conducted on the body twice, with a gap of six hours between each set, within 24 hours of the suspected brain death.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Only when the test results indicate brain death, a certification of brain death is given.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;These tests will also provide information on which organs are fit to be donated and accordingly family is informed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finding recipients&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;At the same time, at least 10 recipients will be informed about the availability of the organ depending on the priority of the patient and blood groups. Blood group matching is the same as blood donation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stats&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Over last seven years, only 58 people have successfully donated organs but 936 patients are still waiting for the donors who can save them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hearse-van&#34;&gt;Hearse van&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The BBMP hearse service may be contacted on 080 22493 202 and 2249 3203 or on WhatsApp number 87921 62736. The service is free and available between 7 am and 10 pm on all days.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fleet of 96 vehicles in 2021; 27.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;crematoria---location-and-time&#34;&gt;Crematoria - Location and time&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;8AM to 5PM on all the days&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hebbal&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bellary Rd, Near Esteem Mall, Chiranjeevi Layout, Hebbal Kempapura, Bengaluru, Karnataka 560024&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Land line No.- 080-22720704.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;bbmp &lt;a href=&#34;https://site.bbmp.gov.in/PDF/otherpdfs/Crematorium%20details.pdf&#34;&gt;cell list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;bbmp-process&#34;&gt;BBMP process&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After death of the deceased you need to collect doctor certificate in Natural death and in case of Unnatural death you need to collect police NOC.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Generally, the deceased name, gender, religion, address, primary cause of death, secondary cause of death should be very clearly mentioned in doctor certificate. Any discrepancies in the same shall be rejected.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Online booking is compulsory, you need to select a particular crematorium and time slot while booking &lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.bbmpgov.in/crematorium/forms/onlinebookingfrm.aspx&#34;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt;. Registration cost 250 (as of 2024). Take acknowledgement copy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Set up Ambulance/ van, purohiths and samagries.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Generally a bamboo pier (chatta), ash collection pot are compulsory.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reach 15 min early to the crematorium and report to crematorium manager.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Need to produce the certificate and photo id proof copy to the crematorium Manager. Crematorium Manager will verify the details and he/she proceeds further.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The deceased needs to have some kind of address proof of the residing city or the city where the last rites are supposed to be taken place.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They will complete the process of burning within 1-1.5 hours later you can collect the ash.  It takes 2- 3 hrs inclusive of the puja time and ashes collection time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After the completion of process they will provide you the acknowledgment of death you need to produce the same in your BBMP ward to collect the death certificate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It takes about 21 days to get the actual municipal death certificate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
