<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;3 Winding up on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/3_winding_up/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;3 Winding up on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/3_winding_up/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>41 Passing the Baton</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/3_winding_up/41_Passing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/3_winding_up/41_Passing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I reflected on the predicament of Suharto in 1998, when he was forced to resign and hand power over to a vice-president he considered inadequate to succeed him, I was glad that I had resigned as prime minister in November 1990. I was still in command of the political situation and of a humming economy. I was physically still vigorous. But had I not stood down, I might have found myself trapped in the financial crisis, with my faculties less acute and my energy levels down. Instead, for the past nine years I helped to ease the way for my successor, Goh Chok Tong, and his team of younger ministers to take full charge of the Singapore government. Prime Minister Goh retained me in his cabinet as senior minister. Without the pressures of daily decision-making, I was able to reflect on the bigger and longer-term issues and contribute towards more rounded solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>42 My Family</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/3_winding_up/42_My_Fami/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/3_winding_up/42_My_Fami/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The communists impressed me by the great importance they placed on the woman a prospective cadre was attached to. They knew a wife could make an enormous difference to a man’s reliability and commitment to the cause. They had objected to my political secretary Jek Yeun Thong’s steady girlfriend, whom they regarded as not politically suitable. He ignored this objection, and without his knowledge they dropped him from their cell network. They were right; she was not supportive of their cause.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>43 Epilogue</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/3_winding_up/43_Epilogu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/yew_lee_kuan/third-world_to_first/3_winding_up/43_Epilogu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a boy of six, I rode in a bullock-cart on wooden wheels bound in a metal strip, without springs or shock absorbers, enjoying a hilariously bumpy ride on a dirt track to my grandfather’s rubber estate. Fifty years later, in 1977, I flew in a supersonic Concorde from London to New York in three hours. Technology has changed my world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have had to sing four national anthems: Britain’s &lt;em&gt;God Save the Queen&lt;/em&gt;, Japan’s &lt;em&gt;Kimigayo&lt;/em&gt;, Malaysia’s &lt;em&gt;Negara Ku&lt;/em&gt;, and finally Singapore’s &lt;em&gt;Majulah Singapura&lt;/em&gt;; such were the political upheavals of the last 60 years. Foreign troops have come and gone – British, Australian and Indian, then the Japanese, with their auxiliaries, the Taiwanese and Koreans. The British returned after the war and fought the communist insurgency. Then came independence for Singapore. Indonesia mounted Confrontation against Malaysia. The swirling currents of political changes swept me along.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
