<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;30 The Triumph of Christianity A D 306-325 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/30_The_Triumph_of_Christianity_A_D_306-325/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;30 The Triumph of Christianity A D 306-325 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/30_The_Triumph_of_Christianity_A_D_306-325/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 THE WAR OF CHURCH AND STATE A D 64-311</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/30_The_Triumph_of_Christianity_A_D_306-325/01_THE_WAR_OF_CHURCH_AND_STATE_A_D_64-311/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/30_The_Triumph_of_Christianity_A_D_306-325/01_THE_WAR_OF_CHURCH_AND_STATE_A_D_64-311/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IN pre-Christian days the Roman government had for the most part allowed to the rivals of orthodox paganism a tolerance which they in turn had shown to the official and imperial cults; nothing was demanded from the adherents of new faiths except an occasional gesture of adoration to the gods and head of the state. The emperors were piqued to find that of all the heretics under their rule only the Christians and the Jews refused to join in honoring their &lt;em&gt;genius.&lt;/em&gt; The burning of incense before a statue of the emperor had become a sign and affirmation of loyalty to the Empire, like the oath of allegiance required for citizenship today. On its side the Church resented the Roman idea that religion was subordinate to the state; it saw in emperor-worship an act of polytheism and idolatry, and instructed its followers to refuse it at any cost. The Roman government concluded that Christianity was a radical—perhaps a communist—movement, subtly designed to overthrow the established order.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 THE RISE OF CONSTANTINE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/30_The_Triumph_of_Christianity_A_D_306-325/02_THE_RISE_OF_CONSTANTINE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/30_The_Triumph_of_Christianity_A_D_306-325/02_THE_RISE_OF_CONSTANTINE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Diocletian, peaceful in his Dalmatian palace, saw the failure of both the persecution and the tetrarchy. Seldom had the Empire witnessed such confusion as followed his abdication. Galerius prevailed upon Constantius to let him appoint Severus and Maximinus Daza as “Caesars” (305). At once the principle of heredity asserted its claims: Maxentius, son of Maximian, wished to succeed his father’s authority, and a like resolution fired Constantine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Flavius Valerius Constantinus had begun life at Naissus in Moesia (272?) as the illegitimate son of Constantius by his legal concubine Helena, a barmaid from Bithynia.27 On becoming a “Caesar,” Constantius was required by Diocletian to put away Helena and to take Maximian’s stepdaughter Theodora as his wife. Constantine received only a meager education. He took up soldiering early, and proved his valor in the wars against Egypt and Persia. Galerius, on succeeding Diocletian, kept the young officer near him as a hostage for the good behavior of Constantius. When the latter asked Galerius to send the youth to him Galerius procrastinated craftily; but Constantine escaped from his watchers, and rode night and day across Europe to join his father at Boulogne and share in a British campaign. The Gallic army, deeply loyal to the humane Constantius, came to love his handsome, brave, and energetic son; and when the father died at York (306), the troops acclaimed Constantine not merely as “Caesar” but as &lt;em&gt;Augustus&lt;/em&gt;—emperor. He accepted the lesser title, excusing himself on the ground that his life would be unsafe without an army at his back. Galerius, too distant to intervene, reluctantly recognized him as a “Caesar.” Constantine fought successfully against the invading Franks, and fed the beasts of the Gallic amphitheaters with barbarian kings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 CONSTANTINE AND CHRISTIANITY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/30_The_Triumph_of_Christianity_A_D_306-325/03_CONSTANTINE_AND_CHRISTIANITY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/30_The_Triumph_of_Christianity_A_D_306-325/03_CONSTANTINE_AND_CHRISTIANITY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Was his conversion sincere—was it an act of religious belief, or a consummate stroke of political wisdom? Probably the latter.33 His mother Helena had turned to Christianity when Constantius divorced her; presumably she had acquainted her son with the excellences of the Christian way; and doubtless he had been impressed by the invariable victory that had crowned his arms under the banner and cross of Christ. But only a skeptic would have made so subtle a use of the religious feelings of humanity. The &lt;em&gt;Historia Augusta&lt;/em&gt; quotes him as saying, “it is &lt;em&gt;Fortuna&lt;/em&gt; that makes a man emperor”34—though this was a bow to modesty rather than to chance. In his Gallic court he had surrounded himself with pagan scholars and philosophers.35 After his conversion he seldom conformed to the ceremonial requirements of Christian worship. His letters to Christian bishops make it clear that he cared little for the theological differences that agitated Christendom—though he was willing to suppress dissent in the interests of imperial unity. Throughout his reign he treated the bishops as his political aides; he summoned them, presided over their councils, and agreed to enforce whatever opinion their majority should formulate. A real believer would have been a Christian first and a statesman afterward; with Constantine it was the reverse. Christianity was to him a means, not an end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 CONSTANTINE AND CIVILIZATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/30_The_Triumph_of_Christianity_A_D_306-325/04_CONSTANTINE_AND_CIVILIZATION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/30_The_Triumph_of_Christianity_A_D_306-325/04_CONSTANTINE_AND_CIVILIZATION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A year after the Council Constantine dedicated, amid the desolation of Byzantium, a new city which he termed Nova Roma, and which posterity called by his name. In 330 he turned his back upon both Rome and Nicomedia, and made Constantinople his capital. There he surrounded himself with the impressive pomp of an Oriental court, feeling that its psychological influence upon army and people would make its expensive pageantry a subtle economy in government. He protected the army with able diplomacy and arms, tempered despotism with humane decrees, and lent his aid to letters and the arts. He encouraged the schools at Athens, and founded at Constantinople a new university where state-paid professors taught Greek and Latin, literature and philosophy, rhetoric and law, and trained officials for the Empire.52 He confirmed and extended the privileges of physicians and teachers in all provinces. Provincial governors were instructed to establish schools of architecture, and to draw students to them with divers privileges and rewards. Artists were exempted from civic obligations, so that they might have time to learn their art thoroughly and transmit it to their sons. The art treasures of the Empire were drawn upon to make Constantinople an elegant capital.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
