<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;1 The Deep History of Our Species on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/1_The_Deep_History_of_Our_Species/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;1 The Deep History of Our Species on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/1_The_Deep_History_of_Our_Species/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 How the Genome Explains Who We Are</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/1_The_Deep_History_of_Our_Species/1_How_the_Genome_Explains_Who_We_Are/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/1_The_Deep_History_of_Our_Species/1_How_the_Genome_Explains_Who_We_Are/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-master-chronicle-of-human-variation&#34;&gt;The Master Chronicle of Human Variation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To understand why genetics is able to shed light on the human past, it is necessary to understand how the genome—defined as the full set of genetic code each of us inherits from our parents—records information. Francis Crick, Rosalind Franklin, James Watson, and Maurice Wilkins showed in 1953 that the genome is written out in twin chains of about three billion chemical building blocks (six billion in all) that can be thought of as the letters of an alphabet: A (adenine), C (cytosine), G (guanine), and T (thymine).&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; What we call a “gene” consists of tiny fragments of these chains, typically around one thousand letters long, which are used as templates to assemble the proteins that do most of the work in cells. In between the genes is noncoding DNA, sometimes referred to as “junk” DNA. The order of the letters can be read by machines that perform chemical reactions on fragments of DNA, releasing flashes of light as the reactions pass along the length of the DNA sequence.+++(5)+++ The reactions emit a different color for each of the letters A, C, G, and T, so that the sequence of letters can be scanned into a computer by a camera.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Encounters with Neanderthals</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/1_The_Deep_History_of_Our_Species/2_Encounters_with_Neanderthals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/1_The_Deep_History_of_Our_Species/2_Encounters_with_Neanderthals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;../images/000031.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;../images/000031.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Age of Neanderthals&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Meeting of Neanderthals and Modern Humans&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, the particular subgroup of humans to which we belong—modern humans—is alone on our planet. We outcompeted or exterminated other humans, mostly during the period after around fifty thousand years ago when modern humans expanded throughout Eurasia and when major movements of humans likely happened within Africa too. Today, our closest living relatives are the African apes: the chimpanzees, bonobos, and gorillas, all incapable of making sophisticated tools or using conceptual language. But until around forty thousand years ago, the world was inhabited by multiple groups of archaic humans who differed from us physically but walked upright and shared many of our capabilities. The question that the archaeological record cannot answer—but the DNA record can—is how those archaic people were related to us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Ancient DNA Opens the Floodgates</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/1_The_Deep_History_of_Our_Species/3_Ancient_DNA_Opens_the_Floodgates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/1_The_Deep_History_of_Our_Species/3_Ancient_DNA_Opens_the_Floodgates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Surprise from the East&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2008, Russian archaeologists dug up a pinky bone at Denisova Cave in the Altai Mountains of southern Siberia, named after an eighteenth-century Russian hermit named Denis who had made his home there. The bone’s growth plates were not fused, showing that the bone came from a child. Its date was uncertain, as it was too small to be dated by radiocarbon analysis, and it was found in a mixed-up soil layer of the cave that contained artifacts dating to both less than thirty thousand and more than fifty thousand years ago. The leader of the excavation, Anatoly Derevianko, reasoned that the bone’s owner could have been a modern human, and the sample was so labeled. Alternatively, could the bone’s owner have been a Neanderthal, as Neanderthal remains were also found near the cave?1 Derevianko sent part of the bone to Svante Pääbo in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
