<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;volume 3 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;volume 3 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>170 BUDDHISTIC INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/170_buddhistic_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/170_buddhistic_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;buddhistic-india&#34;&gt;BUDDHISTIC INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Reproduced from the &lt;em&gt;Swami Vivekananda Centenary Memorial Volume&lt;/em&gt;,&#xA;published by the Swami Vivekananda Centenary, Calcutta, in 1963. The&#xA;additions in square brackets have been made for purposes of&#xA;clarification. Periods indicate probable omissions. — &lt;em&gt;Publisher&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at the Shakespeare Club, Pasadena, California, on February&#xA;2, 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Buddhistic India is our subject tonight. Almost all of you, perhaps,&#xA;have read Edwin Arnold&amp;rsquo;s poem on the life of Buddha, and some of you,&#xA;perhaps, have gone into the subject with more scholarly interest, as in&#xA;English, French and German, there is quite a lot of Buddhistic&#xA;literature. Buddhism itself is the most interesting of subjects, for it&#xA;is the first historical outburst of a world religion. There have been&#xA;great religions before Buddhism arose, in India and elsewhere, but, more&#xA;or less, they are confined within their own races. The ancient Hindus or&#xA;ancient Jews or ancient Persians, every one of them had a great&#xA;religion, but these religions were more or less racial. With Buddhism&#xA;first begins that peculiar phenomenon of religion boldly starting out to&#xA;conquer the world. Apart from its doctrines and the truths it taught and&#xA;the message it had to give, we stand face to face with one of the&#xA;tremendous cataclysms of the world. Within a few centuries of its birth,&#xA;the barefooted, shaven-headed missionaries of Buddha had spread over all&#xA;the then known civilised world, and they penetrated even further — from&#xA;Lapland on the one side to the Philippine Islands on the other. They had&#xA;spread widely within a few centuries of Buddha&amp;rsquo;s birth; and in India&#xA;itself, the religion of Buddha had at one time nearly swallowed up&#xA;two-thirds of the population.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
