<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apartment-transition</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/apartment-transition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/apartment-transition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There were enormous problems, especially in the early stages when we resettled farmers and others from almost rent-free wooden squatter huts with no water, power, or modern sanitation, and therefore no utility bills, into high-rise dwellings with all these amenities but also a monthly bill to pay. It was a wrenching experience for them in personal, social, and economic terms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Difficult adjustments were inevitable and there were comic, even absurd, results. Several pig farmers could not bear to part with their pigs and reared them in their high-rise apartments. Some were seen coaxing their pigs up the stairs! One family, a couple with 12 children moving from a hut to a new HDB apartment at Old Airport Road, brought a dozen chickens and ducks to rear in the kitchen. The mother built a wooden gate at the kitchen entrance to stop them from entering the living room. In the evenings, the children would look for earthworms and insects at the grass patches outdoors for feed. They did this for 10 years until they moved into another apartment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daoism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/daoism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/daoism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Daoism seems to be defined negatively: &amp;ldquo;any Chinese religious practise that is not Buddhist or Christian (etc)&amp;rdquo;. Deliverance Ceremonies presided by Quanzhen priests, worship of the local God of Earth, and seances where mediums channel the black and white guards of hell are all equally considered &amp;ldquo;Taoist&amp;rdquo; even though they are very different from one another.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anecdote from my older Singaporean relatives: In that country during the 1960s-1970s, there was a perception that Daoism was &amp;ldquo;Low class&amp;rdquo;&amp;ndash; associated with gaudy, and incomprehensible ceremonies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Religion 2021</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/religion_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/religion_2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some interesting findings on the Buddhist community in Singapore in the latest &amp;ldquo;Our Singaporean Values&amp;rdquo; survey by IPS (&lt;a href=&#34;https://lkyspp.nus.edu.sg/docs/default-source/ips/ips-exchange-series-16.pdf)&#34;&gt;https://lkyspp.nus.edu.sg/docs/default-source/ips/ips-exchange-series-16.pdf)&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most popular religion amongst the Chinese respondents was Buddhism, followed by Protestantism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over 90 per cent of Catholics, Protestants, Muslims, and Hindus; as well as over 80 per cent of Buddhists, Taoists and traditional Chinese belief adherents said they believed in God.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Non-religious, Taoist, and Buddhist respondents were more likely to believe in God if they were older.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Religion loss</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/religion-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/religion-loss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From @edwardW2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;factors-in-loss&#34;&gt;Factors in loss&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Evidently there has been a break in the transmission of the rituals. One of the main reasons as to why this break in transmission has occurred is probably&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1- a desire to moderinse things&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2- language&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There was a prejudice against the popular religion as being superstitious. As such, parents may not wish to transmit the meanings of the various rituals to their children— or abandon them entirely. In turn the children may be disinclined to believe or listen to what are in effect old wives tales; which, do recall, their parents may have never properly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reviving magic traditions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/reviving_magic-traditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/siMhapuram/articles/reviving_magic-traditions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Author: Edward W&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Chinese have several rituals when Moving into a new house. Apart from electing an auspicious date, the act of moving has rituals associated with it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of them is a ritual to rid the house of malefic spirits. Just before you enter the house officially, scatter a mixture of tea-leaves &amp;amp; salt in all the corners of the house. This ritual is so potent you should inform any gods that are found in the House’s altars before doing so.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
