<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;bjp and hindu resurgence on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;bjp and hindu resurgence on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00 Koenraad Elst</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/00_introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/00_introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     Many people inside or close to the BJP, and inside or close to&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the broader Sangh Parivar, have become dissatisfied with what they&#xA;perceive as the increasing distance between the BJP&amp;rsquo;s actual policies&#xA;and the Hindu expectations among the public on which the party&#xA;capitalizes.  To some extent, the problem lies with the BJP itself,&#xA;distinguishing it from other Hindutva organizations, who then tend to&#xA;blame the increasing non-Sangh element inside the BJP for this&#xA;&amp;ldquo;degeneration&amp;rdquo;, especially the opportunists who jumped onto the&#xA;promising BJP bandwagon after the 1989 and 1991 electoral&#xA;breakthroughs.  To a large extent, however, the BJP problem is the RSS&#xA;problem.  In the BJP, the RSS approach is put to the test of day-to-day&#xA;political practice, in confrontation with the enemies of Hindutva,&#xA;without the benefit of the secretiveness which characterizes the&#xA;functioning of other Sangh-affiliated organizations.  Except for the&#xA;recent defection and corruption scandals, the major failures of the BJP&#xA;can be traced to RSS policies and RSS ideological conditioning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 1. Anything but a &#34;Hindu&#34; party</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/01_section1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/01_section1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Anything but a &amp;ldquo;Hindu&amp;rdquo; party&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The strange thing about the BJP is that its voters consider it a Hindu&#xA;party, its enemies denounce it as a Hindu party, but the party will call&#xA;itself anything except a Hindu party.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     Unlike most critics of the BJP, who tend to make their point by&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;quoting sources openly hostile to the party, we should prove our case by&#xA;going to its own formulations of its ideology.  To summarize the&#xA;ideological positions of the BJP and its former avatar, the BJS&#xA;(Bharatiya Jana Sangh), from authentic sources, we will reproduce the&#xA;brief professions of ideological commitment given in the Constitutions&#xA;of the BJS (1973) and of the BJP (1992).  The summary given in the BJS&#xA;Constitution under the heading &amp;ldquo;Aims and Objectives in Brief&amp;rdquo;, a&#xA;programme to which all BJS party members pledged their loyalty, are as&#xA;follows (we give it in its entirety, but change the order so as to group&#xA;the different points under headings of our own making):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 2. &#34;Equal respect for all religions&#34;</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/02_section2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/02_section2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. &amp;ldquo;Equal respect for all religions&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     The only explicitly Indian contribution in the cited BJS/BJP&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;self-declarations is of doubtful value: &amp;ldquo;positive secularism&amp;rdquo; defined as&#xA;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;sarva-dharma-samabhava&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;equal respect for all religions&amp;rdquo;.  We let&#xA;the difference with the original European concept of secularism (equal&#xA;&lt;em&gt;indifference&lt;/em&gt; towards all religions, equal &lt;em&gt;independence&lt;/em&gt; from all&#xA;religions) pass, and focus on the problematic meaning of the slogan&#xA;defining this &amp;ldquo;positive secularism&amp;rdquo;.  Two meanings are attested: the&#xA;political meaning apparently given to it in the cited BJP texts, viz.&#xA;that the state must be equidistant from Hinduism, Islam, Christianity&#xA;and any other religion; and the religious meaning given to it by Mahatma&#xA;Gandhi and his followers, viz. that a religious person should have equal&#xA;respect for Hinduism, Islam etc., because all these religions are&#xA;equally good and satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 3. What is Wrong with &#34;Hindu&#34;?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/03_section3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/03_section3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What is Wrong with &amp;ldquo;Hindu&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     To an extent, the avoidance of the term &amp;quot;Hindu&amp;quot; has&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;characterized many earlier avatars of Hindu nationalism.  Sri Aurobindo&#xA;titled his newspaper &amp;ldquo;Arya&amp;rdquo;, and declared that India would rise with&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Sanatana Dharma&amp;rdquo;, a more profound term than the colloquial &amp;ldquo;Hinduism&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;The Arya Samaj preferred the term &amp;ldquo;Vedic&amp;rdquo;, or the Vedic term &amp;ldquo;Arya&amp;rdquo;&#xA;(denoting adherence to Vedic civilizational standards), to the&#xA;originally purely geographical Persian term &amp;ldquo;Hindu&amp;rdquo;.  Moreover, &amp;ldquo;Hindu&amp;rdquo;&#xA;was a catch-all term which included traditions considered deviant or&#xA;non-Vedic by the Arya Samaj (esp. Puranic, Tantric); in the 1881 census,&#xA;the Arya Samaj even advised its members to register as non-Hindus.  This&#xA;policy was reversed for the 1901 census, but in the 1980s, some Arya&#xA;Samaj factions again made attempts to be recognized as a non-Hindu&#xA;minority.  By then, the term &amp;ldquo;Hindu&amp;rdquo; had not only become a distinctly&#xA;dirty word, but also carried constitutional disadvantages with it (cfr.&#xA;infra).  In the same period, and for the same conformist and opportunist&#xA;reasons, the Ramakrishna Mission unsuccessfully tried to get registered&#xA;as a new non-Hindu religion called Ramakrishnaism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 4. The BJP flag</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/04_section4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/04_section4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. The BJP flag&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     A &amp;quot;Hindu&amp;quot; or non-Hindu party name would matter little if the&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;policies behind it would be the right ones, but as we shall demonstrate,&#xA;the avoidance of a Hindu self‑designation goes hand in hand with the&#xA;avoidance of certain pressing Hindu concerns in the party&amp;rsquo;s policies.&#xA;While we are discussing the party&amp;rsquo;s self‑presentation, we may add to our&#xA;doubts about the chosen name, the question of the party&amp;rsquo;s flag.  Many&#xA;party workers are embarrassed with the green-saffron flag, and I want to&#xA;give a voice to their misgivings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 5. How the Rama card was thrown away</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/05_section5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/05_section5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. How the Rama card was thrown away&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     Ever since the demolition of the Babri Masjid on 6 December&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1996, the BJP has as silent as possible on the Ayodhya issue.  It is&#xA;just too embarrassed, and avoids mentioning the very name of Ayodhya or&#xA;Rama.  On 17 December 1992 already, A.B. Vajpayee declared in the Lok&#xA;Sabha: &amp;ldquo;We are very sad at what happened in Ayodhya on the 6th&#xA;December.&amp;rdquo;  L.K. Advani, who had been the front man of the Ayodhya&#xA;movement until he broke down in tears at the sight of the demolition,&#xA;had narrowly succeeded in making a dignified statement during his first&#xA;press meet after the demolition (thanks to the insistent prodding of one&#xA;of his well-wishers who merely happened to be present, and who convinced&#xA;Advani to replace the weak and apologetic statement which his assistant&#xA;had prepared with a better one), but more recently he too joined&#xA;Vajpayee in dismissing the historic event as a &amp;ldquo;Himalayan blunder&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 6. Sangh Parivar, the last Gandhians</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/06_section6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/06_section6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Sangh Parivar, the last Gandhians&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     When in 1980, the secularist tendency led by Nana Deshmukh and&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Atal Behari Vajpayee imposed &amp;ldquo;Gandhian socialism&amp;rdquo; on the newly founded&#xA;BJP as its official ideology, all the establishment secularists laughed&#xA;at this transparent attempt to acquire a new secular&#xA;identity.&lt;a href=&#34;#_edn1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;  &amp;ldquo;This party is neither Gandhian nor&#xA;socialist&amp;rdquo;, they said.  The party was in fact more socialist than it&#xA;would like to admit after liberalization became the new orthodoxy,&#xA;certainly more socialist than the non-socialist &amp;ldquo;cleverest bourgeois&#xA;scoundrel&amp;rdquo; Gandhi ever was, but we can agree that it was less socialist&#xA;than was normative in 1980.  What interests us more, is whether the BJP,&#xA;always accused of having historical links with Gandhi&amp;rsquo;s assassin, can&#xA;legitimately be called Gandhian.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 7. Gandhian non-violence</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/07_section7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/07_section7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Gandhian non-violence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     One point where the BJP seems to be decidedly un-Gandhian is&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;defence policy.  Whereas Gandhi had advocated a strictly non-violent&#xA;strategy including an unarmed defence against the impending Japanese&#xA;invasion, the BJP advocates a strong defence capability including&#xA;weapons of mass destruction.  Yet, even here the BJP is more Gandhian&#xA;than one would expect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     The famous quotation of Mahatma Gandhi on Hindu cowards and&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Muslim bullies deserves to be read in full: &amp;ldquo;There is no doubt in my&#xA;mind that in the majority of quarrels the Hindus come out second best.&#xA;But my own experience confirms the opinion that the Mussalman as a rule&#xA;is a bully, and the Hindu as a rule is a coward.  I have noticed this in&#xA;railway trains, on public roads, and in the quarrels which I had the&#xA;privilege of settling.  Need the Hindu blame the Mussalman for his&#xA;cowardice?  Where there are cowards, there will always be bullies.  They&#xA;say that in Saharanpur the Mussalmans looted houses, broke open safes&#xA;and, in one case, a Hindu woman&amp;rsquo;s modesty was outraged.  Whose fault was&#xA;this?  Mussalmans can offer no defence for the execrable conduct, it is&#xA;true.  But I, as a Hindu, am more ashamed of Hindu cowardice than I am&#xA;angry at the Mussalman bullying.  Why did not the owners of the houses&#xA;looted die in the attempt to defend their possessions?  Where were the&#xA;relatives of the outraged sister at the time of the outrage?  Have they&#xA;no account to render of themselves?  My non-violence does not admit of&#xA;running away from danger and leaving dear ones unprotected.  Between&#xA;violence and cowardly flight, I can only prefer violence to&#xA;cowardice.&amp;rdquo;&lt;a href=&#34;#_edn1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 8. The Sangh&#39;s anti-intellectualism </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/08_section8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/08_section8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. The Sangh&amp;rsquo;s anti-intellectualism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     A very serious flaw which Gandhians and the Sangh have in&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;common is their anti-intellectualism.  Though Gandhi reputedly rebuked&#xA;RSS founder K.B. Hedgewar for not publishing any doctrinal statements,&#xA;i.e. for not giving any intellectual articulation to his nationalist&#xA;movement, he essentially shared Hedgewar&amp;rsquo;s aversion for an intellectual&#xA;job well done.  Both of them made people march many miles, both led&#xA;their followers to make great sacrifices, and both failed to&#xA;substantially raise their followers&amp;rsquo; political understanding.  They did&#xA;not bother to educate them (and themselves) in analyzing the character&#xA;of the different forces in the field, all on the plea that &amp;ldquo;an ounce of&#xA;practice is worth more than a ton of theory&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 9. The Sangh as dinosaur </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/09_section9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/09_section9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. The Sangh as dinosaur&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     The anti-intellectualism of the Sangh Parivar is a sufficiently&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;serious problem to warrant a closer discussion.  The situation on the&#xA;ground is that RSS men seldom sit down to do any thinking, but are&#xA;always on the move.  As a US-based Hindutva activist told me: &amp;ldquo;When I&#xA;make a phone call to an RSS office-bearer in India, he will most often&#xA;not be in the Delhi office, not in Nagpur or another town, but somewhere&#xA;on the way.&amp;rdquo;  And the wife of a BJP stalwart told me: &amp;ldquo;Being on the way&#xA;from one place to another is a status symbol among RSS men.&amp;rdquo;  With all&#xA;this physical locomotion, little time and occasion is left for&#xA;concentrated mental work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 10. Anti-intellectualism in action</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/10_section10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/10_section10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Anti-intellectualism in action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     The two most important consequences of the anti-intellectual&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;prejudice animating the Sangh are, firstly, an extreme ineptness at&#xA;public relations, and secondly, the stunted development of the Sangh&#xA;Parivar&amp;rsquo;s own intellectual grip on the world.  An example of the first&#xA;is the staggering failure of the Hindu campaign reclaiming Ayodhya to&#xA;communicate its case to the world, as already discussed.  The worst part&#xA;of it is not that the Sangh people failed to communicate the Hindu case&#xA;(the biased press was indeed a formidable obstacle), but that it never&#xA;took the trouble of verifying whether its message came across nor of&#xA;devising ways to deal with the hostile climate in the media and among&#xA;India-watchers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 11. &#34;I am a Hindu communalist&#34;</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/11_section11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/11_section11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11. &amp;ldquo;I am a Hindu communalist&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     A symptom of the ideological power equation is the Sangh&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Parivar&amp;rsquo;s permanent checkmate in the &amp;ldquo;war of the words&amp;rdquo;.  The Sangh is&#xA;at the mercy of the meanings which its enemies allot to important terms,&#xA;such as &amp;ldquo;communalism&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     Originally (at least in Indian politics), &amp;quot;communal&amp;quot; was the&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;term by which the British labelled political arrangements, such as&#xA;separate electorates and quota-based recruitment, which took the&#xA;religious community as the operative unit rather than the individual or&#xA;the family or the region or the nation.  The term was never hurled at&#xA;people who rejected these arrangements, but was quite sincerely accepted&#xA;by the people who proposed the &amp;ldquo;communalization&amp;rdquo; of the polity: the&#xA;British and the Muslim League advocated it openly, the Congress started&#xA;defending it after becoming a party to it through the Lucknow Pact&#xA;(1916).  When the British proposed the Communal Award, its beneficiaries&#xA;never thought of treating &amp;ldquo;communal&amp;rdquo; as a dirty word and throwing it at&#xA;the Communal Award&amp;rsquo;s opponents.  Today, by contrast, the mores of&#xA;discourse have sunk to the level where politicans and journalists and&#xA;scholars systematically apply the term to a movement which never used it&#xA;as a description of its own positions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 12. Vulgar nationalism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/12_section12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/12_section12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12. Vulgar nationalism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     A consequence of this lack of self-developed understanding of&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the forces in the field is that the Sangh is not able to discern&#xA;objective allies and enemies on the world stage, so that it is unable to&#xA;make friends.  E.g., after liberalization and globalization became hot&#xA;items, the Sangh Parivar including the BJP has been multiplying and&#xA;intensifying its attacks on the USA.  Time and again, Hindutva spokesmen&#xA;have been presenting the impersonal process of globalization as an&#xA;American ploy to take over the world (just as Westerners once depicted&#xA;earlier developments in capitalism as Jewish conspiracies to dispossess&#xA;the workers and smallholders).  Much of their anti-Americanism could&#xA;have been borrowed quite literally from Leftist pamphlets of yesteryear,&#xA;some of it also from Ayatollah Khomeini&amp;rsquo;s speeches; the only thing&#xA;missing is the &amp;ldquo;Great Satan&amp;rdquo; label.  Meanwhile, these Hindutva exegetes&#xA;of the globalization conspiracy have not even bothered to notice that in&#xA;the USA itself, globalization is being criticized both from the Left and&#xA;the Right.  This movement spurns its potential friends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 13. Hindutva and other peoples&#39; nationalism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/13_section13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/13_section13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13. Hindutva and other peoples&amp;rsquo; nationalism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     The BJP&#39;s subordination of any and every ideological or&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;religious conflict to questions of &amp;ldquo;national unity and integrity&amp;rdquo;, this&#xA;most mindless form of territorial nationalism, is also a worrying&#xA;retreat from the historical Hindu conception of Indian nationhood and&#xA;its implications for the evaluation of foreign problems of national&#xA;unity.  Along with Mahatma Gandhi and other Freedom Fighters, the BJS&#xA;used to be convinced that India was a self-conscious civilizational unit&#xA;since several thousands of years, strengthened in its realization of&#xA;unity by the Sanskrit language, the Brahmin caste, the pilgrimage cycles&#xA;which brought pilgrims from every part of India all around the country&#xA;(&amp;ldquo;country&amp;rdquo; rather than the &amp;ldquo;Subcontinent&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;South Asia&amp;rdquo;, terms which&#xA;intrinsically question this unity), and other socio-cultural factors of&#xA;national integration.  The notions that India was an artificial creation&#xA;of the British and a &amp;ldquo;nation in the making&amp;rdquo;, were floated by the British&#xA;themselves and by Jawaharlal Nehru, respectively, and both are obvious&#xA;cases of unfounded self-flattery.  Gandhi&amp;rsquo;s and the BJS&amp;rsquo;s viewpoint that&#xA;India is an ancient nation conscious of its own unity is historically&#xA;more accurate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 14. The Sangh&#39;s Muslims</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/14_section14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/14_section14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14. The Sangh&amp;rsquo;s Muslims&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     In criticizing the Sangh&#39;s simplistic anti-Americanism, I am&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;not holding a brief for American foreign policy.  The &lt;em&gt;Organiser&lt;/em&gt; is&#xA;entirely right in arguing that American officials are being extremely&#xA;silly when they base their policies on the assumption that Pakistan is a&#xA;bulwark &lt;em&gt;against&lt;/em&gt; (rather than &lt;em&gt;of&lt;/em&gt;) Islamic fundamentalism.  But this&#xA;mistake is hardly typically American: in &lt;em&gt;Organiser&lt;/em&gt; itself, columnists&#xA;play the same game of labelling Muslim entities, without asking their&#xA;consent, as bulwarks against Islamic fanaticism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 15. A party of shopkeepers</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/15_section15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/15_section15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15. A party of shopkeepers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     The BJP eagerly wants to be friends with everyone who counts as&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;respectable.  The best predictor of their positions in upcoming&#xA;political issues is: what will the opinion-making establishment say?&#xA;When new fads appear on the public scene, whether it is the Ambedkar&#xA;cult or reservations for women in Parliament, the BJP is sure to pick&#xA;them up in due course.&lt;a href=&#34;#_edn1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;  Instead of radicalism, the record&#xA;of its manifestoes, resolutions, interventions in parliament, and public&#xA;statements, shows a goody-goody approach to all the forces which are&#xA;animated by a declared and unyielding hatred of the BJP.  This may have&#xA;something to do with the party&amp;rsquo;s castewise roots.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 16. Things to do for the BJP</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/16_section16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/16_section16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16. Things to do for the BJP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     The cleverness of the BJP is in evidence again in its choice to&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;put the enactment of a Common Civil Code on India&amp;rsquo;s political agenda.&#xA;In India, marriage, divorce and inheritance are regulated by&#xA;religion-based law codes which are different for Hindus, Muslims,&#xA;Christians and Parsis.  Thus, a Hindu who wants to marry two women,&#xA;knows that he will be punishable, but no longer if he converts to Islam&#xA;(which is why there are actual cases of conversion for the sake of&#xA;bigamy).  For Christian men and women, divorce laws are equal but make&#xA;it very difficult to obtain a divorce.  For Hindus, it is a bit easier,&#xA;but divorce is the easiest by far for Muslim men, who only have to&#xA;pronounce triple &lt;em&gt;talaq&lt;/em&gt;; Muslim women, by contrast, have to plead their&#xA;case before a judge.  This totally non-secular arrangement was meant to&#xA;be only temporary, for the Constitution stipulates in its directive&#xA;principles (Art. 44) that the State shall endeavour to enact a Common&#xA;Civil Code.  In 1995, the Supreme Court reminded the Government of this&#xA;directive principle, and directed it to report on the progress made in&#xA;the matter.  The BJP has replaced Ayodhya with the Common Civil Code as&#xA;its central &amp;ldquo;communal&amp;rdquo; theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 17. Christ in India</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/17_section17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/17_section17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17. Christ in India&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     The Sangh is even less combative vis-à-vis Christianity than&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;vis-à-vis Islam.  The Christian Churches must be counted among&#xA;Hindutva&amp;rsquo;s most determined enemies.  Much of the negative image which&#xA;the BJP has acquired internationally is due to the lasting powerful&#xA;impact of the Churches on the information stream concerning the Third&#xA;World.  In quarrels between the Hindutva forces and the Muslims or the&#xA;secularists, the Christian institutions are invariably on the anti-Hindu&#xA;side.  There are also Christian armed separatist movements in Nagaland&#xA;and Mizoram, which are openly supported by the World Council of Churches&#xA;and by a number of Catholic institutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 18. Hindus wielding the sword of Islam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/18_section18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/18_section18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18. Hindus wielding the sword of Islam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     When Akbar had Rajput armies fight his Rajput enemies, he&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;rejoiced at the sight of &amp;ldquo;Hindus wielding the sword of Islam&amp;rdquo;.  When his&#xA;archers could not distinguish between the Rajput mercenaries and the&#xA;Rajput freedom-fighters, he told them that it didn&amp;rsquo;t matter, since&#xA;anyone killed would be a Kafir anyway.  India&amp;rsquo;s greatest Moghul is often&#xA;mindlessly lauded by Hindus as a &amp;ldquo;secular&amp;rdquo; ruler, but while he should be&#xA;credited with a certain wisdom, he was and remained an enemy of the&#xA;Infidels.  Unlike the Delhi sultans, who constantly provoked Hindu&#xA;uprisings with their cruel politics of jihad (apart from weakening&#xA;themselves with their internecine fighting), Akbar managed to&#xA;&lt;em&gt;consolidate a Muslim empire&lt;/em&gt; by incorporating a sufficient number of&#xA;Hindus in his apparatus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 19. How not to deal with Islam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/19_section19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/19_section19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19. How not to deal with Islam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     When dealing with Islam, it is crucially important to keep in&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;mind the distinction between Islam as a doctrine and the Muslims, a&#xA;group of people who were born or tricked into an Islamic environment.&#xA;There is nothing intrinsically Islamic about human beings, not even when&#xA;they are named Mohammed or Aisha.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     In Europe, the secularist Left accuses the mushrooming&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;national‑populist and xenophobic parties of a &amp;ldquo;biologization of cultural&#xA;differences&amp;rdquo;.  When the said parties plead that they have put &amp;ldquo;racism&amp;rdquo;&#xA;behind them, that they have nothing against coloured people or&#xA;foreigners per se, and that they only fear for social disharmony as a&#xA;consequence of the co‑existence of European and immigrant &lt;em&gt;cultures&lt;/em&gt;,&#xA;their opponents rightly argue that this implies a belief in the&#xA;permanent character of people&amp;rsquo;s cultural identity.  By assuming that&#xA;immigrant foreigners are bound to remain culturally foreign, the&#xA;xenophobes treat cultural identity as if it were a racial&#xA;characteristic: a permanent and hereditary trait.  In reality, of&#xA;course, cultural identities change, e.g. most second‑generation Hindu&#xA;immigrants have moved rather closely towards the mainstream culture of&#xA;their adopted countries.  Cultural identity including religion is not a&#xA;permanent or hereditary trait.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 20. How to deal with Islam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/20_section20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/20_section20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20. How to deal with Islam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     The &amp;quot;communal&amp;quot; problem is simple, and so is its solution.  The&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;root cause of communal riots, of the Partition with its nearly a million&#xA;victims, and of the East Bengal genocide with its three million victims,&#xA;is the Islamic doctrine of permanent hostility against the&#xA;unbelievers.&lt;a href=&#34;#_edn1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;  As the Quran says: &amp;ldquo;Fight them until&#xA;idolatry is no more and religion belongs to Allah alone&amp;rdquo; (2:193 and&#xA;8:39), and: &amp;ldquo;Enmity and hate shall reign between us until ye believe in&#xA;Allah alone&amp;rdquo; (60:4).  More than 70 passages in the Quran teach that&#xA;non-Muslims are to be shunned and treated as enemies, that they are&#xA;bound for hellfire, and that rulership in this and bliss in the next&#xA;world is reserved for Muslims alone.  This body of doctrine is further&#xA;corroborated and enriched with like-minded statements and model acts of&#xA;Mohammed and his companions, and systematized by theologians and&#xA;jurists.  The solution is obvious: remove the intrinsically communal and&#xA;separatist doctrine of Islam from the minds of its misguided followers.&#xA;Educate them so that they can laugh at the primitive beliefs which have&#xA;held them captive for so long, just as adults can take a laugh at their&#xA;own childhood illusions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 21. Know the truth, and the truth shall make you free</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/21_section21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/21_section21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21. Know the truth, and the truth shall make you free&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     The struggle against Islamic aggression cannot be won without&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;taking issue with the basic doctrines of Islam, i.e. explaining to the&#xA;Muslims that they have no reason to stay with the refuted dogmas of&#xA;Islam.  The same is true for Christianity.  The Sangh Parivar has made&#xA;much ado about the Christian demand for reservations for &amp;ldquo;Christian&#xA;Dalits&amp;rdquo;, and about continuing Christian proselytization in tribal&#xA;areas.  It is, however, impossible to sustain this objection against the&#xA;strategies of evangelization as long as Christianity is accepted as a&#xA;valid religion qualified to enjoy the Hindus&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;sarva-dharma-samabhava&lt;/em&gt;.&#xA;Why in the world should Indian citizens not embrace Christianity if it&#xA;is true, at least &amp;ldquo;equally true&amp;rdquo; with Hinduism?  Especially now that&#xA;Christianity in India has largely &amp;ldquo;indianized&amp;rdquo; itself in its cultural&#xA;expressions (e.g. by giving Hindu first names to their children), the&#xA;Sangh should not object to conversions to Christianity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 22. Hindu objections</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/22_section22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/22_section22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22. Hindu objections&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     A Hindu policy of ideological confrontation with hostile&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;religions is necessary for the survival of India as an essentially Hindu&#xA;country.  After having flattered Christianity and Islam for several&#xA;centuries, Hindus inside and outside the Sangh may come up with many&#xA;objections against such a policy.  As a BJP man once told me: &amp;ldquo;When we&#xA;attack Christianity, it is not the Christians who leave us &amp;ndash; they are&#xA;not with us anyway &amp;ndash;, it is the Hindus who won&amp;rsquo;t vote for us.&amp;rdquo;  This&#xA;much is certainly true, that the rotten sentimentalism of &amp;ldquo;equal truth&#xA;of all religions&amp;rdquo; has gone fairly deep into the Hindu psyche.  Before&#xA;explaining anything to Christians and Muslims, the true story must be&#xA;explained to Hindus, whose obstinate self-deception is the greatest&#xA;obstacle to Hindu liberation.  While Muslims consider it only logical&#xA;that non-Muslims disbelieve Islam&amp;rsquo;s defining dogmas, Hindus can get&#xA;quite indignant when someone dares to say that the Islamic creed is&#xA;wrong (more than when he scolds and ridicules Hinduism).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 23. Conclusion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/23_section23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/23_section23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23. Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     In spite of Hinduism&#39;s nominal magnitude, the chance that&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hinduism gets wiped out by its enemies can no longer be discounted.&#xA;More than ever, fortunes are spent on the war to destroy Hinduism in&#xA;favour of Islam or some suitably adapted variety of Christianity or&#xA;Marxism.  The hostile activities of Islamic and Christian agitators and&#xA;the attempts at Hindu demoralization and loss of Hindu self-respect by&#xA;the secularists are now compounded by a fast-spreading loss of Hindu&#xA;memory at the mass level by consumerism and Western pulp media.  I have&#xA;seen with my own eyes how local cultures within European civilization&#xA;are being as good as wiped out in a few decades by the onslaught of&#xA;mindless &amp;ldquo;Americanism&amp;rdquo;, and this loss of cultural roots is a major&#xA;factor in the current defencelessness of the affected populations&#xA;vis-à-vis the rising threat of Islam.  Hindus would be mistaken to think&#xA;that this cannot happen to their old civilization; most civilizations at&#xA;the time of their demise were old and venerable.  For Hinduism too, time&#xA;is running out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/24_appendix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/elst/bjp_and_hindu_resurgence/24_appendix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;appendix-a-reply-to-kanchan-gupta&#34;&gt;Appendix: A Reply to Kanchan Gupta&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     On 14 and 15 January 1997, the *Observer of Business and&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Politics* published a reply by Kanchan Gupta to my own two-part article,&#xA;&amp;ldquo;BJP retreat on Ayodhya&amp;rdquo;, on which the present booklet is based.  I do&#xA;not know what Kanchan Gupta&amp;rsquo;s exact relation with the BJP is; I have met&#xA;him several times at the BJP office and assume that he is a BJP&#xA;supporter though not from an RSS background.  It deserves mention and&#xA;praise that the article is polite and to the point, two qualities which&#xA;are the exception rather than the rule in communalism-related debates in&#xA;India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
