<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Kennan - cragged hill on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Kennan - cragged hill on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/00/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/00/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;books-by-george-f-kennan&#34;&gt;BOOKS BY GEORGE F. KENNAN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;American Diplomacy, 1900–1950&lt;/em&gt; (1951)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Realities of American Foreign Policy&lt;/em&gt; (1954)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Soviet-American Relations, 1917–1920&lt;/em&gt; (2 vols., 1956–58)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Russia, the Atom, and the West&lt;/em&gt; (1958)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Russia and the West under Lenin and Stalin&lt;/em&gt; (1961)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Memoirs, 1925–1950&lt;/em&gt; (1967)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Prague after Munich: Diplomatic Papers, 1938–1940&lt;/em&gt; (1968)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Marquis de Custine and His “Russia in 1839”&lt;/em&gt; (1971)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Memoirs, 1950–1963&lt;/em&gt; (1972)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Decline of Bismarck’s European Order: Franco-Russian Relations, 1875–1890&lt;/em&gt; (1979)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 MAN, THE CRACKED VESSEL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/01_MAN_THE_CRACKED_VESSEL/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/01_MAN_THE_CRACKED_VESSEL/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(PART ONE)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They sneer at me for leaning all awry:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What! did the Hand then of the Potter shake?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—Omar Khayyám, &lt;em&gt;Rubáiyát&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;M&lt;/em&gt;an, to the degree that he tries to shape his behavior to the requirements of civilization, is unquestionably a cracked vessel. His nature is the scene of a never-ending and never quite resolvable conflict between two very profound impulses. One of these, built into him from birth and not a matter of his own choice, is something he shares with the animals: namely, the imperative impulse to preserve and proliferate his own kind, with all the powerful compulsions that engenders. The other is the need—a need underlying the entire historical development of civilization—to redeem human life, at least partially, of its essentially animalistic origins by lending to it such attributes as order, dignity, beauty, and charity—this last meaning the love of or at least the respect for one’s fellow man, and the capacity for compassion. A central feature of the human predicament is the conflict between these so frequently conflicting impulses—a conflict for which man’s own soul constitutes the field of battle.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 FAITH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/02_FAITH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/02_FAITH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I sing the progresse of a deathlesse soule,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whom Fate, which God made, but doth not controule,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Plac’d in most shapes;. . .&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—John Donne, &lt;em&gt;Metempsychosis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;T&lt;/em&gt;here may be some, I suppose, who will say, Why, these limitations you have been talking about, these imperfections and contradictions in the nature and situation of the human individual—these are merely expressions of “original sin,” of the ineradicable taint imposed upon all future humanity by the disobedience of Adam and Eve in their tasting of the forbidden fruit that offered the knowledge of good and evil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 ON GOVERNMENT AND GOVERNMENTS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/03_ON_GOVERNMENT_AND_GOVERNMENTS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/03_ON_GOVERNMENT_AND_GOVERNMENTS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cromwell, I charge thee, fling away ambition;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By that sin fell the angels; how can man then,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The image of his maker, hope to win by’t?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—Shakespeare, &lt;em&gt;Henry VIII&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-necessity&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Necessity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Government is a universal feature of civilized life. Whatever the form it takes, however liberal or oppressive it may be, however large or small the community to which its power extends, government is an absolute necessity. Its adoption or acceptance is not, therefore, a matter of deliberate choice. The only conceivable alternative would be a state of anarchy which would constitute self-destruction for the community in question—which is, in effect, no choice at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 THE NATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/04_THE_NATION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/04_THE_NATION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is beyond doubt is that the [nationalist] doctrine divides humanity into separate and distinct nations, claims that such nations must constitute sovereign states, and asserts that the members of a nation reach freedom and fulfillment by cultivating the peculiar identity of their own nation and by sinking their own persons in the greater whole of the nation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—E. Kedourie, &lt;em&gt;Nationalism&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;T&lt;/em&gt;here seems to have been, from time untold, a universal need for people to feel themselves a part of something larger than themselves, and larger than just the family. Sometimes, in the more distant past, it has been the tribe, or, in other instances, the native valley, or a religious association, or membership in a given caste. In the modern world it is the nation—the country—the social, cultural, and political unit in which one was born and brought up or in which, by the force of circumstances, one has been extensively acclimatized. For most of us, particularly in America, it seems self-evident that the nation is the entity in which all political life should proceed—that it is within the national framework that the process of government should take place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 IDEOLOGY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/05_IDEOLOGY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/05_IDEOLOGY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ideology&lt;/strong&gt;, a systematic body of beliefs about the structure and working of society that includes a program of practical politics based on a comprehensive theory of human nature and requiring a protracted social struggle to enact.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;—The New Encyclopaedia Britannica&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;mong the reproaches that have been leveled against me for failing to make clear my various philosophical views or commitments are those that have centered on the questions of “ideology.” These place me in some difficulty, for they bring up the question of what an ideology really is; and this propels me at once into that laborious search for categories and for the meanings of abstract words and concepts which, as it seems to me, attends all philosophical exploration and which is foreign, I am afraid, to my world of thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 EGALITARIANISM AND DIVERSITY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/06_EGALITARIANISM_AND_DIVERSITY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/06_EGALITARIANISM_AND_DIVERSITY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The distinction of ranks and &lt;em&gt;persons&lt;/em&gt; is the firmest basis of a mixed and limited government. . . . The perfect equality of men is the point in which the extremes of democracy and despotism are confounded. . ..&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—Edward Gibbon, &lt;em&gt;The Decline and Fall of the Roman Empire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;O&lt;/em&gt;ne of the difficulties in writing such a book as this lies in the problem of classification. Because the effort is addressed to very broad concepts, vague at the edges and often intertwining and interlocking, it is hard to find clear divisions between one concept and another. One can only plunge headlong into this subject matter, hoping that the reader will himself perceive the interrelationships among the various headings and topics and will discern something of the broad unity of philosophical concept that presumably unites them all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 DIMENSIONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/07_DIMENSIONS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/07_DIMENSIONS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;. . . too many of us.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—the author (see below)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;T&lt;/em&gt;he next of the situations in American life which I should like to mention, and the one to which the remainder of this chapter will be devoted, relates primarily to the size and populousness of the country. If I were to be asked by a foreigner what strikes me most about my own people, two points, I think, would come most readily to mind: first, that we are a nation of bad social habits and, second, that there are far too many of us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 THE ADDICTIONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/08_THE_ADDICTIONS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/08_THE_ADDICTIONS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is not our affluence, or our plumbing, or our clogged highways that grip the imagination of others. Rather, it is the values on which our system is built. These values imply our adherence not only to liberty and individual freedom, but also to international peace, law and order, and constructive social purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—William Fulbright, speaking in the U.S. Senate in 1961&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; expressed, in chapter 3, the confidence I share with so many other Americans in the general form of government established by the American Constitution, and my preference for this form of government, with the various checks and balances and assurances against distortion into oppressive rule that it contains, over other forms of government that do not provide comparable safeguards. To have this confidence and this preference is not, however, to assume that this form of government could not be affected by radical changes in the technological and social environment in which our society is called upon to function; and it is not to say that to meet these changes successfully would not call for adjustments in existing governmental outlooks and policies. When problems arise in the life of a nation of such seriousness that they seem to jeopardize its very future and to undermine the confidence of a great many of its citizens in the soundness of its political institutions, and when the government confesses itself, explicitly or implicitly, unable to cope successfully with these problems, then one has no choice but to question the adequacy of Western democracy itself, as we know it, for responding successfully to the changing environmental conditions in which it is obliged to exist.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 FOREIGN POLICY, NONMILITARY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/09_FOREIGN_POLICY_NONMILITARY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/09_FOREIGN_POLICY_NONMILITARY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I do not say that we ought to prefer the happiness of one particular society to the happiness of mankind; but I say that, by exerting ourselves to promote the happiness of the society with which we are most nearly connected, and with which we are best acquainted, we shall do more to promote the happiness of mankind than by busying ourselves about matters which we do not understand and cannot efficiently control.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 FOREIGN POLICY, MILITARY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/10_FOREIGN_POLICY_MILITARY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/10_FOREIGN_POLICY_MILITARY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not until statesmen had at last perceived the nature of the forces that had emerged in France, and had grasped that new political conditions now obtained in Europe, could they foresee the broad effect all this would have on war; and only in that way could they appreciate the scale of the means that would have to be employed, and how best to apply them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—Clausewitz, on the military consequences of the French Revolution&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 WHAT IS TO BE DONE?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/11_WHAT_IS_TO_BE_DONE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/11_WHAT_IS_TO_BE_DONE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;. . . the advantage, even the necessity, of having somewhere in the state a person beyond the competition for office, who is entitled to be heard in any matter on which he may think it his duty to speak; who has the right to warn, to encourage, and therefore, to be consulted by, the agents of authority.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;G. M. Young,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Victorian England: Portrait of an Age&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-problem&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Problem&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It should be clear, even from what little was said above about our national problems, that there are a number of these problems with which the political system of the country has not been coping successfully, and where there is little reason to hope, as things stand today, that it will cope more successfully in the future. There is no need to attempt to draw up at this point an exhaustive list of these problems. They include social, educational, financial, technological, cultural, and, in a sense, even spiritual ones. And if one looks for a single characteristic that explains the difficulty the country’s political establishment has in confronting them, one will find it, I believe, in the fact that they are all long-term problems rather that short-term ones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Epilogue</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/12_Epilogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/sustainability/articles/kennan_cragged_hill/12_Epilogue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;. . . despair, is only for those who see the end beyond all doubt.+++(5)+++&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—J. R. R. Tolkien, &lt;em&gt;The Fellowship of the Ring&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt;t is with a certain wonder and curiosity that I look back on what was written above. I sometimes had the feeling, while writing it, of an affinity with the proverbial old lady who is supposed to have said, on one occasion, “How do I know what I think until I hear what I say?” I comfort myself with the thought that I can scarcely have been the first writer who learned what he thought only when he had looked at what he had written. But such is the case; and I find it necessary to review what I have done before offering any comments on it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
