<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;2 The Diffusion of Sultanate Systems, 1200–1400 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/2_The_Diffusion_of_Sultanate_Systems_12001400/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;2 The Diffusion of Sultanate Systems, 1200–1400 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/2_The_Diffusion_of_Sultanate_Systems_12001400/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 IMPERIAL EXPANSION ACROSS THE VINDHYAS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/2_The_Diffusion_of_Sultanate_Systems_12001400/01_IMPERIAL_EXPANSION_ACROSS_THE_VINDHYAS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/2_The_Diffusion_of_Sultanate_Systems_12001400/01_IMPERIAL_EXPANSION_ACROSS_THE_VINDHYAS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With their tallest peaks barely exceeding 700 metres, the Vindhya Mountains that span west-central India are hardly imposing. They certainly cannot compete with the Sulaiman Mountains on South Asia’s north-west frontier with Afghanistan, which reach 3,800 metres, much less the snow-capped Himalayas on India’s frontier with Tibet, with peaks at 8,800 metres. Rather, the importance of this 1,000-kilometre-long discontinuous range, which runs east to west just north of the Narmada River, lies in its historic role of demarcating the Indo-Gangetic plain – or ‘Hindustan’, in early Arabic and Persian sources – from the Deccan plateau to the south. Its craggy ravines, dense forests and reputedly fierce tribes rendered the terrain inaccessible, or even impassable. Historically, few states straddled both sides of these mountains, and few invasions were launched from one side to the other.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 SETTLERS, SHAIKHS AND THE DIFFUSION OF SULTANATE INSTITUTIONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/2_The_Diffusion_of_Sultanate_Systems_12001400/02_SETTLERS_SHAIKHS_AND_THE_DIFFUSION_OF_SULTANATE_INSTITUTIONS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/2_The_Diffusion_of_Sultanate_Systems_12001400/02_SETTLERS_SHAIKHS_AND_THE_DIFFUSION_OF_SULTANATE_INSTITUTIONS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two outstanding themes of fourteenth-century India were the expansion and contraction of the Delhi sultanate’s political frontiers and, more quietly, the diffusion of institutions, norms and tastes informed by the circulation of Persian texts. The two processes were not unrelated. The spread of Persianate culture accompanied the establishment of new urban centres, which in turn followed the sultanate’s annexation of new territories.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sizeable settlements to the south and east of Delhi began to appear in the second half of the thirteenth century after Sultan Balban’s punitive raids against rebels in those regions. In the course of these raids, Balban cleared the jungles of present-day Rohilkhand, enlarging the agrarian base that could support both migrants from north India and refugees arriving from beyond the Khyber Pass displaced by Mongol invasions. In the more arid Punjab to the west of Delhi, it was a technological innovation that helped increase agricultural production. Already by the twelfth century, and possibly earlier, the Punjab had seen the introduction of the Persian wheel, a mechanical device for raising water from open wells. Powered by draught animals and using wheels, gears, a crankshaft and buckets, the device could raise water from depths of ten to twenty metres, distributing it over the land through troughs and channels. The technology considerably expanded the production of the Punjab’s primary grain crop, wheat, which in turn sustained growing urban settlements in Delhi’s western and southern hinterlands.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 THE EARLY BENGAL SULTANATE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/2_The_Diffusion_of_Sultanate_Systems_12001400/03_THE_EARLY_BENGAL_SULTANATE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/2_The_Diffusion_of_Sultanate_Systems_12001400/03_THE_EARLY_BENGAL_SULTANATE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bengal is a low-lying floodplain laced with numerous rivers and channels, making overland communication and transportation extremely difficult. By the eighth century large, regionally based imperial systems had emerged in the greater delta region, some of them, such as the Palas (750–1161) and Chandras (&lt;em&gt;c&lt;/em&gt;.825–1035), patronizing Buddhism and others a revitalized Brahmanism, in particular the Senas (&lt;em&gt;c&lt;/em&gt;.1097–1223). The latter, after wresting their independence from their Pala overlords, consolidated their base in western Bengal and then moved into the eastern hinterland. By the early thirteenth century, the centre of civilization and social power in eastern India had moved from Bihar to Bengal, while royal patronage had shifted from a mainly Buddhist to a mainly Hindu orientation. By this time, too, the granting of land to Brahmins who officiated at court rituals had become a kingly duty. As elsewhere in India, kings of the Sena dynasty sought to replicate cosmic order by building monumental stone temples housing an image of their patron overlord.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 SULTANATES OF THE DECCAN: THE BAHMANIS AND VIJAYANAGARA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/2_The_Diffusion_of_Sultanate_Systems_12001400/04_SULTANATES_OF_THE_DECCAN_THE_BAHMANIS_AND_VIJAYANAGARA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/2_The_Diffusion_of_Sultanate_Systems_12001400/04_SULTANATES_OF_THE_DECCAN_THE_BAHMANIS_AND_VIJAYANAGARA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Deccan in the fourteenth century witnessed a pattern similar to that of Bengal: the political expansion of the Delhi sultanate, the diffusion of Persianate culture, and rebellion followed by the establishment of not one but two independent regional sultanates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1342, as his caravan lumbered southwards from Delhi to the Tughluqs’ co-capital of Daulatabad, Ibn Battuta described the road he was using as ‘bordered with willow trees and others in such a manner that a man going along it imagines he is walking through a garden; and at every mile there are three postal stations … At every station [&lt;em&gt;dawa&lt;/em&gt;] is to be found all that a traveller needs.’24 Such a description indicates Muhammad bin Tughluq’s earnest attempts to link north India politically with the Deccan. But the Moroccan also recorded that those roads were infested with bandits, armed tribal groups and other miscreants, suggesting the sultan’s failure to build the sort of transport and communication infrastructure that is essential for any large state. The ever-resilient world traveller did manage to wriggle out of dangerous encounters with bandits on the road to Daulatabad, as he did many other times in his global travels. But there is no doubting the fragility of the lifeline that linked the Deccan to Delhi, suggesting that the sultanate’s attempt to annex the plateau was doomed from the start.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 THE EARLY KASHMIR SULTANATE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/2_The_Diffusion_of_Sultanate_Systems_12001400/05_THE_EARLY_KASHMIR_SULTANATE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/2_The_Diffusion_of_Sultanate_Systems_12001400/05_THE_EARLY_KASHMIR_SULTANATE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Directly north of Delhi, protected by massive walls of snowcapped mountains, lies the fertile and densely populated valley of Kashmir, an oval-shaped plain approximately 145 kilometres long and forty wide. For centuries, the valley’s physical properties have enchanted its visitors: ‘A garden of perpetual spring’ is how the Mughal administrator Abu’l-fazl characterized it. Surrounded on all sides by towering mountains attaining 5,500 metres in height, the valley – 1,800 metres above sea level – is watered by the Jhelum River, which springs from the valley floor and flows gently westwards until it plunges through a narrow gorge in the Pir Panjal Mountains, which form the valley’s western edge. After cutting through this range, the river turns abruptly south, eventually forming the westernmost of the five rivers that flow over the Punjab; in all, it drops over 1,000 metres from its headwaters in the Kashmir valley to the plains of the Punjab.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 THE DECLINE OF THE TUGHLUQ EMPIRE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/2_The_Diffusion_of_Sultanate_Systems_12001400/06_THE_DECLINE_OF_THE_TUGHLUQ_EMPIRE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/2_The_Diffusion_of_Sultanate_Systems_12001400/06_THE_DECLINE_OF_THE_TUGHLUQ_EMPIRE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although the Delhi sultanate was still in its ascendency of wealth and power at the turn of the fourteenth century, by mid-century the state was on the wane. On nearly all its frontiers Sultan Muhammad bin Tughluq’s patchwork empire experienced rebellions, most dramatically in Gujarat. Topographically, this region is far less uniform than the Bengal delta, the valley of Kashmir, or even the Deccan plateau. Gujarat’s long coastline jutting into the Arabian Sea for centuries exposed the region to outsiders who came as invaders, settlers and, especially, merchants. The latter integrated Gujarat with wider Indian Ocean networks of trade, making it one of the most globalized regions in the world – in contrast to the nearly hermetically sealed Kashmir. Unlike Gujarat’s coastal areas, the hinterland of the Saurashtra peninsula is an arid and hilly mix of desert and scrubland, and hence a mainly pastoral region. Historically, nomadic herding communities moved in from Rajasthan to the north-east and from Sind to the north-west. Eastern Gujarat features a fertile north–south corridor of rich farmland, capable of producing surplus food and cash crops, especially cotton. These geographical differences engendered distinctive occupational specialists: cosmopolitan merchants along the coasts, pastoral nomads in Saurashtra, and grain-producing agriculturalists in the eastern corridor. Yet despite their differences, Gujarat’s subregions were historically interdependent. Rulers in the eastern corridor, for example, took measures to enhance region-wide security with a view to promoting coastal trade.50&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 CONCLUSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/2_The_Diffusion_of_Sultanate_Systems_12001400/07_CONCLUSION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/2_The_Diffusion_of_Sultanate_Systems_12001400/07_CONCLUSION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although Sultan Muhammad bin Tughluq ruled the Delhi sultanate for only twenty-six years, the spectre of this towering and complex figure loomed over the entire fourteenth century. When he came to power in 1325, the sultanate had reached the height of its might, prestige and cultural florescence. By that time, the state no longer relied on recruiting luminaries from beyond the Khyber, since a class of India-born intellectuals had emerged within the Delhi sultanate. The most famous of these, the brilliant poet Amir Khusrau, was just as proud of his Indian heritage as he was skilled at turning a Persian verse. Nor were the Khalaji or Tughluq courts the sole foci of intellectual talent: men of letters attached themselves to the &lt;em&gt;khanaqah&lt;/em&gt;s of charismatic Sufi shaikhs across all of north India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
