<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maratha-Rajput relations: 1720 to 1795 A.D. on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/D_AchArya/marATha_rAjpUt_relations_1720-1795/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Maratha-Rajput relations: 1720 to 1795 A.D. on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/D_AchArya/marATha_rAjpUt_relations_1720-1795/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>0 Preface</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/D_AchArya/marATha_rAjpUt_relations_1720-1795/0_preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/D_AchArya/marATha_rAjpUt_relations_1720-1795/0_preface/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The present thesis &amp;quot; Maratha-Rajput relations from 1720 to 1795 A.D.&amp;quot; begins with the career of Peshwa Bajirao I and ends with the death of Peshwa Madhaorao in 1795 A.D. The work &amp;lsquo;Rajput&amp;rsquo; refers to the Rajput States of Rajasthan in the 18th century and particularly to the former States of Jaypur, Jodhpur and Udaypur as of the 15 States the leading Houses were three-the Sisodias of Mewad, the Rathods of Marwad and the Kachawahas of Ambar, History of other smaller States like Bundi, Kotal Alwar, Kishangadh or Bikaner, comes into picture wherever it touches the main theme. (1)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 RAJASTHAN AND THE RAJPUTS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/D_AchArya/marATha_rAjpUt_relations_1720-1795/2_RAJASTHAN_AND_THE_RAJPUTS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/D_AchArya/marATha_rAjpUt_relations_1720-1795/2_RAJASTHAN_AND_THE_RAJPUTS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;rajasthan---physiography&#34;&gt;Rajasthan - Physiography&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rajasthan comprises the area between 23rd degree to 30th degree North latitude and 68th degree to 78th East longitude. The earliest reference to Rajasthan is in connection with its agidity. The word Maru is found in Rugwed the Mahabharat (Vanaparva, 201.41) and Brahatsamhita.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aravalli range runs through Rajasthan, northeast to southwest, for about 430 miles, starting from Delhi (known as Delhi ridge) and extending to Ahmadabad. The word Aravalli, is derived from Ada-vala, meaning &amp;ldquo;a beam lying across&amp;rdquo;. In the past, the entire length of this range was a complete barrier to all kinds of movements from east to west. But today the effectiveness of the barrier is felt only in the Central and Southern parts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 THE PHASE OF FRIENDSHIP (1720 TO 1743 A.D.)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/D_AchArya/marATha_rAjpUt_relations_1720-1795/3_THE_PHASE_OF_FRIENDSHIP/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/D_AchArya/marATha_rAjpUt_relations_1720-1795/3_THE_PHASE_OF_FRIENDSHIP/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE FIRST PHASE : (1720 TO 1743 A.D.)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;THE PHASE OF FRIENDSHIP (1720 TO 1743 A.D.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-marathas-the-rajputs-and-the-nizam&#34;&gt;The Marathas, The Rajputs and The Nizam&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The factions at the Court of Delhi after the death of Aurangzeb, especially from the beginning of the reign of Farrukh Siyar till 1720 A.D., made the Emperor a puppet in the hands of either the Sayyad brothers or the Nizam who was the head of the Turani party. And every time the Emperor reacted, by trying to set himself   free from the grip of the former or the latter, it only added to the disintegration of the Mughal Empire. Actuated by selfishness(1), every Courtier of eminence and every thief tried to secure a share for him out of the spoil. The Marathas had secured the Sanads (2) of the Chauth and Sardeshmukhi of the six subhas of Deccan (March 1719 A.D.) and had begun to cast their covetous eyes on the Subhas of Gujarat and Malwa(3). The Rajput chiefs were also not lagging behind. The House of Jodhpur had fixed its gaze on Ajmer and Gujarat whereas Agra and Malwa were the expected possessions for the House of Jaypur. The Rajput Chiefs in fact had lost all interest in the survival of the Mughal Empire(4), and their contact with the Court was merely to secure the coveted provinces with the Imperial sanction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 THE SECOND PHASE : (1743 TO 1766 A. D.)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/D_AchArya/marATha_rAjpUt_relations_1720-1795/4_THE_SECOND_PHASE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/D_AchArya/marATha_rAjpUt_relations_1720-1795/4_THE_SECOND_PHASE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-march-of-the-maratha-empire&#34;&gt;THE MARCH OF THE MARATHA EMPIRE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-change-in-the-relationship-reasons&#34;&gt;The Change in the Relationship, Reasons&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There existed nothing but cordial relations between the Rajputs and the Maratha till 1743 A.D., but within less than 10 years, the former turned into the most bitter enemies of the latter and conspired with Najib Khan Rohilla and the Durani Chief Ahmad Shah Abdali for their destruction. And even though this enmity turned into a friendship for a temporary period of a few years during 1764 to 1769 A.D., it was the effect of the Jat ascendancy and the individual policy of Malharrao Holkar in befriending the Rohillas and the Rajputs persistently played the role of the opponents of the Marathas, throughout the latter half of the 18th century. What was the reason that turned the friendly Rajputs into the deadly enemies of the Marathas?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 THIRD PHASE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/D_AchArya/marATha_rAjpUt_relations_1720-1795/5_THIRD_PHASE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/D_AchArya/marATha_rAjpUt_relations_1720-1795/5_THIRD_PHASE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-inevitable&#34;&gt;THE INEVITABLE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the exit of the Jat power under Nawalsing, after its rout at Gowardhan (5th of April 1770 A.D.) at the hands of the Marahtas, from the politics of Delhi and with the entry of Mahadaji as Vakil-ul-Mutlak (November 1784 A.D.) subsequent to the treaty of Salbye with the English, the Maratha-Rajput relations entered into the last phase of severe contest in which both sides, disregarding that they belonged to the same religion, culture and land, fought with the determination to annihilate each other. This was the strange culmination of the relationship that started with the friendship that between Bajirao and Sawai Jaysing. But such an end though shocking was inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAHARASHTRA AND THE MARATHAS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/D_AchArya/marATha_rAjpUt_relations_1720-1795/1_mahArASHtra_and_marATha-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/D_AchArya/marATha_rAjpUt_relations_1720-1795/1_mahArASHtra_and_marATha-s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;maharashtra-physiography&#34;&gt;Maharashtra Physiography&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Besides being simple and honest in their habits, Maharashtrians from ancient times (1) have always been brave warrior sufficiently hardy to meet any challenge and tenacious to hold on inspite of unspeakable hardships. That has been their nature for which to a greater extent, the physical conditions of the country are responsible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The characteristic features (2) of the Maharashtra country are the great mountain ranges which enclose it on two sides, the Sahyadri range running from north to south, and the Satpura and Vindhya ranges running from east to west, The minor ranges, which break out in rugged outline from these mountain Chains and from the watersheds of many rivers which fall ultimately into the Godavari and into the Krishna, give the whole country an appearance ruggedness and unevenness not to be met with in other parts of India on such a scale. The country thus defined forms a sort of a triangle of which the Sahyadri range and the sea, from Daman to Karwar, form the base, the Satpura range forms the perpendicular side, reaching to the east beyond Nagpur as far as the watershed of the Godavari and its tributaries extend, and the hypotenuse which joins these two ranges has been determined not so much by natural features as by the test of language.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
