<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Horse on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/horse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Horse on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/horse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Landscapes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/horse/landscapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/horse/landscapes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirement&#34;&gt;Requirement&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Relatively flat grasslands are best.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Relatively flat plains. Good horses need to run around in the first year.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;More grass implies more horses.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;thumbnail&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;../images/horse-biomes.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;../images/horse-biomes.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;suitable-spots&#34;&gt;Suitable Spots&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eastern steppe, aka Mongolian-Manchurian steppe - between Tibet, below altai mountains, from Taklamakan desert right up to Manchurian mountains.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Very undulating terrain.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Severe cold winds from the north - climate change prone.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Very fertile. Lush green grass.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kazakh Steppe (Central Steppe) - Mostly desert -  Kara-Kum, Kizil-kum. Amu and Syr darya-s draining into Aral Sea provide water. Turan area. Big fertile patches surrounded by flat desert provide good horse growing areas. Sournce of major invasions into India.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the south east is the fergAna valley.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the west : Khwarezm oasis, Samarkand oasis and Bukhara oasis along the Zeravshan River. Khwarezm is bigger than sAmarkanD and bukhAra put together - hence dominated those + oft persia.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pontic–Caspian steppe (Western Steppe) - above black sea.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Drier grassland compared to Eastern steppe.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bulgaria / Thrace. Source of Greek horces. Very fertile.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Miscellaneous Europenan spots&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Macedonian depression&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hungarian plains&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Persia&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Southern caspian.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;South of herat in afghAnistAn.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Arabia&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Southern Arabia and Yemen (Tihamah) - narrow coastal fog fed fertile patch. Horse growing area much bigger than that in India.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;India&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tiny sliver between kAThiawar, mewar, mArvAr. Famous Indian breeds - balUchi, kAThiawadi, mewari. Most of kAThiawar peninusula: Shrubbery prevents massive horse-rearing. Mewar/ mArvAr - much drier, less fertile than say - similar sized sAmarkanD oasis.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One hourse would take area which would support 60 people.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gangetic plain is flat - but forested and agriculture intensive.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;US great plains&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Uruguay, argentina&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;central-asia&#34;&gt;Central Asia&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Central Asia &amp;amp; Middle East didn’t have horses until 1500 years after Europe did. Their raiders were less effective, &amp;amp; improvements on land were more valuable as result of lack of horses perhaps. No wild horses in southern Central Asia - only onagers. Horses first introduced around 2000 BC - same time as Mesopotamia &amp;amp; Iran. They were not eaten, &amp;amp; were a status symbol &amp;amp; trade commodity imported from the steppe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Military advantage</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/horse/military-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/horse/military-advantage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Horse-poor populations were at a great military disadvantage - especially in the plains. See Indian example &lt;a href=&#34;https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/notes/history/homo/sapiens/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/v2/defence/military/Adaption_-_technology_and_tactics/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;provenance&#34;&gt;Provenance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Horses were advantageous in the charriot age. Eg. IA invasion.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They increased their advantage in the horse-back age. Eg. kushAna, shaka, huNa, Turkik invasions into India.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;battle-tactics&#34;&gt;Battle tactics&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Could rapidly outflank infantry blocks and attack from sides.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Could use archery or long spears to harrass from a distance, while rapidly changing positions, without risking precious horses.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-per-rider&#34;&gt;Numbers per rider&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Horses can charge full speed about 2-3 miles a day. Fully exhausted after that. So, 2-3 chargers per men needed in battle.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mongols often used multiple (7-10) horses per rider, and stored meat between saddle and the horse to each on horseback. They&amp;rsquo;d drink mare&amp;rsquo;s milk and meat in extreme situations. So all they needed was fodder.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Turks - 2-3 mounts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;range&#34;&gt;Range&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Range depended on breed, the weight of the rider (and armor), and many other factors, such as environmental conditions. Mongol ponies, for instance, were bred for stamina - i.e., traveling long hours and distances at a steady pace. The scrappy little Indian-bred horses used by the far-ranging Maratha cavalry in India were similarly bred for long-haul stamina.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Infantry could cover at most 30 km per day.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;During the invasion of Hungary in early 1241, they covered up to 100 miles (160 km) per day.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cavalry in the 19th century, marching and using one horse, would usually limit their daily march to about 40 miles. The troopers also didn’t ride the horses the whole time. They would alternate between riding and walking beside the horses.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There were warhorses that could cover 360 km in 1 day. (&amp;ldquo;The trade in horses between Khorasan and India in the 13th - 17th centuries&amp;rdquo; by Ali Bahrani Pour.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;equalizers&#34;&gt;Equalizers&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Battle of Agincourt was fought in a place where archers held advantage due to topography. English were helped by topography in most places. Indian northern plains had rarely such topographical advantages.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Guns and cannons made things more equal.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/horse/size/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/horse/size/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;See images &lt;a href=&#34;images/size/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;bronze-age&#34;&gt;Bronze Age&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;mostly-wagon-age&#34;&gt;Mostly Wagon age&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The earlier ones could provide milk and probably pull wagons. These are what the IEs had when they conquered Europe.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Scientific studies show that horses were kept for their milk ~3500 to 3000 BCE, widely accepted as indicating domestication. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.ade2451&#34;&gt;SA2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-riding-evidence&#34;&gt;Early riding evidence&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;five Yamnaya individuals well-dated to 3021 to 2501 calibrated BCE from kurgans in Romania, Bulgaria, and Hungary, displaying changes in bone morphology and distinct pathologies associated with horseback riding.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.ade2451&#34;&gt;SA2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technology</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/horse/technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/horse/technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;riding&#34;&gt;Riding&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bare back riding is very uncomfortalbe for both the rider and the horse - delicate spine protrudes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;blankets&#34;&gt;Blankets&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Alexander depicted in Roman mosaic was riding on a blanket; no stirrups; no belt under the horse to hold the blanket in place.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Horses needed to be gripped with thighs.  Alexandrian Greek horse riding manual : &amp;ldquo;Riding a horse is like standing upright on your thighs&amp;rdquo;. This while galloping at 20 kms per hour and weilding bows and lances, controlling the horse with the bridle.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t use a buckle - the blanket would keep rotating.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;saddles&#34;&gt;Saddles&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First around 100BCE. Slowly spread.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Superior weight distribution.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Relief for the spine - so gap or rise in the middle is critical.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Precise fit required for best effect.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Increased weight bearing capacity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Could now use a buckle - to keep saddle in place.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;stirrups&#34;&gt;Stirrups&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Seen in sanchi 200 BCE.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No longer holding on to the horse with thighs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Another way to control the horse (+ can add spurs).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;better weight distribution for horse.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;By 600 AD seen from Central Asia to Europe. By 700 AD, seen in Iran as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
