<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/urbanism/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/urbanism/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Competition effect</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/urbanism/articles/competition_effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/urbanism/articles/competition_effect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From SVembu (Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1349171803357212672&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1349171803357212672&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the psychological and spiritual effects of concentration of talent (which is what large scale urbanization ultimately is about) is the &amp;ldquo;rat race&amp;rdquo;.Large urban areas don&amp;rsquo;t give us space - the sheer physical room, and young children acutely perceive that lack of space. If you are talented and caught in that rat race, moving to a smaller community may cure it. You will simply stop caring about many of the &amp;ldquo;prestige traps&amp;rdquo; that afflict our minds - what brands of clothes, shoes, phones, cars and so on and on. That is profoundly liberating!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kennan memoirs</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/urbanism/articles/kennan-memoirs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/urbanism/articles/kennan-memoirs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1501396975077535750.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cars&#34;&gt;Cars&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From George Kennan&amp;rsquo;s memoirs on his childhood memories the rural Wisconsin of the pre automobile era in contrast to the new era. Note the carnage of turtles he mentions, the # of small wildlife killed on roads by automobiles is very high.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I thought, by way of contrast, of the sociable English highway of Chaucer&amp;rsquo;s day, sometimes full of human danger but full, also, of life and companionship. It seemed to me that we had impoverished ourselves by the change; and I could not, after the years in Europe, accustom myself&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarkington</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/urbanism/articles/tarkington/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/urbanism/articles/tarkington/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://kirkcenter.org/extracts/strange-inhabitants-of-the-new-world/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our friend and Front Porch Republic founder Jeremy Beer has just edited and released a new edition of Booth Tarkington’s memoirs, parts of which have not been previously collected. Tarkington (1869–1946), whom we have had occasion to discuss before is one of America’s great forgotten novelists and a proud son of the Midwest. He was the author of, among other works, The Magnificent Ambersons and shares with Faulkner and Updike the distinction of having won the Pulitzer for fiction more than once. More importantly, he represents a specific regionalist sensibility worth retrieving in our centralizing age. We are happy to publish this exclusive excerpt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tree-effect</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/urbanism/articles/tree-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/urbanism/articles/tree-effect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1398286150243176452.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What if I told you there was a single intervention we could deliver in our cities that would cool them during heatwaves, reduce flooding, scrub pollutants from the air, boost biodiversity, improve public health, and even reduce crime? You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t believe me. But it&amp;rsquo;s true.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What if I told you one study in Manchester found that shade from street trees reduced surface temperatures by an average of 12°C and that concrete surfaces shaded permanently by a bank of trees were cooled by up to 20°C in the summer? You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t believe me. But it&amp;rsquo;s true.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
