<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Persistent-surplus &amp; protectionism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/persistent-surplus_protectionism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/persistent-surplus_protectionism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent interview Katherine Tai &lt;a href=&#34;https://ielp.worldtradelaw.net/2023/04/katherine-tai-on-protectionism-free-trade-and-industrial-policy.html&#34;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Our industrial policy is one that has to work with trade policy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would put it even more strongly. I would say that there is no fundamental difference between industrial policy and most forms of trade policy. An industrial policy must have trade effects because all industrial policies affect the relationship between savings and investment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that the most mercantilists economies in the world, with the biggest trade surpluses, rarely if ever see themselves as protectionist or as having implemented trade policies. They usually think of their polices as industrial polices designed mainly to raise manufacturing employment by putting into place policies that increase the competitiveness of the manufacturing sector. Their large, persistent surpluses, they claim, are simply the consequence of efficient manufacturing and household thrift.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Threats to constant growth model</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/threats_to_constant-growth-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/articles/threats_to_constant-growth-model/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rattibha.com/thread/1507391873379454981?lang=en&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The modern financial system is based on the premise of constant (and relatively smooth) growth indefinitely, including persistent credit growth. War and commodity shortages threaten the whole model. 🧵&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;financial-leverage&#34;&gt;Financial leverage&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A low-leverage system can take shocks. For example, a solid business with little/no debt can have its cash flows go up and down based on economic conditions, without blowing up. Up years are fun, down years aren&amp;rsquo;t, but it&amp;rsquo;s okay either way. In a low-leverage system, high commodity prices can result in recessionary conditions, higher interest rates, and thus less demand. The demand side shrinks to match the tight supply side. Meanwhile, new capital is incentivized to come in and bring new commodity supply to market.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
