<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/pygmy/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/pygmy/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ota Benga</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/pygmy/articles/ota-benga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/pygmy/articles/ota-benga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On this day in 1916, Ota Benga, an African native who suffered inhumane treatment by being kept in a zoo, committed suicide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He had been kidnapped in 1904 from Congo, and taken to America and exhibited at the Bronx Zoo with monkeys.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He was born around 1883, part of the Mbuti tribe which lived in the Kasai Forest in what is now the Republic of Congo. Theirs was a hunter-gatherer society, and they lived deep in the forest.&#xA;When Ota became a man, his teeth were chipped into sharp points, part of his tribal customs. He married and had two children, supporting them with hunting. Like most of his tribe, Ota was small in stature, under five feet tall and just a little over one hundred pounds in weight. Tooth sharpening is customary in various cultures. Historically it was done for spiritual and identification purposes. (1st pic- Congo, 2nd-Cameroon, 3rd-Ethiopia)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>still-a-pygmy - nemets</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/pygmy/articles/still-a-pygmy_nemets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/niger-congo/pygmy/articles/still-a-pygmy_nemets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://unrollthread.com/t/1624572393556672512/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thread with excerpts from &amp;ldquo;Still a Pygmy: The unique memoir of one man&amp;rsquo;s fight to save his identity from extinction&amp;rdquo; by Isaac Bacirongo&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pygmy customs: dowry, polygyny, male choice of divorce, violent disputes over hunting rights, &amp;amp; resolution of murders with a bride giveaway to family of deceased. Seems Pygmies used gourds rather than pots for liquid storage. Alcohol is very popular with them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pygmies push their daughters to be promiscuous from a young age in hopes of snagging a man who would provide food for the family. Forest life was idealized since food that was hunted or gathered there could be kept for oneself. In a village, food had to shared with all. Pygmies (at least the author’s parents and their lovers) are quite promiscuous. Some lived a nomadic life in the forest, hunting and gathering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
