<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Asian split</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/articles/MT/asian-split/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/articles/MT/asian-split/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some notes concerning the recent report of a pre-Neolithic young forager woman from Leang Panninge, South Sulawesi. Unfortunately, due to magazine fever many molecular paleoanthropology papers while presenting important specimens are shitilly written &amp;amp; illustrated. So we have to&#xA;wade through some of that to get points of interest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ancestral Asian split up into several far ranging groups by at least 50ky:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;i. The Tianyuan man-like Eastern group.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ii Onge-Hòabìnhian group extending from at least at least the Andamans through Laos, Vietnam&amp;amp; Malayasia&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;iii. An early-diverging sister group of the Onge-Hòabìnhian clade were the hunter-gatherers of the Indian subcontinent from whom Indians on an average get a major fraction of our ancestry.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;iv. The Tibetan-Jomon group which once stretched over Asia from at least Nepal-Tibet to Japan before the classical Koreanic-type east Asian invasion.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;v. A group probably branching close to the stem after the Tianyuan-like &amp;amp; Onge-like groups somehow reached America and contributed to the ancestry of some South Americans. Today other than the Indian HG-component, the Onge-like group include the Philippines Negritos, Papuans &amp;amp; Australians.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Onges &amp;amp; Hòabìnhians lack high Denisovan ancestry but the Papuans &amp;amp; Australians show evidence for at least two introgression events with Denisovans. The Philippines Negritos too had 1 or 2 Denisovan admixtures. Thus, Onge-like peoples spreading over South East Asia encountered Denisovan races all the way from Philippines to Sahul (Pap+Aus) &amp;amp; annihilated them across the Indo-Pacific islands while mating with them on occasion. On their march at some point they also reached South America. There they were absorbed within the Americans of North Asian ancestry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
