<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Annihilation of caste on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ambedkar/caste_annihilation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Annihilation of caste on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ambedkar/caste_annihilation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Intro</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ambedkar/caste_annihilation/01_Intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ambedkar/caste_annihilation/01_Intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ANNIHILATION OF CASTE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WITH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A REPLY TO MAHATMA GANDHI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;_&amp;quot;_&lt;em&gt;Know Truth as Truth and Untruth as Untruth &amp;ldquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—buddha&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;He that WILL NOT reason is a bigot He that CANNOT reason is a fool He that DARE NOT reason is a slave &amp;ldquo;&lt;/em&gt; H. drummond&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Printed from the third edition of 1944&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;_____________________________________________________________________&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#p01&#34;&gt;Preface to the Second Edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#p02&#34;&gt;Preface to the Third Edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#p03&#34;&gt;Prologue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#s01&#34;&gt;Speech Prepared By Dr. B. R. Ambedkar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 PROLOGUE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ambedkar/caste_annihilation/02_PROLOGUE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ambedkar/caste_annihilation/02_PROLOGUE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On December 12, 1935, I received the following letter from Mr. Sant Ram, the Secretary of the Jat-Pat-Todak Mandal :&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My dear Doctor Saheb,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many thanks for your kind letter of the 5th December. I have released it for press without your permission for which I beg your pardon, as I saw no harm in giving it publicity. You are a great thinker, and it is my well-considered opinion that none else has studied the problem of Caste so deeply as you have. I have always benefited myself and our Mandal from your ideas. I have explained and preached it in the &lt;em&gt;Kranti&lt;/em&gt; many times and I have even lectured on it in many Conferences. I am now very anxious to read the exposition of your new formula—&amp;quot; It is not possible to break Caste without annihilating the religious notions on which it, the Caste system, is founded.&amp;quot; Please do explain it at length at your earliest convenience, so that we may take up the idea and emphasise it from press and platform. At present, it is not fully clear to me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Text</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ambedkar/caste_annihilation/03_Text/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ambedkar/caste_annihilation/03_Text/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i&#34;&gt;I&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Friends,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am really sorry for the members of the Jat-Pat-Todak Mandal who have so very kindly invited me to preside over this Conference. I am sure they will be asked many questions for having selected me as the President. The Mandal will be asked to explain as to why it has imported a man from Bombay to preside over a function which is held in Lahore. I believe the Mandal could easily have found some one better qualified than myself to preside on the occasion. I have criticised the Hindus. I have questioned the authority of the Mahatma whom they revere. They hate me. To them I am a snake in their garden. The Mandal will no doubt be asked by the politically-minded Hindus to explain why it has called me to fill this place of honour. It is an act of great daring. I shall not be surprised if some political Hindus regard it as an insult. This selection of mine cannot certainly please the ordinary religiously-minded Hindus. The Mandal may be asked to explain why it has disobeyed the &lt;em&gt;Shastric&lt;/em&gt; injunction in selecting the President. Accoding to the &lt;em&gt;Shastras&lt;/em&gt; the Brahmin is appointed to be the Guru for the three &lt;em&gt;Varnas, varnanam bramhano garu&lt;/em&gt;, is a direction of the &lt;em&gt;Shastras.&lt;/em&gt; The Mandal therefore knows from whom a Hindu should take his lessons and from whom he should not. The &lt;em&gt;Shastras&lt;/em&gt; do not permit a Hindu to accept any one as his Guru merely because he is well versed. This is made very clear by Ramdas, a Brahmin saint from Maharashtra, who is alleged to have inspired Shivaji to establish a Hindu Raj. In his &lt;em&gt;Dasbodh,&lt;/em&gt; a socio-politico-religious treatise in Marathi verse &lt;em&gt;Ramdas&lt;/em&gt; asks, addressing the Hindus, can we accept an Antyaja to be our Guru because he is a Pandit &lt;em&gt;(i.e. learned)&lt;/em&gt; and gives an answer in the negative. What replies to give to these questions is a matter which I must leave to the Mandal. The Mandal knows best the reasons which led it to travel to Bombay to select a president, to fix upon a man so repugnant to the Hindus and to descend so low in the scale as to select an Antyaja— an untouchable—to address an audience of the &lt;em&gt;Savarnas.&lt;/em&gt; As for myself you will allow me to say that I have accepted the invitation much against my will and also against the will of many of my fellow untouchables. I know that the Hindus are sick of me. I know that I am not a &lt;em&gt;persona grata&lt;/em&gt; with them. Knowing all this I have deliberately kept myself away from them. I have no desire to inflict myself upon them. I have been giving expression to my views from my own platform. This has already caused a great deal of heartburning and irritation. I have no desire to ascend the platform of the Hindus to do within their sight what I have been doing within their hearing. If I am here it is because of your choice and not because of my wish. Yours is a cause of social reform. That cause has always made an appeal to me and it is because of this that I felt I ought not to refuse an opportunity of helping the cause especially when you think that I can help it. Whether what I am going to say today will help you in any way to solve the problem you are grappling with is for you to judge. All I hope to do is to place before you my views on the problem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 APPENDIX I A VINDICATION OF CASTE BY MAHATMA GANDHI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ambedkar/caste_annihilation/04_APPENDIX_I_A_VINDICATION_OF_CASTE_BY_MAHATMA_GANDHI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ambedkar/caste_annihilation/04_APPENDIX_I_A_VINDICATION_OF_CASTE_BY_MAHATMA_GANDHI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(A Reprint of his Articles in the &amp;quot; Harijan &amp;ldquo;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;dr-ambedkars-indictment-i&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Ambedkar&amp;rsquo;s Indictment I&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The readers will recall the fact that Dr. Ambedkar was to have presided last May at the annual conference of the Jat-Pat-Todak Mandal of Lahore. But the conference itself was cancelled because Dr. Ambedkar&amp;rsquo;s address was found by the Reception Committee to be unacceptable. How far a Reception Committee is justified in rejecting a President of its choice because of his address that may be objectionable to it is open to question. The Committee knew Dr. Ambedkar&amp;rsquo;s views on caste and the Hindu scriptures. They knew also that he had in unequivocal terms decided to give up Hinduism. Nothing less than the address that Dr. Ambedkar had prepared was to be expected from him. The committee appears to have deprived the public of an opportunity of listening to the original views of a man, who has carved out for himself a unique position in society. Whatever label he wears in future, Dr. Ambedkar is not the man to allow himself to be forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 APPENDIX II A REPLY TO THE MAHATMA BY DR B R AMBEDKAR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ambedkar/caste_annihilation/05_APPENDIX_II_A_REPLY_TO_THE_MAHATMA_BY_DR_B_R_AMBEDKAR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/ambedkar/caste_annihilation/05_APPENDIX_II_A_REPLY_TO_THE_MAHATMA_BY_DR_B_R_AMBEDKAR/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i&#34;&gt;I&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I appreciate greatly the honour done me by the Mahatma in taking notice in his Harijan of the speech on Caste which I had prepared for the Jat Pat Todak Mandal. From a perusal of his review of my speech it is clear that the Mahatma completely dissents from the views I have expressed on the subject of Caste. I am not in the habit of entering into controversy with my opponents unless there are special reasons which compel me to act otherwise. Had my opponent been some mean and obscure person I would not have pursued him. But my opponent being the Mahatma himself I feel I must attempt to meet the case to the contrary which he has sought to put forth. While I appreciate the honour he has done me, I must confess to a sense of surprize on finding that of all the persons the Mahatma should accuse me of a desire to seek publicity as he seems to do when he suggests that in publishing the undelivered speech my object was to see that I was not &amp;quot; forgotten &amp;ldquo;. Whatever the Mahatma may choose to say my object in publishing the speech was to provoke the Hindus to think and take stock of their position. I have never hankered for publicity and if I may say so, I have more of it than I wish or need. But supposing it was out of the motive of gaining publicity that I printed the speech who could cast a stone at me ? Surely not those, who like the Mahatma live in glass houses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
