<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Cochran Gregory on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/animal-husbandry/articles/cochran_gregory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Cochran Gregory on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/animal-husbandry/articles/cochran_gregory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Megafaunal Extinctions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/animal-husbandry/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-05-20_megafaunal-extinctions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/animal-husbandry/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-05-20_megafaunal-extinctions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.wordpress.com/2012/05/20/megafaunal-extinctions/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Megafaunal Extinctions&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When competent human hunters encountered naive fauna, the biggest&#xA;animals, things like mammoths and toxodons+++(=big hipppo-like)+++ and diprotodons+++(=giant wombat)+++, all went&#xA;extinct. It is not hard to see why this occurred. Large animals are&#xA;more worth hunting than rabbits, and easier to catch, while having a far&#xA;lower reproductive rate. Moreover, humans are not naturally narrow&#xA;specialists on any one species, so are not limited by the abundance of&#xA;that species in the way that the lynx population depends on the hare&#xA;population. Being omnivores, they could manage even when the megafauna&#xA;as a whole were becoming rare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unwilding America</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/animal-husbandry/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-05-11_unwilding-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/animal-husbandry/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-05-11_unwilding-america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.wordpress.com/2012/05/11/unwilding-america/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unwilding America&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the Amerindians arrived, North America had much more varied (and&#xA;dangerous) wildlife than it does today: particularly when it comes to&#xA;large animals, the megafauna. Today, or for that matter during colonial&#xA;times. there are only a few dangerous creatures around: grizzly bears,&#xA;black bears, polar bears, and a few poisonous snakes. Mountain lions&#xA;attack people, but rarely. I suppose some people die from drunkenly&#xA;running their pickup into a buck on a country road.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ecological dominance</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/animal-husbandry/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-05-02_ecological-dominance-turtles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/animal-husbandry/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-05-02_ecological-dominance-turtles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.wordpress.com/2012/05/02/ecological-dominance-turtles/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ecological dominance: turtles&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, humans aren’t much concerned about being devoured. We may&#xA;have to worry about blowing ourselves up, or being blotted out by an&#xA;asteroid strike, but we don’t worry much about lions and tigers and&#xA;bears.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;But it was not always thus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Three million years ago, we were more prey than predator. Africa was&#xA;predator-rich, more so than anywhere today, with familiar beasties such&#xA;as leopards, lions, and hyenas, but also bears, three kinds of&#xA;saber-toothed cats, and giant otters. Judging from the chewing marks and&#xA;punctures in &lt;em&gt;australopithecus&lt;/em&gt; skulls, leopards were the biggest&#xA;threat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diamond on domestication</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/animal-husbandry/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-02-15_diamond-on-domestication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/animal-husbandry/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-02-15_diamond-on-domestication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.wordpress.com/2012/02/15/diamond-on-domestication/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Diamond on domestication&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jared Diamond, in discussing animal domestication, claims that the local&#xA;availability of species with the right qualities for domestication was&#xA;key, rather than anything special about the biology or culture of the&#xA;humans living there. In some cases that may be true: there aren’t many&#xA;large mammals left in Australia, and they’re all marsupials anyway.&#xA;Stupid marsupials. He claims that since Africans and Amerindians were&#xA;happy to adopt Eurasian domesticated animals when they became available,&#xA;it must be that that suitable local animals just didn’t exist. But&#xA;that’s a non sequitur: making use of an already-domesticated species is&#xA;not at all the same thing as the original act of domestication. That’s&#xA;like equating using a cell phone with inventing one.+++(4)+++ He also says that&#xA;people have had only mixed success in recent domestication attempts –&#xA;but the big problem there is that a newly domesticated species doesn’t&#xA;just have to be good, it has to be better than already-existing domestic&#xA;animals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
