<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Emergency prep</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/emergency-prep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/emergency-prep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1919695817079701932.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some advice. Install water tanks &amp;amp; stock up your pantry with non-perishable foods such as milk powder, flattened rice, rolled oats, iodine salt, wheat, lentils.. get battery or solar panel radios (and tune in your radio!), extra batteries, warm clothes, gas tank, stock up your medicine cabinet with disinfectants, sewing kit, gauze &amp;amp; bandages, broad-spectrum antibiotics, NSAIDs, antibacterial creams, diphenhydramine, loperamide, ORS &amp;amp; antidiarrheals (this is important!!).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are on prescription such as insulin then stock up on those stock up on soaps and toothpaste too, easiest way to avoid illness is washing yourself. stock up on diapers &amp;amp; period pads. Buy flashlights, map &amp;amp; compass. Write important telephone numbers on a notebook and teach your children to be able to tell their full name, parents full name and make your children memorise important numbers, landmarks &amp;amp; basic self defence. Keep your ID cards, passports &amp;amp; other important documents near you! Get a pair of good shoes (easiest way to avoid tetanus)!!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lie spotting - pamela meyer</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/lie-spotting_pamela-meyer_lying/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/lie-spotting_pamela-meyer_lying/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/pamela_meyer_how_to_spot_a_liar?hasSummary=true&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pamela Meyer: How to spot a liar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Okay, now I don&amp;rsquo;t want to alarm anybody in this room,&#xA;but it&amp;rsquo;s just come to my attention that the person to your right is a liar. (Laughter) Also, the person to your left is a liar. Also the person sitting in your very seats is a liar. We&amp;rsquo;re all liars.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m going to do today is I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you what the research says about why we&amp;rsquo;re all liars, how you can become a liespotter, and why you might want to go the extra mile and go from liespotting to truth seeking, and ultimately to trust building.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tyranny-of-meritocracy-review</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/tyranny-of-meritocracy-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/tyranny-of-meritocracy-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विश्वास-टिप्पनी&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anti-meritocracy is worse. DEI and quota-lands are super dystopias - so viveks of India have fled.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Biggest criticism - meritocracy over long time scales is natural. Nothing can stop a Temujin or NaMo or Ramanujan. If one state or company doesn&amp;rsquo;t adopt it, another will + win.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;videoEmbed&#34;  caption=&#34;Video&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0E2TqMOIu2M&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a world where every individual regardless of his Origins would get an equal opportunity to succeed in life [[0:07]] a place where persons Merit is the only deciding factor behind the success achieved by him [[0:13]] wouldn&amp;rsquo;t that be an ideal Society shouldn&amp;rsquo;t that be our Collective? I&amp;rsquo;m sure most of us would love to be a [[0:19]] part of it because we aspire to live in a purely meritocratic Society. I believe the same and so I was fairly [[0:26]] surprised to know that the person who coined the phrase meritocracy didn&amp;rsquo;t think the same way as we do. [[0:33]] For him that were denoted and inevitably dystopian Society. So I got curious to [[0:38]] know what is wrong with the idea of having a world where EV where individual Merit is the ultimate parameter to [[0:44]] classify people and how can such a society be unjust and tyrannical. [[0:49]] Welcome to the new episode of bookmark and today we&amp;rsquo;ll be discussing a book that aims to answer the shades of [[0:55]] meritocracy and how its absolutism may result in tyranny. we are talking about the book The [[1:02]] Tyranny of Merit - what&amp;rsquo;s become of the common good by Harvard Professor Michael J sandal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>दुःख-प्रबन्धः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/duHkha-prabandhaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/articles/duHkha-prabandhaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://kadaxara.blogspot.com/2022/09/blog-post.html?m=1&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;दुःख-प्रबन्धः&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;अत्र दैत्य(Deutsche, German)-दर्शनकारः श्रीमान् अर्ण्ष्ट-युङ्गरः इत्यस्य पुस्तकात् केचन सुविचाराः।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;लेखकोऽयं युवसु प्रियतां गतो ऽधुना,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;विशिष्य तेषु सिख-हिन्दुकेषु यय् उदार-वादिभ्यः द्विषन्तः स्वराष्ट्रम् इच्छन्ति।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;किन्तु, एषां युङ्गरस्य विषये दुर्बोधः स्याद् इति मन्ये।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;एहि पश्यामः।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some thoughts &amp;amp; snippets from German soldier-philosopher Ernst Junger&amp;rsquo;s book. A new surge of popularity in this prophetic writer among Indian and American nationalists alike, who are dissatisfied with Liberalism. But there are misunderstandings about Junger. A review through an Indian eye:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
