<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Womb on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/womb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Womb on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/womb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Female abduction</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/womb/female-abduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/womb/female-abduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: TW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ganga-Jamuna Tehzeeb before the rise of the Marathas is a myth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reality behind the tern is that Ganga and Yamuna rivers both were closely used by Nawabs of Agra and Bangāl to disguise themselves as Hindus during Hindu festivals and carry off young Hindu girls through boats.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Law was by no means an admirer of Aliverdi Khan&amp;rsquo;s successor, Siraj-ud-daula, a young man of twenty-four or twenty-five, very common in appearance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Love jihAd 2022</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/womb/love-jihAd_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/womb/love-jihAd_2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://unrollthread.com/t/1535551508644630528/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Twitter : @AlageshChelliah&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Attention all non-Muslim parents:&lt;/em&gt; Today I was called to help in a love-jihad case. In the last three months, this is the fourth or fifth such case. I am writing this because it&amp;rsquo;s very necessary to make parents aware of the risks children are facing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Out of the five odd cases that have come to me, only one is what is known to be a &amp;rsquo;lower&amp;rsquo; caste.&#xA;2.G irls are trapped at any age. One was a widow with two children. But all other girls were between 14 and 16 when the affair started.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In almost all cases, the boys take the girls out on bike rides. Girls are made to feel that this is &amp;lsquo;freedom&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Muslim boys are trained to make the girls sexually aware. They then start by holding hands, giving a friendly hug, touching inappropriate places by &amp;lsquo;mistake&amp;rsquo;. They then move on to kissing and physical relationship when the girl is in 10th or 12th and under educational stress. Videos of their physical relationship is made secretly.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Most parents are unaware till it is too late.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once parents come to know and try to break the relationship, either the girl is pressured to run away, or the girls are blackmailed to continue relationship by blackmailing them with videos of their physical relationship. Till this point, the girl is unaware that a video was made without her knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If the girl insists on breaking up, the boy will get his friends to force physical relationship with the girl with threat or blackmail. All the time, he will keep saying that he will marry the girl.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If parents interfere, the boy will stay away temporarily. Once the girl is 18, this starts again and this time the girl is completely trapped.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mostly, marriage takes place. Girl is converted. For about six months, there are no problems. Then starts the torture. Continuous pregnancies and termination of pregnancies take place.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After two years, the boy will get married again to some other girl while remaining married to the first girl.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Now the first girl will definitely resist. To keep her in the marriage, she is raped by boy&amp;rsquo;s father and brothers. Other women members of the family will beat the girl routinely.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Police and other family members (if still on talking terms) will counsel the girl to adjust and continue in the marriage.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In many cases, if the girl resists, she will be jailed inside the house without a mobile.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If she manages to run away, she will not get custody of the children or get only one child custody. The other child(ren) will remain with husband.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Even if court gives monthly maintenance, husband will never pay.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is an unusual marriage because girl will be converted only after marriage, NOT BEFORE. So she cannot claim right to husband&amp;rsquo;s property. But boy can claim right to girl&amp;rsquo;s parent&amp;rsquo;s property as per Hindu customs!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Please enlighten your children of this Muslim menace called love jihad before too late.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Share this with all non-Muslim parents.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a curse to this Nation to have such a minded society. Hindus have lost their soil Pakistan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mogol Harem</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/womb/mogol-harem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/womb/mogol-harem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Mughal Women Who Wouldn’t Stay in the Harem&lt;br&gt;&#xA;From musket-wielding empress Nur Jahan to writer Gulbadan Begum, meet the influential women of the early-modern Muslim empire.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Sarah Durn August 31, 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Mughal Women Who Wouldn’t Stay in the Harem&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was a cool fall day in 1619 when the empress and emperor of India set out from Agra. Their itinerant court, 150,000 people and 10,000 elephants strong, marched toward the Himalayan foothills. But, as servants began to pitch the elaborate imperial tents, a group of local hunters begged for help—a man-eating tiger stalked their home. The emperor, Jahangir, had vowed to give up hunting and could provide no help. But the empress, Nur Jahan, a famed markswoman, stepped in. On October 23, 1619, armed with an exquisite firearm and seated atop an elephant, the empress searched for any sign of the tiger in the dense forest. When the powerful cat emerged, Nur’s elephant tried to flee, jostling the empress’s litter. She lined up the shot and pulled the trigger. The tiger fell. One shot was all she needed to kill the beast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
