<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/village/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/village/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mandya bride shortage 23</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/village/articles/mandya-bride-shortage-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/village/articles/mandya-bride-shortage-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/karnataka/scarcity-of-brides-hits-old-mysore-region/article69481383.ece/amp/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bachelors taking out a padayatra to M.M. Hills in February 2023. | Photo Credit: special arrangement&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;About a month ago, residents of Maduvanahalli in Kollegal taluk of Chamarajanagar district witnessed the bizarre sight of a youth perched on the higher reaches of a metal structure supporting the overhead high-tension cables passing through the village.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Notwithstanding the cries of his mother and pleas by other villagers, who had gathered beneath, cautioning him against taking any extreme step, the youth, identified as Masanashetty, 27, waved at the people and held the high-tension electric wire with his hands to be instantaneously electrocuted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mohit and Rustics</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/village/articles/mohit_and_rustics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/village/articles/mohit_and_rustics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;visit-mania&#34;&gt;Visit-mania&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jun 28, 2021&lt;br&gt;&#xA;After living in village for 2 years, I’d say it is not true that there is no peace in the city life.. If you’re not into a job, there’s more peace in the city life..&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In village, everyday more than one person comes to visit just for time pass.. How long can you avoid ? And you’ve to be much more diplomatic in the village life, because from BPL families to sometimes city-level real rich people, all are found in one place.. You’ve to change the way you talk, sit, think, body language everything so many times a day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NAgeshvara and village</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/village/articles/nAgeshvara_and_village/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/india/village/articles/nAgeshvara_and_village/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/MNageswarRaoIPS/status/1894298323365835027&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Author is a Telangana Kamma.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;harvest-shares&#34;&gt;Harvest shares&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My father was a farmer. As has been the custom, a part of the first harvest is given to the village Purohit, then to people of all other vocations such as carpenter, blacksmith, washerman, barber, etc. While the grains are delivered to the Purohit, others collect their share from the threshing floor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The paddy harvest season coincides with Makar Sankranti/Pongal school holidays. My father used to take me to the farm during holidays. One of my duties was to deliver a few sacks of paddy at the home of our Purohit. He and his wife were affectionate and would treat me with some snacks, etc. And while I was eating snacks he would enquire about my studies, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
