<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;2 Indira versus the Janata on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/2_Indira_versus_the_Janata/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;2 Indira versus the Janata on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/2_Indira_versus_the_Janata/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1974; May 5: Delhi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/2_Indira_versus_the_Janata/1974_May_5_Delhi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/2_Indira_versus_the_Janata/1974_May_5_Delhi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;81% Hindus, 12% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Delhi: none, Delhi was, as of that date, a Union Territory, not a state&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Troubles erupted in Delhi in the locality of Sadar Bazar where Hindus and Muslims live side by side. The incidents were triggered by a minor quarrel between two Muslim youths and a Hindu boy. As each of them subsequently called his friends, among whom there were petty criminals, the small dispute rapidly degenerated into a serious Hindu-Muslim confrontation. Arson, heavy brick-batting, and weapons firing took place. The police were targeted by rioters, and were unable to maintain control of the situation. The Muslim community suffered particularly. Eleven persons lost their lives in these riots, after which a curfew was imposed on the locality for 45 days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1977; October 22–23: Varanasi (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/2_Indira_versus_the_Janata/1977_October_2223_Varanasi_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/2_Indira_versus_the_Janata/1977_October_2223_Varanasi_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;68% Hindus, 31% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: Ram Naresh Yadav, Janata Party, June 1977–February 1979&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Troubles erupted in Varanasi (Uttar Pradesh). The first clashes occurred on October 1 after an altercation between Hindu students and a Muslim weaver. On October 22, tensions arose again when a Hindu Durga Puja procession attempted to pass through a Muslim area. This had never happened previously and the Muslims wanted to avoid any precedent being set on that matter which would subsequently permit similar future processions. On October 23, the procession, with much fanfare, tried to enter the Muslim area. The Muslims resisted. Violence flared up. Both sides were armed for battle. Some reports established that the police took an active part in the looting and arson in Muslim localities. Stabbing incidents also took place. Paradoxically, there were not many casualties (around ten).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1978; March 29: Sambhal (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/2_Indira_versus_the_Janata/1978_March_29_Sambhal_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/2_Indira_versus_the_Janata/1978_March_29_Sambhal_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;54% Hindus, 46% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: Ram Naresh Yadav, Janata Party, June 1977–February 1979&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Violence took place in Sambhal (Uttar Pradesh), a tehsil (sub - district) of Moradabad district in which 70 percent of the population is Muslim. A Holi procession led by a local Hindu Congressman and a beauty contest in which two Muslim girls had participated enraged Manzar Shafi, a Muslim League leader. Tensions increased following a gherao (protest demonstration), led by sweepers who had not been paid for three months. Aided by goondas (criminals) Manzar Shafi took this opportunity to call for a bandh (general strike). Violence flared up when a Hindu panwallah (betel seller) refused to follow the strike. Twenty-five persons were killed in these riots, among them 22 Hindu victims.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1978; March 31–April 4: Hyderabad (Andhra Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/2_Indira_versus_the_Janata/1978_March_31April_4_Hyderabad_Andhra_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/2_Indira_versus_the_Janata/1978_March_31April_4_Hyderabad_Andhra_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;54% Hindus, 43% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Andhra Pradesh: Marri Chenna Reddy , Congress Party, March 1978–October 1980&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After three relatively peaceful decades, violence erupted in Hyderabad (Andhra Pradesh) after a Muslim woman, Rameeza Bee, was allegedly raped and her husband, Ahmad Hussain, murdered by policemen on March 24. A Muslim crowd gathered around the police station to express its anger. On March 31, a rumor circulated that Rameeza Bee had eventually been killed by the police. Although the rumor proved to be false, it was enough to spark off violence. Fifteen persons were killed, some of them after being shot by police. After these initial events in 1978, Hyderabad was to experience communal riots almost on a yearly basis, particularly during the Ganesh festival, the public celebration of which was encouraged by the then chief minister Chenna Reddy in order to serve his own political ends (see Chapter 4 in «Hindu–Muslim Communal Riots in India II (1986–2011)» by Violette Graff and Juliette Galonnier [2012]).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1978; October 5 and November 6: Aligarh (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/2_Indira_versus_the_Janata/1978_October_5_and_November_6_Aligarh_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/2_Indira_versus_the_Janata/1978_October_5_and_November_6_Aligarh_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;57% Hindus, 41% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: Ram Naresh Yadav, Janata Party, June 1977–February 1979&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Serious riots took place on two occasions in the city of Aligarh (Uttar Pradesh). The annual report (1979) of the National Minorities’ Commission established that troubles started after the stabbing of Bhure Lal - a wrestler in a Hindu akhara (traditional physical training center) and a notorious criminal - by Muslim criminals on October 3. Hindu wrestlers close to Bhure Lal organized a procession to protest his death: his body was paraded through the city while slogans such as &amp;ldquo;blood for blood&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;ten for one&amp;rdquo; were shouted. On October 5, a riot erupted in which 12 people died. A report by the PUCL (People’s Union for Civil Liberties) (1978) emphasized that communal agitation in the city had been stirred up for months by RSS elements over the issue of Aligarh Muslim University’s minority status. The report criticized local Hindu nationalist leader K. K. Navman for his involvement in the violence. The PAC (Provincial Armed Constabulary, Uttar Pradesh Police Force) was also accused of complicity with Hindu rioters. In addition, the local administration had demonstrated little urgency in controlling the situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1979; April 11: Jamshedpur (Bihar)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/2_Indira_versus_the_Janata/1979_April_11_Jamshedpur_Bihar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/2_Indira_versus_the_Janata/1979_April_11_Jamshedpur_Bihar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;81% Hindus, 9% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Bihar: Karpoori Thakur, Janata Party, June 1977 - 21 April 1979&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A riot rampaged in Jamshedpur (Bihar) and it is worth recalling the chain of events that led to the violence. After the troubles of 1964, Muslims had been relocated to specific areas, such as the Sabirnagar neighborhood. During the same period, Hindu nationalist organizations were actively leading campaigns to &amp;ldquo;Hinduize&amp;rdquo; the adivasis by introducing Hindu deities and rituals within their neighborhoods. In 1978, the RSS tried to hold a Ram Navami Hindu procession starting from the adivasi colony of Dimna Basti. It was then slated to pass through the Muslim section of Sabirnagar, but the district’s administration refused to grant authorization at that time. In 1979, the RSS tried, once again, to organize the procession. The atmosphere in the city had been tense ever since the speech of the RSS chief, Balasaheb Deoras ; on April 1. The local RSS - affiliated Member of Legislative Assembly (MLA) and leader of the BMS (Bharatiya Mazdoor Sangh, Indian Workers’ Union, a Hindu trade - union), Dinanath Pandey, organized a propaganda campaign in favor of allowing the procession to pass through Sabirnagar. On April 7, a pamphlet circulated asking people to gather on April 11 in order to hold the procession forcibly. Muslim leaders were persuaded by the district administration to accept the procession’s itinerary. On the morning of April 11, a 15,000 - strong mob gathered. The procession stopped near a mosque in the Mango Area of the Muslim sector. Muslims were prepared for the violence. Stones were thrown and a riot erupted. The Jitendra Narain Commission held the RSS responsible for having created a climate conducive to communal violence. The leaflet distributed on April 7 was denounced as a challenge to the authorities, a threat to the Muslim minority, and an incitement to violence. Adivasis took an active part in attacking the economically well-off Muslims of Jamshedpur. One hundred and eight persons lost their lives in this riot according to the Jitendra Narain Commission of Inquiry, among whom 79 Muslims and 25 Hindus were identified. Other estimates put the death toll at 120, more than half of whom were Muslims. The Commission established that RSS elements and the local MLA, Dinanath Pandey, played a key role in engineering the riots.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
