<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/dardic/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/dardic/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>‘Nysa in India’ &amp; the</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/dardic/articles/2021-12-17_nysa-in-india-the-related-narratives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/dardic/articles/2021-12-17_nysa-in-india-the-related-narratives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://cestlaviepriya.wordpress.com/2021/12/17/nysa-in-india-the-related-narratives/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘Nysa in India’ &amp;amp; the Related Narratives&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-question-of-greek-descent&#34;&gt;The Question of ‘Greek Descent’&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The claims that these Greek settlements, either Alexandrian or&#xA;pre-Alexandrian left such an imprint on the Indian sub-continent that&#xA;some tribes believe themselves to be their descendants has been alluded&#xA;to in the start of the post. Why is that? And how is that connected to&#xA;the ‘Nysa in India’? To explain the point further – the ancient Indian&#xA;north-west, the main region with which this post is concerned, is also&#xA;the habitat of some of the peculiar tribes, with fascinating culture and&#xA;traditions. In the current times, the Kalash tribe in&#xA;Khyber-Pakhtunkhwa province of Pakistan represents remnants of such&#xA;people. They belong to the Dardic Indo-Aryan group of people. Before&#xA;late nineteenth century, the Kalash were part of a much more widespread&#xA;zone of the Dardic Indo-Aryan indigenous culture that included the&#xA;erstwhile Kafiristan (the land of infidels for &lt;em&gt;Kafir&lt;/em&gt; means an infidel)&#xA;region of Afghanistan whose people were called the Kafirs. Despite the&#xA;violent rise of Islam in the region, they had for a very long time&#xA;preserved their indigenous religion and culture. However, in 1896-7,&#xA;they were forcefully converted to Islam by Amir of Afghanistan, Abdur&#xA;Rahim Khan (Cacopardo, 2011: 53) and the region was renamed as Nuristan&#xA;(the land of light i.e. the light of Islam). The Kalash survived because&#xA;they were on the Indian side (now Pakistani side) of the Durand&#xA;Agreement of 1893 between Afghanistan and the British Colonial&#xA;Government of India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>drogpa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/dardic/articles/drogpa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/dardic/articles/drogpa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Drogpa are a Dardic Indo-Aryan speaking tribe from Ladakh. They speak Broksat which belongs to the Shina subgroup of Dardic and they call themselves &amp;ldquo;Minaro&amp;rdquo; which means &amp;lsquo;Aryan&amp;rsquo;. Minaro people (calling them by their endonym) seem to have been regular Shina Indo-Aryans who came under Tibeto-Burman influence and adopted some Buddhist practices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of them practice their traditional Indo-Aryan religion mixed with Buddhism. Regardless, one thing I noticed is the similarities with the Kalash in how obsessed they are with ritual impurity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>gilgit-importance</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/dardic/articles/gilgit-importance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/dardic/articles/gilgit-importance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gilgit-Baltistan – The Crossroad of Asia&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A long Thread on the 7000 years’ history of Gilgit-Baltistan and its enduring geo-political Significance&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Geography, as they say, shapes history. The history of Gilgit and Baltistan is proof of this. Sitting at the crossroads of India, China, and civilizations towards the West, Gilgit-Baltistan has long been a hotspot for trade, cultural exchange, and geo-political tussle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The earliest human activity in Gilgit-Baltistan dates back from 5000 to 1000 BCE, evident from carvings of animals, men, and hunting scenes. These carvings provide a rich window into ancient life. Once upon a time, the region was known as Dardistan. It was the home of the Darada tribe. Historical texts across cultures mention the tribe and its region.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kafir anti-islamism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/dardic/articles/kafir-anti-islamism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/dardic/articles/kafir-anti-islamism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threads-web.vercel.app/threads/1484142638215610371&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Indo-Iranian polytheists of Chitral and present-day Nuristan (erstwhile Kafiristan) seemed to have really hated Mohammedans in the 19th century. They would sacrifice to the Gods with a prayer to &amp;ldquo;Kill the Mussulmans&amp;rdquo; and considered killing Mohammedans their religious duty. In the 1800s, these Indo-Iranian &amp;ldquo;Kafir&amp;rdquo; polytheists of Afghanistan and Pakistan killed any Mohammedans who tried to enter their valleys and a young-man was expected to have killed a Mohammedan before he could marry. Lieutenant William Watts McNair of the Indian Surveyor Corps had recorded in 1883 that the Indo-Iranian polytheists of Kafiristan considered “slaying a Muslim” to be the most notable deed. The head of the victim was put on a tall tree.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KafiristAni resistance</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/dardic/articles/kafiristAni-resistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/dardic/articles/kafiristAni-resistance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TrueIndology/status/1787312394525397431&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abandoned to death: Ongoing Hindu genocide of a 1000 years.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Important thread about the unknown genocide of Kalash and Kafiristan tribes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PS: This will be a long but informative thread about the past and present of a hardly known Hindu tribal community. Please read until the end.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-are-the-kalash&#34;&gt;Who are the Kalash?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Kalash is a native tribe of around 4000 people residing in valleys of the Chitral District in Pakistan. This district shares borders with Nuristan in Afghanistan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
