<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Svembu on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/wealth/articles/svembu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Svembu on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/wealth/articles/svembu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Climate change &amp; India dev</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/wealth/articles/svembu/climate-change_india-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/wealth/articles/svembu/climate-change_india-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1436123028660707331&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1436123028660707331&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What should be India&amp;rsquo;s development trajectory? This question is all important and assumes urgency in light of global climate change. We have so far treated development and economic growth as a separate topic from climate change. Yet this dualism cannot provide us answers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I will make an important assumption: the present per capita energy consumption of America is not remotely feasible for India, even if the entire energy were to come from renewable sources. So, we have no option but to seek a way of life that consumes low energy per capita. Does that mean we must give up on economic development? I firmly believe it is possible for our vast population to have a shot at a decent life within the constraint of low energy consumption. We can and must design economic strategies that fit with that overarching goal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India - policy freedom</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/wealth/articles/svembu/india-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/wealth/articles/svembu/india-freedom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://unrollthread.com/t/1524198748578271232/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An important part of woke indoctrination in elite universities as it pertains to India is to understand that India&amp;rsquo;s very existence poses a challenge to the Marxist/materialist world-view that sees itself as the One True Way. India is a weird pagan relic in this view.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As long as India stayed poor - first due to colonialism and later due to socialism - it was only a charity case (&amp;ldquo;basket case&amp;rdquo;), to be rescued with money and evangelism. Crucially Indians could not have intellectual or moral agency. Well, India is no longer a basket case. That poses a serious intellectual problem for both the Marxist/materialists and the &amp;ldquo;civilize the savages&amp;rdquo; crowd. How can this pagan relic, worshipping elephants and monkeys and snakes and other weird forms, produce first rate thought?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manufacturing</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/wealth/articles/svembu/manufacturing-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/wealth/articles/svembu/manufacturing-challenges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;challenges&#34;&gt;Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/svembu/status/1890617207304122736&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Labour costs are much lower in India than China but the productivity of our labour critically depends on capital goods and technology modernization in our manufacturing, particularly from the small and mid-sized manufacturers that collectively dominate the supply chain of consumer goods.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That needs investment, particularly from our small to mid-sized manufacturers. The barriers to that investment are both financial (higher interest rates in India) and cultural (too conservative to adopt the latest production technology). Enabling the small and mid-sized manufacturers to overcome these barriers is the key to India becoming a great manufacturing power.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
