<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Han feizi - misc on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Han feizi - misc on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/00/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/00/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Han Feizi, d. 233 B.C.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[Han Feizi. English Selections]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Han Feizi : basic writings / translated by Burton Watson.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;p. cm.—(Translations from the Asian classics)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Includes index.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Columbia University Press E-book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OUTLINE OF EARLY CHINESE HISTORY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PREFACE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Way of the Ruler&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On Having Standards&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Two Handles&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wielding Power&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Eight Villainies&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Ten Faults&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Difficulties of Persuasion&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mr. He&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Precautions Within the Palace&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Facing South&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 THE WAY OF THE RULER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/01_THE_WAY_OF_THE_RULER/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/01_THE_WAY_OF_THE_RULER/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Section 5)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Way is the beginning of all beings and the measure of right and wrong. Therefore the enlightened ruler holds fast to the beginning in order to understand the wellspring of all beings, and minds the measure in order to know the source of good and bad. He waits, empty and still,1 letting names define themselves and affairs reach their own settlement. Being empty, he can comprehend the true aspect of fullness; being still, he can correct the mover.2 Those whose duty it is to speak will come forward to name themselves; those whose duty it is to act will produce results. When names and results3 match, the ruler need do nothing more and the true aspect of all things will be revealed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 ON HAVING STANDARDS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/02_ON_HAVING_STANDARDS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/02_ON_HAVING_STANDARDS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Section 6)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No state is forever strong or forever weak. If those who uphold the law are strong, the state will be strong; if they are weak, the state will be weak. King Zhuang (r. 613–591) of Chu annexed twenty-six states and extended his territory three thousand &lt;em&gt;li&lt;/em&gt;, but death called him from his altars of the soil and grain, and Chu in time declined.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Duke Huan (r. 685–643) of Qi annexed thirty states and opened up his territory three thousand &lt;em&gt;li&lt;/em&gt;, but death called him from his altars of the soil and grain, and Qi in time declined. King Zhao (r. 311–279)1 of Yan extended his domain to the Yellow River on the south, made his capital at Ji, and strengthened his defenses at Zhuo and Fangcheng; he overran the state of Qi and conquered Zhongshan, until all who allied themselves with him were looked on as powerful and all who did not as insignificant; but death called him from his altars, and Yan in time declined. King Anxi (r. 276–243) of Wei attacked Yan to save&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 THE TWO HANDLES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/03_THE_TWO_HANDLES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/03_THE_TWO_HANDLES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Section 7)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The enlightened ruler controls his ministers by means of two handles alone. The two handles are punishment and favor. What do I mean by punishment and favor? To inflict mutilation and death on men is called punishment; to bestow honor and reward is called favor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Those who act as ministers fear the penalties and hope to profit by the rewards. Hence, if the ruler wields his punishments and favors, the ministers will fear his sternness and flock to receive his benefits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 THE EIGHT VILLAINIES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/04_THE_EIGHT_VILLAINIES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/04_THE_EIGHT_VILLAINIES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Section 9)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are eight strategies which ministers customarily employ to work their villainy. The first is called “Making use of his bedfellows.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What do I mean by this? The ruler is easily beguiled by lovely women and charming boys, by all those who can fawn and play at love. They wait for the time when he is enjoying his ease, take advantage of the moment when he is sated with food and wine, and ask for anything they desire, for they know that by this trick their requests are sure to be heeded. The ministers therefore ply them in the palace with gold and jewels and employ them to delude the ruler.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 THE TEN FAULTS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/05_THE_TEN_FAULTS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/05_THE_TEN_FAULTS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Section 10)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These are the ten faults:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To practice petty loyalty and thereby betray a larger loyalty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To fix your eye on a petty gain and thereby lose a larger one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To behave in a base and willful manner and show no courtesy to the other feudal lords, thereby bringing about your own downfall.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To give no ear to government affairs but long only for the sound of music, thereby plunging yourself into distress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 PRECAUTIONS WITHIN THE PALACE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/06_PRECAUTIONS_WITHIN_THE_PALACE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/06_PRECAUTIONS_WITHIN_THE_PALACE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Section 17)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is hazardous for the ruler of men to trust others, for he who trusts others will be controlled by others. Ministers have no bonds of flesh and blood which tie them to their ruler; it is only the force of circumstance which compels them to serve him. Hence those who act as ministers never for a moment cease trying to spy into their sovereign’s mind, and yet the ruler of men sits above them in indolence and pride. That is why there are rulers in the world who face intimidation and sovereigns who are murdered. If the ruler puts too much trust in his son, then evil ministers will find ways to utilize the son for the accomplishment of their private schemes. Thus Li Dui, acting as aid to the king of Zhao, starved the Father of the Ruler to death.1 If the ruler puts too much trust in his consort, then evil ministers will find ways to utilize the consort for the accomplishment of their private schemes. Thus the actor Shi aided Lady Li to bring about the death of Shensheng and to set Xiqi on the throne.2 Now if someone as close to the ruler as his own consort, and as dear to him as his own son, still cannot be trusted, then obviously no one else is to be trusted either.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 THE FIVE VERMIN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/07_THE_FIVE_VERMIN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/07_THE_FIVE_VERMIN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Section 49)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the most ancient times, when men were few and creatures numerous, human beings could not overcome the birds, beasts, insects, and reptiles. Then a sage appeared who fashioned nests of wood to protect men from harm. The people were delighted and made him ruler of the world, calling him the Nest Builder. The people lived on fruits, berries, mussels, and clams—things rank and evil-smelling that hurt their bellies, so that many of them fell ill. Then a sage appeared who drilled with sticks and produced fire with which to transform the rank and putrid foods. The people were delighted and made him ruler of the world, calling him the Drill Man.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 EMINENCE IN LEARNING</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/08_EMINENCE_IN_LEARNING/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/legalism/articles/han-feizi-misc/08_EMINENCE_IN_LEARNING/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Section 50)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the present age, the Confucians and Mohists are well known for their learning. The Confucians pay the highest honor to Confucius, the Mohists to Mozi. Since the death of Confucius, the Zizhang School, the Zisi School, the Yan Family School, the Meng Family School, the Qidiao Family School, the Zhongliang Family School, the Sun Family School, and the Yuezheng Family School have appeared. Since the death of Mozi, the Xiangli Family School, the Xiangfu Family School, and the Dengling Family School have appeared. Thus, since the death of its founder, the Confucian school has split into eight factions, and the Mohist school into three. Their doctrines and practices are different or even contradictory, and yet each claims to represent the true teaching of Confucius and Mozi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
