<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Nutrients on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/food/nutrients/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Nutrients on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/food/nutrients/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiber</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/food/nutrients/Fiber/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/food/nutrients/Fiber/</guid>
      <description>Fiber can be soluble and insoluble. Insoluble fibers aid bowel movement.
Soluble fiber helps reduce cholesterol, reduces sugar response after eating, normalizes blood lipid levels. Soluble fiber is not broken down until it reaches the large intestine where digestion causes gas (flatulence). In excessive amounts, soluble fiber causes high flatulance, cramps.
Fibers in legumes, such as peanuts, beans is mostly soluble fibers.
Tree Nuts have insoluble fibers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Omega 3 fatty acid</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/food/nutrients/Omega_3_fatty_acid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/food/nutrients/Omega_3_fatty_acid/</guid>
      <description>Vegetarian sources of omega 3 fats: flaxseeds and flaxseed oil, walnuts, hemp seeds, leafy green vegetables. Unfortunately, however, most naturally occurring vegetarian sources of omega 3 fatty acids are not very rich in DHA (a very important type of omega 3 fat). How much DHA is recommended per day? 100-300mg/day [Ref]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phytochemicals</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/food/nutrients/Phytochemicals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/food/nutrients/Phytochemicals/</guid>
      <description>Recent studies indicate that high intake of antioxidant vitamins (vitamins C, E and beta-carotene) does not appear to provide significant protection against Alzheimer’s disease. It is Phytochemicals in fruits or vegetables that provide the real benefit. The skins of fruits and vegetables are particularly rich in these phytochemicals. Recent studies have shown that polyphenols (like resveratrol in wine) extend maximum lifespan by 59 percent and delay age-dependent decay of cognitive performance in animal models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salt</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/food/nutrients/Salt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/food/nutrients/Salt/</guid>
      <description> A study published in the Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Journal revealed that slashing salt consumption reduces the risk of heart disease. [Ref]  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunlight</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/food/nutrients/Sunlight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/food/nutrients/Sunlight/</guid>
      <description>Getting enough UV  But in winter months at latitudes of 52 degrees north (above Birmingham), there is no ultraviolet light of the appropriate wavelength for the body to make vitamin D in the skin, research shows. [Ref]  Stopping excess UV  Denim is the &amp;lsquo;best protection from sun&amp;rsquo;. UK cancer experts agreed sunscreen should be the &amp;ldquo;last line of defense&amp;rdquo;. [Ref] Sun screen: Some of the best, according to Skin Deep, are Alba Botanica Sun’s Fragrance-Free Mineral Sunscreen, Avalon Baby’s Sunscreen SPF 18, Badger’s SPF 30 Sunscreen, Burt’s Bees’ Chemical-Free Sunscreen SPF 15, California Baby’s SPF 30, Juice Beauty’s Green Apple SPF 15 Moisturizer, and Kabana’s Green Screen SPF 15.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vitamins, minerals, antioxidants:</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/food/nutrients/Vitamins_minerals_antioxidants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/food/nutrients/Vitamins_minerals_antioxidants/</guid>
      <description> Have a diverse diet. Get good vitamings. If necessary use supplements.  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>