<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tiles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/matter/materials/tile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tiles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/matter/materials/tile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Clay</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/matter/materials/tile/clay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/matter/materials/tile/clay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;clay-tiles&#34;&gt;Clay tiles&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;roofing&#34;&gt;Roofing&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Common dimensions&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mid tile Coverage: 9 inch x 14 inch.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;flooring&#34;&gt;Flooring&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oft turn black, collect dirt and moss.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Appear to dry very fast - 12% water absorption. To avoid this, glossy or matte finish sealants are available which makes the tile less water and dirt absorbent. This sealants are re-applied every 4 to 5 years .&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cermaic&#34;&gt;Cermaic&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ceramic tiles are made from natural clay that is mixed with water and molded. Creators apply a glaze to the tile to help protect it from water and scratches, then fire the clay in a kiln to harden it.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Glazes are a glassy coat on tiles. Can use heavy metals (including lead) to generate colors and textures. This can leach out.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Water absorption &amp;lt; 3%.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ceramic tiles can get very cold in the winter, proving extremely unpleasant to bare feet.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Direct sunlight may fade the colour over time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;porcelain&#34;&gt;Porcelain&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Clay used is of slightly higher density and is fired longer. Can be further vitrified. Properties more or less analogous to vitrified tiles.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;vitrified-tiles&#34;&gt;Vitrified tiles.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The clay is mixed with quartz and feldspar before it is heated in the kiln. These extra ingredients melt, creating a glass element inside the tile. This glass component makes the vitrified files very hard and resistant to any type of absorption. Water absorption &amp;lt; .7%.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Double Charge vitrified tiles are fed through a press that prints pattern with a double layer of pigment; they are 3 to 4 mm thicker than compared to other tiles. This process does not permit complex patterns but results in a long-wearing tile surface, suitable for heavy traffic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Color&lt;/strong&gt;: Unglazed Vitrified tiles: A dye is mixed in with the clay before it is fired. This dye makes the clay a uniform color, so even if the vitrified tile is scratched, the color will stay the same.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polish&lt;/strong&gt;: Instead of being glazed, vitrified tiles are oft either polished or unpolished.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strength&lt;/strong&gt;: more strength and scratch resistance than marble or granite which are more prone to breakage.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Need a stronger adhesive than ceramic tiles.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;High embodied energy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;absorption-resistence&#34;&gt;Absorption resistence&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vitrified tile has an absorption rate of 0.50 percent, which is nearly-frost proof, while ceramic tile ranges from 7 to 3 percent, making it unsuitable for outdoor applications.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The surface of ceramic tiles directly improves indoor air quality because it cannot be penetrated by allergens such as pollen, dust, or dirt.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;pattern-printing-technology&#34;&gt;Pattern printing technology&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hi Def vs Printed - latter is cheaper.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stone</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/matter/materials/tile/stone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/matter/materials/tile/stone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;marble&#34;&gt;Marble&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Marble is a dense, porous stone with a high water absorption rate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;swirls and veined patterns on the surface&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Commonly found in shades of white, black, green, brown, grey and other natural hues, different grades of marbles will absorb water differently.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Polished marble is used to achieve a glossy finishes while honed and sand marble can be used for matte, rustic textures.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;marble tends to react very easily with most substances. Marble reacts with even dilute acids (read vinegar, mustard, citrus and other common household items) causing stains.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cold to the touch.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;granite&#34;&gt;Granite&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hard rock. Less absorptive.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Not as cold as marble, but still quite cool in bengaLUru winter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
