<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;2 From V P Singh to P V Narasimha Rao on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;2 From V P Singh to P V Narasimha Rao on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1990, September 30: Colonelganj (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_September_30_Colonelganj_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_September_30_Colonelganj_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;81% Hindus, 19% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: Mulayam Singh Yadav, Janata Dal, December 1989–June 1991&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Serious riots broke out in the tehsil (sub-district) of Colonelganj (Uttar Pradesh) and in nearby villages in the Gonda district. The atmosphere had been tense in Colonelganj since the first week of September when a BJP leader, Kalyan Singh, addressed a meeting about the Ram temple in Ayodhya attended by five thousand people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1990; April–October: Gujarat</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_AprilOctober_Gujarat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_AprilOctober_Gujarat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;89% Hindus, 9% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Gujarat: Chimanbhai Patel, Congress Party, March 1990–February 1994&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Violence took place in the communally-sensitive state of Gujarat. In Ahmedabad, several persons lost their lives in April and in October (between 30 and 40 victims). The spark for these riots was provided by the L. K. Advani-led Ram Rath Yatra, which started in the town of Somnath on September 25 and ignited violence in several towns in Gujarat along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1990; December 10–15: Kanpur (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_December_1015_Kanpur_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_December_1015_Kanpur_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;78% Hindus, 20% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: Mulayam Singh Yadav, Janata Dal, December 1989–June 1991&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Communal violence erupted in Kanpur (Uttar Pradesh) on December 10 when Muslim hawkers selling clothes were attacked and their merchandise burned. In retaliation, Muslims looted and set fire to Hindu shops. Hindus then destroyed Muslim shops and damaged a mosque. Six persons were killed in the violence. The PAC cut off telephone lines and water in a number of Muslim houses and made arbitrary arrests. On December 12, Muslims fought against the PAC in a confrontation that claimed four lives in shooting by the police and two other lives in stabbing incidents. By December 14, according to official sources, the toll amounted to 20 deaths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1990; December 15–23 and 1991; January 31–February 5: Khurja (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_December_1523_and_1991_January_31February_5_Khurja_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_December_1523_and_1991_January_31February_5_Khurja_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;79% Hindus, 21% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: Mulayam Singh Yadav, Janata Dal, December 1989–June 1991&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The city of Khurja (Uttar Pradesh) in the Bulandshahar district witnessed communal violence on two occasions due to the Ramjanmabhoomi campaign. In the first riot, which started on December 15, seventy-four people lost their lives (62 Muslims and 12 Hindus). Violence took place after a Muslim government employee was stabbed: although he was sent to Delhi for treatment, the Hindi newspaper Aaj published a false report that he was dead, leading to widespread rioting in the town. Most of the killings took place in the neighborhood of Sarai Sheikh Alam, where Banias and Brahmins (Hindu upper castes) targeted the few Muslim houses in the area. Further rioting took place on January 31 after a bomb exploded in a Muslim house. This second phase of violence lasted till February 5, claiming 22 lives (18 Muslims and four Hindus). It was characterized by the active involvement of the PAC. Rumors spread by the newspapers and inflammatory VHP-inspired pamphlets are said to have stirred up communal hatreds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1990; December 16: Agra (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_December_16_Agra_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_December_16_Agra_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;82% Hindus, 15% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: Mulayam Singh Yadav, Janata Dal, December 1989–June 1991&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Violence took place in Agra (Uttar Pradesh), the media reported 11 lives lost, but according to Engineer there had been 22 victims. The large majority of those killed were poor Muslims. At least eight were killed by the PAC who shot the victims dead inside their homes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;***(Engineer 1991c)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1990; December 7–10: Aligarh (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_December_710_Aligarh_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_December_710_Aligarh_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;57% Hindus, 41% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: Mulayam Singh Yadav, Janata Dal, December 1989–June 1991&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Large riots broke out again in the city of Aligarh (Uttar Pradesh). Communal tensions had been rising in the city since October 30, when kar sevaks were shot dead by the police in the city of Ayodhya (Uttar Pradesh), some 500 kilometers from Aligarh. Devotees carrying the ashes of the dead travelled throughout the state, including to Aligarh, thereby arousing tensions between the communities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1990; December 7–17: Hyderabad (Andhra Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_December_717_Hyderabad_Andhra_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_December_717_Hyderabad_Andhra_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;54% Hindus, 43% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Andhra Pradesh: &lt;a href=&#34;marri-chenna-reddy.html&#34;&gt;Marry Chenna Reddy&lt;/a&gt;, Congress Party, December 1989–17 December 1990&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A new bout of gruesome violence occurred in Hyderabad (Andhra Pradesh). The atmosphere in the city had been tense since October 1990. On October 9, the killing of a notorious criminal by the police led to clashes in different parts of the town, according to the Justice Heeraman Singh Commission of Inquiry. After L. K. Advani&amp;rsquo;s arrest in Bihar on October 23, the BJP and Muslim organizations distributed provocative pamphlets. Eleven people were killed in communal violence between October 29 and November 1 in Hyderabad and in the neighboring Ranga Reddy district. Reciprocal killings between Hindu and Muslim mafia gangs also occurred in the city.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1990; November 14: Delhi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_November_14_Delhi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_November_14_Delhi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;81% Hindus, 12% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Delhi: none, Delhi was then a Union Territory, not a state&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Delhi, which had remained relatively unaffected by communal troubles till then, witnessed riots on November 14, in the Sadar Bazar area (Old City). Violence started after a silent march was conducted by several unknown minority organizations, such as the All Indian Minority Front, the All India Muslim Unity Front, and the Sikh Muslim Dalit Panth-among others. In the seemingly peaceful procession, youths were armed with lathis and daggers. In the Sadar Bazar area, provocative speeches triggered clashes between the marchers and members of the majority community. The violence claimed around ten lives. The Shahi Imam of the Jama Masjid, Syed Abdullah Bukhar condemned the attitude of the procession&amp;rsquo;s participants and blamed the local administration for its inefficiency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1990; October 30–November 2: Ayodhya (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_October_30November_2_Ayodhya_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_October_30November_2_Ayodhya_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: Mulayam Singh Yadav, Janata Dal, December 1989–June 1991&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On October 30, kar sevaks (Hindu religious volunteers) tried to assault the Babri Masjid in Ayodhya (Uttar Pradesh). The chief minister of the state, Mulayam Singh Yadav, gave firm orders that they should be prevented from doing so. The police opened fire. Twenty-six kar sevaks were killed. Immediately after, on October 30, to take revenge for the new «Hindu martyrs», outbreaks of anti-Muslim violence occurred in several places (Baroda, Ahmedabad, and Indore, Uttar Pradesh, and in Bihar on November 1 and 2), claiming dozens of lives. The Uttar Pradesh state government had to impose a curfew on more than thirty towns. The VHP then managed to capitalize on the event by organizing Asthi Kalash Yatras (processions carrying the ashes and bones of the «martyrs») throughout the country. These processions left another bloody trail of communal riots behind them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1990; October 30–November 2: Bijnor (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_October_30November_2_Bijnor_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_October_30November_2_Bijnor_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;56% Hindus, 42% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: Mulayam Singh Yadav, Janata Dal, December 1989–June 1991&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A very serious riot broke out in Bijnor (Uttar Pradesh) due to the «Babri Masjid/Ramjanmabhoomi issue.» Curfew had to be imposed for ten days. Tensions had been rising since Chief Minister Mulayam Singh Yadav&amp;rsquo;s speech on October 9, in which he promised to protect Muslims, the Backward Classes and the Scheduled Castes (SCs) from attacks by Hindu communal organizations. Shops were looted and set on fire after his visit. The arrests, in Ayodhya, of kar sevaks-who were subsequently imprisoned in Bijnor-further communalized the atmosphere. On October 28, demonstrations were organized to protest against their imprisonment conditions. On October 30, when the BBC announced that the VHP had hoisted its flag on the Babri Masjid in Ayodhya, Hindu victory processions marched in Bijnor. They were apparently stoned by Muslims, leading to widespread rioting. Mosques were damaged. Armed gangs launched attacks on villages. The arrival of the PAC led to an increase in anti-Muslim violence. Forty persons died in the town of Bijnor itself and eight in the district according to official reports. Unofficial sources put the death toll at 200.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1990; October: Karnataka</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_October_Karnataka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_October_Karnataka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;84% Hindus, 12% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Karnataka: Veerendra Patil, Congress Party, November 1989–10 October 1990, S. Bangarappa, Congress Party, 17 October 1990–November 1992&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Riots took place in several parts of the state of Karnataka, inaugurating a cycle of communal violence in the south of India. The towns of Ramnagaram, Channapatna, Kolar, Davengere, and Tumkur witnessed communal violence that left 46 people dead according to the official count. Religious sensitivities had been exacerbated by the coincidence of the Hindu week of Dussehra with the birthday of Prophet Mohammed on October 3. Ram Jyoti processions (processions bearing the light of Ram) inflamed communal passions. In Channapatna, the «eve-teasing» (sexual harassment) of a Muslim girl by a Hindu boy triggered riots in which 17 people died (13 Muslims and 4 Hindus). In Kolar, the Ram Jyoti procession was held on October 2, followed by a Muslim procession for the Prophet&amp;rsquo;s anniversary on October 3 during which decorative illuminations were destroyed. Muslim mobs burned several vehicles, leading to retaliations from Hindus, in which two persons were stabbed to death. In Davengere, communal violence occurred during the Ram Jyoti procession leading to one person dead-shot by the police and eight deaths in stabbing incidents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1990; October: Rajasthan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_October_Rajasthan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1990_October_Rajasthan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;89% Hindus, 9% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Rajasthan: B. S. Shekhawat, BJP, March 1990–December 1992&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Troubles erupted in the state of Rajasthan. On October 3, in Udaipur, riots occurred when a Hindu Ram Jyoti procession (bearing the light of Ram) was stoned. A Hindu mob subsequently gathered to protest and demanded a ban on the Muslim Miladun Nabi (Prophet&amp;rsquo;s birthday) procession. A local rivalry between Hindu Sindhis (who came after Partition) and economically well-off Bohra Muslims was the underlying cause of the violence. One person was killed. In Jaipur (Rajasthan), violence took place after the Ram Rath Yatra of L. K. Advani was halted in the town of Samastipur (Bihar) on October 23. Advani was arrested and subsequently imprisoned in Masanjore. This event ignited several tows in Uttar Pradesh, Gujarat, and Rajasthan. In Jaipur, the BJP called for a bandh (general strike) and large numbers of people started gathering in the streets. The (false) rumor that Hindu children were held captive in a mosque in the Muslim-dominated Ramganj area sparked off riots. Houses were burned. Audio cassettes inciting people to violence could be heard in different parts of the city. Well-armed Hindu and Muslim groups fought with each other. The violence claimed around fifty lives. The Justice M. L. Tibrewal Commission of Inquiry denounced the unpreparedness of the police in these riots.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1991; March 24: Bhadrak (Orissa)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1991_March_24_Bhadrak_Orissa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1991_March_24_Bhadrak_Orissa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;94% Hindus, 6% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Orissa: Bijayananda Patnaik, Janata Dal, March 1990–March 1995&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Riots occurred in the usually quiet state of Orissa (which had not experienced any communal riots since 1964). The town of Bhadrak witnessed communal violence on March 24, on the occasion of the Hindu festival of Ram Navami. The procession took place in a tense atmosphere due to the «Babri Masjid/Ramjanmabhoomi issue.» Surprisingly, the police allowed it to pass through a Muslim quarter. The usual scenario reoccurred, abusive slogans were shouted, and violence broke out. Muslims retaliated against the economically dominant Hindu Marwari community. The police were late to intervene. The BJP subsequently called for a state-wide bandh (general strike). Violence flared up in the town of Soro after an altercation between Hindus and Muslims. Respectively, 17 and 16 persons died in Bhadrak and Soro.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1991; March 27: Saharanpur (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1991_March_27_Saharanpur_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1991_March_27_Saharanpur_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;52% Hindus, 44% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: Mulayam Singh Yadav, Janata Dal, December 1989–June 1991&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The usually peaceful city of Saharanpur (Uttar Pradesh) was the site of serious communal riots. As in Bhadrak, these rather unexpected riots took place during the Hindu festival of Ram Navami-which coincided that year with the Muslim month of Ramzan. On March 24, the Ram Navami procession was prevented from passing near a mosque where evening prayers were being said. Hindu communal organizations (the BJP, RSS, VHP and the Bajrang Dal–the student wing of the VHP) insisted on completing the procession and began promulgating active propaganda. Tensions increased between Hindu and Muslim groups. Both sides were poised for a battle. On March 26, the local administration finally gave permission for the procession to complete its route. It was conducted ostentatiously, stopping near the Jama Masjid. Anti-Muslim slogans were shouted. Some of the marchers started to occupy the steps of the mosque. The police proved ineffectual. This provocative attitude triggered communal riots. The rumor that the mosque had been attacked led to violent retaliation by Muslim youths who targeted Hindu shops in several parts of the town. The violence claimed 12 lives officially and more than 40 according to media reports. Before the riots, the superintendent of police had been transferred, leaving the city without any competent officer in charge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1991; May 19: Kanpur (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1991_May_19_Kanpur_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1991_May_19_Kanpur_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;78% Hindus, 20% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: Mulayam Singh Yadav, Janata Dal, December 1989–June 1991&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Riots took place in the industrial and violent city of Kanpur (Uttar Pradesh). Tensions had been steadily rising for more than one year with recurring altercations between Muslims and the PAC (police bullets were responsible for 6 deaths in April and another 20 in December 1990). In May, in the midst of the election campaign and in a context of communal polarization due to the «Babri Masjid/Ramjanmabhoomi controversy,» young BJP activists led an electoral procession through a Muslim locality. Muslim youths retaliated and rioting spread through the entire city. Twenty persons were killed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1991; May 20: Meerut (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1991_May_20_Meerut_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1991_May_20_Meerut_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;61% Hindus, 36% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: Mulayam Singh Yadav, Janata Dal, December 1989–June 1991&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On Election Day, riots also took place in Meerut (Uttar Pradesh). About to lose the Meerut city seat, the BJP organized aggressive campaigns to prevent Muslims from voting. Eighteen persons (16 Muslims and two Dalits) were brutally killed in broad daylight near the Nigar Cinema. The police remained impassive. In retaliation, Muslims burned Hindu shops and widespread rioting engulfed the city. Around 30 people died in the violence as per official records (more than 50 according to unofficial sources).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1991; November 8 and 13: Varanasi (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1991_November_8_and_13_Varanasi_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1991_November_8_and_13_Varanasi_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;68% Hindus, 31% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: Kalyan Singh, BJP, June 1991–December 1992&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two days of communal violence in Varanasi (Uttar Pradesh) left between 15 and 50 people dead according to the media. On November 8, a Kali Puja procession was headed by one of the numerous Hindu clubs of the city, the Navsang Club. While passing through the Muslim area of Madanpura, the marchers shouted anti-Muslim slogans and set off firecrackers, launching a riot. Muslim members of the audience in the nearby cinema hall were harassed by the rioters. A curfew was imposed but subsequently lifted on November 13, leading to strong retaliation from the Muslims. Passers-by were stabbed in Madanpura. As a consequence, the PAC carried out violent search operations in the area in which one Muslim was killed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1992; December 10: Delhi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_December_10_Delhi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_December_10_Delhi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;81% Hindus, 12% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Delhi: none, Delhi was then a Union Territory, not a state&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Violence also took place in Delhi, in the poor neighborhood of Seelampur, on the night of December 10. The immediate cause of the violence remains unknown. Muslims alleged that a rumor declaring that the Mustafa mosque had been razed to the ground triggered the violence, while Hindus claim that riots started after Muslims raped and killed an under-aged Hindu girl. Mobs started demonstrating. Large-scale arson took place. The police intervened. Between sixteen and twenty people died, most of them burned to death or hit by police bullets. A report by the PUCL (People&amp;rsquo;s Union for Civil Liberties) held the police responsible for instigating violence, spreading rumors, and indiscriminant firing at the minority community. Muslims remained permanently terrified of the police forces after this incident.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1992; December 6–11: Kanpur (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_December_611_Kanpur_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_December_611_Kanpur_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;78% Hindus, 20% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: none, President&amp;rsquo;s Rule from 6 December 1992 to 4 December 1993&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The industrial and communally-sensitive city of Kanpur (Uttar Pradesh) was also badly affected by the post-Babri Masjid violence. Muslim mobs upset by certain BBC broadcasts started looting Hindu shops and administrative offices on December 6. Four or five people were killed. Rioting spread to the city in subsequent days, with a peak of massive killings on December 9 and 10. Hindu mobs attacked Muslims with little interference from the police. Particularly notorious incidents occurred in the southern periphery of the city, where the riot spun out of control. According to official sources, 11 people died during four days of rioting in the town. Unofficial reports put the death toll much higher. According to Brass, «the destruction and killings in Kanpur were second only to that which occurred in Bombay,» although he provides no figures. Industrial units and shops were looted and set afire. Muslim houses, properties, and mosques were specifically and heavily targeted. A rapid deployment of troops helped curb the violence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1992; December 6–12: Bombay (Maharashtra)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_December_612_Bombay_Maharashtra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_December_612_Bombay_Maharashtra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Religious composition of the population (as per the 2001 census):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;67% Hindus, 19% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Maharashtra: Sudhakarrao Naik, Congress Party, June 1991–March 1993&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following the demolition of the Babri Masjid, Bombay (Maharashtra) was the scene of serious Hindu–Muslim violence. The December 1992 events constituted the first phase of a communal riot that was to be repeated on a larger scale in January 1993. The Justice B. N. Srikrishna Commission of Inquiry stated that there had been a build-up of communal fervor among Hindus and Muslims in the weeks preceding the demolition of the Babri Masjid. As the news of the demolition spread in the city on December 6, Muslims flowed out into the streets. Spontaneous communal incidents erupted in various parts of the city. Communal Hindu victory processions, such as the celebration rally held by the Shiv Sena in the slum of Dharavi, provoked the rage of Muslims. Transport buses and Hindu temples were damaged. Muslim criminals looted Hindu shops. Policemen were targeted by Muslim mobs: two constables were killed on December 7. The situation further degraded on December 7 and 8. In some places, the violence took the form of a police-versus-Muslim confrontation. According to media sources, ninety percent of the dead were killed by police firing. It is asserted that the police, incontestably, engaged in anti-Muslim behavior during these riots. In the area of Bainganwadi, near the mosque Nur-e-llahi, Shiv Sainiks (activists of the Shiv Sena) had come along with the police who subsequently shot many Muslims to death and set fire to the mosque. In the Dharavi slum, stoning between the two communities began on December 7. The police arrived on December 8, arrested many Muslims and opened fire in many areas of Dharavi: forty-two persons were killed in this slum, among them 40 who were victims of police shooting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1992; December 6–12: Surat (Gujarat)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_December_612_Surat_Gujarat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_December_612_Surat_Gujarat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;84% Hindus, 12% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Gujarat: Chimanbhai Patel, Congress Party, March 1990–February 1994&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The city of Surat (Gujarat) witnessed horrific communal violence. The riot started following a rally that had been organized by the BJP in support of the kar sevaks who were responsible for the destruction of the Babri Masjid in Ayodhya. One thousand persons participated in the procession, including VHP and RSS members. In retaliation, Muslim youths damaged shops in the old city. A small and marginal organization, the BMSS (Bharatiya Minority Suraksha Sangh) subsequently called for a Surat bandh on December 7. By December 8, riots had spread to the whole city. Fifty-seven persons were burned alive and entire slums were razed to the ground. In the area of Varachha Road, a four-thousand-strong armed mob attacked Muslim houses, leaving in their wake 27 people dead. In Ved Road, Muslim houses were marked by Hindu criminals and subsequently looted, leading to the death of 32 persons. In the suburbs of Surat, train passengers were attacked. Workers from the diamond industry and criminals were among the killers. These riots claimed 180–190 lives according to media reports. But for other sources, even a figure of 200 dead would be an underestimation. The majority of those killed were Muslims. The violence produced nineteen thousand new refugees. The usually peaceful city of Surat accounted for nearly two-thirds of the death toll in Gujarat, (Fifty-eight persons also died in Ahmedabad).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1992; December 6–13: Karnataka</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_December_613_Karnataka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_December_613_Karnataka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;84% Hindus, 12% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Karnataka: M. Veerappa Moily, Congress Party, November 1992–December 1994&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The state of Karnataka was the worst hit of the four southern states by the post-demolition (Babri Masjid) violence. Violence flared up in the districts and towns that had already experienced communal troubles in 1990 during the Ram Rath Yatra of L. K. Advani. The media reported 73 deaths in the state. Muslim anger, in the days following the destruction of the Babri Masjid, led to a strong Hindu backlash. There were 19 deaths in Bangalore, most of them in police firing, after Muslim demonstrations incited the BJP to call for a bandh (strike). Nine deaths were reported in Gulbarga following the attack on a police station in a Muslim majority area. In Bidar, Hindu–Muslim troubles claimed ten lives, half of them in police firing. In the twin cities of Hubli and Dharwad, stray stabbing incidents and attacks on individual houses claimed an additional seven lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1992; December 7–12: Calcutta (West Bengal)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_December_712_Calcutta_West_Bengal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_December_712_Calcutta_West_Bengal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;78% Hindus, 20% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of West Bengal: Jyoti Basu, CPI(M), June 1977–November 2000&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contrary to what had occurred in 1990, Calcutta (West Bengal) was seriously affected by the Ayodhya demolition, but the troubles there could not really be qualified as communal in nature. Deep emotions did exist, but the violence which developed was caused by the over-confidence of the Left-led government: the lifting of a curfew was carried out with precipitation (on December 9), and the criminals took over in an attempt to clear a site for their own building plans. The poor Muslim slum of Metiabruz was set afire. In the end, there were a number of casualties (35 deaths) amid a total failure on the part of the administration and political leaders who were completely absent during the events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1992; December 7–15: Bhopal (Madhya Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_December_715_Bhopal_Madhya_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_December_715_Bhopal_Madhya_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;68% Hindus, 27% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Madhya Pradesh: Sunderlal Patwa, BJP, March 1990–15December 1992&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The demolition of the Babri Masjid also triggered large-scale riots in Bhopal (Madhya Pradesh), a city which had generally been spared by communal violence. The atmosphere had been increasingly tense for quite some time because of the influence of Hindu communal activists. On December 6, a victory procession led by the Bajrang Dal through the old city (Muslim populated) and BBC reports about the demolition further inflamed communal passions. Bands of angered Muslim youths targeted government buildings and Hindu residents in the old town. The spread of sensational rumors by the Hindi press and agitation by Hindu nationalist activists led to widespread communal rioting. The main victims were poor Muslims who had already suffered during the 1984 gas catastrophe and middle-class Muslims from the BHEL industry (Bharat Heavy Electricals Limited). Four thousand families were rendered homeless by the violence. The police were accused of connivance with Hindu communal groups. The BJP state government demonstrated little effort in attempting to control the violence. The media reported more than 175 deaths. The Justice K. K. Dubey Commission of Inquiry established that 142 people died in these riots-thirty-four shot dead by the police.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1992; December 7–8: Assam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_December_78_Assam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_December_78_Assam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;65% Hindus, 31% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Assam: Hiteshwar Saikia, Congress Party, June 1991–April 1996&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The state of Assam, already tense due to the Bengali-Assamese language issue and to agitation by the AAMSU (All Assam Minority Students Union), experienced communal violence in the wake of the Babri Masjid destruction. The districts of Nagaon (75 deaths by official counts) and Dhubri (12 deaths) were particularly affected. While official estimates put the death toll for the entire state at 87, the media estimated that 100 to 300 people perished in the violence. Bengalis (Hindus and Muslims) comprised the largest group among the victims. Assamese (Hindus and Muslims) were generally spared. Troubles started on December 7 when Muslim households symbolically turned on their lights to protest against the demolition of the mosque. In the Nagaon district, posters demanding the reconstruction of the Babri Masjid were hung up. The town of Doboka (18 deaths on December 8) was particularly rocked by the violence after a provocative speech by a local Congress leader. Retaliation took place on December 9 in the town of Jamunamukh, claiming around 20 lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1992; December 7–9: Rajasthan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_December_79_Rajasthan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_December_79_Rajasthan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;89% Hindus, 9% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Rajasthan: B. S. Shekhawat, BJP, March 1990–15 December 1992&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The state of Rajasthan also experienced communal violence in the aftermath of the Babri Masjid demolition. The riots claimed 60 lives throughout the state with the capital, Jaipur, being particularly affected (28 dead). Most of the deaths were attributed to shooting by police.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;**(Sunday 27/12/1992–02/01/1993); **(Frontline 01/01/1993)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1992; October 2–9: Sitamarhi (Bihar)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_October_29_Sitamarhi_Bihar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1992_October_29_Sitamarhi_Bihar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;79% Hindus, 21% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Bihar: Laloo Prasad Yadav, Janata Dal, March 1990–March 1995&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Communal riots broke out in the district of Sitamarhi (Bihar), particularly in the town of Sitamarhi and in the village of Riga. Clashes started on October 2 when a Durga Puja procession shouting slogans such as «Jai Shri Ram» («Long live Ram») near a mosque was stopped by some Muslim youths. Brick-batting took place. On October 4, the Puja Samiti (Prayers&amp;rsquo; Committee) decided that the Durga idol was to be immersed in a by-pass pool after passing through a Muslim-dominated area. On October 8, the Durga procession commenced. Members from several akharas (traditional physical training centers) present in the procession shouted anti-Muslim slogans. Violence started between armed marchers and Muslim youths. The police fired, killing one Hindu and one Muslim. The media reported 50 deaths. Official sources put the death toll at 48, which included 41 Muslims, three Hindus, and four unidentified persons. But unofficially the actual death figure might amount to 65, of whom 58 were Muslims and seven, Hindus. Riots also took place in the village of Riga after a rumor spread that a ten-year-old Hindu girl had been brutally attacked and killed by Muslims in Sitamarhi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1993; January 6–20: Bombay (Maharashtra)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1993_January_620_Bombay_Maharashtra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1993_January_620_Bombay_Maharashtra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;67% Hindus, 19% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Maharashtra: Sudhakarrao Naik, Congress Party, June 1991–6 March 1993&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The second phase of the Bombay riots commenced on January 6. While the first phase of rioting in December 1992 was the result of a spontaneous reaction by Muslim mobs who had been angered by the demolition of the Babri Masjid, the Justice Srikrishna Commission of Inquiry established that the second phase of the riots resulted from the communal propaganda disseminated by Hindu nationalist organizations. Inflammatory articles, notably provocative editorials written by Shiv Sena leader Bal Thackeray in the newspapers Samna and Navaakal, inflamed communal passions. The Srikrishna Commission pointed out that preparations had been made after the December 1992 riots: surveys had been conducted by Shiv Sainiks to identify Muslim houses, shops, rickshaws, and taxis. Voters&amp;rsquo; lists with Muslim names had also been made available to the chiefs of Shiv Sena shakhas (branches).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1993; March 12: Bombay (Maharashtra)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1993_March_12_Bombay_Maharashtra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1986-11/2_From_V_P_Singh_to_P_V_Narasimha_Rao/1993_March_12_Bombay_Maharashtra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;67% Hindus, 19% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Maharashtra: Sharad Pawar, Congress Party, 6 March 1993–March 1995&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In retaliation for the Bombay riots of December 1992 and January 1993, a series of bomb blasts occurred in different areas of Bombay: at the Stock Exchange Building in the Fort area; the Air India Building at Nariman Point; the Zaveri-, Katha-, and Century Bazars (the latter at Worli); the Sena Bhavan at Dadar; the Hotel Sea Rock at Bandra; the Hotel Centaur at Juhu; and the Hotel Centaur at Santacruz Airport; killing 257 persons and injuring 713 others according to the Srikrishna Commission. The authors of the blast were Muslims recruited by the Muslim mafia leader &lt;a href=&#34;dawood-ibrahim.html&#34;&gt;Dawood Ibrahim&lt;/a&gt;, operating from Dubai.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
