<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/problems/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/problems/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Muslim demographics 2024</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/problems/articles/muslim-demographics_2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/problems/articles/muslim-demographics_2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/zeneraalstuff/status/1782611634977968301&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Muslim socio-economic indicators are ahead of SCs across India. Except in the Hindi heartland, Muslim socio-economic indicators are on par with OBC numbers across India.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As far as the TFR is concerned, while the gap is narrowing, there are no signs that Hindu and Muslim TFRs will ever converge, so the trend of Muslim share of population increasing is due to continue for the next 30 years at least.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>nehru-envin-pact</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/problems/articles/nehru-envin-pact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/problems/articles/nehru-envin-pact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nehru, like a typical imperialist slave, signed an agreement with Verier Envin, a foreign born missionary, imagine, to block Hindu Sadhus from parts of NE. Not just that, on Verier&amp;rsquo;s orders Nehru followed a policy of isolating NE from rest of India so Verier&amp;rsquo;s missionaries could convert all of NE and persecute Hindus in peace. The shameless man allowed the depraved missionaries to exploit the tribals too. Verier himself got sexually involved with underage women there. Only recently Indian govt has made strides in integrating NE with rest of India while Congress desperately tries to fan violence &amp;amp; separatism there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>nehru-muslim-reinvitation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/problems/articles/nehru-muslim-reinvitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/problems/articles/nehru-muslim-reinvitation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If they were indeed to be regarded as part of the &amp;ldquo;body and spirit&amp;rdquo; of Pakistan, could the Pakistani state legitimately restrict their entry? The Nehru-Liaqat Pact provided the Pakistani state with an agreement which appeared to secure Muslim rights within India, and could be used to argue that as a result there was no imperative for Muslim flight from India to Pakistan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As part of the agreement, the Indian government agreed to take back, in addition to the Muslims displaced in the east, Muslims from UP who had left for Pakistan between February I and May 31, 1950, and restore their properties to them. We have seen how the restoration of properties as part of the Nehru-Liaqat Pact was included in the Indian government&amp;rsquo;s 1960s foreign relations brochure on evacuee property. As a result of this promise, some 95,000 out of an enumerated 135,000 Muslims that had come to West Pakistan in that specified period registered to return to their homes in India. A year later, on June 15, 1951, Liaqat Ali Khan personally saw off 1,500 muhajirs at the train station who were returning to their homes in UP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sikh separatist triggers</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/problems/articles/sikh-separatist-triggers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/problems/articles/sikh-separatist-triggers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;state-reorganization-issue&#34;&gt;State reorganization issue&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nehru’s betrayal of Partition-era promises to Sikhs regarding “a territorial area within the nation to develop its own life and culture (…) with a great deal of autonomy for its constituent units.” (October 1945; reiterated in July 1946). Sikhs had lost a great deal and felt a need to culturally consolidate within India.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Operation Blue Star was not the first time the Golden Temple Complex was assaulted post-Independence. In 1955, protesters gathered there demanding a Punjabi-language State were assaulted by the police.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The linguistic reorganisation of States was completed by 1956, but Punjab was dragged through religious identity-politics and re-partitioned in 1966.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Anandpur Sahib Resolution of 1973 formalised a charter of Sikh demands. National in scope there isn’t a shadow of “separatism” in it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;blue-star&#34;&gt;Blue star&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;But the most immediate trigger for Indira was the fact that Sikhs had been the most well-mobilised protesters against her Emergency rule of 1975-77. She targeted the RSS, too, for the same reason.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;post-blue-star&#34;&gt;Post blue star&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;But her actions immediately after the operation continued, calculated aggression. Lt Gen KS Brar mentions Indira’s letter of appreciation for the operation. More importantly, while remaining in occupation of the temple complex, she challenged the Akali Dal’s hold over the Shiromani Gurdwara Parbandhak Committee and its power to elect head priests. Like the British in earlier times, she sought to insert herself into the organisation of Sikhism. The subsequent burning of the Sikh Reference Library and confiscation of its historic artefacts, many still unaccounted for, indicate that Indira’s target was not Jarnail Singh Bhindranwale, but the backbone of the Sikh tradition itself, holding nothing sacred.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;State media ran propaganda about implacable Sikh separatism. The pogrom of Sikhs on Rajiv Gandhi’s watch followed, fuelling an insurgency that shook the foundations of the State. In parallel, decades of economic mismanagement had come to a head, pushing India to the brink of becoming a failed state &amp;mdash; a precipice that the Narasimha Rao administration held at bay. From then on, challenges to the hold of the Nehru-Gandhi coterie on India grew stronger.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
