<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Outcastes on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Outcastes on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/00/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/00/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;List of illustrations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*page *vi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;vii&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;List of abbreviations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ix&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Glossary&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;x&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction: defiled trades&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART I THE MEANING OF DISHONOR IN EARLY MODERN SOCIETY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; Medieval versus early modern dishonor&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; Honor, status, and pollution&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART II THE DISHONORABLE MILIEU&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; The status of executioners and skinners, –&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; Living on the periphery of dishonor&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART III PARADOXICAL DISHONOR: PUNISHMENT AND HEALING&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; The infamous fur coat, or the unintended consequences of social discipline&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 Medieval versus early modern dishonor</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/01_Medieval_versus_early_modern_dishonor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/01_Medieval_versus_early_modern_dishonor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We begin with a brief discussion of the legal history of dishonor in the empire in the high and late middle ages. Prescriptive legal sources will serve as a foil against which to project the social history of dishonorable people in the early modern period. Medieval Germanic conceptions of dishonor were recorded in high medieval Germanic law books, such as the *Mirror of the Saxons *( &lt;em&gt;Sachsenspiegel&lt;/em&gt;), written around , or the *Mirror of the Swabians *( &lt;em&gt;Schwabenspiegel&lt;/em&gt;), written around &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Honor, status, and pollution</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/02_Honor_status_and_pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/02_Honor_status_and_pollution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Augsburg was one of the empire’s major cities with a population of around ,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;in . Augsburg’s status as a free imperial city had been firmly established since the early fourteenth century. As a sovereign state within the empire, Augsburg had developed an elaborate network of government bureaucracies that regulated life in the city. A brief consideration of Augsburg’s constitutional and social structure will help place *Unehrlichkeit * in context. Augsburg’s &lt;em&gt;Stadtrecht&lt;/em&gt;, the civic code of ,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 The status of executioners and skinners,</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/03_The_status_of_executioners_and_skinners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/03_The_status_of_executioners_and_skinners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Who were Augsburg’s dishonorable people? In the previous chapter we have considered under what circumstances contact between executioners and skinners and honorable citizens resulted in dishonor conflicts and under what circumstances they remained unproblematic. This entailed looking at the boundary of honor through the eyes of honorable society. We now change perspective to get an inside view. How did executioners and skinners experience dishonor? How did dishonor affect their legal, social, and economic status in Augsburg? We shall piece together the lives of individual executioners and skinners in the greatest possible detail, in order to reconstruct their social milieu.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Living on the periphery of dishonor</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/04_Living_on_the_periphery_of_dishonor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/04_Living_on_the_periphery_of_dishonor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have now considered in some detail what dishonor meant to executioners and skinners and how it shaped the particular social niche they occupied in Augsburg.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But beyond this core group of defiled trades, various other groups at times were challenged as dishonorable. Shepherds, bailiffs, grave-diggers, and latrine-cleaners were sometimes involved in dishonor conflicts in Augsburg. This chapter compares and contrasts the position of these groups on the periphery of dishonor with that of executioners and skinners in order to assess how the label of dishonor changed meanings as it was applied to different groups in different contexts. How did *Unehrlichkeit * affect the life chances of these trades on the periphery of dishonor?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 The infamous fur coat, or the unintended consequences of social discipline</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/05_unintended_consequences_of_social_discipline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/05_unintended_consequences_of_social_discipline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the preceding two chapters our focus has been the dishonorable milieu itself. We have detailed the legal, economic, and social effects of dishonor in order to reconstruct the experience and self-identity of dishonorable people. We now turn to the logic of pollution in the minds of honorable artisans who labeled these groups as dishonorable. Artisans identified two main sources of dishonor pollution: contact with animal carcasses and involvement in the performance of criminal punishment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 The executioner’s healing touch: health and honor in early modern German medical practice</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/06_The_executioners_healing_touch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/06_The_executioners_healing_touch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;‘‘It is one thing to let yourself be cured by the hangman, it is another thing entirely to be tortured under his hand.’’ Thus a journeyman embroiderer commented on the case of Augustin Gerstecker discussed in the previous chapter. Augustin’s arrest and torture precipitated a virulent dishonor conflict in the embroiderers’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;guild in . Pressed to justify why torture left a permanent taint on Augustin’s honor despite his innocence, the embroiderers explained, ‘‘If you get a stain on your clothing, you can wash it out. Nonetheless, you cannot say that the stain was never there.’’ To ‘‘be cured by the hangman,’’ however, did not pose a threat to an artisan’s honor. Early modern German executioners carried on an active medical practice and were regularly consulted by honorable guildsmen and by members of all other social estates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 Guardians of honor: artisans versus magistrates</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/07_Guardians_of_honor_artisans_versus_magistrates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/07_Guardians_of_honor_artisans_versus_magistrates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Uncompromising guardians of the boundary of honor, artisans pushed the social exclusion of dishonorable people to new extremes in the course of the early modern period. What was at stake for Augsburg’s honorable artisans in dishonor conflicts?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What did they stand to gain by excluding dishonorable candidates from their guild?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What did the authorities stand to lose if the stigma of dishonor spread? We have examined the symbolic logic of pollution and the ambivalent and paradoxical effects of dishonor in the contexts of punishment and healing. Now we turn to the role of dishonor in urban politics and economics, and in the social practices of daily life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 Honor and dishonor in the eighteenth century</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/08_Honor_and_dishonor_in_the_eighteenth_century/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/08_Honor_and_dishonor_in_the_eighteenth_century/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In  the enlightened Prussian physician and journalist Christian Gottfried Gru¨ner published a pamphlet in which he lauded the humanitarian advances of his century, while lamenting the fact that executioners and skinners had not benefited from such social reforms:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The history of modern times provides inspiring examples of humanitarianism towards the oppressed . . . Here in Germany, Jews have been given greater freedoms . . . In England . . .&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 Conclusion: dishonor and the society of orders</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/09_Conclusion_dishonor_and_the_society_of_orders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/west-german/articles/outcastes/09_Conclusion_dishonor_and_the_society_of_orders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Executioners and skinners and their families, the core group of dishonorable people, occupied a symbolic position as outsiders in early modern German society.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jurists classified them as infamous and listed a multitude of legal, social, and religious disabilities that derived from their dishonor: the executioner or skinner lived ‘‘like a wild animal, . . . excluded from the community of honorable people.’’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These legal scholars vastly exaggerated the discrimination executioners and skinners suffered in social practice, however. Executioners and skinners were not absolute pariahs. In Augsburg the city government did deny executioners and skinners citizenship, but the patrician magistrates did not discriminate against them in any other way. Honorable guildsmen, the lowest honorable estate in the corporate hierarchy within the city, were the social group that most adamantly enforced the social exclusion of dishonorable people. From the early sixteenth century on, no honorable guild incorporated a member of the dishonorable core group. Artisans were also most concerned about the danger of ritual pollution by social or physical contact with the executioner or skinner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
