<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT  on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT  on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Johannes Kepler</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-08-14_johannes-kepler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-08-14_johannes-kepler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;js_include&#34; url=&#34;https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/jyotiSHam/history/articles/MT/2005-08-14_johannes-kepler.md&#34;  newLevelForH1=&#34;5&#34; includeTitle=&#34;false&#34;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Friedrich Wilhelm Herschel’s clan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-07-05_friedrich-wilhelm-herschels-clan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-07-05_friedrich-wilhelm-herschels-clan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/07/05/friedrich-wilhelm-herschels-clan/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Father&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Isak Herschel- amateur astronomer and science enthusiast in addition to being a professional musician. Taught all his sons science and music.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;……………..&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wilhelm (William) Herschel: What more needs to be said? Was fluent of in many European languages.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sophia (sister of Wilhelm) Many descendents of her were professional muscians&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Alexander: Brother of Wilhelm, made most telescopes for Wilhelm, professional telescope maker in Germany&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Carolina (Caroline):Assistant of Wilhelm (scarred by smallpox and Rickettsial infection, hence unmarried). Learnt calculus and spherical trignometry from Wilhelm and was good at lengthy mental trigonometric calculations. Discovered 8 comets on her own. Gauss paid a visit to her to praise her compilation of the deep-sky catalog.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5) Dietrich : Youngest brother of Wilhelm, an entomologist who conducted the systematic survey and taxonomy of European lepidoptera; taught Wilhelm a system of cataloguing to use for his deep sky discoveries.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;………………..&lt;br&gt;&#xA;John (Johannes Friedrich) Herschel: Mathematician (was senior Wrangler), Musician, artist and knew many languages. Invented the contact lens. Had 12 descendents, including two sons who were scientists. Drew the pictures of surroundings of Cape Town and made systematic study of the plants of South Africa, including one named after him. Darwin was inspired by his book and discussed his early formulation of natural selection with him. Invented photographic image capture with silver bromide. Buried next to Darwin and Newton.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Longer survival: Scandinavia</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/MT_lekhAH/longer_survival_in_scandinavia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/MT_lekhAH/longer_survival_in_scandinavia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The heathen tradition survived the longest in Scandinavia. In contrast in Southern &amp;ldquo;Germania&amp;rdquo; the destructive imposition of u2 by Charle etc completely destroyed the original religion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like even in Sweden the killing of the king Sverker in 1156 CE might have been the last attempt at fighting against the crusade by the followers of the original religion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There was also a long struggle against Christian aggression in Norway well after the king converted &amp;amp; tried to impose his religion via missionaries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
