<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;reports in american newspapers on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;reports in american newspapers on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>154 INDIA: HER RELIGION AND CUSTOMS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/154_india_her_religion_and_customs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/154_india_her_religion_and_customs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;india-her-religion-and-customs&#34;&gt;INDIA: HER RELIGION AND CUSTOMS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Salem Evening News&lt;/em&gt;, August 29, 1893)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In spite of the warm weather of yesterday afternoon, a goodly number of&#xA;members of the Thought and Work club, with guests, gathered in Wesley&#xA;chapel to meet Swami Vive Kanonda,&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; a Hindoo monk, now&#xA;travelling in this country, and to listen to an informal address from&#xA;that gentleman, principally upon the religion of the Hindoos as taught&#xA;by their Vedar (Vedas.) or sacred books. He also spoke of caste, as&#xA;simply a social division and in no way dependent upon their religion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>155 HINDUS AT THE FAIR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/155_hindus_at_the_fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/155_hindus_at_the_fair/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hindus-at-the-fair&#34;&gt;HINDUS AT THE FAIR&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Boston Evening Transcript&lt;/em&gt;, September 30, 1893)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chicago, Sept. 23:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a room at the left of the entrance to the Art Palace marked&#xA;&amp;ldquo;No. 1 — keep out.&amp;rdquo; To this the speakers at the Congress of Religions&#xA;all repair sooner or later, either to talk with one another or with&#xA;President Bonney, whose private office is in one corner of the&#xA;apartment. The folding doors are jealously guarded from the general&#xA;public, usually standing far enough apart to allow peeping in. Only&#xA;delegates are supposed to penetrate the sacred precincts, but it is not&#xA;impossible to obtain an &amp;ldquo;open sesame&amp;rdquo;, and thus to enjoy a brief&#xA;opportunity of closer relations with the distinguished guests than the&#xA;platform in the Hall of Columbus affords.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>156 AT THE PARLIAMENT OF RELIGIONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/156_at_the_parliament_of_religions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/156_at_the_parliament_of_religions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;at-the-parliament-of-religions&#34;&gt;AT THE PARLIAMENT OF RELIGIONS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(The Dubuque, Iowa, &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;, September 29, 1893)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WORLD&amp;rsquo;S FAIR, Sept. 28. — (Special.) — The Parliament of religions&#xA;reached a point where sharp acerbities develop. The thin veil of&#xA;courtesy was maintained, of course, but behind it was ill feeling. Rev.&#xA;Joseph Cook criticised the Hindoos sharply and was more sharply&#xA;criticised in turn. He said that to speak of a universe that was not&#xA;created is almost unpardonable nonsense, and the Asiatics retorted that&#xA;a universe which had a beginning is a self-evident absurdity. Bishop J.&#xA;P. Newman, firing at long range from the banks of the Ohio, declared&#xA;that the orientals have insulted all the Christians of the United States&#xA;by their misrepresentations of the missionaries, and the orientals, with&#xA;their provokingly calm and supercilious smile, replied that this was&#xA;simply the bishop&amp;rsquo;s ignorance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>157 PERSONAL TRAITS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/157_personal_traits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/157_personal_traits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-traits&#34;&gt;PERSONAL TRAITS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Critic&lt;/em&gt;, October 7, 1893)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;. . . It was an outgrowth of the Parliament of Religions, which opened&#xA;our eyes to the fact that the philosophy of the ancient creeds contains&#xA;much beauty for the moderns. When we had once clearly perceived this,&#xA;our interest in their exponents quickened, and with characteristic&#xA;eagerness we set out in pursuit of knowledge. The most available means&#xA;of obtaining it, after the close of the Parliament, was through the&#xA;addresses and lectures of Swami Vivekananda, who is still in this city&#xA;[Chicago]. His original purpose in coming to this country was to&#xA;interest Americans in the starting of new industries among the Hindoos,&#xA;but he has abandoned this for the present, because he finds that, as&#xA;&amp;ldquo;the Americans are the most charitable people in the world,&amp;rdquo; every man&#xA;with a purpose comes here for assistance in carrying it out. When asked&#xA;about the relative condition of the poor here and in India, he replied&#xA;that our poor would be princes there, and that he had been taken through&#xA;the worst quarter of the city only to find it, from the standpoint of&#xA;his knowledge, comfortable and even pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>158 REINCARNATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/158_reincarnation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/158_reincarnation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reincarnation&#34;&gt;REINCARNATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Evanston Index&lt;/em&gt;, October 7, 1893)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the Congregational Church, during the past week, there have been&#xA;given a course of lectures which in nature much resembled the Religious&#xA;Parliament which has just been completed. The lecturers were Dr. Carl&#xA;van Bergen of Sweden, and Suami Vivekananda, the Hindu monk. &amp;hellip; Suami&#xA;Vivekananda is a representative from India to the Parliament of&#xA;Religions. He has attracted a great deal of attention on account of his&#xA;unique attire in Mandarin colors, by his magnetic presence and by his&#xA;brilliant oratory and wonderful exposition of Hindu philosophy. His stay&#xA;in Chicago has been a continual ovation. The course of lectures was&#xA;arranged to cover three evenings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>159 HINDU CIVILISATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/159_hindu_civilisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/159_hindu_civilisation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hindu-civilisation&#34;&gt;HINDU CIVILISATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[Although the lecture at Streator on October 9 was well attended, the&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Streator Daily Free Press&lt;/em&gt; of October 9 ran the following somewhat&#xA;dreary review:]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The lecture of this celebrated Hindoo at the Opera House, Saturday&#xA;night, was very interesting. By comparative philology, he sought to&#xA;establish the long admitted relationship between the Aryan races and&#xA;their descendants in the new world. He mildly defended the caste system&#xA;of India which keeps three-fourths of the people in utter and&#xA;humiliating subjection, and boasted that the India of today was the same&#xA;India that had watched for centuries the meteoric nations of the world&#xA;flash across the horizon and sink into oblivion. In common with the&#xA;people, he loves the past. He lives not for self, but for God. In his&#xA;country a premium is placed on beggary and tramps, though not so&#xA;distinguished in his lecture. When the meal is prepared, they wait for&#xA;some man to come along who is first served, then the animals, the&#xA;servants, the man of the house and lastly the woman of the household.&#xA;Boys are taken at 10 years of age and are kept by professors for a&#xA;period of ten to twenty years, educated and sent forth to resume their&#xA;former occupations or to engage in a life of endless wandering,&#xA;preaching, and praying, taking along only that which is given them to&#xA;eat and wear, but never touching money. Vivekananda is of the latter&#xA;class. Men approaching old age withdraw from the world, and after a&#xA;period of study and prayer, when they feel themselves sanctified, they&#xA;also go forward spreading the gospel. He observed that leisure was&#xA;necessary for intellectual development and scored Americans for not&#xA;educating the Indians whom Columbus found in a state of savagery. In&#xA;this he exhibited a lack of knowledge of conditions. His talk was&#xA;lamentably short and much was left unsaid of seeming greater importance&#xA;than much that was said.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>160 AN INTERESTING LECTURE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/160_an_interesting_lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/160_an_interesting_lecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-interesting-lecture&#34;&gt;AN INTERESTING LECTURE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Wisconsin State Journal&lt;/em&gt;, November 21, 1893)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The lecture at the Congregational Church [Madison] last night by the&#xA;celebrated Hindoo monk, Vivekananda, was an extremely interesting one,&#xA;and contained much of sound philosophy and good religion. Pagan though&#xA;he be, Christianity may well follow many of his teachings. His creed is&#xA;as wide as the universe, taking in all religions, and accepting truth&#xA;wherever it may be found. Bigotry and superstition and idle ceremony, he&#xA;declared, have no place in &amp;ldquo;the religions of India&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>161 THE HINDOO RELIGION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/161_the_hindoo_religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/161_the_hindoo_religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-hindoo-religion&#34;&gt;THE HINDOO RELIGION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Minneapolis Star&lt;/em&gt;, November 25, 1893)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Brahminism&amp;rdquo; in all its subtle attraction, because of its embodiment of&#xA;ancient and truthful principles, was the subject which held an audience&#xA;in closest attention last evening at the First Unitarian Church&#xA;[Minneapolis], while Swami Vive Kananda expounded the Hindoo faith. It&#xA;was an audience which included thoughtful women and men, for the&#xA;lecturer had been invited by the &amp;ldquo;Peripatetics,&amp;rdquo; and among the friends&#xA;who shared the privilege with them were ministers of varied&#xA;denominations, as well as students and scholars. Vive Kananda is a&#xA;Brahmin priest, and he occupied the platform in his native garb, with&#xA;caftan on head, orange colored coat confined at the waist with a red&#xA;sash, and red nether garments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>162 THE HINDOO MONK</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/162_the_hindoo_monk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/162_the_hindoo_monk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-hindoo-monk&#34;&gt;THE HINDOO MONK&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Appeal-Avalanche&lt;/em&gt;, January 16, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Swami Vive Kananda, the Hindoo monk, who is to lecture at the Auditorium&#xA;[Memphis] tonight, is one of the most eloquent men who has ever&#xA;appeared on the religious or lecture platform in this country. His&#xA;matchless oratory, deep penetration into things occult, his cleverness&#xA;in debate, and great earnestness captured the closest attention of the&#xA;world&amp;rsquo;s thinking men at the World&amp;rsquo;s Fair Parliament of Religion, and the&#xA;admiration of thousands of people who have since heard him during his&#xA;lecture tour through many of the states of the Union.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>163 PLEA FOR TOLERANCE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/163_plea_for_tolerance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/163_plea_for_tolerance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;plea-for-tolerance&#34;&gt;PLEA FOR TOLERANCE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Memphis Commercial&lt;/em&gt;, January 17, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An audience of fair proportions gathered last night at the Auditorium to&#xA;greet the celebrated Hindu monk. Swami Vive Kananda, in his lecture on&#xA;Hinduism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He was introduced in a brief but informing address by Judge R. J.&#xA;Morgan, who gave a sketch of the development of the great Aryan race,&#xA;from which development have come the Europeans and the Hindus alike, so&#xA;tracing a racial kinship between the people of America and the speaker&#xA;who was to address them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>164 MANNERS AND CUSTOMS IN INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/164_manners_and_customs_in_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/164_manners_and_customs_in_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;manners-and-customs-in-india&#34;&gt;MANNERS AND CUSTOMS IN INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Appeal-Avalanche&lt;/em&gt;, January 21, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Swami Vive Kananda, the Hindoo monk, delivered a lecture at La Salette&#xA;Academy [Memphis] yesterday afternoon. Owing to the pouring rain, a&#xA;very small audience was present.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The subject discussed was &amp;ldquo;Manners and Customs in India.&amp;rdquo; Vive Kananda&#xA;is advancing theories of religious thought which find ready lodgment in&#xA;the minds of some of the most advanced thinkers of this as well as other&#xA;cities of America.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>165 HINDOO PHILOSOPHY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/165_hindoo_philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/165_hindoo_philosophy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hindoo-philosophy&#34;&gt;HINDOO PHILOSOPHY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Detroit Free Press&lt;/em&gt;, February 16, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The second lecture of the Hindoo monk, Swami Vive Kananda, was given&#xA;last evening at the Unitarian church to a large and very appreciative&#xA;audience. The expectation of the audience that the speaker would&#xA;enlighten them regarding &amp;ldquo;Hindoo Philosophy,&amp;rdquo; as the lecture was&#xA;entitled, was gratified to only a limited extent. Allusions were made to&#xA;the philosophy of Buddha, and the speaker was applauded when he said&#xA;that Buddhism was the first missionary religion of the world, and that&#xA;it had secured the largest number of converts without the shedding of a&#xA;drop of blood; but he did not tell his audience anything about the&#xA;religion or philosophy of Buddha. He made a number of cute little jabs&#xA;at the Christian religion, and alluded to the trouble and misery that&#xA;had been caused by its introduction into heathen countries, but he&#xA;skilfully avoided any comparison between the social condition of the&#xA;people in his own land and that of the people to whom he was speaking.&#xA;In a general way he said the Hindoo philosophers taught from a lower&#xA;truth to a higher; whereas, a person accepting a newer Christian&#xA;doctrine is asked and expected to throw his former belief all away and&#xA;accept the newer in its entirety. &amp;ldquo;It is an idle dream when all of us&#xA;will have the same religious views,&amp;rdquo; said he. &amp;ldquo;No emotion can be&#xA;produced except by clashing elements acting upon the mind. It is the&#xA;revulsion of change, the new light, the presentation of the new to the&#xA;old, that elicits sensation.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>166 MIRACLES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/166_miracles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/166_miracles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;miracles&#34;&gt;MIRACLES&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Evening News&lt;/em&gt;, February 17, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I cannot comply with the request of The News to work a miracle in proof&#xA;of my religion,&amp;quot; said Vive Kananda to a representative of this paper,&#xA;after being shown The News editorial on the subject. &amp;ldquo;In the first&#xA;place, I am no miracle worker, and in the second place the pure Hindoo&#xA;religion I profess is not based on miracles. We do not recognize such a&#xA;thing as miracles. There are wonders wrought beyond our five senses, but&#xA;they are operated by some law. Our religion has nothing to do with them.&#xA;Most of the strange things which are done in India and reported in the&#xA;foreign papers are sleight-of-hand tricks or hypnotic illusions. They&#xA;are not the performances of the wise men. These do not go about the&#xA;country performing their wonders in the market places for pay. They can&#xA;be seen and known only by those who seek to know the truth, and not&#xA;moved by childish curiosity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>167 THE DIVINITY OF MAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/167_the_divinity_of_man/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/167_the_divinity_of_man/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-divinity-of-man&#34;&gt;THE DIVINITY OF MAN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Detroit Free Press&lt;/em&gt;, February 18, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Swami Vive Kananda, Hindoo philosopher and priest, concluded his series&#xA;of lectures, or rather, sermons, at the Unitarian church last night,&#xA;speaking on &amp;ldquo;The Divinity of God&amp;rdquo; [sic]. (Actually the subject was&#xA;&amp;ldquo;The Divinity of Man&amp;rdquo;.) In spite of the bad weather, the church was&#xA;crowded almost to the doors half an hour before the eastern brother — as&#xA;he likes to be called — appeared. All professions and business&#xA;occupations were represented in the attentive audience — lawyers,&#xA;judges, ministers of the gospel, merchants, rabbi — not to speak of the&#xA;many ladies who have by their repeated attendance and rapt attention&#xA;shown a decided inclination to shower adulation upon the dusky visitor&#xA;whose drawing-room attraction is as great as his ability in the rostrum.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>168 THE LOVE OF GOD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/168_the_love_of_god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/168_the_love_of_god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-love-of-god&#34;&gt;THE LOVE OF GOD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(The &lt;em&gt;Detroit Free Press&lt;/em&gt; report of this lecture is printed in Vol. VIII&#xA;of the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../../volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/the_love_of_god_ii.htm&#34;&gt;Complete&#xA;Works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Detroit Tribune&lt;/em&gt;, February 21, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The First Unitarian Church was crowded last night to hear Vive Kananda.&#xA;The audience was composed of people who came from Jefferson Avenue and&#xA;the upper part of Woodward Avenue. Most of it was ladies who seemed&#xA;deeply interested in the address and applauded several remarks of the&#xA;Brahman with much enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>169 THE WOMEN OF INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/169_the_women_of_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/reports_in_american_newspapers/169_the_women_of_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-women-of-india&#34;&gt;THE WOMEN OF INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Detroit Free Press&lt;/em&gt;, March 25, 1894)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kananda lectured last night at the Unitarian church on &amp;ldquo;The Women of&#xA;India.&amp;rdquo; The speaker reverted to the women of ancient India, showing in&#xA;what high regard they are held in the holy books, where women were&#xA;prophetesses. Their spirituality then was admirable. It is unfair to&#xA;judge women in the east by the western standard. In the west woman is&#xA;the wife; in the east she is the mother. The Hindoos worship the idea of&#xA;mother, and even the monks are required to touch the earth with their&#xA;foreheads before their mothers. Chastity is much esteemed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
