<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;01 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;01 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/00/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/00/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;dedication&#34;&gt;DEDICATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To all, of whatsoever church or nation, who with love for the Lord Jesus Christ are trying to give His Gospel to Japan, I dedicate this book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Differing as we do upon so many points, it is easy for us to see what we deem defeats in one another&amp;rsquo;s belief and practice; but if He to whose pure eyes all men must seem so imperfect&amp;quot; is not ashamed to call them brethren&amp;quot; whom He is sanctifying, let us not withhold the name from any that love and follow Him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 THE CALL TO JAPAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/01_THE_CALL_TO_JAPAN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/01_THE_CALL_TO_JAPAN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE first attempt to carry the Gospel to Japan was made by Christopher Columbus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nearly two centuries before the discoverer of America set out upon his memorable voyage, a Venetian merchant, who had recently been taken captive in a naval battle, was confined in a prison of Genoa, the city that afterwards became the birthplace of Columbus. The prisoner, who had spent many years in travelling through distant lands, was wont to relieve the tedium of confinement by telling his companions about the many strange things he had seen and heard. Among those that listened to his stories was a prisoner from Pisa, a man who had already written a few books and who saw that these tales furnished excellent material for another. It was at his request that Marco Polo, the Venetian merchant, dictated the narrative that gave to Europeans much more knowledge of the Far East than they had before possessed. One day he spoke as follows of a country which he himself had not visited, but of which he had often heard during his sojourn at the court of Kublai Khan:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 FRANCIS XAVIER IN JAPAN 1549-1551</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/02_FRANCIS_XAVIER_IN_JAPAN_1549-1551/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/02_FRANCIS_XAVIER_IN_JAPAN_1549-1551/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IN order that the events to be described in the following chapters may be better understood, it will be well to pause at this point in order to consider some of the political, social, and religious conditions of Japan at the time when Xavier and his companions reached its shores.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From ancient times the country had been divided into sixty-six provinces. Though the names by which these were designated have continued in use until the present day, the territories of the feudal lords were seldom coterminous with these divisions. In some cases a daimyo possessed several provinces, while in others a single province was divided between two or more of these barons, Xavier and his associates applied the name of &amp;ldquo;king&amp;rdquo; to these feudal lords; and there was much to justify the nomenclature, for many of them were practically sovereigns within their own estates, having little occasion to concern themselves about any person who might claim superiority over them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 WORK OF THE EARLY MISSIONARIES 1551-1570</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/03_WORK_OF_THE_EARLY_MISSIONARIES_1551-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/03_WORK_OF_THE_EARLY_MISSIONARIES_1551-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WHILE Xavier was in Bungo he received letters from Torres and Fernandez telling him of events in Yamaguchi. Immediately after his departure from that city the bonzes forced their way into the house where the missionaries dwelt, and began to make sport of them and their teachings. There also came for several successive days a number of the gentlemen and scholars of the city to propound various questions concerning the Christian religion. Fernandez sent to Xavier a list of these queries and of the answers that Torres made through him as interpreter. The questions were as follows:—&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 RAPID GROWTH OF THE CHURCH 1571-1582</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/04_RAPID_GROWTH_OF_THE_CHURCH_1571-1582/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/04_RAPID_GROWTH_OF_THE_CHURCH_1571-1582/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IT has already been noted that Nobunaga had no love for the Buddhist priests. His anger had been especially excited against those of Mt. Hiei because on several occasions they had rendered aid to his enemies. He therefore determined upon their destruction. When he disclosed the plan to his generals, they were inclined to remonstrate against an attack upon temples which since the building of Kyoto had been considered a protection against demons and had been held in such honour by Emperor and people. Nobunaga insisted that the priests were little better than a band of traitors who were bringing evil upon their country. Their religious professions, he said, ought not to protect them; for they lived in constant violation of the precepts of Buddha, eating fish and keeping concubines. He declared that it was time these hypocrites and rebels were destroyed. In pursuance of this policy, Nobunaga&amp;rsquo;s soldiers forced their way up the steep sides of the mountain, set fire to the buildings, and put to death every person they could find —priests, servants, concubines, and children. This event occurred September 29, 1571.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 HIDEYOSHI 1583-1598</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/05_HIDEYOSHI_1583-1598/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/05_HIDEYOSHI_1583-1598/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HIDEYOSHI AND HIS EDICTS AGAINST CHRISTIANITY 1583-1598&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TOYOTOMI HIDEYOSHI, who succeeded in gaining for himself the power formerly possessed by Nobunaga, seemed at first to regard the Christians with much favour. According to some Japanese writers, he believed that the foreign religion was a source of danger, and so he was only waiting for a favourable opportunity to drive the missionaries from the land. However this may have been, it was worth while to secure the good will of the Christian lords and warriors. Among these Takayama Ukon held a prominent place. In 1583 Konishi Yukinaga, who became commander of Hideyoshi&amp;rsquo;s fleet, was converted through Takayama&amp;rsquo;s influence. Under the name Augustine, which he took at baptism, he has frequent mention in the letters of the Jesuits. They give him the title of Grand Admiral. In connection with the expedition to Korea he holds a prominent place in Japanese history. Another conversion occurring at about the same time as Konishi&amp;rsquo;s was that of Kuroda Yoshitaka, whom the Jesuits term the General of the Cavalry. In their accounts he is called Simon Kondera. The governors of the important cities of Osaka and Sakai were Christians, as were also the officers whom the missionaries call the Secretary of State and the Grand Treasurer. Several daimyos and other men of high rank were either baptised believers or students of Christianity. Magdalen, the secretary of Hideyoshi&amp;rsquo;s wife, and Jane Onogi, wife of the Daimyo of Fukuchiyama and considered the best poetess of that time, held important places among the ladies in Hideyoshi&amp;rsquo;s court.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 INCREASED PERSECUTION UNDER IEYASU 1598-1616</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/06_INCREASED_PERSECUTION_UNDER_IEYASU_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/06_INCREASED_PERSECUTION_UNDER_IEYASU_15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HIDEYOSHI, shortly before his death, had appointed a board of five Regents, with Tokugawa Ieyasu at their head. Under their direction was another board of five Ministers. To these last was committed the care of Hideyoshi&amp;rsquo;s son, Hideyori, who was then six years old. Ieyasu, who was born in 1542, had served under both Nobunaga and Hideyoshi. His original territories had been in the provinces of Mikawa and Totomi; but in the re-distribution of fiefs made by Hideyoshi he had been transferred to the provinces lying about the Bay of Yedo. He made Yedo his capital, building there a castle that became the centre of the great city that quickly grew up around it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 APPARENT EXTIRPATION 1616-1715</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/07_APPARENT_EXTIRPATION_1616-1715/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/07_APPARENT_EXTIRPATION_1616-1715/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APPARENT EXTIRPATION OF CHRISTIANITY 1616-1715&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IEYASU died June 1, 1616. This brought no relief to the Christians, for Hidetada was more violent against them than his father had ever been. Will Adams wrote:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Now this yeear, 1616, the old Emperour died. His son raigneth in his place, and hee is more hot agaynste the romish relligion then his ffather wass: for he hath forbidden thorough all his domynions, on paine of death, none of his subjects to be romish christiane; which romish seckt to prevent everi wayes that he maye, he hath forbidden that no stranger merchant shall abid in any of the great citties.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 JAPANESE TRADITIONS OF THE EARLY MISSIONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/08_JAPANESE_TRADITIONS_OF_THE_EARLY_MISS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/08_JAPANESE_TRADITIONS_OF_THE_EARLY_MISS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IF history is that version of a story which has been able to gain general acceptance, we shall expect to find that what the Japanese have until recently understood to be the history of Christianity in their country is far different from that which is narrated in European books. During most of the Tokugawa period, all publications containing references to the hated religion were prohibited. There lingered among the people various traditions that were sometimes recorded in manuscripts intended for private circulation. The following narrative is compiled from several manuscripts of the eighteenth century, and shows what stories were current among the people.* Owing to the difficulty of identifying names, and the confused state of the narratives, it is not easy to connect these accounts with those derived from the letters of the missionaries. It may be conjectured that &amp;ldquo;Urugan and Furaten&amp;rdquo; were Fathers Organtin and Froez, who, though not the first to preach in Kyoto, were among the best known of the missionaries, and for this reason the traditions may have gathered about their names. Europeans were known as Southern Barbarians because they approached Japan from the south.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 LOOCHOO 1844-1853</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/09_LOOCHOO_1844-1853/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/09_LOOCHOO_1844-1853/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THOUGH missionaries were unable to enter Japan, the Roman Catholic Church could not forget the land where its efforts had once been crowned with so great success, and where so many martyrs had consecrated the soil by their blood. Many were the prayers that the country which had been the scene of such triumphs and such sufferings might again be opened to the heralds of the Cross. There were indications that some knowledge of Christianity yet remained among the people. In 1820, some Japanese came to Batavia for the purpose of purchasing Christian books*&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 THE RESURRECTED CHURCH 1855-1867</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/10_THE_RESURRECTED_CHURCH_1855-1867/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/10_THE_RESURRECTED_CHURCH_1855-1867/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THOUGH the United States in 1854 negotiated a treaty with Japan, this and the similar arrangements made by other Western nations did not provide for the residence of foreigners in the country. It was, however, evident that the first breach had been made in the barriers that shut the Japanese away from other peoples and that the time could not be far distant when it would be possible for even religious teachers to enter within the walls. In accordance with the plans made by M. Colin, Messieurs Girard, Furet, and Mermet were sent in February, 1855, to Loochoo, which was again chosen as the point from which to watch the progress of events in Japan. No more cordial welcome was given to them than had been received by their predecessors. On the arrival of the French merchantman that conveyed them to Napha, the captain of the ship said to the officials:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 PERSECUTION 1867-1873</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/11_PERSECUTION_1867-1873/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/11_PERSECUTION_1867-1873/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IT had been the custom of the Christians to avoid trouble by joining with others in making contributions to the temples, and by allowing deceased friends to be buried with Buddhist rites. Those in Urakami now resolved that, whatever might be the consequences, they would make no more gifts to temples. In April, 1867, the relatives of a Christian who had died asked the missionaries what they ought to do about the funeral. The latter said that the Church, as the enemy of all superstition, disapproved of heathen ceremonies, and they advised that, without having recourse to the Buddhists, they give notice of the death to the officers of the village. Instead of following this advice, the relatives, as had been done in some other cases, buried the body without saying anything to either officers or priests. These last brought the matter to the attention of the Mayor, who summoned the brother of the deceased person, reproved him for what he had done, and threatened to make him exhume the body in order to have it properly buried by the bonzes. The Christians made no reply, and the menace was not carried into effect. A few days later another death occurred. In this case notice was sent to the Mayor, who gave an order for burial by a Buddhist priest. The relatives declared that they would not accept the priest&amp;rsquo;s services, and the Christians of the different villages sent deputies to the Mayor saying that, while they were loyal subjects of the Government, they wished to have no dealings with the bonzes. A few days later, the son and another relative of the deceased person were summoned to appear before a magistrate in Nagasaki. By advice of their Mayor they asked the deputies of the villages to go with them. At two o&amp;rsquo;clock on the morning of the appointed day, they sought strength through the sacrament of the Eucharist, and afterwards went to the magistrate. He said to the son:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 DEVELOPMENT OF THE CHURCH 1873-900</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/12_DEVELOPMENT_OF_THE_CHURCH_1873-900/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/12_DEVELOPMENT_OF_THE_CHURCH_1873-900/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE telegram in which Mgr. Petitjean informed his society of the release of the Roman Catholic exiles called for the sending out of fifteen new missionaries. Evidently the officials of the society felt as he did. that the needs of Japan were very pressing. The thousands of believers now in connection with the missionaries ought to be instructed, other descendants of the ancient believers were to be gathered in, it was necessary to plan for the training of native workers, and there was reason to hope that the changes now going on in Japan would open the way for winning many new converts. By September, eleven of the fifteen missionaries that had been asked for were on the field. M. Laucaigne was raised to the episcopate and made an auxiliary of Mgr. Petitjean. A seminary for the training of evangelists was opened in Nagasaki. One was already in operation at Yokohama. In the latter city twenty young men received instruction in lithography, so that they might multiply copies of the catechism and other books.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 MISSIONS 1901-1909</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/13_MISSIONS_1901-1909/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/13_MISSIONS_1901-1909/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE MISSIONS IN THE TWENTIETH CENTURY   1901-1909&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HOWEVER it may be to those more directly concerned with the progress of the Roman Catholic Church in Japan, its later history presents, to one outside of its communion, but few striking events. Such a person can not be greatly interested in the coming and going of individual missionaries, or even in the appointment of new bishops to take the place of those who have passed away. Year by year, whether those in attendance be many or few, the Church&amp;rsquo;s services of worship are conducted in the same way; it carries on its educational and charitable institutions with some increase in their number, yet with little change in their methods; and it adds slowly though steadily to the number of its adherents; but, except that its edifices are often prominent features in the appearance of the cities where they are located, the missions are carried 011 in ways that but slightly attract the attention of the outside world. There have been, however, some events connected with the development of the Roman Catholic Church in the twentieth century that demand a place in this history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 THE BEGINNING OF THE MISSION 1861-1872</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/14_THE_BEGINNING_OF_THE_MISSION_1861-187/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/14_THE_BEGINNING_OF_THE_MISSION_1861-187/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JAPAN&amp;rsquo;S nearest neighbour is Russia. For a long time subjects of each nation had settlements in Saghalien, and the resulting disputes over territorial rights continued until 1875, when Japan waived its claims to that island, and at the same time received the islands of the Kurile group that had hitherto belonged to Russia. The Kuriles had been visited in the eighteenth century by Russian priests, and not long ago there were still living on one of the islands about a dozen families of Christian Ainu, the descendants of those that had been taught by these missionaries. It is said that some of the priests penetrated into Yezo.*&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 THE EXPANSION OF THE CHURCH 1873-1882</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/15_THE_EXPANSION_OF_THE_CHURCH_1873-1882/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/15_THE_EXPANSION_OF_THE_CHURCH_1873-1882/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JOHN SAKAI had not &amp;ldquo;been very long in his native province before he obtained permission to make a visit to Tokyo. Instead of returning home from that city, he went in May, 1873, to Hakodate. Though he sent word to the officials of the Colonisation Commission that he intended to reside there, he received nothing from them to show that they objected to this or were taking any notice of his presence. He was soon engaged as busily as ever in evangelistic work. At the beginning of the next year, however, the officials of his own prefecture sent a messenger to escort him back. He was brought to the prefectural office and asked why he had gone to Hakodate. To this he replied that, as his wife and child were living in that city, he had found it necessary to go there in order to provide for their support. He was then accused of using the name Sakai illegally. The name was, indeed, that of his ancestors; but his father had &amp;ldquo;married into another house&amp;rdquo; and so taken his wife&amp;rsquo;s name. After his son&amp;rsquo;s birth, the father had left his adopted house. The boy, after remaining for some years with the mother, had gone to the father, and on the latter&amp;rsquo;s death succeeded to his practice as a physician, at the same time assuming the name of Sakai. As there was some irregularity in this procedure, the officials took advantage of the opportunity it gave for bringing a charge against him. That this was used only as a pretext, was shown by the fact that the one who conducted the examination offered to release him on condition that he would renounce Christianity; but since he refused to do this, he was sent to prison for a month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 RECENT HISTORY OF THE MISSION 1883-1909</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/16_RECENT_HISTORY_OF_THE_MISSION_1883-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/16_RECENT_HISTORY_OF_THE_MISSION_1883-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MATERIALS for writing the later history of the Greek Church in Japan are not such as can be utilised to any great extent in the present work. The news columns of the periodicals that it publishes will be of great value to its own historian, but the facts recorded need to be collated by some one so intimately acquainted with the inner working of the Church that he can select those that have proved to be of the most importance. It is to be hoped that the excellent history (in Japanese) whose earlier volumes have helped in the preparation of former chapters will ere long be brought down to a later date.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 INDEX</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/17_INDEX/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/01/17_INDEX/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Acosta, Father Balthazar d&amp;rsquo;, 72&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adams, Will, 140-142, 161, 175, 190&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adnet, Father, 267, 269&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ainu, 279&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Akashi, 99, 106&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Akashi Morishige, 186&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Akechi Mitsuhide, 86, 99&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Akita, 416&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alcaceva, Brother Peter d&amp;rsquo;, 54, 55&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Almeida, Brother Louis, 36, 39, 58, 59, 66-69, 72, 79, 91&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amador, 24, 37&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amakusa, 80, 92, 102, 109, 110, 113, 130, 143, 154, 219-223&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anatolius, Père, 393, 398, 411, 412&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Andronik, Bishop, 422&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Angles, Father, 365&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
