<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Essays on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Essays on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Artisans</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/artisans_pride/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/artisans_pride/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thread by @satoverma on Thread Reader App – Thread Reader App&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some reflections on the caste identity amongst artisan castes and its transformation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;drop-in-pride&#34;&gt;Drop in pride&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In pre-colonial India, artisan castes especially in North India formed anywhere between 15-30% of urban center population. As a group, they were differentiated by their skills in three classes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first ones were the most specialized ones whose products were meant for the royalty and wealthy merchants.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Second ones were the artisans who produced supplies for local gentry and aristocracy.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The last group produced items for the mass consumption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bairy being brahmin</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/bairy_being_brahmin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/bairy_being_brahmin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being Brahmin, Being Modern &lt;em&gt;Exploring the Lives of Caste Today&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;**Ramesh Bairy T. S. **&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2010 Ramesh Bairy T. S.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For my parents, Smt. Lakshmi S. Bairi and Sri. T. Subbaraya Bairi. And, University of Hyderabad.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;0&#34;&gt;0&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chapter 1 Introduction: Seeking a Foothold&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chapter 2 Question of Method: Caste in/and/as Identity&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chapter 3 The Modern World of Brahmins: A Schematic History&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chapter 4 Intersecting Voices, Shifting Identifications: Complicating the Contours of the Non-Brahminical Othering of the Brahmin&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chapter 5 The Bounds of Agency: Engaging the Space of Brahmin Associations&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chapter 6 Identities and Displacements: On the Selfhood of the Contemporary Brahmin&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chapter 7 Agency and Identity in the World of Brahmins&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bibliography&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;About the Author&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Index&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;acknowledgements&#34;&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This work has stayed with me all along the last 13 years. Now thinking back and acknowledging individuals and institutions that sustained me, the emotion that is running through is, mostly, one of relief and immense gratitude.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curbing competition</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/curbing-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/curbing-competition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/infinitchy/status/1707089548818395526&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The nested logic of Jaati-Varna&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is the self? The success of modernity has been in making a mockery of this mystery of mysteries. It has made ordinary people trade their innocent bewilderment with dismissive overconfidence. &amp;ldquo;Why? The self is that nice guy on the corporate id-card.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Who we are was not as plain to the ancients as it is to the moderns. For the ancients, selfhood was a spectrum, the two poles of which were the individual and the collective. And even today, it is this very spectrum that makes us socially functional. Our position on it is not set in stone, it is a matter of context.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hereditary posts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/hereditary-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/hereditary-posts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/984054110239514625&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/984054110239514625&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The intrinsic risk in attempting to divorce religious offices from hereditary contexts (by hereditary, it can be ANY group; so don&amp;rsquo;t come here &amp;amp; bark) &amp;amp; linking it purely with a system of &amp;ldquo;training&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;merit&amp;rdquo; is that it tends to result in the over-rationalization of traditions and non-abrahamic polytheisms in particular have this rich body of narratives &amp;amp; mythos linking the divine world with the human one as a defining characteristic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jAti-kanging</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/jAti-kanging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/jAti-kanging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Aryamsha&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My opinion on caste is pretty simple. Does it matter? yes. Is it the end all of things? no. It’s perfectly fine to be proud of your tribe and like its history, but if your primary identity becomes that in this age and era, you’re likely terminally online (dehatis dont really browse reactionary twitter).  There are genetic and sociocultural differences in Indian castes and tribes, but for the broad part, Hindu savarnas resemble each other a lot in terms of ancestry and have similar cultures, mores once they urbanize.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Late sindh</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/sindh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/sindh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from essay (by shikShA sharma?) in ‘Sindhi Tapestry’ by Saaz Aggarwal&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;experiences&#34;&gt;Experiences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of my earliest memories is having people of my community, much older than me, touch my feet for my blessings. As an instinctive, knee-jerk response, I always jumped back, surprised each time it happened. Why was this happening to me? TV serials were a large part of my growing-up years, thanks to my mother and grandmother. In them, I saw younger people touching the feet of their elders. It seemed terribly inappropriate for a ten-year-old to have her feet touched by women almost the age of her own grandmother! “But you are the daughter of Brahmans,” the aunties explained when they saw the shock on my face, and my grandmother nodded her confirmation. As the years passed, I found it interesting when people claimed that Sindhi society was free of caste – because I have always felt my life marked by caste. Even my surname, ‘Sharma’, my parents told me, was a caste-marker which every Brahman has. Our real family surname, Shingrani, was for only us to know.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Muslim caste drift</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/muslim-caste-drift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/muslim-caste-drift/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Basir Ahmed Dabla&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Directory of Castes in Kashmir&amp;rdquo; shows examples of caste mobility among Kashmiri Muslims claiming to be of a higher caste.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>nikhil on patrilinearity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/nikhil_on_patrilinearity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/nikhil_on_patrilinearity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ā́rya designation is a marker of patriline rather than race; Ā́rya-s can have diverse genetic composition, as we indeed find today in India, so long as they are patrilineally descended from Ā́rya-s.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That being said, even in Vedic times (as of course among most old societies) it was viewed as far more virtuous to marry among your own kind (specifically, várṇa).  Thus we have Brāhmaṇá-s being excluded by their peers for having a Şūdrā́ mother (PB 14.6.6) or a Dāsī́ mother (ĀiB 2.19.1)—but, ultimately, still being considered Brāhmaṇá-s and accepted after proving their favor with the Gods.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Provincial-propertied-class</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/provincial-propertied-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/provincial-propertied-class/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/24557471211021506&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why Does the ‘Provincial Propertied Class’ Remain Provincial? Reading the Agrarian Question of Capital Through Caste&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Indian agriculture has been experiencing adverse terms of trade since the economic reforms of the early 1990s (Dev &amp;amp; Rao, 2015). Compounded by vulnerabilities in the domain of production such as water access and depletion of soil quality, farmers have been cultivating in distress. Since the early 2010s, the country has also witnessed a series of agitations from castes with major stakes in agriculture such as the Jats in Haryana and Punjab, Marathas in Maharashtra and the Patels in Gujarat (Jaffrelot &amp;amp; Kalaiyarasan, 2019, 2020). They demand, among other things, backward caste status to be able to benefit from affirmative action policies that can facilitate access to employment and education opportunities, and thus their entry into the urban formal economy. While scholars point to the relative affluence of segments within these castes to argue against such claims (Deshpande, 2016), they do acknowledge the inability of members of such castes to access the urban labour market on favourable terms, particularly in a globalising environment. While this relates to the question of labour transition from the rural to the urban, there is little discussion on how caste intersects with diversification of capital from the rural to the Indian urban. This is particularly interesting given the extensive debate on the mode of transition in the 1980s when commercialisation of agriculture led to accumulation of considerable surpluses within agriculture (Omvedt, 1992; Thorner, 1982). While the debate on terms of trade dwelt upon the political economy of surplus transfers between agriculture and non-agricultural sectors, the extent to which capitalist farmers could diversify into capital accumulation in the urban is less studied. Scholars like Rutten (1999) and Upadhya (1988) point to the possibility of such diversification in certain regions. However, the fact that it has happened only in specific regions has not been accounted for adequately.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vimAna-venkateshvara  legend</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/vimAna-venkaTeshvara-legend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/articles/vimAna-venkaTeshvara-legend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Legend of Vimana Venkateshwara Swamy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After having the divine darshan of Lord Venkateshwara Swamy, devotees go around the Vimana Prakaram and have the darshanam of Vimana Venkateshwara Swamy, who is on the North-eastern corner on the middle tier of the 3 tiered Vimana gopuram.  There is a board pointing towards  this and also there is a Silver Prabhavali or Silver Makarathorana around the Vimana Venkateshwara Swamy on the Vimanam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
