<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;aurobindo India rebirth on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;aurobindo India rebirth on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00 IR editnote</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/00_IR_editnote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/00_IR_editnote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editors&amp;rsquo; Note&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book presents Sri Aurobindo&amp;rsquo;s vision of India as it grew from his&#xA;return from England in 1893 to his political days in the first decade&#xA;of the century and finally to his forty-year-long withdrawal from&#xA;public view during which he plunged into his “real work” of&#xA;evolutionary action.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This brief chronological selection from all that Sri Aurobindo said or&#xA;wrote on India, her soul and her destiny, is by no means integral, but&#xA;we trust it offers a sufficiently wide view of the lines of&#xA;development Sri Aurobindo wished India to follow if she was to&#xA;overcome the deep-rooted obstacles standing in the way of her rebirth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 IR part1</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/01_IR_part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/01_IR_part1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1893-1910&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(After thirteen years in England where he received a thoroughly Western&#xA;education, Sri Aurobindo returned to India on February 6, 1893, at the&#xA;age of twenty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bankim Chatterji&amp;rsquo;s Anandamath, which contained “Bande Mataram,” the hymn&#xA;to the Motherland, had been published eleven years earlier. Swami&#xA;Vivekananda had just come to the end of his first pilgrimage round&#xA;India, and was preparing to sail for America. But it was going to take&#xA;another dozen years for their call to their countrymen to find&#xA;expression in the political field. For the present, the eight-year-old&#xA;Indian National Congress, whose members were mostly drawn from the&#xA;Anglicized upper classes of society, had full faith in British&#xA;fair-mindedness and the “providential character” of British rule in&#xA;India, and year after year swore its “unswerving allegiance to the&#xA;British crown”; it was content with submitting petitions which were&#xA;simply ignored by the Colonial rulers. There was another twelve years to&#xA;go before the start of the open struggle for freedom in 1905, and&#xA;twenty-five years before Mahatma Gandhi&amp;rsquo;s entry on the political scene&#xA;in 1918.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 IR part2</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/02_IR_part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/02_IR_part2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1910-1922&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(On April 4, 1910, Sri Aurobindo, still wanted by the British, reached&#xA;Pondicherry clandestinely. A third charge of sedition against him, for&#xA;an article in the Karmayogin, failed in his absence. For several years&#xA;he was going to live in this French colony as a fugitive, with spies and&#xA;rumours hovering about him and his small group of companions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For some time Sri Aurobindo thought of returning to British India, but&#xA;he soon saw that “enough had been done to change the whole face of&#xA;Indian politics and the whole spirit of the Indian people to make&#xA;independence its aim,” as he wrote later. “His own personal intervention&#xA;in politics would therefore no longer be indispensable. Apart from all&#xA;this, the magnitude of the spiritual work set before him became more and&#xA;more clear to him, and he saw that the concentration of all his energies&#xA;on it was necessary.” But Sri Aurobindo&amp;rsquo;s retirement from political&#xA;activity “did not mean, as most people supposed, that he had retired&#xA;into some height of spiritual experience devoid of any further interest&#xA;in the world or in the fate of India.”¹⁸&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 IR part3</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/03_IR_part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/03_IR_part3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;III&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1923-1926&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(In these years, Sri Aurobindo used to have daily talks with a few&#xA;disciples on a wide variety of subjects, from his yoga to the prevailing&#xA;national or international situation. The following excerpts from these&#xA;talks, noted down from memory by some of the disciples present, provide&#xA;glimpses of Sri Aurobindo&amp;rsquo;s views on India&amp;rsquo;s political, social, cultural&#xA;systems and her spiritual possibilities.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 9, 1923&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    The ancients \[in India\] based their society on the structure&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;of religion—I do not mean narrow religion but the highest law of our&#xA;being. The whole social fabric was built up to fulfil that purpose.&#xA;There was no talk in those days of individual liberty in the present&#xA;sense of the term, but there was absolute communal liberty. Every&#xA;community was completely free to develop its own religion,—the law of&#xA;its being. Even the selection of the line was a matter of free choice&#xA;for the individual&amp;hellip;. In ancient times each community had its own&#xA;Dharma and within itself it was independent; every village, every city&#xA;had its own organization quite free from all political control and&#xA;within that every individual was free—free to change and take up another&#xA;line for his development. But all this was not put into a definite&#xA;political unit. There were, of course, attempts at that kind of&#xA;expression of life but they were only partially successful. The whole&#xA;community in India was a very big one and the community culture based on&#xA;Dharma was not thrown into a kind of [political or national]&#xA;organization which would resist external aggression.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 IR part4</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/04_IR_part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/04_IR_part4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IV&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1929-1938&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(At the end of 1926, Sri Aurobindo withdrew completely, leaving the&#xA;material responsibility of the disciples and the growing Ashram to&#xA;Mother. Apart from three and later four yearly “darshans,” Sri Aurobindo&#xA;kept in external touch with the disciples through letters—thousands of&#xA;letters in which he tirelessly dealt with their questions or&#xA;difficulties or revolts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This section consists mostly of excerpts from some of Sri Aurobindo&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;letters.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Undated&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 IR part5</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/05_IR_part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/05_IR_part5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;V&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1938-1940&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(In the night of November 23-24, 1938, Sri Aurobindo fell down while&#xA;walking in concentration and broke his right leg. In the years that&#xA;followed, a small group of disciples, mostly attendants and physicians,&#xA;met him every day. Two of them recorded the informal talks that ensued,&#xA;which often touched on the Indian political scene, the rising threat of&#xA;Nazism, and then World War II which Sri Aurobindo followed closely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 IR part6</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/06_IR_part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/06_IR_part6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VI&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1940-1950&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This section consists of excerpts from writings, letters, and&#xA;messages.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Early 1940&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    At present mankind is undergoing an evolutionary crisis in which&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;is concealed a choice of its destiny&amp;hellip;. Man has created a system of&#xA;civilisation which has become too big for his limited mental capacity&#xA;and understanding and his still more limited spiritual and moral&#xA;capacity to utilise and manage, a too dangerous servant of his&#xA;blundering ego and its appetites&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 IR chrono</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/07_IR_chrono/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/07_IR_chrono/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;Section1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chronology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1872, Aug. 15      - Sri Aurobindo is born in Calcutta; he spends his&#xA;first years at Rangpur (now in Bangladesh), and at the age of 5 is sent&#xA;to Loreto Convent School, Darjeeling.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1878, Feb. 21      - Mother is born in Paris.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1879, June          - Sri Aurobindo leaves India for England with his&#xA;parents and his two elder brothers. He spends 5 years in Manchester,&#xA;enters St. Paul&amp;rsquo;s School, London, in 1884, and King&amp;rsquo;s College,&#xA;Cambridge, in 1890.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 IR ref</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/08_IR_ref/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/misc/aurobindo_India_rebirth/08_IR_ref/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We give below, section by section, either detailed references or, when&#xA;these would be too cumbersome to list in full, guides to the sources.&#xA;The bold numerals refer to the volumes of the Centenary Edition of Sri&#xA;Aurobindo&amp;rsquo;s works (Sri Aurobindo Ashram, Pondicherry, 1972); they are&#xA;followed by the page number. “A. &amp;amp; R.” refers to the half-yearly&#xA;series &lt;em&gt;Archives and Research&lt;/em&gt; (Sri Aurobindo Ashram, Pondicherry,&#xA;1977-94).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reader wishing to know more about Sri Aurobindo&amp;rsquo;s immense&#xA;contribution to India is invited to study the following titles: &lt;em&gt;Bande&#xA;Mataram, The Karmayogin, The Secret of the Veda, Essays on the Gita,&#xA;The Foundations of Indian Culture, On Himself&lt;/em&gt;, as well as Sri&#xA;Aurobindo&amp;rsquo;s talks with disciples: &lt;em&gt;Evening Talks&lt;/em&gt; (noted by A. B.&#xA;Purani) and &lt;em&gt;Talks with Sri Aurobindo&lt;/em&gt; (four volumes noted by&#xA;Nirodbaran).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
