<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Infection on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Infection on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apparel</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/Apparel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/Apparel/</guid>
      <description>Eye glasses - Wear any, but prefer full eye covering.  Masks  Even cloth masks help. Refer - masks4all1, masks4all2 WHO is retarded: &amp;ldquo;The WHO also recommends public mask usage during high-severity influenza pandemics – just not during this Coronavirus pandemic.&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;WHO describes a MINIMAL standard. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that we couldn&amp;rsquo;t do MORE.&amp;rdquo; Errors in reasoning about masks by NN Taleb here. Suprising demo of effectiveness of masks: &amp;quot; the salon story where two infected stylists failed to infect all their 140 clients (making the probability of infection for bilateral mask wearing safely below 1% for a salon-style exposure) — we know the probability of infection for non mask wearers from tens of thousands of data points and the various R0 estimations) plus&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grocery disinfection</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/Grocery_disinfection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/Grocery_disinfection/</guid>
      <description> &amp;ldquo;KMnO4 1% 1min is a good disinfectant for the viruses like the Wuhan virus. Hardier viruses like polio it is less effect.&amp;rdquo;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hand sanitization</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/Hand_sanitization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/Hand_sanitization/</guid>
      <description>Technique   hand-wash-steps   Material  Soap works because it&amp;rsquo;s OH part mixes with water, while the organic part bonds with fat membranes of viruses. Alcohol based disinfectant - &amp;gt; 60% strength. Vodka might do as well.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human persistence</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/human_persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/human_persistence/</guid>
      <description>Immuno-compromised folks Cancer patients and those who have a compromised immune system keep shedding viruses for long. Example: a cancer patient who had chemotherapy kept shedding virus till 105 days( 3 months) despite twice being titrated with Remdesivir and plasma therapy.
In internal organs The virus can persist in various internal organs.The gastrointestinal system is a good nidus for this virus. The biopsy of the gut from asymptomatic infected patients 3 months later showed persistence of the virus in the gut.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinfection</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/reinfection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/reinfection/</guid>
      <description>Uncommon cases  There have been re-infections of the Corona virus have been described around the world. Not all reinfections seen so far are milder.  General antibody persistence  &amp;ldquo;Reinfections with the four coronaviruses that cause the common cold occur after an average of 12 months, a team led by virologist Lia van der Hoek at Amsterdam University Medical Center recently showed. Van der Hoek thinks COVID-19 may follow that pattern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk models</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/risk_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/risk_models/</guid>
      <description>Adjustible simulations/ models: natgeo 202008 Successful Infection = Virus Dose x Time &amp;ldquo;Indoor spaces, with limited air exchange or recycled air and lots of people, are concerning from a transmission standpoint. We know that 60 people in a volleyball court-sized room (choir) results in massive infections. Same situation with the restaurant and the call center. Social distancing guidelines don&amp;rsquo;t hold in indoor spaces where you spend a lot of time, as people on the opposite side of the room were infected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seasonality</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/seasonality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/seasonality/</guid>
      <description> Cold / indoor weather increases death rate even without Wuhan epidemic. Cold and low humidity air is good for the virus. Most experts believe: it will run a seasonal course for next 5 years despite vaccination.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transmission mechanics</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/Transmission_mechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/Transmission_mechanics/</guid>
      <description>Overview  &amp;ldquo;We know that at least 44% of all infections&amp;ndash;and the majority of community-acquired transmissions&amp;ndash;occur from people without any symptoms (asymptomatic or pre-symptomatic people). You can be shedding the virus into the environment for up to 5 days before symptoms begin.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Some experts estimate that as few as 1000 SARS-CoV2 infectious viral particles are all that will be needed.&amp;rdquo; - EB    corona-growth-visualization   Virus expulsion mechanics  &amp;ldquo;A single breath releases 50 - 5000 droplets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaccination</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/vaccination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/health/disease/contagion/wuhan_epidemic/Infection/vaccination/</guid>
      <description>Effectiveness expectations  There are different strains - so vaccination may not be totally effective (just as in case of reinfection). Flare-up possibility: The antibodies the vaccine elicits will have virus neutralizing capabilities and that is what needed. But there are other non neutralizing antibodies that gets produced that can flare up the disease. Called ADE (antibody dependent enhancement) has been observed in Dengue and other viral infections.  Effectiveness duration  T cell response following even mild and asymptomatic infection can last upto 6 months.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>