<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Greek merc innovations</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/greek-merc-innovations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/greek-merc-innovations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1539332395228442624.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hello friends I have written a thread on how the military innovations of Greek mercenary adventurers changed the Greek world, bringing about the transition from Classical to Hellenistic eras and the death of ancient democracy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Late classical warfare was characterised by phalanx push, citizen soldiers and small-scale warfare. Crucially, war was fought by conscript citizen-soldiers rather than professionals. Mercenary activity was limited, though there was demand for hoplite infantry outside of Greece. The Peloponnesian War changed everything. The devastation it wrought was total. Rudimentary siege technology meant Greeks largely didnt participate in sieges but rather pillaged the countryside - agriculture and land value plummeted. Many farmers joined mercenary bands, leading to the rise of prominent mercenary captains and an increasing presence of mercenaries on the battlefield.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leper-lazarus-order</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/leper-lazarus-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/leper-lazarus-order/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thread by @LandsknechtPike on Thread Reader App – Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/LandsknechtPike/status/1679331550385651715&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The forgotten leper warriors of the crusades.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Knights who suffered from leprosy joined the Order of Saint Lazarus, which was established to take care of lepers, and continue to fight in battles. These leper warriors were known as the Living Dead and were very intimidating!🧵 Yes, the leper knights were a real thing!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To understand what led to this we need to understand the attitude towards leprosy among medieval Christians. It was a terrible disease, but it was also seen as a &amp;ldquo;holy disease&amp;rdquo; and special religious meanings were attributed to it! Leprosy is a disease in which bacterial infection causes skin lesions, nerve damage and gradual disfigurement, progressively triggering a deterioration of control over one&amp;rsquo;s limbs, causing gradual decay of the body. It was an ancient disease and endemic in medieval Europe. Because of fear of getting infected, lepers were often treated as outcasts in their societies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
