<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;notes of class talks and lectures on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;notes of class talks and lectures on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>832 NOTES OF CLASS TALKS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/832_notes_of_class_talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/832_notes_of_class_talks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes-of-class-talks&#34;&gt;NOTES OF CLASS TALKS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WHEN WILL CHRIST COME AGAIN?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I never take much notice of these things. I have come to deal with&#xA;principles. I have only to preach that God comes again and again, and&#xA;that He came in India as Krishna, Rāma, and Buddha, and that He will&#xA;come again. It can almost be demonstrated that after each 500 years the&#xA;world sinks, and a tremendous spiritual wave comes, and on the top of&#xA;the wave is a Christ.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>833 MAN THE MAKER OF HIS DESTINY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/833_man_the_maker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/833_man_the_maker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;man-the-maker-of-his-destiny&#34;&gt;MAN THE MAKER OF HIS DESTINY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There was a very powerful dynasty in Southern India. They made it a rule&#xA;to take the horoscope of all the prominent men living from time to time,&#xA;calculated from the time of their birth. In this way they got a record&#xA;of leading facts predicted, and compared them afterwards with events as&#xA;they happened. This was done for a thousand years, until they found&#xA;certain agreements; these were generalised and recorded and made into a&#xA;huge book. The dynasty died out, but the family of astrologers lived and&#xA;had the book in their possession. It seems possible that this is how&#xA;astrology came into existence. Excessive attention to the minutiae of&#xA;astrology is one of the superstitions which has hurt the Hindus very&#xA;much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>834 GOD: PERSONAL AND IMPERSONAL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/834_god_personal_and_impersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/834_god_personal_and_impersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;god-personal-and-impersonal&#34;&gt;GOD: PERSONAL AND IMPERSONAL&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My idea is that what you call a Personal God is the same as the&#xA;Impersonal Being, a Personal and Impersonal God at the same time. We are&#xA;personalised impersonal beings. If you use the word in the absolute&#xA;sense, we are impersonal; but if you use it in a relative meaning, we&#xA;are personal. Each one of you is a universal being, each one is&#xA;omnipresent. It may seem staggering at first, but I am as sure of this&#xA;as that I stand before you. How can the spirit help being omnipresent?&#xA;It has neither length, nor breadth, nor thickness, nor any material&#xA;attribute whatsoever; and if we are all spirits we cannot be limited by&#xA;space. Space only limits space, matter matter. If we were limited to&#xA;this body we would be a material something. Body and soul and everything&#xA;would be material, and such words as &amp;ldquo;living in the body&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;embodying&#xA;the soul&amp;rdquo; would be only words used for convenience; beyond that they&#xA;would have no meaning. Many of you remember the definition I gave of the&#xA;soul; that each soul is a circle whose centre is in one point and&#xA;circumference nowhere. The centre is where the body is, and the activity&#xA;is manifested there. You are omnipresent; only you have the&#xA;consciousness of being concentrated in one point. That point has taken&#xA;up particles of matter, and formed them into a machine to express&#xA;itself. That through which it expresses itself is called the body. So&#xA;you are everywhere; when one body or machine fails, you, the centre,&#xA;move on and take up other particles of matter, finer or grosser, and&#xA;work through that. This is man. And what is God? God is a circle with&#xA;its circumference nowhere and centre everywhere. Every point in that&#xA;circle is living, conscious, active, and equally working; with us&#xA;limited souls, only one point is conscious, and that point moves forward&#xA;and backward. As the body has a very infinitesimal existence in&#xA;comparison with that of the universe, so the whole universe, in&#xA;comparison with God, is nothing. When we talk of God speaking, we say He&#xA;speaks through His universe; and when we speak of Him beyond all&#xA;limitations of time and space, we say He is an Impersonal Being. Yet He&#xA;is the same Being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>835 THE DIVINE INCARNATION OR AVATARA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/835_the_divine_incarnation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/835_the_divine_incarnation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-divine-incarnation-or-avatara&#34;&gt;THE DIVINE INCARNATION OR AVATARA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jesus Christ was God — the Personal God become man. He has manifested&#xA;Himself many times in different forms and these alone are what you can&#xA;worship. God in His absolute nature is not to be worshipped. Worshipping&#xA;such God would be nonsense. We have to worship Jesus Christ, the human&#xA;manifestation, as God. You cannot worship anything higher than the&#xA;manifestation of God. The sooner you give up the worship of God separate&#xA;from Christ, the better for you. Think of the Jehovah you manufacture&#xA;and of the beautiful Christ. Any time you attempt to make a God beyond&#xA;Christ, you murder the whole thing. God alone can worship God. It is not&#xA;given to man, and any attempt to worship Him beyond His ordinary&#xA;manifestations will be dangerous to mankind. Keep close to Christ if you&#xA;want salvation; He is higher than any God you can imagine. If you think&#xA;that Christ was a man, do not worship Him; but as soon as you can&#xA;realise that He is God, worship Him. Those who say He was a man and then&#xA;worship Him commit blasphemy; there is no half-way house for you; you&#xA;must take the whole strength of it. &amp;ldquo;He that hath seen the Son hath seen&#xA;the Father&amp;rdquo;, and without seeing the Son, you &lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; see the Father. It&#xA;would be only tall talk and frothy philosophy and dreams and&#xA;speculations. But if you want to have a hold on spiritual life, cling&#xA;close to God as manifest in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>836 PRANAYAMA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/836_pranayama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/836_pranayama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;pranayama&#34;&gt;PRANAYAMA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First of all we will try to understand a little of the meaning of&#xA;Prānāyama. Prāna stands in metaphysics for the sum total of the energy&#xA;that is in the universe. This universe, according to the theory of the&#xA;philosophers, proceeds in the form of waves; it rises, and again it&#xA;subsides, melts away, as it were; then again it proceeds out in all this&#xA;variety; then again it slowly returns. So it goes on like a pulsation.&#xA;The whole of this universe is composed of matter and force; and&#xA;according to Sanskrit philosophers, everything that we call matter,&#xA;solid and liquid, is the outcome of one primal matter which they call&#xA;Âkāsha or ether; and the primordial force, of which all the forces that&#xA;we see in nature are manifestations, they call Prana. It is this Prana&#xA;acting upon Akasha, which creates this universe, and after the end of a&#xA;period, called a cycle, there is a period of rest. One period of&#xA;activity is followed by a period of rest; this is the nature of&#xA;everything. When this period of rest comes, all these forms that we see&#xA;in the earth, the sun, the moon, and the stars, all these manifestations&#xA;melt down until they become ether again. They become dissipated as&#xA;ether. All these forces, either in the body or in the mind, as&#xA;gravitation, attraction, motion, thought, become dissipated, and go off&#xA;into the primal Prana. We can understand from this the importance of&#xA;this Pranayama. Just as this ether encompasses us everywhere and we are&#xA;interpenetrated by it, so everything we see is composed of this ether,&#xA;and we are floating in the ether like pieces of ice floating in a lake.&#xA;They are formed of the water of the lake and float in it at the same&#xA;time. So everything that exists is composed of this Akasha and is&#xA;floating in this ocean. In the same way we are surrounded by this vast&#xA;ocean of Prana — force and energy. It is this Prana by which we breathe&#xA;and by which the circulation of the blood goes on; it is the energy in&#xA;the nerves and in the muscles, and the thought in the brain. All forces&#xA;are different manifestations of this same Prana, as all matter is a&#xA;different manifestation of the same Akasha. We always find the causes of&#xA;the gross in the subtle. The chemist takes a solid lump of ore and&#xA;analyses it; he wants to find the subtler things out of which that gross&#xA;is composed. So with our thought and our knowledge; the explanation of&#xA;the grosser is in the finer. The effect is the gross and the cause the&#xA;subtle. This gross universe of ours, which we see, feel, and touch, has&#xA;its cause and explanation behind in the thought. The cause and&#xA;explanation of that is also further behind. So in this human body of&#xA;ours, we first find the gross movements, the movements of the hands and&#xA;lips; but where are the causes of these? The finer nerves, the movements&#xA;of which we cannot perceive at all, so fine that we cannot see or touch&#xA;or trace them in any way with our senses, and yet we know they are the&#xA;cause of these grosser movements. These nerve movements, again, are&#xA;caused by still finer movements, which we call thought; and that is&#xA;caused by something finer still behind, which is the soul of man, the&#xA;Self, the Âtman. In order to understand ourselves we have first to make&#xA;our perception fine. No microscope or instrument that was ever invented&#xA;will make it possible for us to see the fine movements that are going on&#xA;inside; we can never see them by any such means. So the Yogi has a&#xA;science that manufactures an instrument for the study of his own mind,&#xA;and that instrument is in the mind. The mind attains to powers of finer&#xA;perception which no instrument will ever be able to attain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>837 WOMEN OF THE EAST</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/837_women_of_the_east/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/837_women_of_the_east/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;women-of-the-east&#34;&gt;WOMEN OF THE EAST&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(As many women as could crowd into Hall 7 yesterday afternoon flocked&#xA;thither to hear something as to the lives of their sisters of the&#xA;Orient. Mrs. Potter Palmer and Mrs. Charles Henrotin sat upon the&#xA;platform, surrounded by turbanned representatives of the women of the&#xA;East.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It may interest the readers to know that the published addresses of&#xA;Swami Vivekananda at the Parliament of Religions in Chicago are not&#xA;exhaustive and many addresses, specially those delivered at the&#xA;Scientific Section of the Parliament were not all reported. The&#xA;Scientific Sessions were conducted simultaneously with the open session&#xA;at the Hall of Columbus. Swami Vivekananda spoke on the following&#xA;subjects at the Scientific Section:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>838 CONGRESS OF RELIGIOUS UNITY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/838_congress_of_religious_unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/838_congress_of_religious_unity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;congress-of-religious-unity&#34;&gt;CONGRESS OF RELIGIOUS UNITY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Report of a lecture in the&lt;/em&gt; Chicago Sunday Herald, &lt;em&gt;September 24,&#xA;1893&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Swami Vivekananda said, &amp;ldquo;All the words spoken at this parliament come to&#xA;the common conclusion that the brotherhood of man is the&#xA;much-to-be-desired end. Much has been said for this brotherhood as being&#xA;a natural condition, since we are all children of one God. Now, there&#xA;are sects that do not admit of the existence of God — that is, a&#xA;Personal God. Unless we wish to leave those sects out in the cold — and&#xA;in that case our brotherhood will not be universal — we must have our&#xA;platform broad enough to embrace all mankind. It has been said here that&#xA;we should do good to our fellow men, because every bad or mean deed&#xA;reacts on the doer. This appears to me to savour of the shopkeeper —&#xA;ourselves first, our brothers afterwards. I think we should love our&#xA;brother whether we believe in the universal fatherhood of God or not,&#xA;because every religion and every creed recognises man as divine, and you&#xA;should do him no harm that you might not injure that which is divine in&#xA;him.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>839 THE LOVE OF GOD - I</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/839_the_love_of_god_i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/839_the_love_of_god_i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-love-of-god---i&#34;&gt;THE LOVE OF GOD - I&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Report of a lecture in the&lt;/em&gt; Chicago Herald, &lt;em&gt;September 25, 1893&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An audience that filled the auditorium of the Third Unitarian Church at&#xA;Laflin and Monroe streets heard Swami Vivekananda preach yesterday&#xA;morning. The subject of his sermon was the love of God, and his&#xA;treatment of the theme was eloquent and unique. He said that God was&#xA;worshipped in all parts of the world, but by different names and in&#xA;different ways. It is natural for men, he said, to worship the grand and&#xA;the beautiful, and that religion was a portion of their nature. The need&#xA;of God was felt by all, and His love prompted them to deeds of charity,&#xA;mercy, and justice. All men loved God because He was love itself. The&#xA;speaker had heard since coming to Chicago a great deal about the&#xA;brotherhood of man. He believed that a still stronger tie connected&#xA;them, in that all are the offsprings of the love of God. The brotherhood&#xA;of man was the logical sequence of God as the Father of all. The speaker&#xA;said he had travelled in the forests of India and slept in caves, and&#xA;from his observation of nature he had drawn the belief that there was&#xA;something above the natural law that kept men from wrong, and that, he&#xA;concluded, was the love of God. If God had spoken to Christ, Mohammed,&#xA;and the Rishis of the Vedas, why did He not speak also to him, one of&#xA;his children?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>840 THE LOVE OF GOD - II</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/840_the_love_of_god_ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/840_the_love_of_god_ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-love-of-god---ii&#34;&gt;THE LOVE OF GOD - II&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;A lecture delivered in the Unitarian Church of Detroit on February 20,&#xA;1894&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and reported in the&lt;/em&gt; Detroit Free Press)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vivekananda delivered a lecture on &amp;ldquo;The Love of God&amp;rdquo; at the Unitarian&#xA;Church last night before the largest audience that he has yet had. The&#xA;trend of the lecturer&amp;rsquo;s remarks was to show that we do not accept God&#xA;because we really want Him, but because we have need of Him for selfish&#xA;purposes. Love, said the speaker, is something absolutely unselfish,&#xA;that which has no thought beyond the glorification and adoration of the&#xA;object upon which our affections are bestowed. It is a quality which&#xA;bows down and worships and asks nothing in return. Merely to love is the&#xA;sole request that true love has to ask.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>841 INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/841_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/841_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;india&#34;&gt;INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Report of a lecture delivered at Detroit on Thursday, February 15,&#xA;1894, with&lt;br&gt;&#xA;the editorial comments of the&lt;/em&gt; Detroit Free Press)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An audience that filled the Unitarian Church heard the renowned monk,&#xA;Swami Vivekananda, deliver a lecture last night on the manners and&#xA;customs of his country. His eloquent and graceful manner pleased his&#xA;listeners, who followed him from beginning to end with the closest&#xA;attention, showing approval from time to time by outbursts of applause.&#xA;While his lecture was more popular in character than the celebrated&#xA;Address before the religious congress in Chicago, it was highly&#xA;entertaining, especially where the speaker diverted from the instructive&#xA;portions and was led to an eloquent narration of certain spiritual&#xA;conditions of his own people. It is upon matters religious and&#xA;philosophic (and necessarily spiritual) that the Eastern brother is most&#xA;impressive, and, while outlining the duties that follow the&#xA;conscientious consideration of the great moral law of nature, his softly&#xA;modulated tones, a peculiarity of his people, and his thrilling manner&#xA;are almost prophetic. He speaks with marked deliberation, except when&#xA;placing before his listeners some moral truth, and then his eloquence is&#xA;of the highest kind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>842 HINDUS AND CHRISTIANS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/842_hindus_and_christians/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/842_hindus_and_christians/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hindus-and-christians&#34;&gt;HINDUS AND CHRISTIANS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;A lecture delivered at Detroit on February 21, 1894, and reported&lt;br&gt;&#xA;in the&lt;/em&gt; Detroit Free Press)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of the different philosophies, the tendency of the Hindu is not to&#xA;destroy, but to harmonise everything. If any new idea comes into India,&#xA;we do not antagonise it, but simply try to take it in, to harmonise it,&#xA;because this method was taught first by our prophet, God incarnate on&#xA;earth, Shri Krishna. This Incarnation of God preached himself first: &amp;ldquo;I&#xA;am the God Incarnate, I am the inspirer of all books, I am the inspirer&#xA;of all religions.&amp;rdquo; Thus we do not reject any.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>843 CHRISTIANITY IN INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/843_christianity_in_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/843_christianity_in_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;christianity-in-india&#34;&gt;CHRISTIANITY IN INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;A lecture delivered at Detroit on March 11, 1894 and reported&lt;br&gt;&#xA;in the&lt;/em&gt; Detroit Free Press)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Vive Kananda spoke to a crowded audience at the Detroit Opera House&#xA;last night. He was given an extremely cordial reception and delivered&#xA;his most eloquent address here. He spoke for two hours and a half.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hon. T. W. Palmer, in introducing the distinguished visitor, referred to&#xA;the old tale of the shield that was copper on one side and silver on the&#xA;other and the contest which ensued. If we look on both sides of a&#xA;question there would be less dispute. It is possible for all men to&#xA;agree. The matter of foreign missions has been dear to the religious&#xA;heart. Vive Kananda, from the Christian standpoint, said Mr. Palmer, was&#xA;a pagan. It would be pleasant to hear from a gentleman who spoke about&#xA;the copper side of the shield.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>844 THE RELIGION OF LOVE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/844_the_religion_of_love/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/844_the_religion_of_love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-religion-of-love&#34;&gt;THE RELIGION OF LOVE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Notes of a lecture delivered in London on November 16, 1895&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just as it is necessary for a man to go through symbols and ceremonies&#xA;first in order to arrive at the depth of realisation, so we say in&#xA;India, &amp;ldquo;It is good to be born in a church, but bad to die in one&amp;rdquo;. A&#xA;sapling must be hedged about for protection, but when it becomes a tree,&#xA;a hedge would be a hindrance. So there is no need to criticise and&#xA;condemn the old forms. We forget that in religion there must be&#xA;&lt;em&gt;growth&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>845 JNANA AND KARMA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/845_jnana_and_karma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/845_jnana_and_karma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jnana-and-karma&#34;&gt;JNANA AND KARMA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Notes of a lecture delivered in London, on November 23, 1895&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The greatest force is derived from the power of thought. &lt;em&gt;The finer the&#xA;element, the more powerful it is&lt;/em&gt;. The silent power of thought&#xA;influences people even at a distance, because mind is one as well as&#xA;many. The universe is a cobweb; minds are spiders.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The universe equals the phenomena of one Universal Being. He, seen&#xA;through our senses, is the universe. This is Maya. So the world is&#xA;illusion, that is, the imperfect vision of the Real, a semi-revelation,&#xA;even as the sun in the morning is a red ball. Thus all evils and&#xA;wickedness are but weakness, the i&lt;em&gt;mperfect vision of goodness&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>846 THE CLAIMS OF VEDANTA ON THE MODERN WORLD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/846_the_claims_of_vedanta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/846_the_claims_of_vedanta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-claims-of-vedanta-on-the-modern-world&#34;&gt;THE CLAIMS OF VEDANTA ON THE MODERN WORLD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Report of a lecture delivered in Oakland on Sunday, February 25, 1900,&#xA;with&lt;br&gt;&#xA;editorial comments of the&lt;/em&gt; Oakland Enquirer)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The announcement that Swami Vivekananda, a distinguished savant of the&#xA;East, would expound the philosophy of Vedanta in the Parliament of&#xA;Religions at the Unitarian Church last evening, attracted an immense&#xA;throng. The main auditorium and ante-rooms were packed, the annexed&#xA;auditorium of Wendte Hall was thrown open, and this was also filled to&#xA;overflowing, and it is estimated that fully 500 persons, who could not&#xA;obtain seats or standing room where they could hear conveniently, were&#xA;turned away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>847 THE LAWS OF LIFE AND DEATH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/847_the_laws_of_life_and_death/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/847_the_laws_of_life_and_death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-laws-of-life-and-death&#34;&gt;THE LAWS OF LIFE AND DEATH&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Report of a lecture delivered in Oakland on March 7, 1900, with&#xA;editorial comments of the&lt;/em&gt; Oakland Tribune)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Swami Vivekananda delivered a lecture last evening on the subject, &amp;ldquo;The&#xA;Laws of Life and Death&amp;rdquo;. The Swami said: &amp;ldquo;How to get rid of this birth&#xA;and death — not how to go to heaven, but how one can stop going to&#xA;heaven — this is the object of the search of the Hindu.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>848 THE REALITY AND THE SHADOW</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/848_the_reality_and_the_shadow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/848_the_reality_and_the_shadow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-reality-and-the-shadow&#34;&gt;THE REALITY AND THE SHADOW&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Report of a lecture delivered in Oakland on March 8, 1900, with&#xA;editorial comments&lt;br&gt;&#xA;of the&lt;/em&gt; Oakland Tribune)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Swami Vivekananda, the Hindu philosopher, delivered another lecture in&#xA;Wendte Hall last evening. His subject was: &amp;ldquo;The Reality and The Shadow&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;He said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The soul of man is ever striving after certainty, to find something&#xA;that does not change. It is never satisfied. Wealth, the gratification&#xA;of ambition or of appetite are all changeable. Once these are attained,&#xA;man is not content. Religion is the science which teaches us whence to&#xA;satisfy this longing after the unchangeable. Behind all the local&#xA;colours and derivations they teach the same thing — that there is&#xA;reality only in the soul of man.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>849 WAY TO SALVATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/849_way_to_salvation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/849_way_to_salvation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;way-to-salvation&#34;&gt;WAY TO SALVATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Report of a lecture delivered in Oakland on Monday, March 12, 1900,&#xA;with&lt;br&gt;&#xA;editorial comments of the&lt;/em&gt; Oakland Enquirer)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wendte Hall of the First Unitarian Church was crowded last evening with&#xA;a large audience to hear the &amp;ldquo;Way to Salvation&amp;rdquo; from the standpoint of&#xA;the Hindu priest, Swami Vivekananda. This was the last lecture of a&#xA;series of three which the Swami has delivered. He said in part:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>850 THE PEOPLE OF INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/850_the_people_of_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/850_the_people_of_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-people-of-india&#34;&gt;THE PEOPLE OF INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Report of a lecture delivered in Oakland on Monday, March 19, 1900,&#xA;with&lt;br&gt;&#xA;editorial comments of the&lt;/em&gt; Oakland Enquirer)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The lecture which the Swami Vivekananda gave Monday night in his new&#xA;course on &amp;ldquo;The People of India&amp;rdquo;, was interesting, not only for what he&#xA;had to relate of the people of that country, but for the insight into&#xA;their mental attitude and prejudices which the speaker gave without&#xA;really meaning it. It is apparent that the Swami, educated and&#xA;intellectual man that he is, is no admirer of Western civilisation. He&#xA;has evidently been a good deal embittered by the talk about child&#xA;widows, the oppression of women, and other barbarisms alleged against&#xA;the people of India, and is somewhat inclined to resort to the &lt;em&gt;tu&#xA;quoque&lt;/em&gt; in reply.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>851 I AM THAT I AM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/851_i_am_that_i_am/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/851_i_am_that_i_am/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-am-that-i-am&#34;&gt;I AM THAT I AM&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Notes of a lecture give in San Francisco on March 20, 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The subject tonight is man, man in contrast with nature. For a long time&#xA;the word &amp;ldquo;nature&amp;rdquo; was used almost exclusively to denote external&#xA;phenomena. These phenomena were found to behave methodically; and they&#xA;often repeated themselves: that which had happened in the past happened&#xA;again — nothing happened only once. Thus it was concluded that nature&#xA;was uniform. Uniformity is closely associated with the idea of nature;&#xA;without it natural phenomena cannot be understood. This uniformity is&#xA;the basis of what we call law.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>852 UNITY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/852_unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/852_unity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;unity&#34;&gt;UNITY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Notes of a lecture delivered at the Vedanta Society, New York, in&#xA;June, 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The different sectarian systems of India all radiate from one central&#xA;idea of unity or dualism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They are all under Vedanta, all interpreted by it. Their final essence&#xA;is the teaching of unity. This, which we see as many, is God. We&#xA;perceive matter, the world, manifold sensation. Yet there is but one&#xA;existence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These various names mark only differences of degree in the expression of&#xA;that One. The worm of today is the God of tomorrow. These distinctions&#xA;which we do love are all parts of one infinite fact, and only differ in&#xA;the degree of expression. That one infinite fact is the attainment of&#xA;freedom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>853 THE WORSHIP OF THE DIVINE MOTHER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/853_the_worship_of_the_divine_mother/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/853_the_worship_of_the_divine_mother/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-worship-of-the-divine-mother&#34;&gt;THE WORSHIP OF THE DIVINE MOTHER&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Fragmentary notes taken on a Sunday afternoon in New York in June,&#xA;1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the tribal or clan-God, man arrives, in every religion, at the sum,&#xA;the God of gods.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Confucius alone has expressed the one eternal idea of ethics. &amp;ldquo;Manu&#xA;Deva&amp;rdquo; was transformed into Ahriman. In India, the mythological&#xA;expression was suppressed; but the idea remained. In an old Veda is&#xA;found the Mantra, &amp;ldquo;I am the empress of all that lives, the power in&#xA;everything.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>854 THE ESSENCE OF RELIGION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/854_the_essence_of_religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_8/notes_of_class_talks_and_lectures/854_the_essence_of_religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-essence-of-religion&#34;&gt;THE ESSENCE OF RELIGION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Report of a lecture delivered in America&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In France the &amp;ldquo;rights of man&amp;rdquo; was long a watchword of the race; in&#xA;America the rights of women still beseech the public ear; in India we&#xA;have concerned ourselves always with the rights of Gods.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Vedanta includes all sects. We have a peculiar idea in India.&#xA;Suppose I had a child; I should not teach him any religion, but the&#xA;practice of concentrating his mind; and just one line of prayer — not&#xA;prayer in your sense, but this: &amp;ldquo;I meditate on Him who is the Creator of&#xA;the universe; may He enlighten my mind.&amp;rdquo; Then, when old enough, he goes&#xA;about hearing the different philosophies and teachings, till he finds&#xA;that which seems the truth to him. He then becomes the Shishya or&#xA;disciple of the Guru (teacher) who is teaching this truth. He may choose&#xA;to worship Christ or Buddha or Mohammed: we recognise the rights of each&#xA;of these, and the right of all souls to their own Ishta or chosen way.&#xA;It is, therefore, quite possible for my son to be a Buddhist, my wife to&#xA;be a Christian, and myself a Mohammedan at one and the same time with&#xA;absolute freedom from friction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
