<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v1-origin/brit-age/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v1-origin/brit-age/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allUri-sItArAma-rAju</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v1-origin/brit-age/articles/allUri-sItArAma-rAju/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v1-origin/brit-age/articles/allUri-sItArAma-rAju/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ti-essay&#34;&gt;TI essay&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.rattibha.com/thread/1635507361136914432&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The film #RRR earned an Oscar. This film was inspired by a Hindu Sanyasi named Alluri Sitarama Raju. Alluri Sitarama Raju used to travel from village to village &amp;amp; preach Bhagavad Gita among tribals. He urged Hindus to revolt against foreign rule. A thread about his life🧵&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alluri Sitarama Raju was born on July 4, 1898 in Andhra Pradesh. His was a lower middle class Hindu family. His father died when he was 8. Like most Hindus, Alluri Sitarama Raju was taught Ramayana and Mahabharata in his childhood and he took an extreme liking to these epics. By the age of 14, Alluri learnt Sanskrit, Hindi &amp;amp; English. At the age of 18, he took Diksha &amp;amp; became a Sanyasi. By 24, he visited by foot various holy places such as Gangotri, Nashik and Varanasi. Adorning Kamandalu, saffron clothes &amp;amp; preaching Gita, he travelled everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beni mAdhav Ray</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v1-origin/brit-age/articles/beNi-mAdhava-rAy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v1-origin/brit-age/articles/beNi-mAdhava-rAy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://bhabatarinibangabhumi.home.blog/2022/06/20/dacaoits-of-bengal/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dacoits of Bengal – Part 1.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Durge Durgotinashini 🔱&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sacrificing Yavanas to Ma Kali was very prevalent in Bengal in old days. This can be seen in the 1946 riots too, where, for every one Hindu life lost, atleast 10 Yavanas (Mohammadians) used to be sacrificed. Today I’ll share about a Bengali shakta who used to sacrifice Yavanas infront of Ma Kali. Beni Madhav Ray or Beni Ray, popularly called “Pundit Dakait” was a Kulin varendra Brahmin who had a beautiful wife.+++(5)+++ His wife was abducted by a Pathan. To avenge his wife’s abductor (Pathan, a Yavana), he turned to banditry. Beni Madhav Ray was a sanskrit scholar, which is why he was called “Pundit Dakait” (dacoit). He gathered Hindu followers from different castes and made an armed outfit of dacoits. He along with his dakait sena used to live in an isolated island in Chalan Beel which was surrounded by forest. At this island, he erected a Kali Murti called “যবনমর্দিনী”/ “Yavan-Mardini.”+++(4)+++ The place where Pundit Dakalt lived was called “Pundit Dakait er Bhita (estate of Pundit Dakait). Beni Ray and his Dakait sena unleashed reign of terror on muslim invaders of Bengal. That’s why muslims called his place “Shoitaner Bhita&amp;quot; (estate of Satan).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevadAsI lands</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v1-origin/brit-age/articles/devadAsI-lands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v1-origin/brit-age/articles/devadAsI-lands/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latestlaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Tamil-Nadu-Devadasis-Prevention-of-Dedication-Act-1947.pdf&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Dravidian Movement and the Devadasi Abolition Act: Did a ‘Brahiminical conspiracy’ oppose reforms to the practice as alleged?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Dravidian movement has long claimed the mantle of progressive politics in Tamil Nadu. Among their claims in support of women’s emancipation was their contribution to the passing of the Devadasi Abolition Act.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;17 November, 2020&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Devadasi Abolition Act and the Dravidian Movement&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Dravidian movement has long claimed the mantle of progressive politics in Tamil Nadu. Among their claims in support of women’s emancipation was their contribution to the passing of the Devadasi Abolition Act.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gopal mukhyopAdhyaya pAtha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v1-origin/brit-age/articles/Gopal_mukhyopAdhyaya_pAtha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v1-origin/brit-age/articles/Gopal_mukhyopAdhyaya_pAtha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opindia.com/2023/02/gopal-patha-wikipedia-page-removed-pakistani-editors/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1946, the massacre of Hindu community in Bengal was intricately planned. Jinnah is recalled as having said that he will either have India divided or India burnt and that he had given up on Constitutional methods to demand the creation of Pakistan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jinnah had chosen the 16th of August as Direction Action Day because it was the 18th day of Ramzan, the day when the Battle of Badr was fought and won – a war fought by Prophet Muhammad himself, against the Kaffirs, and is considered to be won by Allah’s divine intervention by Muslims.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KAnhere anant organizer</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v1-origin/brit-age/articles/kAnhere-anant-organizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/misc_v1-origin/brit-age/articles/kAnhere-anant-organizer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anant Lakshman Kanhere: Sacrificing for Swaraj&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After assassinating a British officer, Anant Lakshman Kanhere was brave enough to admit that he carried out the act to take revenge for the oppression of Hindus by the British&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;anant-lakshman-kanhere&#34;&gt;Anant Lakshman Kanhere&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anant Lakshman Kanhere or Anantrao was born on January 7, 1891, to a Brahmin family in Aayani (Anjani), a small village in the Khed Taluka of the Ratnagiri district. He received his primary education in Nizamabad, also known as Indur at the time, and had his English education in Aurangabad, where his uncle stayed. Kanhere went back to Aurangabad in 1908, where he met people from secret revolutionary groups. Anantrao used to stay with his friend Gangaram Marwadi, a businessman. Ganagram had taken the oath of ‘Abhinav Bharat’. Kashinath Tonape was a friend of Gangaram’s at Yewale. He belonged to Nashik’s Secret Society. Anantrao was put to the test by Gangaram before receiving the oath of allegiance. In Anantrao’s hand, he kept a pair of hot iron tongs. With tenacity and grit, he endured the fire. He once asked Anantrao to hold a lit lamp’s hot glass. It was in both of Anantrao’s palms. Even though his palms were burned, he did not release the glass. Anantarao was given the oath of secrecy of the Secret Organisation by Kashinath Tonape, a member of the Nashik, Maharashtra-based Secret Society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
