<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>cixi vs yaqub-spawn</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/cixi_vs_yaqub-spawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/cixi_vs_yaqub-spawn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From: Empress Dowager Cixi: The Concubine Who Launched Modern China&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But Cixi refused to let go of Xinjiang, and as soon as she returned to power in 1875 she dispatched General Zuo Zongtang to win it back. The expedition was a matter of urgency for her: Russia had occupied a key area in the region, Ili, for the past four years and, unless China acted now, Russian ownership would become a fait accompli.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>dungan-excerpts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/dungan-excerpts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/dungan-excerpts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the date of these edicts up till 1862 A.D., the last year of Hien Feng&amp;rsquo;s reign, there is nothing recorded of special note. In this last mentioned year, however, there broke out the great Mohammedan insurrection of the north-west, which is comparable only to the Panthay rebellion in the south, and lasted from 1862 to 1876 A.D.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1861 A.D. some rebels who had been devastating the province of Szechwan invaded Shensi. Some have asserted that these rebels were connected with the Taiping Rebellion, but that is uncertain. To resist them the people of Shensi organised their local militia, the Mohammedan militia keeping themselves distinct from the Chinese troops under their own leaders. The rebels were successful in capturing the city of Weinanhsien, situated on the river some thirty English miles east of the capital. The Mohammedan militia from the neighbouring city of Hwachow marched against them and retook the city, in which they found considerable treasure, either brought by the rebels as booty from Szechwan or abandoned by the original inhabitants of the city who had fled. This stroke of good fortune on the part of the Mohammedans created envy in the minds of the native Chinese militia who claimed at least a share of their gains. This was refused, and thus was engendered bitter feelings of antagonism, which only needed a suitable opportunity to lead to strife.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hehuang 1895</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/hehuang_1895/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/hehuang_1895/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During Japan vs Qing war of 1895, Mohammedans in China raised their 3rd major jihad of 1800&amp;rsquo;s (much smaller than Panthay &amp;amp; Dungan) when they realized Qing army was busy fighting Japan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;第三次河湟事变 (3rd Hehuang Incident) is what its called in Chinese&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NYT report on Qing reaction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The New York Times&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Published: August 14, 1896&lt;br&gt;&#xA;SLAUGHTER OF MOHAMMEDANS.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The Chinese Commander Showing No Mercy to Insurrectionists.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;TOKIO, Aug. 2-The Mohammedan rebellion in Kansu, China, appears to be developing large proportions. The General in Chief of the imperial forces apparently has commands to carry on a war of extermination.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;In the affected district, in one place, he Flew 8,000 trades people and sold their wives and female children.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is expected to provoke terrible resistance, in which Mohammedans across the border, in Russia, are expected to take a hand.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;With reference to the outbreak of the insurrection In Formosa and cruelty on the part of the Japanese civil and military authorities, the Niche Nichi Shinbun characterizes the reports of cruelties as reckless fables, base calumnies, and deserving no attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>hodong kim: holy war</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/hodong_kim_holy-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/hodong_kim_holy-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;religious-motivation&#34;&gt;Religious motivation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;katakis&#34;&gt;Katakis&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although the influence of the Katakis had weakened considerably since the end of the sixteenth century because of the successful activities of rival Naqshbandi Sufis,146 Arshad al-Din, together with Satuq Boghra Khan during the Qarakhanid period, became one of the most revered saints among the Muslims in Eastern Turkestan. He was called Allah&amp;rsquo;s companion (Wali Allah) and his mausoleum in Kucha was considered a sacred place of worship. As a descendant of that holy Sufi and as a guardian of his mausoleum Rashidin Khwaja had been &amp;ldquo;living with prayer (du&amp;rsquo;a) and cultivation (talab) and, not being mixed with people, treading the path of an ascetic (darvish).&amp;ldquo;147 He commanded respect and submission from a large number of Muslims-both the Turks and the Tungans-who considered themselves his disciples (murid).148&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Islam in china</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/islam_in_china/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/islam_in_china/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ISLAM IN CHINA Photos by Mr. Hans Döring.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE REPUTED TOMB OF MOHAMMED&amp;rsquo;S MATERNAL UNCLE AT CANTON.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the legends concerning the tomb see especially Chapter IV. &amp;ldquo;Chinese Mohammedan Tradition.&amp;rdquo; For a discussion as to the claim see especially Chapter VII. &amp;ldquo;The Mosques and Tombs of Canton.&amp;rdquo; This tomb is greatly venerated and made an object of pilgrimage by Chinese Moslems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Frontispiece.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SLAM ISLA IN CHINA A NEGLECTED PROBLEM WITH ILLUSTRATIONS MONUMENTAL RUBBINGS MAPS, ETC.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lipman on jihAd</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/lipman_on_jihAd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/lipman_on_jihAd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Familiar Strangers: A History of Muslims in Northwest China&#xA;By Jonathan N. Lipman&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; in the villages, Deng Zeng and his commanders were not able to prevent non-Muslims from being ambushed and slaughtered by Muslims in broad daylight, within sight of Xining&amp;rsquo;s walls. Nonetheless, as the weather improved, so did conditions for infantry and cavalry assaults, supported by the few Qing artillery pieces. Finally, in March, the Duoba Muslims, their numbers greatly reduced through unsuccessful sorties and depleted food supplies, surrendered unconditionally. Their leaders lost their heads, and the common soldiers dispersed to their ruined, empty villages. Thousands of Muslims tried to follow the tracks of Bai Yanhu west toward a Muslim refuge. Unlike Bai&amp;rsquo;s veterans in the 1870s, they never reached Russian territory but were hunted down by pursuing armies, frozen by the late winter of the north Tibetan marches, and starved by the barren wasteland. Finally captured and relocated near Korla, in Xinjiang, fewer than two thousand survived.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rjrasva on dungan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/rjrasva_on_dungan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/rjrasva_on_dungan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;circumstance&#34;&gt;Circumstance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Religious motivations - sUfi rAshidIn khwAja&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Qing were exhausted from massive Taiping rebellion by the Chinese brother of Jesus &amp;amp; Panthay jihad (1856–1873). Western observers feared a Mohammedan China.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The 1 long term effect of Mongol rule was expansion of Hui Mohammedan numbers, the Yuan Khanate itself was &amp;ldquo;secular&amp;rdquo; but Anandai the grandson of Qubilai became a Mohammedan &amp;amp; in areas under his control spread it by force before he was executed. The slowly expanding Hui numbers would continue &amp;amp; explode in the largest jihad of history in total numbers that I know of, the Dungan jihad (1862-1877) which depopulated large swathes of Qing empire &amp;amp; resulted in extermination of most Mohammedans in China.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;impact&#34;&gt;Impact&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Panthay 17 yr rebellion with heavy Mohammedan element, overlapped with Dungan jihad. Jahangir Khoja→Panthay Rebellion (1 mill dead)→1st Dungan (8-12 mill dead) 1862–77 →2nd Dungan (1895 during 1st S-J war)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;(80% of sullas in empire died when curbing Dungan, Panthay etc).&amp;rdquo; [TW]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This Dungan jihad tmk is the largest jihad in hist in total #&amp;rsquo;s &amp;amp; yet is mostly unknown to non historians, even most Mohammedans including Pakistanis have no idea.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beg even established a caliphate of sorts with all that usually entails. He was even conducting diplomacy with Ottomans, Russians, &amp;amp; Western powers before the Qing steamroller turned the tide around.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;costly-suppression&#34;&gt;Costly suppression&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;During the initial phase the Manchu &amp;amp; Han were caught off guard &amp;amp; for a time western observers of the time thought a caliphate would be born in western China before they turned the tide&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Dungan revolt: 8-12 mill dead, lasted 15 yrs,sullas prob around 10% of Qing : 32-48 mill or more dead(Indian pop 4X Qing &amp;amp; sulla % higher)&amp;rdquo; [TW]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Famous General Tso&amp;rsquo;s chicken btw is named after Zuo Zongtang who carried on a part war of extermination of Mohammedans to put down the jihad.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zuo reported 60K of 700K Shaanxi Mohammedans left. &amp;ldquo;Among those fortunate to survive this catastrophe, some had relocated &amp;hellip; while others were forced to abandon their religion and become part of today&amp;rsquo;s Han people&amp;rdquo;. Islam in Shaanxi was completely destroyed as a result of the policy of “demolishing Hui” in the late Qing Dynasty. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Rjrasva/status/972870662023860224&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;economic-and-social-restrictions&#34;&gt;Economic and social restrictions&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;[&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Rjrasva/status/471303134216998912&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;All our villages, farms, houses and graveyards were now owned by those from other religions. More than eight hundred mosques were destroyed by fire.&amp;rdquo; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Rjrasva/status/972871308919808001/photo/1&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Their mosques were either damaged or destroyed by fire, or converted to family shrines and temples of the Han people.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Rjrasva/status/972870662023860224&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;punishing-leaders&#34;&gt;Punishing Leaders&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sons &amp;amp; grandsons of Yaqub Beg the Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi of the Dungan jihad (the largest mass jihad in recorded history afaik) were castrated &amp;amp; sold as slaves despite Western protests while the earlier jihadist Jahangir Khoja was paraded in Beijing &amp;amp; dispatched to his 72 hoors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>stoddard on dungan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/stoddard_on_dungan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/stoddard_on_dungan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Lothrop Stoddard in his &amp;ldquo;New World of Islam&amp;rdquo; (1922) commenting on the great Dungan Jihad:)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In China, likewise, the nineteenth century witnessed an extraordinary development of Moslem energy. Islam had reached China in very early times, brought in by Arab traders and bands of Arab mercenary soldiers. Despite centuries of intermarriage with Chinese women, their descendants still differ perceptibly from the general Chinese population, and regard themselves as a separate and superior people. The Chinese Mohammedans are mainly concentrated in the southern province of Yunnan and the inland provinces beyond.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wen chu - rebellion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/wen-chu_rebellion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/religion/islam/articles/wen-chu_rebellion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE MOSLEM REBELLION IN NORTHWEST CHINA 1862-1878 CENTRAL ASIATIC STUDIES MONOGRAPH SERIES DEVOTED TO THE CULTURE, HISTORY, AND LANGUAGES OF CENTRAL ASIA AND ITS PEOPLES Edited by KARL JAHN and JOHN R. KRUEGER University of Leiden Indiana University 1966&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE MOSLEM REBELLION IN NORTHWEST CHINA 1862-1878 A STUDY OF GOVERNMENT MINORITY POLICY by WEN-DJANG CHU&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Memory of my Beloved Father KING CHU 1887-1951&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;0&#34;&gt;0&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;preface&#34;&gt;PREFACE&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The great Moslem rebellion in Northwest China in the sixties and seventies of the 19th century has undoubtedly been greatly underestimated in most history books. Some writers have devoted a short paragraph to this subject; others have dismissed it with one sentence. This is hardly justifiable, because the aforesaid rebellion lasted more than 15 years, spread from Shensi to Sinkiang, covering almost one fourth of China&amp;rsquo;s territory, and directly disturbed the life of more than 10,000,000 people. According to one source:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
