<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;01 ROUSING NATIONAL CONSCIOUSNESS on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;01 ROUSING NATIONAL CONSCIOUSNESS on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 XVII Meeting the Historic Need</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/01_XVII_Meeting_the_Historic_Need/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/01_XVII_Meeting_the_Historic_Need/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our indebtedness to society-The best service – Past glory – Destruction by enemies – Once powerful and free – Race of Jayachands leads to Muslim and British success – The malady continues, formation of Pakistan – A house divided – History repeating itself, Dravidanad etc. – Federal structure, a poisonous seed – Basic cure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE founder of the organisation used to put forth the aim of the Sangh in a small pithy sentence: &amp;ldquo;We have to organise and make our Hindu Society so powerful that no power on earth will dare cast an evil eye upon it.&amp;rdquo; To fulfil this is the foremost duty that has devolved upon all the children of this great society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 XVIII Wanted a Unitary State</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/02_XVIII_Wanted_a_Unitary_State/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/02_XVIII_Wanted_a_Unitary_State/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An article by Sri M.S. Golwalkar just after the publication of the Report of States Reorganisation Committee in 1956.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE Report of the S.R.C. is out for about a fortnight. Prominent persons in the political field stated giving free expression to their reactions to the recommendations of the Commission even before the report was officially published. Nobody seems to be satisfied. The whole atmosphere is charged with antagonism to the report. Feelings are rising high. All legislative groups are giving free vent to feelings of antagonism towards one another. No one group appears to be in a mood to co-operate with, and live side by side with another in one common administrative unit. Antagonism has been so intensified and aggravated as to take the form of deep-rooted hostility.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 XIX The Eternal Basis</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/03_XIX_The_Eternal_Basis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/03_XIX_The_Eternal_Basis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Need for positive basis – Efforts of reactionary approach – Sangh for permanent organised life – Fate of temporary movements; Congress - Nation in drifting – The remedy – Red signal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE work of the Rashtriya Swayamsevak Sangh had a very humble beginning. Steadily and gradually it has spread its work and today we find the Sangh branches working in full swing in all provinces of our country. This constant growth, this steady expansion has been an unfailing feature of the Sangh all through the trials and turmoils posed by the vagaries of the external situations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 XX Nourish The Roots*</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/04_XX_Nourish_The_Roots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/04_XX_Nourish_The_Roots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Education for manifesting the Inner Personality – Teacher as Character-moulder –Purge present perversions in learning habits – Be true to Hindu spirit – Our stultifying history – Uphold right spirit of nationalism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It goes without saying that the teachers are the key figures in the field of education. It is but proper that we briefly touch upon a few fundamentals in this context.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our Basic Concept&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To start with, what does ‘education’ connote in the modern sense of the term? It is to draw out the latent faculties in man. Merely stuffing pieces of information into the brain is not education. Making man’s brain a lumber room is not its aim. Recognising and bringing out the diverse talents and genius in man has been taken to be the cornerstone of education everywhere. And this has yielded substantial results too. We can find men of great achievements in several fields of arts and sciences in various countries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 XXI The One Answer to Many Challenges*</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/05_XXI_The_One_Answer_to_Many_Challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/05_XXI_The_One_Answer_to_Many_Challenges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Obstacles in path of Hindu consolidation – Absence of Pride – Parochial palls – Ex: Telangana agitation – Declare Unitary State – Danger of corruption – Muslims’ opposition to Vande Mataram revived – Hindu, the real child – Denial of Truth harmful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE work of the Rashtriya Swayamsevak Sangh has been started with the one aim of building up an organised and consolidated life of our Hindu People. It is indeed a difficult and an uphill task. In order to achieve this goal, we have to first find out what are the obstacles and the problems, which we have to face on the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 XXII The Elixir of National Life</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/06_XXII_The_Elixir_of_National_Life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/06_XXII_The_Elixir_of_National_Life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;WORLD OF REALITY&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Strong devours weak – Great fact of world history – The present world picture – Slogans change, fact remains – Mirage of mutual friendship – Friendship of strong and weak – Strength for peace and freedom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WE, the children of this great and ancient nation, naturally desire that our nation should scale ever new heights of prosperity, glory and honour in this world. This is a very legitimate desire, no one can deny it. However, life is not all smooth-sailing in this world of hard reality. Even in the fulfilment of just and legitimate desire one is confronted with impediments and challenges from outside forces. If we have to bring to life the dream of our national glory, we have to assess and analyse the nature of this challenge and prepare ourselves to meet it effectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 XXIII Worshippers of Victory</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/07_XXIII_Worshippers_of_Victory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/07_XXIII_Worshippers_of_Victory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deifying the great – Misreading of scriptures – Selfishness, helplessness at the root – Effort is God – Great examples – Worship of the victorious – Martyr, great but not ideal – Lesson of Rajput martyrdom – Act, do not react – Philosophy of right action.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OUR great men stand as lamp posts on the path to the fulfillment of our national life- mission and national glory. In order that the coming generations may pursue that path with success, it is essential that their inspiring memories and examples are kept undimmed in the national mind and the lessons of the lives and deeds of those masters of thought and action are presented in their true perspective. It is precisely with this end in view that the celebration of the anniversaries of birth and death of our ancient heroes has found a pride of place in our national tradition since hoary times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 XXIV Fight to Win*</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/08_XXIV_Fight_to_Win/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/08_XXIV_Fight_to_Win/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;THE RIGHT MEASURES&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nature and magnitude of threat - Steel people&amp;rsquo;s will - Robust national leadership required - Keep up nation&amp;rsquo;s morale - Watchword: Economise! - Dangers of personality cult - Communist &amp;lsquo;split&amp;rsquo;, a ruse - Warning of Chinese &amp;lsquo;Cease-fire&amp;rsquo; - Beware Pakistani fifth column - Appeasing Pakistan suicidal - Recognise friends - Fotify trusted sentinels.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SINCE the 20th of October 1962 there has been an invasion of our country by China. However, the present drive of the Chinese is not unexpected, though our Government seems to have been taken by surprise. When China invaded and annexed Tibet, it was clear that they had no benevolent intentions towards us. Surrounded by Russia on the one side and the ocean on the other, the only direction, the only weak spot China could look to for expansion was Tibet. The British had maintained an independent status for Tibet so that it may serve as a buffer State between Bharat and China. In their zeal to undo what the Britishers had done, our present rulers accepted sovereignty of China over Tibet. And again, as our Government itself has confessed, the Chineese had pressed forward and illegally occupied 12,000 square miles of our territory. In the face of these facts we can hardly accuse China of treachery. Their attitude to our country has been openly hostile for years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 Ch 25 Nation At War</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/09_Ch_25_Nation_At_War/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/09_Ch_25_Nation_At_War/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(*) In the wake of Pakistani aggression in August 1965.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CALL OF A NEW ERA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Self-respect, nation&amp;rsquo;s life-breath - Superiority of &amp;lsquo;man&amp;rsquo; over &amp;lsquo;machine&amp;rsquo; - Myth exploded - Nation&amp;rsquo;s heroic mettle - Guideline for national policies-Destroying the real war potential - Akhand Bharat, only solution - UNO in true colours -Rule of international friendship - Kashmir, a closed chapter - Welcome bigger war.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE recent war with Pakistan has as if electrified the entire length and breadth of our land and inspired the hearts and minds of millions of our countrymen with a new purpose and a new confidence as nothing else had done during the last eighteen years after the quitting of the British.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Ch 26 Forget Not The Lessons (*)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/10_Ch_26_Forget_Not_The_Lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/10_Ch_26_Forget_Not_The_Lessons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(*) In the wake of War of Liberation of Bangladesh&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Realities of world situation - Allow not Shatru-shesh - 0ur traditional attitude towards war - People&amp;rsquo;s support, the mainstay -The lessons.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE present war has thrown the country into a melting-pot and cast the nation&amp;rsquo;s mind in an inspiring mood of unity and patriotic fervour. It has once again proved that our nation is intrinsically one. It has also cleared, as nothing else had done so far, the many cobwebs of confusions and illusions, which had enmeshed our thinking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Ch 27 Keep The Flag Flying Aloft (*)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/11_Ch_27_Keep_The_Flag_Flying_Aloft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/01_ROUSING_NATIONAL_CONSCIOUSNESS/11_Ch_27_Keep_The_Flag_Flying_Aloft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Invoke national self-respect – The true ambassadors – Necessity for regular Samskars – Imbibe good from others – Serve local population – Bitter African lesson – As world missionaries– Question and Answers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE first point to be borne in mind by our brothers and sisters living abroad is to keep alive their day-to-day behaviour a spirit of intense national self-respect. And for this, a keen awareness of the glorious heritage that our forbears have left for us should ever be present in our minds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
