<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/proto-onge/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/proto-onge/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>niShAda-s and shabara-s of jambudvIpa: What you see is what it is</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/proto-onge/articles/MT/2012-07-09_nishada-s-and-shabara-s-of-jambudvipa-what-you-see/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/proto-onge/articles/MT/2012-07-09_nishada-s-and-shabara-s-of-jambudvipa-what-you-see/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2012/07/09/nishada-s-and-shabara-s-of-jambudvipa-what-you-see-is-what-it-is/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The vast land of jambudvIpa is home to many different types of tribal people. They were noted right from the times of the ancient Hindu texts. The R^igveda hardly mentions any of them, but one that is mentioned is kIkaTa. In the later Vedic layers, epics, purAna-s and dharma literature, the mentions of them increase and include niShAda, kirAta, pulinda, shabara, mataMga, bhilla and kola among others. This suggests that as the Arya-s expanded over the subcontinent they became acquainted with more of these tribal populations. The recent autosomal data allows us to understand the tribal peoples of India at an unprecedented level in terms of their affinities and origins. By means of k-cluster analysis of the Old World data derived from the studies of Chaubey et al, Behar et al, Metspalu et al, Yunusbayev et al, the Gujarati genetics project, and the 1000 genomes project at k=7 one can discern three major sources of ancestry for most people of the Indian subcontinent. One can simply model the ethnogenesis of India based on three components and their sub-components based on the above k7 results. The first is a native Indian component which is present in all Indians. It corresponds to what was modeled as the “Ancestral South Indian” component by Reich et al. We prefer calling it either simply Indian or proto-Indian. The negritos of Andaman are primarily related to this component. The second component is the Inner Eurasian component. This component splits up at k7 as what may be considered Western Eurasian proper/Caucasian and Northern European. The third component is the East Eurasian component, which splits up at k7 into East Asian proper and North East Asian. Thus, at k=7 of the above data collections we have the following components:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;1@k7= proto-Indian; 2@k7= Western Eurasian; 3@k7= Northern European; 4@k7= East Asia; 5@k7= Northeast Asia; 6@k7= West Asian/Mediterranean; 7@k7= African.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
