<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Non-Africans and their migrations.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/MT/2005-04-14_non-africans-and-their-migrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/MT/2005-04-14_non-africans-and-their-migrations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/04/14/non-africans-and-their-migrations/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most idiotic ideas that has entered the minds of many contemporary Indians is that the Aryans never entered India from outside and are probably autochthonous. However, the wealth of evidence from recent genetic studies points to exactly the opposite. The newly launched National Geographic project is likely to lay to rest this myth of the “Out of India” theory and restore the Aryan invasion theory. However, it is likely to make the mainstream model of elite dominance untenable. The Indo-Aryans invaded India on a largescale and not as a trickle. This is indicated by the Y-chromosome R1A1 (M17) marker, which I believe to correspond to the expansion of the satem branch of the Indo-European languages. This of course raises the issue as to when the “Caucasoid” physical type came into being !&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ball-game</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/MT/ball-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/MT/ball-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1639133290429816832.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Could a game with the ball have been invented very deep in time in Eurasia before the separation of the ancestors of the core 1st Americans from the remaining Eurasians? Or was it independently invented by the core 1st Americans in meso-America &amp;amp; convergently in Eurasia? Most people seem to accept the latter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In meso-America the ball game was often accompanied by the ritual slaughter of the losers. And the ball is believed to have been vulcanized in some site by sulfur from burning human remains. It is interesting that a motif of the killing of 2 cosmogonic figures One-Death &amp;amp; Seven-Death in a ball game. We have come across a version of killing of the heroes with a bladed-ball.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fox-wedding</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/MT/fox-wedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/MT/fox-wedding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://unrollthread.com/t/1281782208303439872/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Blust had published a detailed study of this. He note the connection between sunshowers and the fox/jackal wedding in Japan, Korea (not chIna), India, Iran, W.Eur, Basque areas, Finland, Bulgaria, Turkey (wolf wedding). For such an odd connection to be found across different Eurasiatic locales spanning different language families does suggest an early origin in pre-IE inner Eurasia followed by dissemination by the diverging groups. It does seem to be a motif descending from an early Eurasiatic folkloric tradition that might be older than 6000 years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hare moon</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/MT/hare_moon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/MT/hare_moon/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>steppe-capital</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/MT/steppe-capital/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/MT/steppe-capital/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1637138246923591680.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is an interesting parallel across steppe-derived civilizations that persisted across time &amp;amp; even post-settlement. Did the steppe-derived empires have a capital? The Chingizid great Khans invested in building a grand capital, Qaraqorum whose etymology is uncertain. Today it is a fairly remote township near Erdene Zuu. A relative who visited it said he found it to be a great place for meditation in solitude.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chingiz Khan rallied his people in an assembly of yurts at Qaraqorum before campaigns but the more permanent structures were built by his son Ogodei. He is said to have installed several robots there which have striking parallels to those constructed by the great bhojadeva paramAra. It suggests that such technology had survived &amp;amp; reached Mongolia in the 200 years after him. 1st person accounts survive of how the robots would respond to the Khan&amp;rsquo;s (tactile?) commands&amp;amp; play music&amp;amp; serve kumis. While the Khan held annual festivals @ Qaraqorum&amp;amp; entertained guests/embassies there on special occasions, his court did not live there most of the time. Instead they moved around the empire with their herds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>steppe-history-overview</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/MT/steppe-history-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/MT/steppe-history-overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oocities.org/somasushma/steppe.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Asiatic Steppes have over the past 10000 years radiated an amazing number of people who have influenced the fate of much of Asia and some of Europe. These people of different ethnic backgrounds can be classified based on the language family which their speech belongs to.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-indo-european-speakers&#34;&gt;1) Indo-European speakers&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-The Turfanians&#xA;-The Sarmatians&#xA;-The Tocharians&#xA;-The Shakas&#xA;-The Kushanas&#xA;-The Parthians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These represent the last waves of Indo-European people emanting from the steppes. The earlier such migrations established the settled Aryan civilizations of India, Iran and the Middle East and other Indo-European cultures of the West. Some of these later migrants founded kingdoms in central Asia and Northern China. They invaded northern India too and founded some dynasties there such as prominently the Kushan dynasty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
