<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;00 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/00/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;00 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/00/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 CONTENTS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/00/01_CONTENTS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/00/01_CONTENTS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cover&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Other Books by This Author&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Title Page&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Copyright&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dedication&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; The Shores of the Cosmic Ocean&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;II&lt;/em&gt; One Voice in the Cosmic Fugue&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;III&lt;/em&gt; The Harmony of Worlds&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IV&lt;/em&gt; Heaven and Hell&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;V&lt;/em&gt; Blues for a Red Planet&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;VI&lt;/em&gt; Travelers’ Tales&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;VII&lt;/em&gt; The Backbone of Night&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;VIII&lt;/em&gt; Travels in Space and Time&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IX&lt;/em&gt; The Lives of the Stars&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt; The Edge of Forever&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;XI&lt;/em&gt; The Persistence of Memory&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 INTRODUCTION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/00/02_INTRODUCTION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/00/02_INTRODUCTION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The time will come when diligent research over long periods will bring to light things which now lie hidden. A single lifetime, even though entirely devoted to the sky, would not be enough for the investigation of so vast a subject…And so this knowledge will be unfolded only through long successive ages. There will come a time when our descendants will be amazed that we did not know things that are so plain to them…Many discoveries are reserved for ages still to come, when memory of us will have been effaced. Our universe is a sorry little affair unless it has in it something for every age to investigate…Nature does not reveal her mysteries once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/00/03_ACKNOWLEDGMENTS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/places/cosmos/articles/sagan-carl/cosmos/00/03_ACKNOWLEDGMENTS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Besides those thanked in the introduction, I am very grateful to the many people who generously contributed their time and expertise to this book, including Carol Lane, Myrna Talman, and Jenny Arden; David Oyster, Richard Wells, Tom Weidlinger, Dennis Gutierrez, Rob McCain, Nancy Kinney, Janelle Balnicke, Judy Flannery, and Susan Racho of the &lt;em&gt;Cosmos&lt;/em&gt; television staff; Nancy Inglis, Peter Mollman, Marylea O’Reilly, and Jennifer Peters of Random House; Paul west for generously lending me the title of Chapter 5; and George Abell, James Allen, Barbara Amago, Lawrence Anderson, Jonathon Arons, Halton Arp, Asma El Bakri, James Blinn, Bart Bok, Zeddie Bowen, John C. Brandt, Kenneth Brecher, Frank Bristow, John Callendar, Donald B. Campbell, Judith Campbell, Elof Axel Carlson, Michael Carra, John Cassani, Judith Castagno, Catherine Cesarsky, Martin Cohen, Judy-Lynn del Rey, Nicholas Devereux, Michael Devirian, Stephen Dole, Frank D. Drake, Frederick C. Durant III, Richard Epstein, Von R. Eshleman, Ahmed Fahmy, Herbert Friedman, Robert Frosch, Jon Fukuda, Richard Gammon, Ricardo Giacconi, Thomas Gold, Paul Goldenberg, Peter Goldreich, Paul Goldsmith, J. Richard Gott III, Stephen Jay Gould, Bruce Hayes, Raymond Heacock, Wulff Heintz, Arthur Hoag, Paul Hodge, Dorrit Hoffleit, William Hoyt, Icko Iben, Mikhail Jaroszynski, Paul Jepsen, Tom Karp, Bishun N. Khare, Charles Kohlhase, Edwin Krupp, Arthur Lane, Paul MacLean, Bruce Margon, Harold Masursky, Linda Morabito, Edmond Momjian, Edward Moreno, Bruce Murray, William Murnane, Thomas A. Mutch, Kenneth Norris, Tobias Owen, Linda Paul, Roger Payne, Vahe Petrosian, James B. Pollack, George Preston, Nancy Priest, Boris Ragent, Dianne Rennell, Michael Rowton, Allan Sandage, Fred Scarf, Maarten Schmidt, Arnold Scheibel, Eugene Shoemaker, Frank Shu, Nathan Sivin, Bradford Smith, Laurence A. Soderblom, Hyron Spinrad, Edward Stone, Jeremy Stone, Ed Taylor, Kip S. Thorne, Norman Thrower, O. Brian Toon, Barbara Tuchman, Roger Ulrich, Richard Underwood, Peter van de Kamp, Jurrie J. Van der Woude, Arthur Vaughn, Joseph Veverka, Helen Simpson Vishniac, Dorothy Vitaliano, Robert Wagoner, Pete Waller, Josephine Walsh, Kent Weeks, Donald Yeomans, Stephen Yerazunis, Louise Gray Young, Harold Zirin, and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration. I am also grateful for special photographic help by Edwardo Castañeda and Bill Ray.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
