<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;lectures and discourses on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_and_discourses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;lectures and discourses on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_and_discourses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>103 UNITY, THE GOAL OF RELIGION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_and_discourses/103_unity_the_goal_of_religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_and_discourses/103_unity_the_goal_of_religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;unity-the-goal-of-religion&#34;&gt;UNITY, THE GOAL OF RELIGION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in New York, 1896&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This universe of ours, the universe of the senses, the rational, the&#xA;intellectual, is bounded on both sides by the illimitable, the&#xA;unknowable, the ever unknown. Herein is the search, herein are the&#xA;inquiries, here are the facts; from this comes the light which is known&#xA;to the world as religion. Essentially, however, religion belongs to the&#xA;supersensuous and not to the sense plane. It is beyond all reasoning and&#xA;is not on the plane of intellect. It is a vision, an inspiration, a&#xA;plunge into the unknown and unknowable, making the unknowable more than&#xA;known for it can never be &amp;ldquo;known&amp;rdquo;. This search has been in the human&#xA;mind, as I believe, from the very beginning of humanity. There cannot&#xA;have been human reasoning and intellect in any period of the world&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;history without this struggle, this search beyond. In our little&#xA;universe, this human mind, we see a thought arise. Whence it arises we&#xA;do not know; and when it disappears, where it goes, we know not either.&#xA;The macrocosm and the microcosm are, as it were, in the same groove,&#xA;passing through the same stages, vibrating in the same key.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>104 THE FREE SOUL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_and_discourses/104_the_free_soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_and_discourses/104_the_free_soul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-free-soul&#34;&gt;THE FREE SOUL&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in New York, 1896&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The analysis of the Sānkhyas stops with the duality of existence —&#xA;Nature and souls. There are an infinite number of souls, which, being&#xA;simple, cannot die, and must therefore be separate from Nature. Nature&#xA;in itself changes and manifests all these phenomena; and the soul,&#xA;according to the Sankhyas, is inactive. It is a simple by itself, and&#xA;Nature works out all these phenomena for the liberation of the soul; and&#xA;liberation consists in the soul discriminating that it is not Nature. At&#xA;the same time we have seen that the Sankhyas were bound to admit that&#xA;every soul was omnipresent. Being a simple, the soul cannot be limited,&#xA;because all limitation comes either through time, space, or causation.&#xA;The soul being entirely beyond these cannot have any limitation. To have&#xA;limitation one must be in space, which means the body; and that which is&#xA;body must be in Nature. If the soul had form, it would be identified&#xA;with Nature; therefore the soul is formless, and that which is formless&#xA;cannot be said to exist here, there, or anywhere. It must be&#xA;omnipresent. Beyond this the Sankhya philosophy does not go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>105 ONE EXISTENCE APPEARING AS MANY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_and_discourses/105_one_existence_appearing_as_many/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_3/lectures_and_discourses/105_one_existence_appearing_as_many/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-existence-appearing-as-many&#34;&gt;ONE EXISTENCE APPEARING AS MANY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in New York, 1896&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vairāgya or renunciation is the turning point in all the various Yogas.&#xA;The Karmi (worker) renounces the fruits of his work. The Bhakta&#xA;(devotee) renounces all little loves for the almighty and omnipresent&#xA;love. The Yogi renounces his experiences, because his philosophy is that&#xA;the whole Nature, although it is for the experience of the soul, at last&#xA;brings him to know that he is not in Nature, but eternally separate from&#xA;Nature. The Jnāni (philosopher) renounces everything, because his&#xA;philosophy is that Nature never existed, neither in the past, nor&#xA;present, nor will It in the future. The question of utility cannot be&#xA;asked in these higher themes. It is very absurd to ask it; and even if&#xA;it be asked, after a proper analysis, what do we find in this question&#xA;of utility? The ideal of happiness, that which brings man more&#xA;happiness, is of greater utility to him than these higher things which&#xA;do not improve his material conditions or bring him such great&#xA;happiness. All the sciences are for this one end, to bring happiness to&#xA;humanity; and that which brings the larger amount of happiness, man&#xA;takes and gives up that which brings a lesser amount of happiness. We&#xA;have seen how happiness is either in the body, or in the mind, or in the&#xA;Âtman. With animals, and in the lowest human beings who are very much&#xA;like animals, happiness is all in the body. No man can eat with the same&#xA;pleasure as a famished dog or a wolf; so in the dog and the wolf the&#xA;happiness is entirely in the body. In men we find a higher plane of&#xA;happiness, that of thought; and in the Jnani there is the highest plane&#xA;of happiness in the Self, the Atman. So to the philosopher this&#xA;knowledge of the Self is of the highest utility, because it gives him&#xA;the highest happiness possible. Sense-gratifications or physical things&#xA;cannot be of the highest utility to him, because he does not find in&#xA;them the same pleasure that he finds in knowledge itself; and after all,&#xA;knowledge is the one goal and is really the highest happiness that we&#xA;know. All who work in ignorance are, as it were, the draught animals of&#xA;the Devas. The word Deva is here used in the sense of a wise man. All&#xA;the people that work and toil and labour like machines do not really&#xA;enjoy life, but it is the wise man who enjoys. A rich man buys a picture&#xA;at a cost of a hundred thousand dollars perhaps, but it is the man who&#xA;understands art that enjoys it; and if the rich man is without knowledge&#xA;of art, it is useless to him, he is only the owner. All over the world,&#xA;it is the wise man who enjoys the happiness of the world. The ignorant&#xA;man never enjoys; he has to work for others unconsciously.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
