<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;2 The Shattered Jade Realm 1242–1470 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/2_The_Shattered_Jade_Realm_12421470/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;2 The Shattered Jade Realm 1242–1470 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/2_The_Shattered_Jade_Realm_12421470/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>5 War Against Women</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/2_The_Shattered_Jade_Realm_12421470/5_War_Against_Women/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/2_The_Shattered_Jade_Realm_12421470/5_War_Against_Women/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IN THE FALL OF 1237, AFTER EIGHT YEARS IN OFFICE, OGODEI KHAN ordered the most horrendous crime of his twelve-year reign and one of the worst Mongol atrocities recorded. The nearly unbearable horror was committed not against enemies, but against the nation’s daughters.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;His soldiers assembled four thousand Oirat girls above the age of seven together with their male relatives on an open field. The soldiers separated out the girls from the noble families and hauled them to the front of the throng. They stripped the noble girls naked, and one by one the soldiers came forward to rape them. As one soldier finished with a screaming girl, another mounted her. “Their fathers, brothers, husbands, and relatives stood watching,” according to the Persian report, “no one daring to speak.” At the end of the day, two of the girls lay dead from the ordeal, and soldiers divvied out the survivors for later use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Granddaughters of Resistance</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/2_The_Shattered_Jade_Realm_12421470/6_Granddaughters_of_Resistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/2_The_Shattered_Jade_Realm_12421470/6_Granddaughters_of_Resistance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AT THE HEIGHT OF THE MONGOL EMPIRE, AROUND 1271, young Marco Polo set out from Venice to the Mongol capital at Beijing with his father and uncle, who had just completed the same round-trip. The era of conquests begun by Genghis Khan had concluded, and although its shape differed radically from what he had intended, the Silk Route still bustled with caravans, merchants, and exotic wares. Marco Polo easily made his way overland from the Mediterranean to the Mongol court of Khubilai Khan, making almost the entire trip within the Mongol Empire and under the protection of Mongol soldiers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 The Rabbit Demon’s Revenge</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/2_The_Shattered_Jade_Realm_12421470/7_The_Rabbit_Demons_Revenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/2_The_Shattered_Jade_Realm_12421470/7_The_Rabbit_Demons_Revenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EVEN AS THE EMPIRE OF GENGHIS KHAN COLLAPSED, MOST of the Mongols did not want to return home to Mongolia. Members of the Borijin clan in Russia and Persia intermarried with local elites, changed their religion and language as readily as their clothes, and forgot that they were Mongols in order to blend into the new social order.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of the three major branches of the Borijin family ruling abroad, only the Chinese branch attempted to flee home when their rule collapsed, but most of their Mongol subjects stayed in China. According to the Mongol accounts, a dispersed population of 400,000 Mongols lived across China in 1368. Yet, only 60,000 managed to escape or were willing to flee with the court. The Borijin rulers, now neither Chinese nor Mongol, had so alienated their Mongol subjects and soldiers that at their final moment of expulsion from China by the newly rising and natively authentic Ming Dynasty, the majority of the Mongol commoners chose to stay in China. They preferred to serve China rather than return to Mongolia with the Borijin clan and its corrupt horde of foreign advisors, sexually permissive monks, alien guards, pampered astrologers, and nondenominational spiritual quacks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Daughter of the Yellow Dragon</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/2_The_Shattered_Jade_Realm_12421470/8_Daughter_of_the_Yellow_Dragon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/2_The_Shattered_Jade_Realm_12421470/8_Daughter_of_the_Yellow_Dragon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MANDUHAI WAS BORN IN 1448, THE STRONGEST AND most imperial of all the zodiac years, and the only one with a sign designated for a supernatural being: the Yellow Dragon. According to some records at the time of her birth, her parents lived well south of the Gobi, possibly near the oasis of Hami in modern Xinjiang; according to another tradition, she was born on the Tumed Plain in the vicinity of what later became the city of Hohhot, the capital of today’s Inner Mongolian Autonomous Region. In either case, she grew up in relatively arid zones of what is now northern China, and this area and type of environment remained sentimentally important to her throughout her life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 The Falling Prince and the Rising Queen</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/2_The_Shattered_Jade_Realm_12421470/9_The_Falling_Prince_and_the_Rising_Quee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/2_The_Shattered_Jade_Realm_12421470/9_The_Falling_Prince_and_the_Rising_Quee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SEXUAL POLITICS DESTROYED THE COURT OF MANDUUL KHAN. The Tibetan chronicle states that the horrendous charges and countercharges about the incidents were too dreadful to repeat, but of course the author teases the reader with a hazy sketch of events displayed to tantalize more than inform. The Mongolian chroniclers more eagerly described specific details of some events while obscuring others, depending on the genealogical connections and political allegiances of the writer. Each chronicler had some personal connection to the people in the story and often wanted to protect a particular person’s reputation while placing the blame firmly on another.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
