<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>NYT-family-control</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/NYT-family-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/NYT-family-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1621195859345182720.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thread by @SamoBurja on Thread Reader App – Thread Reader App&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of our most important Briefs so far.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How does a family dynasty keep control of a powerful public institution in an ideological environment that is largely hostile to dynasties?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Sulzberger family uses three tools.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First: legally-binding agreements. The NYT Company is public, but has a dual-class stock structure.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Class A shares select 30% of the board of directors and are publicly traded.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Class B shares select 70% of the board. They, however, are 94% owned by a family trust. The Ochs-Sulzberger Family Trust owns basically all Class B shares.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It also can’t really sell them. Per a 1986 agreement, any Class B shares sold outside the family would be automatically converted to Class A shares. The trust is run by a committee of eight family members.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;As a result: eight Sulzbergers run a trust, which owns 94% of the Times’ Class B shares, which selects 70% of the NYT board of directors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This arrangement is enshrined in the NYT’s incorporation certificate. A. G. Sulzberger is, naturally, one of the trustees. In America, you can give your family a dynastic birthright over a newspaper. It just takes some imagination and clerical creativity. While this cuts against the spirit of popular meritocracy, it is perfectly legal. It may, however, come under other kinds of attacks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This leads to the second tool: the family studiously avoids the appearance of dynastic succession.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Many examples here. The family’s private holdings of Class A stock are, naturally, not heavily advertised.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The official purpose of the family trust is to “maintain the editorial independence” of the Times. If the Times could be bought, then its front page could be bought. This equates editorial independence with ownership by the Sulzberger family by design.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Most notably, not a single Sulzberger in a prominent position at the NYT joined the company before the age of 27. Every single one of them began their careers outside the Times. Most, including A. G. Sulzberger, in local journalism! By starting their careers outside the Times, the Sulzbergers build up the skills, experience, and networks that, should they later join the Times, can be effectively used to negate accusations of nepotism or favoritism.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They become professionals just like anyone else. Both professionalism and journalistic ethics are social technologies the family uses to protect itself. After all, it is unprofessional to accuse a colleague of nepotism, merely for being born in the wrong family. Or to fault that family for valuing editorial independence&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This synergies with how the family only allows its most capable members to rise to the top. It does not funnel its young generation into comfy sinecures at the family business. Most Sulzbergers have nothing to do with the paper, but pursue careers in other institutions. According to A. G. Sulzberger, he wasn’t sure he even wanted to be a journalist as late as university. Whether or not this is the case, he proved he was a journalist, as a local reporter in both Rhode Island and Oregon. It only made sense he joined the Times later. He was, however, not a shoo-in for publisher.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ROE obsession</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/ROE-obsession/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/orgs/articles/ROE-obsession/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1453753924960219145&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1453753924960219145&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What caused all the supply chain bottlenecks? Modern finance with its obsession with &amp;ldquo;Return on Equity.&amp;ldquo;To show great ROE almost every CEO stripped their company of all but the bare minimum of assets. Just in time everything. No excess capacity. No strategic reserves. No cash on the balance sheet. Minimal R&amp;amp;D.+++(5)+++ We stripped the shock absorbers out of the economy in pursuit of better short term metrics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Big businesses are supposed to be more stable and resilient than small ones. And economy built around giant corporations like America&amp;rsquo;s should be more resilient to shock. However the obsession with ROE means that no company was prepared for the inevitable hundred year storms. Now as we&amp;rsquo;re facing a hundred year storm of demand, our infrastructure simply can&amp;rsquo;t keep up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
