<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;lectures and discourses on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;lectures and discourses on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>177 THE RAMAYANA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/177_the_ramayana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/177_the_ramayana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ramayana&#34;&gt;THE RAMAYANA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at the Shakespeare Club, Pasadena, California, January 31,&#xA;1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two great epics in the Sanskrit language, which are very&#xA;ancient. Of course, there are hundreds of other epic poems. The Sanskrit&#xA;language and literature have been continued down to the present day,&#xA;although, for more than two thousand years, it has ceased to be a spoken&#xA;language. I am now going to speak to you of the two most ancient epics,&#xA;called the Rāmāyana and the Mahābhārata. They embody the manners and&#xA;customs, the state of society, civilisation, etc., of the ancient&#xA;Indians. The oldest of these epics is called Ramayana, &amp;ldquo;The Life of&#xA;Rāma&amp;rdquo;. There was some poetical literature before this — most of the&#xA;Vedas, the sacred books of the Hindus, are written in a sort of metre —&#xA;but this book is held by common consent in India as the very beginning&#xA;of poetry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>178 THE MAHABHARATA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/178_the_mahabharata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/178_the_mahabharata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-mahabharata&#34;&gt;THE MAHABHARATA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at the Shakespeare Club, Pasadena, California, February 1,&#xA;1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The other epic about which I am going to speak to you this evening, is&#xA;called the Mahābhārata. It contains the story of a race descended from&#xA;King Bharata, who was the son of Dushyanta and Shakuntalā. Mahā means&#xA;great, and Bhārata means the descendants of Bharata, from whom India has&#xA;derived its name, Bhārata. Mahabharata means Great India, or the story&#xA;of the great descendants of Bharata. The scene of this epic is the&#xA;ancient kingdom of the Kurus, and the story is based on the great war&#xA;which took place between the Kurus and the Panchālas. So the region of&#xA;the quarrel is not very big. This epic is the most popular one in India;&#xA;and it exercises the same authority in India as Homer&amp;rsquo;s poems did over&#xA;the Greeks. As ages went on, more and more matter was added to it, until&#xA;it has become a huge book of about a hundred thousand couplets. All&#xA;sorts of tales, legends and myths, philosophical treatises, scraps of&#xA;history, and various discussions have been added to it from time to&#xA;time, until it is a vast, gigantic mass of literature; and through it&#xA;all runs the old, original story. The central story of the Mahabharata&#xA;is of a war between two families of cousins, one family, called the&#xA;Kauravas, the other the Pāndavas — for the empire of India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>179 THOUGHTS ON THE GITA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/179_thoughts_on_the_gita/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/179_thoughts_on_the_gita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts-on-the-gita&#34;&gt;THOUGHTS ON THE GITA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During his sojourn in Calcutta in 1897, Swami Vivekananda used to stay&#xA;for the most part at the Math, the headquarters of the Ramakrisnna&#xA;Mission, located then at Alambazar. During this time several young men,&#xA;who had been preparing themselves for some time previously, gathered&#xA;round him and took the vows of Brahmacharya and Sannyāsa, and Swamiji&#xA;began to train them for future work, by holding classes on the Gitā and&#xA;Vedanta, and initiating them into the practices of meditation. In one of&#xA;these classes he talked eloquently in Bengali on the Gita. The following&#xA;is the translation of the summary of the discourse as it was entered in&#xA;the Math diary:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>180 THE STORY OF JADA BHARATA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/180_the_story_of_jada_bharata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/180_the_story_of_jada_bharata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-story-of-jada-bharata&#34;&gt;THE STORY OF JADA BHARATA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in California&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There was a great monarch named Bharata. The land which is called India&#xA;by foreigners is known to her children as Bhārata Varsha. Now, it is&#xA;enjoined on every Hindu when he becomes old, to give up all worldly&#xA;pursuits — to leave the cares of the world, its wealth, happiness, and&#xA;enjoyments to his son — and retire into the forest, there to meditate&#xA;upon the Self which is the only reality in him, and thus break the bonds&#xA;which bind him to life. King or priest, peasant or servant, man or&#xA;woman, none is exempt from this duty: for all the duties of the&#xA;householder — of the son, the brother, the husband, the father, the&#xA;wife, the daughter, the mother, the sister — are but preparations&#xA;towards that one stage, when all the bonds which bind the soul to matter&#xA;are severed asunder for ever.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>181 THE STORY OF PRAHLADA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/181_the_story_of_prahlada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/181_the_story_of_prahlada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-story-of-prahlada&#34;&gt;THE STORY OF PRAHLADA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in California&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hiranyakashipu was the king of the Daityas. The Daityas, though born of&#xA;the same parentage as the Devas or gods, were always, at war with the&#xA;latter. The Daityas had no part in the oblations and offerings of&#xA;mankind, or in the government of the world and its guidance. But&#xA;sometimes they waxed strong and drove all the Devas from the heaven, and&#xA;seized the throne of the gods and ruled for a time. Then the Devas&#xA;prayed to Vishnu, the Omnipresent Lord of the universe, and He helped&#xA;them out of their difficulty. The Daityas were driven out, and once more&#xA;the gods reigned. Hiranyakashipu, king of the Daityas, in his turn,&#xA;succeeded in conquering his cousins, the Devas, and seated himself on&#xA;the throne of the heavens and ruled the three worlds — the middle world,&#xA;inhabited by men and animals; the heavens, inhabited by gods and godlike&#xA;beings; and the nether world, inhabited by the Daityas. Now,&#xA;Hiranyakashipu declared himself to be the God of the whole universe and&#xA;proclaimed that there was no other God but himself, and strictly&#xA;enjoined that the Omnipotent Vishnu should have no worship offered to&#xA;Him anywhere; and that all the worship should henceforth be given to&#xA;himself only.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>182 THE GREAT TEACHERS OF THE WORLD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/182_the_great_teachers_of_the_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/182_the_great_teachers_of_the_world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-great-teachers-of-the-world&#34;&gt;THE GREAT TEACHERS OF THE WORLD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at the Shakespeare Club, Pasadena, California, February 3,&#xA;1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The universe, according to the theory of the Hindus, is moving in cycles&#xA;of wave forms. It rises, reaches its zenith, then falls and remains in&#xA;the hollow, as it were, for some time, once more to rise, and so on, in&#xA;wave after wave and fall after fall. What is true of the universe is&#xA;true of every part of it. The march of human affairs is like that. The&#xA;history of nations is like that: they rise and they fall; after the rise&#xA;comes a fall, again out of the fall comes a rise, with greater power.&#xA;This motion is always going on. In the religious world the same movement&#xA;exists. In every nation&amp;rsquo;s spiritual life, there is a fall as well as a&#xA;rise. The nation goes down, and everything seems to go to pieces. Then,&#xA;again, it gains strength, rises; a huge wave comes, sometimes a tidal&#xA;wave — and always on the topmost crest of the wave is a shining soul,&#xA;the Messenger. Creator and created by turns, he is the impetus that&#xA;makes the wave rise, the nation rise: at the same time, he is created by&#xA;the same forces which make the wave, acting and interacting by turns. He&#xA;puts forth his tremendous power upon society; and society makes him what&#xA;he is. These are the great world-thinkers. These are the Prophets of the&#xA;world, the Messengers of life, the Incarnations of God.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>183 ON LORD BUDDHA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/183_on_lord_buddha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/183_on_lord_buddha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-lord-buddha&#34;&gt;ON LORD BUDDHA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered in Detroit&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In every religion we find one type of self-devotion particularly&#xA;developed. The type of working without a motive is most highly developed&#xA;in Buddhism. Do not mistake Buddhism and Brāhminism. In this country you&#xA;are very apt to do so. Buddhism is one of our sects. It was founded by a&#xA;great man called Gautama, who became disgusted at the eternal&#xA;metaphysical discussions of his day, and the cumbrous rituals, and more&#xA;especially with the caste system. Some people say that we are born to a&#xA;certain state, and therefore we are superior to others who are not thus&#xA;born. He was also against the tremendous priestcraft. He preached a&#xA;religion in which there was no motive power, and was perfectly agnostic&#xA;about metaphysics or theories about God. He was often asked if there was&#xA;a God, and he answered, he did not know. When asked about right conduct,&#xA;he would reply, &amp;ldquo;Do good and be good.&amp;rdquo; There came five Brāhmins, who&#xA;asked him to settle their discussion. One said, &amp;ldquo;Sir, my book says that&#xA;God is such and such, and that this is the way to come to God.&amp;rdquo; Another&#xA;said, &amp;ldquo;That is wrong, for my book says such and such, and this is the&#xA;way to come to God&amp;rdquo;; and so the others. He listened calmly to all of&#xA;them, and then asked them one by one, &amp;ldquo;Does any one of your books say&#xA;that God becomes angry, that He ever injures anyone, that He is impure?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;No, Sir, they all teach that God is pure and good.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Then, my friends,&#xA;why do you not become pure and good first, that you may know what God&#xA;is?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>184 CHRIST, THE MESSENGER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/184_christ_the_messenger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/184_christ_the_messenger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;christ-the-messenger&#34;&gt;CHRIST, THE MESSENGER&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at Los Angeles, California, 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The wave rises on the ocean, and there is a hollow. Again another wave&#xA;rises, perhaps bigger than the former, to fall down again, similarly,&#xA;again to rise — driving onward. In the march of events, we notice the&#xA;rise and fall, and we generally look towards the rise, forgetting the&#xA;fall. But both are necessary, and both are great. This is the nature of&#xA;the universe. Whether in the world of our thoughts, the world of our&#xA;relations in society, or in our spiritual affairs, the same movement of&#xA;succession, of rises and falls, is going on. Hence great predominances&#xA;in the march of events, the liberal ideals, are marshalled ahead, to&#xA;sink down, to digest, as it were, to ruminate over the past — to adjust,&#xA;to conserve, to gather strength once more for a rise and a bigger rise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>185 MY MASTER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/185_my_master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/185_my_master/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-master&#34;&gt;MY MASTER&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Two lectures delivered in New York and England in 1896 were combined&#xA;subsequently under the present heading.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Whenever virtue subsides and vice prevails, I come down to help&#xA;mankind,&amp;rdquo; declares Krishna, in the Bhagavad-Gitā. Whenever this world of&#xA;ours, on account of growth, on account of added circumstances, requires&#xA;a new adjustment, a wave of power comes; and as a man is acting on two&#xA;planes, the spiritual and the material, waves of adjustment come on both&#xA;planes. On the one side, of the adjustment on the material plane, Europe&#xA;has mainly been the basis during modern times; and of the adjustment on&#xA;the other, the spiritual plane, Asia has been the basis throughout the&#xA;history of the world. Today, man requires one more adjustment on the&#xA;spiritual plane; today when material ideas are at the height of their&#xA;glory and power, today when man is likely to forget his divine nature,&#xA;through his growing dependence on matter, and is likely to be reduced to&#xA;a mere money-making machine, an adjustment is necessary; the voice has&#xA;spoken, and the power is coming to drive away the clouds of gathering&#xA;materialism. The power has been set in motion which, at no distant date,&#xA;will bring unto mankind once more the memory of its real nature; and&#xA;again the place from which this power will start will be Asia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>186 INDIAN RELIGIOUS THOUGHT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/186_indian_religious_thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/186_indian_religious_thought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;indian-religious-thought&#34;&gt;INDIAN RELIGIOUS THOUGHT&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered under the auspices of the Brooklyn Ethical Society, in the&#xA;Art Gallery of the Pouch Mansion, Clinton Avenue, Brooklyn, U.S.A.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;India, although only half the size of the United States, contains a&#xA;population of over two hundred and ninety millions, and there are three&#xA;religions which hold sway over them — the Mohammedan, the Buddhist&#xA;(including the Jain), and the Hindu. The adherents of the first&#xA;mentioned number about sixty millions, of the second about nine&#xA;millions, while the last embrace nearly two hundred and six millions.&#xA;The cardinal features of the Hindu religion are founded on the&#xA;meditative and speculative philosophy and on the ethical teachings&#xA;contained in the various books of the Vedas, which assert that the&#xA;universe is infinite in space and eternal in duration. It never had a&#xA;beginning, and it never will have an end. Innumerable have been the&#xA;manifestations of the power of the spirit in the realm of matter, of the&#xA;force of the Infinite in the domain of the finite; but the Infinite&#xA;Spirit Itself is self-existent, eternal, and unchangeable. The passage&#xA;of time makes no mark whatever on the dial of eternity. In its&#xA;supersensuous region which cannot be comprehended at all by the human&#xA;understanding, there is no past, and there is no future. The Vedas teach&#xA;that the soul of man is immortal. The body is subject to the law of&#xA;growth and decay, what grows must of necessity decay. But the in&#xA;dwelling spirit is related to the infinite and eternal life; it never&#xA;had a beginning and it never will have an end, One of the chief&#xA;distinctions between the Hindu and the Christian religions is that the&#xA;Christian religion teaches that each human soul had its beginning at its&#xA;birth into this world, whereas the Hindu religion asserts that the&#xA;spirit of man is an emanation of the Eternal Being, and had no more a&#xA;beginning than God Himself. Innumerable have been and will be its&#xA;manifestations in its passage from one personality to another, subject&#xA;to the great law of spiritual evolution, until it reaches perfection,&#xA;when there is no more change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>187 THE BASIS FOR PSYCHIC OR SPIRITUAL RESEARCH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/187_the_basis_for_psychic_or_spiritual_research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/187_the_basis_for_psychic_or_spiritual_research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-basis-for-psychic-or-spiritual-research&#34;&gt;THE BASIS FOR PSYCHIC OR SPIRITUAL RESEARCH&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was not often that Swami Vivekananda, while in the West, took part in&#xA;debates. One such occasion in London when he did so was during the&#xA;discussion of a lecture on, &amp;ldquo;Can Psychic Phenomena be proved from a&#xA;Scientific Basis?&amp;rdquo; Referring first to a remark which he had heard in the&#xA;course of this debate, not for the first time in the West, he said:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>188 ON ART IN INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/188_on_art_in_india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/188_on_art_in_india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-art-in-india&#34;&gt;ON ART IN INDIA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Arts and Sciences in India&amp;rdquo; was the topic under which the Swami&#xA;Vivekananda was introduced to the audience at Wendte Hall, San&#xA;Francisco. The Swami held the attention of his hearers throughout as was&#xA;demonstrated by the many questions which were put to him after his&#xA;address.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Swami said in part:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the history of nations, the government at the beginning has always&#xA;been in the hands of the priests. All the learning also has proceeded&#xA;from the priests. Then, after the priests, the government changes hands,&#xA;and the Kshatriya or the kingly power prevails, and the military rule is&#xA;triumphant. This has always been true. And last comes the grasp of&#xA;luxury, and the people sink down under it to be dominated by stronger&#xA;and more barbarous races.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>189 IS INDIA A BENIGHTED COUNTRY?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/189_is_india_a_benighted_country/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/189_is_india_a_benighted_country/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-india-a-benighted-country&#34;&gt;IS INDIA A BENIGHTED COUNTRY?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following is a report of a lecture at Detroit, United States,&#xA;America, with the editorial comments of the &lt;em&gt;Boston Evening Transcript&lt;/em&gt;,&#xA;5th April, 1894:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Swami Vivekananda has been in Detroit recently and made a proofed&#xA;impression there. All classes flocked to hear him, and professional men&#xA;in particular were greatly interested in his logic and his soundness of&#xA;thought. The opera-house alone was large enough for his audience. He&#xA;speaks English extremely well, and he is as handsome as he is good. The&#xA;Detroit newspapers have devoted much space to the reports of his&#xA;lectures. An editorial in the &lt;em&gt;Detroit Evening News&lt;/em&gt; says: Most people&#xA;will be inclined to think that Swami Vivekananda did better last night&#xA;in his opera-house lecture than he did in any of his former lectures in&#xA;this city. The merit of the Hindu&amp;rsquo;s utterances last night lay in their&#xA;clearness. He drew a very sharp line of distinction between Christianity&#xA;and Christianity, and told his audience plainly wherein he himself is a&#xA;Christian in one sense and not a Christian in another sense. He also&#xA;drew a sharp line between Hinduism and Hinduism, carrying the&#xA;implication that he desired to be classed as a Hindu only in its better&#xA;sense. Swami Vivekananda stands superior to all criticism when he says,&#xA;&amp;ldquo;We want missionaries of Christ. Let such come to India by the hundreds&#xA;and thousands. Bring Christ&amp;rsquo;s life to us and let it permeate the very&#xA;core of society. Let him be preached in every village and corner of&#xA;India.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>190 THE CLAIMS OF RELIGION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/190_the_claims_of_religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/190_the_claims_of_religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-claims-of-religion&#34;&gt;THE CLAIMS OF RELIGION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Sunday, 5th January&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Portions of this lecture were published in &lt;a href=&#34;../../volume_3/lectures_and_discourses/unity_the_goal_of_religion.htm&#34;&gt;Vol.&#xA;III&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;The published portions are reproduced here in small type. The year of&#xA;the lecture is not known.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many of you remember the thrill of joy with which in your childhood you&#xA;saw the glorious rising sun; all of you, sometimes in your life, stand&#xA;and gaze upon the glorious setting sun, and at least in imagination, try&#xA;to pierce through the beyond. This, in fact, is at the bottom of the&#xA;whole universe — this rising from and this setting into the beyond, this&#xA;whole universe coming up out of the unknown, and going back again into&#xA;the unknown, crawling in as a child out of darkness, and crawling out&#xA;again as an old man into darkness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>191 CONCENTRATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/191_concentration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/191_concentration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;concentration&#34;&gt;CONCENTRATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at the Washington Hall, San Francisco, on March 16, 1900&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[This and the following two lectures (&lt;a href=&#34;meditation.htm&#34;&gt;Meditation&lt;/a&gt; and&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;the_practice_of_religion.htm&#34;&gt;The Practice of Religion&lt;/a&gt;) are reproduced&#xA;here from the &lt;em&gt;Vedanta and the West&lt;/em&gt; with the kind permission of the&#xA;Vedanta Society of Southern California, by whom is reserved the&#xA;copyright for America. The lectures were recorded by Ida Ansell under&#xA;circumstances which she herself relates thus:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Swami Vivekananda&amp;rsquo;s second trip to the West occurred in 1899-1900.&#xA;During the first half of 1900 he worked in and around San Francisco,&#xA;California. I was a resident of that city, twenty-two years old at the&#xA;time. &amp;hellip; I heard him lecture perhaps a score of times from March to May&#xA;of 1900, and recorded seventeen of his talks. …&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>192 MEDITATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/192_meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/192_meditation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;meditation&#34;&gt;MEDITATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at the Washington Hall, San Francisco, April 3,&#xA;1900&lt;a href=&#34;concentration.htm&#34;&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meditation has been laid stress upon by all religions. The meditative&#xA;state of mind is declared by the Yogis to be the highest state in which&#xA;the mind exists. When the mind is studying the external object, it gets&#xA;identified with it, loses itself. To use the simile of the old Indian&#xA;philosopher: the soul of man is like a piece of crystal, but it takes&#xA;the colour of whatever is near it. Whatever the soul touches &amp;hellip; it has&#xA;to take its colour. That is the difficulty. That constitutes the&#xA;bondage. The colour is so strong, the crystal forgets itself and&#xA;identifies itself with the colour. Suppose a red flower is near the&#xA;crystal and the crystal takes the colour and forgets itself, thinks it&#xA;is red. We have taken the colour of the body and have forgotten what we&#xA;are. All the difficulties that follow come from that one dead body. All&#xA;our fears, all worries, anxieties, troubles, mistakes, weakness, evil,&#xA;are front that one great blunder — that we are bodies. This is the&#xA;ordinary person. It is the person taking the colour of the flower near&#xA;to it. We are no more bodies than the crystal is the red flower.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>193 THE PRACTICE OF RELIGION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/193_the_practice_of_religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/lectures_and_discourses/193_the_practice_of_religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-practice-of-religion&#34;&gt;THE PRACTICE OF RELIGION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Delivered at Alameda, California, on April 18,&#xA;1900&lt;a href=&#34;concentration.htm&#34;&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We read many books, many scriptures. We get various ideas from our&#xA;childhood, and change them every now and then. We understand what is&#xA;meant by theoretical religion. We think we understand what is meant by&#xA;practical religion. Now I am going to present to you my idea of&#xA;practical religion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We hear all around us about practical religion, and analysing all that,&#xA;we find that it can be brought down to one conception — charity to our&#xA;fellow beings. Is that all of religion? Every day we hear in this&#xA;country about practical Christianity — that a man has done some good to&#xA;his fellow beings. Is that all?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
