<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Life of Barrister Savarkar on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Life of Barrister Savarkar on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Preface</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/01_Preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/01_Preface/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Memories of those momentous years and trying days rise in a flood and struggling to find a vent keep knocking at the gates of our heart. How we wish we could have spoken of them all and recited our reminiscences, but our lips must be sealed. How we long to write of it all&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thus wrote Veer V.D. Savarkar contributing a tribute to V.V.S. Aiyer after his sudden and sad demise to Maratha in 1925. The political situation was the same when “Life of Barrister Savarkar” by Chitragupta was published a year later in December 1926. Though many a detail is wanting, it is the first biography of Veer Savarkar in English. It covers the period of Savarkar&amp;rsquo;s life up to 30th January, 1911, when he was sentenced to second Transportation for life. After hearing the sentence, Savarkar rose and declared: “I am prepared to face ungrudgingly the extreme penalty of your laws in the belief that our Motherland can march on an assured if not a speedy triumph”. The &amp;ldquo;Life‟ deals with the formative years of the work of the Revolutionary on the European soil. Prof. S.G. Malshe owes our gratitude for making available a rare copy of the Life‟, which is now moreover extinct, to Shri Balarao Savarkar for bringing out this edition. Veer Savarkar&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Londonchin Batamipatre‟ (News letters from London) and &amp;ldquo;Shatruchya Shibirat‟ (in the Enemy Camps) contribute the most reliable and valuable sources material for the period. &amp;ldquo;Daryapar‟ (Beyond the seas) and V.V.S. Aiyer &amp;ldquo;provide us with new material of great importance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 CHILDHOOD AND EARLY YOUTH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/02_CHILDHOOD_AND_EARLY_YOUTH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/02_CHILDHOOD_AND_EARLY_YOUTH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Oh hush thee my baby the time soon will come When thy sleep shall be broken by trumpet and drum Then hush thee, my darling, take rest while you may For strife comes with manhood and waking with day”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Scott.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shrijut Damodarpant Savarkar, the father of the distinguished patriot whose life we mean to sketch here was a cultured gentleman, belonging to the chitpavan section of the Maratha Brahmins. It is this section that has long been the eyesore of the English Imperialists of Curzon type for the peculiar guilt that attaches to it of producing men in an unbroken succession for the last two hundred years to so who ever constituted the vanguard of the Indian forces in the struggle of Indian freedom. The first Peshwa Balaji Vishwanath, was a chitpavan. Bajirao, who was one of the foremost generals India ever produced, was a chitpavan; the hero of Panipat was a chitpavan; Nana Fadnavis the great Indian Statesman, Nana saheb who rose in the National rising of 1857, Vasudeo Balwant who revolted against the British Government and aimed to achieve Indian Independence, the Chaphekar brothers and Ranade who were hanged as murderers for killing the British officers responsible for the Plague administration in Poona, were all chitpavans. Shrijut Gokhale, Justice Ranade and the Great Tilak all these were chitpavans. No wonder then that destiny should have chosen this particular caste to bring forth and nestle the child which was to be, to quote Valentine Chirol, one of the most brilliant of modern Indian revolutionalists. For it was amongst these chitpavans that Vinayakrao Savarkar was born in 1883 A.D. Damodarpant had three sons; Ganesh was the eldest, Vinayak was his second son and Narayana was the youngest of the three. These three together were to form the famous &amp;ldquo;Savarkar Brothers,‟ whose activities and suffering continue to exercise such fascinating an influence on the minds of Indian youths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 WORK IN THE COLLEGE DAYS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/03_WORK_IN_THE_COLLEGE_DAYS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/03_WORK_IN_THE_COLLEGE_DAYS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Hero is not fed on sweets Daily his own heart he eats”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-Emerson&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1901 Vinayak passed his entrance examination In spite of his political preoccupations he never neglected his studies nor allowed his comrades to do that. So throughout his educational career he never failed. A large party arranged by the society and attended by several leading men of the city gave him a hearty send off on the eve of his leaving Nashik for Poona. When he meant to enter the Ferguson College, Vinayak significantly observed &amp;ldquo;we had up till now to confine our activities to the Nashik District alone. But now I have decided to utilize this opportunity of my entering the Ferguson College at Poona to further our cause and to spread our mission throughout Maharashtra. For, there I can find grouped together many of the rising youths who later on would be the leaders of public thought and action. If I could mould their minds and inspire them all with our principles then when they back to their different districts and towns, they would carry with them the torch that would perhaps set all Maharashtra a flame. In the small residency of the Ferguson College I shall be able to sound the heart of Maharashtra at a touch, to mould the province at a stroke. These are my hopes; at least I mean to try my best to accomplish it - whatever the results be.‟&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 PROPAGANDA IN ENGLAND</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/04_PROPAGANDA_IN_ENGLAND/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/04_PROPAGANDA_IN_ENGLAND/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Resistance to aggression is not only justifiable but imperative. Non-resistance hurts both egoism and altruism”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Herbert Spencer&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even while on board the ship Mr. Savarkar lay not idle though for a man of his tender heart and loving and lovable nature homesickness was bound to weigh heavily on his mind yet in spite of the dear memory of devoted friends and favourites and relations that made him pine and often moved him to tears he immediately opened his patriotic campaign amongst the few Indian students who sailed by the same steamer. A characteristic reminiscence was relate to us by one of them now a distinguished Barrister in Northern India, which will illustrate the inner working of Savarkar&amp;rsquo;s mind this gentleman was then, like Mr. Savarkar himself, a raw youth of some 21 years of age and the only son of his mother. He came off a rich and respectable family. Naturally he was so overpowered by the trying experience of being left alone amidst strangers and the insolent foreigners who generally from the majority of the passengers that return to England by those statements after their stay in the “Dependency”, and physically so weakened by the terrible sea sickness to which he like many an Indian unused for generation to sea voyages fell a victim, that he once actually thought of returning home as soon as the steamer touched the first port of her voyage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 THE STORM GATHERS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/05_THE_STORM_GATHERS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/05_THE_STORM_GATHERS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“When he who adores thee has left But the name of his faults and sorrows behind. Oh say! Wilt thou weep when they darken The fame of a life that for thee was resigned!!”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While the indomitable activities of the Abhinava Bharat became so serious as to be a cause of anxiety to the Scotland Yard which had to extend its scope to France and Germany, to cope with the Indian revolutionist propaganda, India too, lay not idle. The Manicktola case, the campaign of assassinations of Police officers and informers carried on in Bengal, the arrest of the Great Tilak and Paranjpe and several other leaders in Maharashtra, the consequent big anti-British riots in Bombay, all and many other factors made the Indian Government wild with anxiety and rage. The spread of the secret literature of the Abhinava Bharat could not be stopped. Lieut. Governors and Governors for example, that of United Provinces, thought it necessary to personally combat the influence, of the pamphlets such as &amp;ldquo;Oh Martyrs, Grave danger, Choose Oh Indian Princes‟ all of which reported to come from the powerful pen of Mr. Savarkar. Besides this, the Abhinava Bharat conducted fiery papers in Europe, namely, the “Vande Mataram” edited by Madame Cama, the “Talwar,” Mr. Shamji&amp;rsquo;s independently conducted Indian Sociologist-all these found their way to Indian colleges, hostels and clubs and even down to the regimental lines, in spite of the most vigilant watch, proscription and fury of the Indian Government. To make the matters worse Mr. Savarkar issued from time to time pamphlets highly inflammatory, addressed to the Sikhs printed in the Gurumukhi tongue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 THE STORM BURSTS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/06_THE_STORM_BURSTS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/06_THE_STORM_BURSTS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Behold! We enter this sacrificial fire today The first instalment of our debt of love we pay!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Savarkar.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The excessive strain that was taxing the physical capacity of Mr. Savarkar at last broke down his health. He was attacked by high fever which developed into acute bronchitis. His developed friends and followers nursed him more tenderly than a mother would do and ultimately on medical advice removed him to sanatorium under the charge of an efficient Indian Doctor in Wells. There even while he was confined to bed he lay not idle. He began his work on the History of Sikhs and wrote articles for the Talwar and other revolutionist papers. A passage from the opening article of the Talwar is worth quoting here as it throws a flood of light on the revolutionist mentality. “We feel no special love for secret organizations or surprise and secret warfare. We hold that whenever the open preaching and practicing of truth is banned by enthroned violence, then alone secret societies and secret warfare are justified as an inevitable and indispensable means to combat violence by force. Whenever the natural process of national and political evolutions is violently suppressed by the forces of wrong, then revolution must step in as a natural reaction and therefore ought top be welcomed as the only effective instrument to re- enthrone Truth and Right. But otherwise where constitutional means that enable a people to rule themselves as suits their rightful interests best, are within reached as now in the case of England or France or America, there any attempt at secret revolutionary organization and activity and war should be held condemnable and must not be resorted to. As soon as such a peaceful and constitutional path is thrown open to us in our nation that would lead to the destined goal of our people, we would be the first to set our sternly against all secret revolutionary agitation. India must be Independent: how devoutly we wish that we could arrive to that consummation by peaceful and constitutional ways alone. But your violence has rendered it impossible. You rule by bayonets and under these circumstances it is mockery to talk of constitutional agitation where no constitution exists at all. But it would be worse than a mockery, even a crime, to talk of revolution and freest development of a nation. Only because you deny us a gun and we pick a pistol. Only because you deny us light that we gather in darkness to compass means to knock out the fetters that hold our mother down.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 MARSEILLES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/07_MARSEILLES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/07_MARSEILLES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The day when Mr. Savarkar was to be extradited and sail for India to the intense grief and anxiety of his friends and comrades in arms, he received most touching letters from several Indians as well as European gentlemen. In response he wrote the following letter and managed through a private source to send it out to France from his prison on the eve of his extradition in 1910.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Whose heart to by silken ties is knit of friendship sweet, that sweeter grows by far partaking of the Godly sacrament of mother&amp;rsquo;s creed Divine: Oh friends! Farewell! As tender and fresh as the morning dew that wakes the fragrance! Friends, adieu! Adieu!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 AT LAST!</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/08_AT_LAST/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/08_AT_LAST/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Oh blest are the bravest friends Who shall live the day of glory to see! But next dearest blessing that heaven can give Is the pride of thus dying for thee.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thomas Moore&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At last Mr. Savarkar landed back on those native shores for which “he longed and he pined”—but in a very different way. As soon as steamer reached Bombay he was escorted down through rows of drawn swords and cuffed. He was immediately huddled into a motor, then in a train with doors and shutters closed. He was made to get down from the train and, once more in a close motor, driven to a big stone building. There he knew that he was in Nashik in the Police lock-up. He was taken with his hands tied with a rope which was held back by the sergeants and in that condition exposed to the gaze of all passed-by. None but the most trusted and tried sergeants were ordered to watch him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 APPENDIX I</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/09_APPENDIX_I/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/09_APPENDIX_I/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just to let in a ray or two more into the secret chambers of the activities of Abhinava Bharat which must long remain dark and sealed to the outside public for the simple reason, that their disclosure cannot be made by the actors who took part in them under the present political conditions in India, we take the liberty of reproducing two reminiscences as related by two distinguished men who wrote them from personal knowledge. One is from the pen of Mr. Savarkar himself. Only this year he wrote it in the “Maratha” of Poona on the news of the sudden and sad demise of Mr. V.V.S. Aiyer, who went to England as a confirmed moderate, slowly drifted towards revolutionary tenets after he came in contact with Mr. Savarkar and ultimately worked so jealously and so fearlessly in that party that he became the most trusted comrade of Mr. Savarkar and rose to be the Vice-President of the Abhinava Bharat. The Rowlatt Report tells us how he was suspected of being the leader of the Pondicherry branch of that Society and how it was under his guidance that a Shakt Brahman shot the collector of Tuticorin in 1911. The Rowlatt Report calls Mr. Aiyer “The right hand man of Savarkar.” Says the letter to the “Mahratta”:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 APPENDIX II</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/10_APPENDIX_II/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/10_APPENDIX_II/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second reminiscence comes from the fascinating pen of Mr. Asaf Ali, Bar-at-law, and will enable the reader to see Mr. Savarkar as seen by others in London who were more or less in the know.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Darkness and light divide the course of time, and oblivion shares with memory a great part even of our living beings: we slightly remember our felicities, and the smartest strokes of affliction leave but a short smart upon us. Sense endureth no extremities, miseries are slippery, or fall like snow upon us&amp;hellip; To be ignorant of evils to come and forgetful of evils past, is a merciful provision in nature, whereby we digest the mixture of our few and evil days.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 APPENDIX III</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/11_APPENDIX_III/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/11_APPENDIX_III/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few extracts from the Judgment of the Special Tribunal in the case of Mr. Savarkar which resulted in his conviction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“The case for the prosecution is that we have here to deal with certain members of a revolutionary conspiracy existing in Nashik, Bombay, Pen, Poona, Yeola, Aurangabad and other places in the Deccan, the activities of which were directly by the energy of Vinayak Savarkar towards political assassination by means of pistols and explosives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 APPENDIX IV</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/12_APPENDIX_IV/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/life_of_barrister_savarkar_by_chitragupta/12_APPENDIX_IV/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A libellous publication against the Savarkar brothers and how the Capital had to tender an object apology to them for having published the same.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Which the Savarkar brothers well still rotting in the jail and all public efforts to get them released were doggedly being set at naughty by the then authorities, the Capital, a leading Anglo-Indian Journal of Calcutta, came forward to break a lance or two in defence of the authorities. But this chivalrous attempts whether inspired or spontaneous proved a pitiable failure: for the youngest of the Savarkar brothers, Dr. Narayan D. Savarkar, immediately challenged the Capital people to their statements as published in their issue of the 16th of May 1921 and brought them to their toes. The objectionable passage ran thus:-&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
