<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;vembu-shrIdharaH on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/articles/svembu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;vembu-shrIdharaH on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/articles/svembu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting handle on problems</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/articles/svembu/getting-handle-on-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/articles/svembu/getting-handle-on-problems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1265886437116981248&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1265886437116981248&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I perform a lot of thought experiments. They let us ask better questions and deepen our understanding.Here is one: Mentally move to the state of Bihar. Start from zero today, assume no prior know-how and skills, how long would it take to design and build a Boeing 747? If you immediately find yourself thinking about &amp;ldquo;bad education system&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;poor infrastructure&amp;rdquo; and so on, I would remind you to focus on the 747 problem and not lose track of that problem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HindI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/articles/svembu/hindI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/articles/svembu/hindI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/svembu/status/1904012784201072908&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last week I met a smart Odiya entrepreneur (and Zoho customer) hailing from a small village, and he spoke halting English but his Hindi is quite decent. He was forced to use English to speak to me. My speaking halting Hindi mixed with English words would have been easier for us to do business. That is what I am aiming to get to.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Tamil Nadu we learned English to do business globally, because you speak the language of your customer, you don&amp;rsquo;t get to dictate what the customer speaks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical work</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/articles/svembu/mechanical-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/articles/svembu/mechanical-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We need enough self-discipline so we can get things done but not so much that the work becomes so routine and mechanical it doesn&amp;rsquo;t give us any joy. We need just enough structure to keep things sane but not so much that it becomes stifling. How do we achieve that balance? That balance between structure and unstructure is not static, it is a dynamic evolving thing. A product in its very early stages will need very loose structure so we maximize our freedom to explore. As we approach a public release, we need to become much more structured.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mistakes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/articles/svembu/mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/articles/svembu/mistakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we attempt to do anything new - and often when we repeat something we have done before! - it is inevitable that we will make mistakes. I have made plenty in life and I continue to make them. So many that I came up with &amp;ldquo;how to make mistakes&amp;rdquo; and I will infict that now!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, try to make small mistakes and learn bigger lessons from them. That way you make the mistake pay for itself. What is a small mistake? Anyone that doesn&amp;rsquo;t kill you or permanently haunt you is a small mistake. Now it is obvious why I like small mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social media</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/articles/svembu/social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/articles/svembu/social-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: https://threader. app/thread/1351390924136345607)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I want to put the social media abuse in perspective.  I live and work in villages and I visit many villages in Tamil Nadu, particularly very poor areas as part of our school initiative.  I see only love and affection and absolutely no hostility of any kind. I have received enormous outpouring of love via email and via direct messages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have never once received the kind of hate you encounter on media like Twitter. The people who are doing this on Twitter are not causing me damage, but create a distorted image of Tamil Nadu.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whim projects</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/articles/svembu/whim-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/articles/svembu/whim-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One common trap for smart people is &amp;ldquo;I want to do something important&amp;rdquo;. In reality, most world changing things happen not because we planned and anticipated them but because our passionate efforts in seemingly unimportant projects evolved to make those projects important. Nothing I have done in life was started with the aim &amp;ldquo;I want to change the world&amp;rdquo;. I have spent a lot of time in obscure projects out of personal passion - and I never worried if those will lead to fame or fortune, only worried if we could pay the bills.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
