<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/genetics/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/genetics/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chenchus, Lambadis and the L1 haplogroup</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/genetics/articles/MT/2005-12-25_chenchus-lambadis-and-the-l1-haplogroup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/genetics/articles/MT/2005-12-25_chenchus-lambadis-and-the-l1-haplogroup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/12/25/chenchus-lambadis-and-the-l1-haplogroup/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Analysis of some additional data from the Cordaux paper and the earlier works of the group from Vanga reveals further interesting trends in the distribution of the L1 haplogroup, which was seen to be predominant in numerous Tamils-speaking populations, with a peak occurrence in the Tamil Low and middle castes. Not unexpectedly the Kallars, a middle level warrior Tamil caste, has up to 50% L1 markers. L1 haplogroup is also found in the Yadava caste, a group of cowherds from from the Andhra country (the clan of the famous cowherd hero kATaM rAju) show about 19%, Kammas of Andhra 17%, so also the Sinhalese show about 17% of it. These numbers suggest that indeed L1 is probably associated with the spread of the spread of the Megalithic culture through peninsular India. The Tamil cultural revolution, probably marking the first Dravidian “civilization”, spread out northwards actively with a declining gradient of influence. In the south it similarly influence Shri Lanka. As a result of this spread of the Dravidians, who already possessed a certain social standing, the L1 haplogroup bearing males were able to enter the Indo-Aryan caste hierarchy at the middle level and show further upward mobility. The later point is illustrated by the fact that in Brahmins of Tamil Nad, Andhra and Maharashtra (the Konkanastha Brahmins) the L1 haplogroup is seen in 10-13% frequency. Most interestingly, the Saurashtrans who are an immigrant group into Tamil Nad from the Gujarat-Maharastra zone show upto 25% frequency of the L1 marker. This is in fact in contrast to the overall level of L1 in Gujarat being around 10% (Albeit a relatively small sample of 29 males), and in general in Maharashtran upper and middle castes around 10-11%. Thus, despite retaining their unique language of the Indo-Aryan family, the Saurashtrans have acquired a considerable component from the Tamil gene pool (lower bound of 15%). This suggests that even the rather insulated Saurashtrian jAti was genetically porous to a certain degree. Probably the Saurashtran jAti’s tight connection with certain professional guilds strongly preserved its language while letting people in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Socio-genetic stratification of India</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/genetics/articles/MT/2005-12-20_socio-genetic-stratification-of-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/genetics/articles/MT/2005-12-20_socio-genetic-stratification-of-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/12/20/socio-genetic-stratification-of-india/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/1600/caste.png&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/320/caste.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/320/caste.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;A recent paper by Sengupta et al in AJHG caused much excitement in some circles, because it was seen by some as providing evidence that the Indo-Europeans/Aryans may not have invaded India after all. The paper provides a wealth of Y-chromosome haplogroup data with extensive sampling of several Indian communities. The conclusions of the paper itself are a bit confused and it does not do full justice to the data it analyzes. So we decided to reanalyze the data and reach some tentative conclusions. A summary of the analysis is presented in the form of a vector diagram showing the frequencies of individual haplogroups (rows). Redder the box the more frequent is a haplogroup. The 3 main groups&#xA;(columns) are upper castes (brAhmaNas and rAjpUts= u), middle-lower&#xA;castes (Marathas, Mahishyas, Vellalar, Vanniyar, Pallar etc=m), and scheduled or nomadic tribes/castes (Toda, Irula, Konda Reddi, Kota, Santhal, Muria, Kammar etc=l). One thing that strikes you is that there are clear frequency differences of Haplogroups that demarcate these social strata (As was earlier suggested by Cordaux et al).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
