<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Death age consideration</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/articles/death-age-consideration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/articles/death-age-consideration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tressel.xyz/threads/1502786920073498625&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How old will your kids be if you die at 85? Here are 4 bizarre insights that will make you want to work waaaay less:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;inheritance&#34;&gt;Inheritance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I die at 85, my oldest daughter will be 50. We’ll probably be able to leave a decent inheritance. But is that really the best outcome?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not all dollars are created equal If I gave my 90 year old grandma $10,000 there’s nothing she could do with it. As you get older, your ability to “buy experiences” goes to zero. The opposite is true for someone in their 20s. $500 for a guys’ trip can create a lifelong memory. Paying for a gap year can shift a child’s perspective of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>moxy career-advice</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/articles/moxy-career-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/articles/moxy-career-advice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://moxie.org/2013/01/07/career-advice.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Career Advice&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Jan 07, 2013&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To my great surprise, young people now somewhat frequently contact me in order to solicit career advice. They are usually in college or highschool, and want to know what the best next steps are for a career in security or software development.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is, honestly, a really complicated question, mostly because I’m usually concerned that the question itself might be the wrong one to be asking. What I want to say, more often than not, is something along the lines of don’t do it; when I got out of highschool and focused on the answer to that same question, it was very nearly one of the biggest mistakes of my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>n UPSC apttempts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/articles/n_upsc_attempts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/articles/n_upsc_attempts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://theprint.in/features/what-next-for-upsc-negatives-indians-with-wasted-youth-dont-want-to-return-empty-handed/1096546/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘What Next’ for UPSC-negatives? Indians with wasted youth don’t want to return empty-handed&lt;br&gt;&#xA;While the passionate preparatory struggle of India&amp;rsquo;s UPSC aspirants is widely acknowledged, their years after the negative result is spent in quiet solitude, loss of esteem, even shame.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Nootan Sharma&lt;br&gt;&#xA;24 August, 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aspirants outside the Union Public Service Commission (UPSC) on the day of the civil services prelims exam, New Delhi, 5 June 2022 | ANI Photo&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rich life</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/articles/rich-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/articles/rich-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/Molson_Hart/status/1835105022234833278&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Based on my conversations with self-made rich people, these are the greatest things about rich ranked:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sense of accomplishment and confidence financial achievement gives you. We all have tough times. Being able to look back and think “I am great because I did something great” is helpful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People treat you better everywhere. You need to signal various ways, from donations to clothes and watches, but it is real and feels good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
