<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/rags/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/rags/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bollywood boycotts hindus</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/rags/articles/bollywood_boycotts_hindus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/rags/articles/bollywood_boycotts_hindus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1574367258553774080.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thread by @ByRakeshSimha on Thread Reader App – Thread Reader App&#xA;Conversations with a Creative - How Bollywood boycotts Hindus&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A friend in his mid 50s used to be a screenwriter in Bollywood. He was doing very well in terms of the number of movies and ads he was getting. But when he started exposing the Left he was cancelled by Bollywood. The number of jobs he got turned into a trickle. “Producers and directors stopped calling me. I was getting assignments only when there was nobody willing to undertake the script for a particular movie.” Since he was financially sound he managed to absorb the losses. “I was at that stage of my life when there were no large liabilities or responsibilities so I managed without a large income.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brahmin in WSJ 2020</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/rags/articles/brAhmin_wsj_oped/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/rags/articles/brAhmin_wsj_oped/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Reaction to WSJ anti-brahmin op-ed)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I write today on behalf of the Hindu community to express our outrage regarding WSJ’s Op-Ed,titled “Canceling Student Debt Will Be a Brahmin Bailout” (Nov. 29th, 2020) by Mr. Zaid Jilani. It is a telling sign of our times that an Op-Ed lacking erudition and factual accuracy while reinforcing Hinduphobia and stereotypes of Hindus, is part of a newspaper such as the WSJ. The callous usage of the word “Brahmin” amounts to blatant propaganda and a thinly veiled attack on the Hindu community and will promote hatred and animosity towards Hindus in the United States and worldwide.Mr. Jilani pejoratively uses words such as “Brahmin Left” and “Brahmin Bailout” to describe certain policies being considered by the Democratic party, deeming these policies as benefiting the elitist “upper class” of the American society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fake names and films</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/rags/articles/fake-names_and_films/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/rags/articles/fake-names_and_films/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1458720850203398145&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1458720850203398145&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jai Bhim is a propoganda movie based on real events &amp;amp; all real names have been retained in the film; except that of the main villain. The villain whose real name is &amp;ldquo;Anthony Sami&amp;rdquo; has been changed to &amp;ldquo;Gurumoorthy&amp;rdquo; on screen; thus making him a Hindu Vanniyar and making the movieall about caste discrimination. In real life, it was a Christian sub-inspector who framed the victims and tortured them. But in the movie, his name, religion and caste have been changed to falsely portray it as atrocities committed by upper caste Hindus on lower caste.+++(5)+++ Not just that,derogatory language is also used against Brahmins to insinuate that they r a vile untrustworthy community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opindia Fake news</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/rags/articles/opindia_fake_news_examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/rags/articles/opindia_fake_news_examples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We copy the below top-fake-news-lists from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opindia.com/page/2/?s=Lies+spread&#34;&gt;opindia.com&lt;/a&gt;, a news analysis site - just in case that website goes away in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-notable-fakes&#34;&gt;General notable fakes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Breast tax in kerala. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opindia.com/2018/01/the-recurring-myth-of-breast-tax-doesnt-seem-to-die-down-this-time-propagated-by-scroll/&#34;&gt;OP18&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2019&#34;&gt;2019&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opindia.com/2019/09/the-wire-uses-2015-survey-and-laces-it-with-lies-to-say-mental-health-issues-on-the-rise-in-kashmir-post-abrogation-of-article-370/&#34;&gt;The Wire uses 2015 survey and laces it with lies to say mental health issues on the rise in Kashmir post abrogation of Article 370&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The report resorts to a classic propaganda method. It tries to add useless information in order to obfuscate from what the headline claims, that is, mental health deteriorating after the abrogation of Article 370. While the article includes a host of useless information that has nothing to do with the subject, it then uses conjecture and speculation to tie it all together and somehow, assert that Kashmiris are facing mental health issues after the abrogation of Article 370.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tamil movie v-1 women</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/rags/articles/tamil-movie-v1-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/rags/articles/tamil-movie-v1-women/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/zeneraalstuff/status/1884133239788593278&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Tamil movies, perversion around Brahmin women is an old phenomenon. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if people born into the community are involved.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;K Balachander movie Arangetram - orthodox Shastri&amp;rsquo;s daughter becomes a prostitute due to poverty&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;KB again in Apoorva Ragangal - older divorced Brahmin woman starts an affair with much younger man, while her daughter runs away and has an affair with the father&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sila Nerangalil Sila Manithargal - Brahmin college girl is raped. She leaves the house, finds her rapist and becomes friends with him.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sirai - orthodox Shastri&amp;rsquo;s wife is raped by a Christian thug. The Shastri is unable to take it and leaves her. She moves in with her rapist and eventually has a platonic relationship. The rapist is again shown in a positive light towards the end.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Idu Namma Aalu - barbers son pretends to be a Brahmin and moves into a Brahmins house. Falls in love, marries the daughter. He finally gives a lecture to the Brahmin father on being inclusive and open minded&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Setu - stalks and kidnaps a Brahmin girl. She is supposed to fall for the protagonist upon his promise of sex and his disgust for her orthodox tuft-bearing fiancee.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The trajectory is prostitution due to poverty &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; rape as a tool of conquest &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; cheating and impersonation &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; stalking and kidnap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter-files</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/rags/articles/twitter-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/rags/articles/twitter-files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1598822959866683394.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thread: THE TWITTER FILES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What you’re about to read is the first installment in a series, based upon thousands of internal documents obtained by sources at Twitter. The “Twitter Files” tell an incredible story from inside one of the world’s largest and most influential social media platforms. It is a Frankensteinian tale of a human-built mechanism grown out the control of its designer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Twitter in its conception was a brilliant tool for enabling instant mass communication, making a true real-time global conversation possible for the first time. In an early conception, Twitter more than lived up to its mission statement, giving people “the power to create and share ideas and information instantly, without barriers.” As time progressed, however, the company was slowly forced to add those barriers. Some of the first tools for controlling speech were designed to combat the likes of spam and financial fraudsters. Slowly, over time, Twitter staff and executives began to find more and more uses for these tools. Outsiders began petitioning the company to manipulate speech as well: first a little, then more often, then constantly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wikipedia</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/rags/articles/wikipedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/rags/articles/wikipedia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1235098631738281984.html&#34;&gt;TW20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;skewed-control&#34;&gt;Skewed control&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to note that there are many Bengali and Malayali senior editors on Wikipedia who have been editing Wikipedia pages for years. They&amp;rsquo;re staunch Leftists and their job is ensure that Wikipedia doesn&amp;rsquo;t say nice things about non-left personalities and media.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;A gang of about 50 Indian editors are on top of a chain of editors and they have complete control over Wikipedia. The top 50 editors are mostly from IT companies with much free time on their hands and they are on Wiki the whole day. They are on top of a chain of command. A team consists of about 10 editors. A newbie proposes an edit and a chain of command approves it and further edits it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;skewing-techniques&#34;&gt;Skewing techniques&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;How do they vilify pages? Well that&amp;rsquo;s another interesting thing. For personalities, they will highlight their flaws. For example, create a separate section for an unverified allegation levelled against him just by citing a newspaper report. But for others, they would ignore it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;For people who are known to have anti-left views, the attacks get more vicious. They scour the internet for publicly available articles that show you in bad light. Once they get such an article, a new editor will edit and the senior editors will ensure that it sticks to the page.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting how they organise the malicious edits. They will form a team. Usually such teams are formed on secret chat rooms outside of Wikipedia. They will ensure that the edits come from different locations. So it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to figure out that it&amp;rsquo;s a coordinated attack. If seniors from Virginia, Kolkata, Vietnam, Karachi &amp;amp; Mumbai are saying the same thing about an article, then the edit sticks. No matter how much you try, you will not be able to modify it.Everytime new senior editors will come and block you from editing or will reverse the edit&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Examples: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1235098631738281984.html&#34;&gt;TW20&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opindia.com/2020/03/delhi-anti-hindu-riots-wikipedia-bias-edits-dbigxray-investigation/&#34;&gt;OI20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;frustrating-to-change-narrative&#34;&gt;Frustrating to change narrative&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Picture this: You do a lot of research to edit a page on Wikipedia. Backed with data, you edit the article on Wikipedia only to find that it has been reversed the next day. Imagine this happening to you frequently. Day after day. You get frustrated and angry. Right? This is the why new editors have left Wikipedia out of frustration. What is the point of research and editing articles if they get deleted?&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1235098631738281984.html&#34;&gt;TW20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wikipedia has a system where you can &amp;ldquo;Talk&amp;rdquo; to your &amp;ldquo;seniors&amp;rdquo; about why your edits have disappeared. This is where the bullying happens. There are these &amp;ldquo;Talk&amp;rdquo; pages where you can ask why your edits have been deleted. These pages are public and the language is monitored. It is here that the senior editors will bully you by clever usage of words. They&amp;rsquo;ll tell you that your edits were &amp;ldquo;pretty pointless&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;vague&amp;rdquo;.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1235098631738281984.html&#34;&gt;TW20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;corruption&#34;&gt;Corruption&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Here&amp;rsquo;s a payment structure for these Wiki editors in the command chain: 1. Top Editor: 30% (one) 2. Senior editor: 25% 3. Mid editor: 15% 4. Young editor: 10% 5. Agency: 20%.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;1. The top editors make about 5 lakhs every month as &amp;ldquo;consultants&amp;rdquo;. 2. The agencies make about 3 lakh per month. 3. Students are enrolled as interns and may later on become mid-level editors. Wikipedia is a big business opportunity, hence tightly controlled.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
