<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/weapons/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/weapons/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Antiquity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/weapons/articles/MT/antiquity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/weapons/articles/MT/antiquity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have proposed that more popular a weapon with early IEans, the more likely they were to incorporate non-IE words for them: a predominantly oral culture tends to acquire clusters of synonyms for meeting metrical constraints. We see this for bow, arrow &amp;amp; axe. Compare it to organisms with a diversified metabolism acquiring multiple paralogous copies of genes of enzymes catalyzing a similar reaction in slightly different biochemical contexts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bows</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/weapons/articles/MT/bows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/weapons/articles/MT/bows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two englishmen &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/244fplvRAL&#34;&gt;talking&lt;/a&gt; about a crossbow and a longbow. Having not shot in ages I&amp;rsquo;ve totally lost longbow accuracy. But some years ago an acquaintance showed me how to shoot a crossbow. Reasonable accuracy could be gained the next day. Speed vs accuracy might have been a major factor &amp;ndash; I know this first hand having shot from both longbows &amp;amp; crossbow in the past.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is notable that though both chIna-s &amp;amp; Iranians on the respective flanks, &amp;amp; H kingdoms of SE Asia extensively used crossbows. The subcontinental H seem to have used it much less. In fact that picture you posted is the only one I know of from early time. However, the jAmadagnya interpreted as the mahAshara-yantra (mentioned by kauTilya) might have used ballista.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine gun</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/weapons/articles/MT/machine-gun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/weapons/articles/MT/machine-gun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/2005136524745060694&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a technology takes a long time to really meet its potential. This is well illustrated by the machine gun.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The American Gatling invents a primitive version of it and sells it to many countries. The Union side uses it during the American civil war but does not realize its utility.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A little later, the Americans underperform with it in their wars against the First American tribal armies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The British buy it from Gatling and then adopt it for their war against African tribal armies, and show its true military potential for the first time, mowing down charging Zulus and others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
