<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;AUTOBIOGRAPHY DH Chapekar on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;AUTOBIOGRAPHY DH Chapekar on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 PREFACE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/01_PREFACE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/01_PREFACE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-object-in-writing-my-autobiography&#34;&gt;MY OBJECT IN WRITING (MY) AUTOBIOGRAPHY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My countrymen, for a long time I have been actuated by a desire to commit to writing, in the&#xA;form of a treatise, my experiences, good and bad, of life, from the time of my birth. But whenever&#xA;that thought occurred to me, it was accompanied by a consciousness that any incidents, to be&#xA;embodied in a treatise, must be of a singularly marvellous or unprecedented character. In the&#xA;absence of these characteristics, the treatise will be of no interest. For, a consideration of the matter makes it obvious that every being that is born must pass through some good or bad experiences&#xA;before it ceases to exist. If the story of one&amp;rsquo;s life does not contain anything that is not to be found in the lives of the generality of men, if the perusal of one&amp;rsquo;s good or bad career does not arouse in the minds of the people any feeling of pleasure or pain, or, if one&amp;rsquo;s righteous conduct is barren in its effect in inculcating a wholesome moral or in gratifying the public taste, then of what avail is such a treatise ? What is the use of a needless waste of time (in writing it) ?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Grandfather&#39;s guidance</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/02_Grandfathers_guidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/02_Grandfathers_guidance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;determination-of-the-time-of-birth&#34;&gt;DETERMINATION OF THE TIME OF BIRTH&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At 3 ghatikas after sunrise on Friday, partly first and partly second day of the dark half of the&#xA;month of Jyeshtha, hot season dakshinayana, Shak year, 1791, called Shukla, and under the Karka&#xA;Lagna and the Purvashada-nakshatra, Phaladevasharma belonging to the Manushyagan (was&#xA;born).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-family&#34;&gt;MY FAMILY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was born at the village of Chinchwad. My family was rich at the time I was born, but its&#xA;wealth began to vanish as I grew up. This may be ascribed either to my ill-luck or to the&#xA;adverseness of the times. For we daily see great men fall from their high estate and vice versa in the extraordinary transformations effected by&#xA;the Almighty. Why may it not be said, then, that the depressed state to which my family was&#xA;reduced was brought about by the same law of nature ? My grandfather&amp;rsquo;s name was Vinayak, the&#xA;names of my father, myself and my mother being, respectively, Hari, Damodar and Dwarka. My&#xA;grandfather was a great lover of independence. He, therefore, did not accept service, which means&#xA;subjection to others, though he was a man of ability.+++(4)+++ This is the fruit of knowledge. But now-a-days a&#xA;state of subjection is liked by the people to such an extent that he alone is considered a talented&#xA;man who (instead of) devoting his vast knowledge acquired by life long labour in serving the people&#xA;accepts the service (of Government).+++(5)+++ This also must be attributed to the influence of adverse times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Father&#39;s profession</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/03_Fathers_profession/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/03_Fathers_profession/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-due-to-poverty&#34;&gt;ALL DUE TO POVERTY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have already said that the adoption by my father of the profession of Haridas commended&#xA;itself to the approval only of my father and grandfather, but not of any other (member of our family).&#xA;Hence of course it cannot be said that a man will satisfactorily do anything in which he feels no&#xA;interest. Even during my grandfather&amp;rsquo;s lifetime, some of my uncles behaved in a self-willed manner.&#xA;One of them joined a dramatic company, another began to learn to sing, another learnt to play on a&#xA;tambora and another became a vagrant. The saying &amp;quot; Men without money care nothing for one&#xA;another &amp;quot; is not untrue. I am sure that had my grandfather possessed even a small sum of money,&#xA;this dispersion would not have taken place.+++(4)+++ This is quite obvious, (for) if my grandfather had (any)&#xA;money he would not have left his own house and gone to Indore. When one is without money,&#xA;unexpected calamities befall him. Brothers quarrel with him ; relatives and friends keep at a distance&#xA;from him ; he is not honoured by men of position ; nay, he loses credit even with his own wife, that is&#xA;to say, even she insults him, unheard of accusations are levelled at him, and they are believed&#xA;simply because of his extreme poverty.+++(5)+++ These are the consequences of the displeasure of the&#xA;Goddess of wealth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Education</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/04_Education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/04_Education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-took-to-kirtan-as-a-profession&#34;&gt;WE TOOK TO KIRTAN AS A PROFESSION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thus our company being composed only of the members of our family, who were zealous in&#xA;promoting the common interest, was now much admired by the public. It is now about twelve years&#xA;since we adopted the performance of kathas as our permanent profession. Each one of us has now&#xA;become perfectly proficient in the art. Everywhere praises are showered on our musical&#xA;performance and on the excellence of our father&amp;rsquo;s kirtan. Now at last, some people on hearing my&#xA;father&amp;rsquo;s kirtan remember the late Trimbakboa of Nasik. As our profession was not like that of a&#xA;vendor who can sell his goods while permanently residing at any one place, my father&amp;rsquo;s good&#xA;company opened up to me two principal means of acquiring knowledge, namely, a constant hearing&#xA;of kirtans and travelling over the country. A poet has truly said, &amp;quot; By travelling in (different) countries&#xA;a man gains the friendship of scholars, admittance into assemblies, knowledge of scientific books&#xA;and great astuteness.&amp;quot; It is immaterial even if one keeps a stall, provided it be for selling flowers.&#xA;Accordingly, though we followed the profession of performing kirtans as a means of earning our&#xA;livelihood, I derived from it the benefit of hearing&#xA;God&amp;rsquo;s name (recited) and also all the benefits enumerated in the verse quoted above. Travelling&#xA;over the country, hearing bon-mots, witnessing darbars held by great princes, seeing assemblies of&#xA;eminent scholars, visiting holy shrines and deities—these and several other benefits were derived&#xA;by me without any trouble, for which I am greatly indebted to my father and chiefly to the Almighty&#xA;who is the regulator of the universe.+++(5)+++ Compared with all the benefits mentioned above, the ever-&#xA;lasting benefit of knowledge is indeed unique. The idea that true knowledge can be acquired by&#xA;study or by attending a school or by passing two or three examinations is, in my opinion, entirely&#xA;erroneous.+++(5)+++ I have come across the following verse which corroborates the above assertion made by&#xA;me : &amp;quot; Fools remain fools even after studying the sciences.&amp;quot;+++(5)+++ That man is learned indeed who&#xA;performs the various duties prescribed by the Shastras. I have seen hundreds, nay thousands, of&#xA;learned men who, though proficient in more sciences than one, are addicted to evil habits. Of what&#xA;use is their learning ? Fie upon their learning and their study ! That man alone is learned who&#xA;performs the duties laid down in the Shastras.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 Battle prepration</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/05_Battle_prepration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/05_Battle_prepration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-account-of-us-two-brothers&#34;&gt;AN ACCOUNT OF US, TWO BROTHERS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot; A Yogabhrashsta individual takes birth in the house of a holy and wealthy men.&#xA;There he regains the discipline which his mind had undergone in a former existence.&amp;quot;&#xA;In our youth, we two brothers travelled a great deal with our father with the object of&#xA;performing kirtan. In the course of our travels, while we were proceeding by train to Rajpur, a town&#xA;beyond Nagpur, we saw the mountainous region thickly covered with trees through which we had to&#xA;pass. I have still a vivid recollection of the effect which this sight produced on my mind. Just as&#xA;some trivial incident strikes us with wonder at the resuscitation of an object which has long faded&#xA;from our memory, so the sight of that mountainous tract suddenly gave rise in our minds to the&#xA;thought that the place was admirably suited for refuse after the perpetration of terrible deeds. Since&#xA;then we began to meditate upon such terrible deeds. At this time our respective ages were probably&#xA;15 and 12 years. In this wise came about the awakening of our minds. One has some reason for&#xA;entertaining feelings of hatred towards another, but when we try to trace the origin of our hatred towards the English, we fail to recollect any incident in this life&#xA;calculated to arouse it. Hence it may be said that, the origin of the thought which rose up within us&#xA;that the English were our implicable enemies and engrossed our untutored minds in our childhood,&#xA;is to be found in the sacred shloka of the Bhagwatgita quoted above. As I feel ashamed to recall the&#xA;puerile thoughts of our childhood I do not propose to refer to them here except in two instances&#xA;wherein they were realised.+++(4)+++ We knew that physical strength and a sufficiency of men were&#xA;indispensable for overpowering and expelling the powerful brigand and pretender who had entered&#xA;and taken possession of our house. Of the various thoughts of our childhood, these two only which&#xA;were truly momentous survived the destruction that overtook the rest and continued to actuate our&#xA;minds to the last. Recognising the value of a strong physique from our childhood, we two brothers&#xA;exerted ourselves day and night to acquire it. With a view to educate us in Sanskrit, our father&#xA;began to teach us Amar-kosh, Rupavali, Raghu, Kirat and other poems, and considering that the&#xA;medical profession enables one to earn an independent living, he began to instruct us in medical&#xA;science. Whatever progress we made in our studies was confined to our childhood and was&#xA;ascribable to the fear inspired by our father.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 Skirmishes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/06_Skirmishes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/06_Skirmishes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;incident-with-a-missionary&#34;&gt;INCIDENT WITH A MISSIONARY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It happened one day that while our men had assembled at the foot of the Parvati before our&#xA;arrival there, they saw a native missionary accompanied by a friend passing by. One of them had a&#xA;double-barrelled gun in his hand. Taking the men to be pervert, our boys began to jeer at him. But&#xA;they, through fright, took no notice of the jeers and went their way. When we two brothers came&#xA;there afterwards we were informed of the incident, when we censured the boys for what they had&#xA;done and advised them not to embroil themselves with any one without any reason. After giving this&#xA;advice we started to return to the city in batches as usual. We both of us, accompanied by two or&#xA;four boys used to start after all had left. While we were on our way back into the city as usual, we&#xA;saw coming from the opposite direction along the bank of the Parvati tank, the two men who had&#xA;been jeered at by our boys. On catching sight of them, our companions showed us by signs that&#xA;these were the same men. They too recognised our companions, and with a view to pick a quarrel&#xA;with us, seeing that our number was small at the time, demanded of us why we were abusing them.&#xA;Thereupon, although the fault lay primarily with our boys, we took their side thinking that they had&#xA;been (sufficiently) censured in secret and that it would be undignified on our part to remain aloof at&#xA;this time, though our party was in the wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 Staging</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/07_Staging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/07_Staging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-shifted-to-other-places&#34;&gt;WE SHIFTED TO OTHER PLACES&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We then began to consider how to act next. Having thought over the matter, we made up our&#xA;mind to select an open space within the city and to train our boys there. We, therefore, hired the&#xA;open piece&amp;rsquo; of ground belonging to Londhe for Rs. 2 per month, and having placed the image of&#xA;Maruti therein prepared a wrestling ground in front of the image. Here we used to teach the&#xA;following exercises : Wrestling, dandpatta, kathi, lance exercise, high and wide jumping and boxing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 Reformer vs Orthodox camps</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/08_Reformer_vs_Orthodox_camps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/08_Reformer_vs_Orthodox_camps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;congress-and-social-reform-controversy&#34;&gt;CONGRESS AND SOCIAL REFORM CONTROVERSY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile (the time for holding) the National Congress arrived. As it was to be held at Poona&#xA;that year, we were desirous of seeing personally what sort of a revolutionary movement it was.&#xA;Before this, a fierce dispute was going on in the city between the orthodox and the reform parties&#xA;with regard to the Social Conference. We do not approve of the National Congress, much less of the&#xA;Social Conference. But though there is no possibility of any good resulting from the National&#xA;Congress, it does not entail any loss either, except in so far as the expenditure of money is&#xA;concerned. The lakhs of rupees that are spent upon it are lost (to the country), but it has this&#xA;redeeming feature that it has nothing to do with religious matters. We, therefore, do not care if the&#xA;Congress were held even twenty-five times a year. But we cannot view with patience the chandalin&#xA;(i.e., Social Conference) that has been thrust into its bosom by these reformers. This is the principal&#xA;reason why we look upon them as our inveterate enemies. We are aware that as we are not&#xA;independent, now, everybody adopts whatever course he likes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 Quest for Military entry</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/09_Quest_for_Military_entry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/09_Quest_for_Military_entry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-meet-a-maratha-subedar&#34;&gt;I MEET A MARATHA SUBEDAR&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was well acquainted with Kashinath Baneh, the Subhedar Major of the 4th (Infantry)&#xA;Regiment. At my first visit to him he asked me what I had come for. I said to him, &amp;ldquo;I am very fond of&#xA;a military carrer. Can I be enrolled (in your regiment)&amp;rdquo;. Thereupon that man knit his brows, and&#xA;giving an emphatic nasal twang to his voice said to me in the Konkani dialect, &amp;quot; Bhatji Bova, what&#xA;you say is true, but how will you be able to observe the customs of your caste in the regiment ? A&#xA;regiment is not a place for eating sweetmeat balls. Look at my feet, and see how very bronzed they&#xA;have become. This is the way we are required to move about (from place to place) ; we alone can&#xA;do that.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Surveying the landscape</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/10_Surveying_the_landscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/10_Surveying_the_landscape/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-shivaji-celebration&#34;&gt;THE SHIVAJI CELEBRATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just at this time, the first occasion on which the anniversary of Shivaji&amp;rsquo;s birth was to be&#xA;celebrated with festivities approached. My brother and myself do not at all like this festival. Such&#xA;undertakings as involved a great deal of talk highly exasperated us. Besides, some features of the&#xA;festival held in honour of Shivaji are so extravagant that he himself would not have liked them. In the&#xA;first place, he would not at all have approved of the custom of celebrating the anniversary of his&#xA;birth as it was tentamount to placing him on en equal footing with God. For though he was a most&#xA;ambitious man, and this was natural, since he who would expose his life to such dangers would do&#xA;so only for glory, he would not have insisted on being worshipped like God.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Fight the English</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/11_Fight_the_English/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/11_Fight_the_English/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-hatred-of-the-english&#34;&gt;OUR HATRED OF THE ENGLISH&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the meanwhile we again tried to get ourselves enlisted in a regiment, but failed. This was&#xA;the last disappointment suffered by us and we strongly reviled the English as follows : &amp;quot; A system of&#xA;administration so cruel as that of the English cannot, if search be made, be found, in any region of&#xA;this globe. Far better were the tyrannical Yavan kings, who, with sword in hand, actually cut the&#xA;throats of men as if they were so many goats. But the English are perfidious and I positively declare&#xA;that no other people can be found on this earth who are as villainous as they and who like them ruin&#xA;others by a show of kindness. As god has given men different features, so He has endowed them&#xA;with different temperaments. Men&amp;rsquo;s desires necessarily vary according to their temperaments. The&#xA;three principles of sattva (goodness or excellence), raja (passion of foulness) and tama (darkness or&#xA;ignorance) exist in a greater or less proportion in all men and are the cause of the difference&#xA;between their respective bent of mind as manifested in their conduct. If a sovereign were to act in&#xA;opposition to human disposition or inclinations implanted by God, would not that be tantamount to&#xA;ordering an innocent man, on the strength of authority, to do a particular act against his will or, in&#xA;other words, to sentencing him to rigorous imprisonment ? If he be found to entertain any immoral&#xA;desire it would be right to check him. But our request though legal, was refused. Who will call him&#xA;king who exercises such arbitrary powers ? Hitherto there have been many cruel Yavan kings in&#xA;India, but they made no rules for excluding Hindus from particular appointments or for limiting the&#xA;number of those open to them. It is a fact well-known in history that our people have even&#xA;discharged the duties of a premier requiring tact and trust worthiness. It is also possible even now to&#xA;point out the descendants of persons who served in the army and obtained jahgirs by performing&#xA;deeds of valour.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Capture</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/12_Capture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/chapekar_autobio/12_Capture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-write-another-letter&#34;&gt;WE WRITE ANOTHER LETTER&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As they (the English) suspected that the Brahmins alone were responsible for this affair, we&#xA;hit upon a device to transfer their suspicion to the Muhammadans by sending a letter (to the&#xA;newspapers ?) purporting to be signed by a Ghazi. We thought it would be a good thing if the letter&#xA;were written in Hindustani, but as there was no one amongst us who knew the language, we&#xA;decided to send it in English, and just as we had made the editor of the Suryodaya to publish a letter&#xA;in connection with a previous incident, viz., the tarring of the Queen&amp;rsquo;s statue, so we wrote to the&#xA;editor of the Mumbai Vaibhav asking him to send (to the newspaper) a letter in English signed &amp;rsquo; A&#xA;Ghazi&amp;rsquo; who should take upon himself the responsibility for the deed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
