<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Wilson translation on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Wilson translation on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Although it stands</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/01_Although_it_stands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/01_Although_it_stands/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;way-of-the-samurai&#34;&gt;Way of the samurai&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although it stands to reason that a samurai should be mindful of the Way of the Samurai, it would seem that we are all negligent. Consequently, if someone were to ask, “What is the true meaning of the Way of the Samurai?” the person who would be able to answer promptly is rare. This is because it has not been established in one’s mind beforehand. From this, one’s unmindfulness of the Way can be known.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 It is said that</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/02_It_is_said_that/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/02_It_is_said_that/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is said that &lt;strong&gt;much sāke, self-pride and luxury are to be avoided by a samurai&lt;/strong&gt;.+++(5)+++ There is no cause for anxiety when you are unhappy, but when you become a little elated, these three things become dangerous. Look at the human condition. It is unseemly for a person to become prideful and extravagant when things are going well. Therefore, it is better to have some unhappiness while one is still young, for if a person does not experience some bitterness, his disposition will not settle down. A person who becomes fatigued when unhappy is useless.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Lord Naoshige once said</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/03_Lord_Naoshige_once_said/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/03_Lord_Naoshige_once_said/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lord Naoshige once said, “There is nothing felt quite so deeply as giri. There are times when someone like a cousin dies and it is not a matter of shedding tears. But we may hear of someone who lived fifty or a hundred years ago, of whom we know nothing and who has no family ties with us whatsoever, and yet from a sense giri shed tears.”+++(5)+++&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Lord Naoshige was passing by a place called Chiriku, someone said to him, ’ ’In this place there lives a man who is over ninety years old. Since this man is so fortunate, why don’t you stop and see him?” Naoshige heard this and said, “How could anyone be more pitiful than this man? How many of his children and grandchildren do you suppose he has seen fall before his very eyes? Where is the good fortune in that?” It seems that he did not stop to see the man.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 When Nabeshima Tadanao</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/04_When_Nabeshima/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/04_When_Nabeshima/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Nabeshima Tadanao was fifteen years old, a manservant in the kitchen committed some rude act and a foot soldier was about to beat him, but in the end the servant cut the soldier down.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The clan elders deemed the death sentence appropriate, saying that the man had in the first place erred in matters concerning the ranks of men, and that he had also shed the blood of his opponent. Tadanao heard this and said, “Which is worse, to err in matters concerning the ranks of men or to stray from the Way of the Samurai ?” The elders were unable to answer. Then Tadanao said, ”I have read that when the crime itself is unclear, the punishment should be light. Put him in confinement for a while.“&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 When Lord Takanobu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/06_When_Lord_Takanobu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/06_When_Lord_Takanobu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Lord Takanobu was at the Battle of Bungo, a messenger came from the enemy camp bearing sake and food. Takanobu wanted to partake of this quickly, but the men at his side stopped him, saying, “Presents from the enemy are likely to be poisoned. This is not something that a general should eat.” Takanobu heard them out and then said, “Even if it is poisoned, how much of an effect would that have on things? Call the messenger here!” He then broke open the barrel right in front of the messenger, drank three large cups of sake, offered the messenger one too, gave him a reply, and sent him back to his camp.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 Narutomi Hyogo said</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/07_Narutomi_Hyogo_said/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/07_Narutomi_Hyogo_said/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Narutomi Hyogo said, “What is called winning is defeating one’s allies. Defeating one’s allies is defeating oneself, and defeating oneself is vigorously overcoming one’s own body.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“It is as though a man were in the midst of ten thousand allies but not a one were following him. If one hasn’t previously mastered his mind and body, he will not defeat the enemy.” During the Shimabara Rebellion, his armor being still at the encampment, Shugyo Echizen no kami Tanenao participated in the fight dressed only in hakama and haori. It is said that he died in battle in this attire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 On the night of the thirteenth day</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/08_On_the_night_of_the_thirteenth_day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/08_On_the_night_of_the_thirteenth_day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the night of the thirteenth day of the ninth month in the fourth year of Teikyo, there was a group of ten No actors moon-viewing at the house of Nakayama Mosuke, a foot soldier, in Sayanomoto.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Beginning with Naotsuka Kanzaemon they all began to make fun of the foot soldier Araki Kyozaemen because he was so short.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Araki became angry, killed Kanzaemon with his sword, and then began striking at the others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 When Shimomura Shoun</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/09_When_Shimomura_Shoun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/09_When_Shimomura_Shoun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Shimomura Shoun was on service at the castle, Lord Naoshige said, “How wonderful it is that Katsushige is so vigorous and powerful for his age. In wrestling with his peers he even beat those who are older than he is.” Shoun replied, “Even though I’m an old man, I’ll bet I’m best at seated wrestling.” So saying, he jerked up Katsushige and threw him so forcefully that it hurt. He then said, “To be prideful about your strength while your mettle is not yet established is likely to bring you shame in the midst of people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 There was a certain retainer</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/10_There_was_a_certain_retainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/10_There_was_a_certain_retainer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was a certain retainer of Ikeda Shingen’s who started an argument with a man, grappled him to the ground, thrashed him soundly, and trampled on him until his companions ran up and pulled them apart. The elders conferred over this and said, “The man who was trampled should be punished.” Shingen heard this and said, “A fight is something that goes to the finish. A man who forgets the Way of the Samurai and does not use his sword will be forsaken by the gods and Buddhas. As an example to subsequent retainers, both men should be crucified.” The men who had pulled them apart were banished.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 In the “Notes on Martial Laws”</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/11_In_the_Notes_on_Martial_Laws/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/11_In_the_Notes_on_Martial_Laws/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the “Notes on Martial Laws” it is written that: The phrase, ”Win first, fight later, ” can be summed up in the two words, “Win beforehand.” The resourcefulness of times of peace is the military preparation for times of war. With five hundred allies one can defeat an enemy force of ten thousand.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When advancing on the enemy’s castle and then pulling back, do not retreat by the main road, but rather by the side roads.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Late night idle talk</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/12_Late_night_idle_talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/military/hagakure/wilson-translation/12_Late_night_idle_talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a retainer of the Nabeshima clan, one should have the intention of studying our province’s history and traditions, but provincial studies are made light of nowadays. The basic reason for this study is to understand the foundation of our clan, and to know that the clan’s forefathers established its perpetuity by means of their suffering and compassion. The fact that our clan has perpetually continued in an unrivaled manner up to this very day is due to the humanity and martial valor of Master Ryuzoji Iekane, the charity and faith of Master Nabeshima Kiyohisa, and the appearance of Lord Ryuzoji Takanobu and Lord Nabeshima Naoshige and their might.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
