<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Democracy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/articles/MT/democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/articles/MT/democracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1823218056530723073&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;flaws&#34;&gt;Flaws&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I don&amp;rsquo;t have a democracy fetish, I agree that if reasonably operational it at least gives an opportunity for course correction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The pa~nchanetraka confederation has ensured that democracy is fraught with danger for most nations other than its members +++(via &amp;ldquo;revolutions&amp;rdquo;)+++. An exception is Japan, with a large homoethnic population. Those like India with a wider ethnic spectrum are more vulnerable to mlechCha attacks. But it does seem things have changed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Judicial control</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/articles/MT/judicial-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/articles/MT/judicial-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1888641223860138449&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, Americans have been learning that the separation of the judiciary and executive powers is a two-edged sword. In general, we believe that an over-empowered judiciary is bad for a nation, for it typically has less &amp;ldquo;skin in the game,&amp;rdquo; is prone to activism, and is subvertible by inimical interests.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;bukele&#34;&gt;Bukele&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1974872257286623552&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a widespread problem confronting various nations as the global left-liberal forces realized that the best way to achieve their goals in (quasi)-democractic systems is to subvert the judiciary eventually leading to a judicial dictatorship which operates in their favors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Political-orientation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/articles/MT/political-orientation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/articles/MT/political-orientation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1680262562447761408.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Political orientation is something that rises from deep within; as we have noted before, it has a biological basis. There might be some truth to its relationship with polymorphism in odorant receptors.+++(4)+++&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is something like reaching your &amp;ldquo;preferred station&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; an equilibrium. Some people reach that point early in life (that was my case). However, due to environment, others might not immediately do so. The journey to the fixed point might be a gradual spiral or through chaotic fluctuations. Many go through chaos in the 20s/30s but in small number it may take them till their 50s to get to their home. Yet they all converge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proto-constitutions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/articles/MT/proto-constitutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/economics/state-level/government/articles/MT/proto-constitutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1576611291716026368&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One aside: It is important for H history writers when writing their own history to pay careful attention to the development of the unified Arya states of the vaidika age starting from the ones on the steppe to those in northern India. The roots of the H nation lie therein with the way the internal rivalries were handled &amp;amp; the conception of the ever-expanding Arya horizon was developed. The emergence of a new constitution in India in form of the much malign puruShasUkta build off an old IE foundation &amp;amp; the accommodation of the niShada-sthapati-s finally culminating in the grand constitution which is give  via the mouth of the pitAmaha of the kuru-s. The path to this lies in the various discussion in the shruti, such as that discussed in the RT, that give the pramANa for the H state.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
