<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Red velesov on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/animal-husbandry/farms/articles/red-velesov/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Red velesov on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/animal-husbandry/farms/articles/red-velesov/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Big pasture</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/animal-husbandry/farms/articles/red-velesov/big-pasture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/animal-husbandry/farms/articles/red-velesov/big-pasture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Homesteading doesn&amp;rsquo;t really work if you don&amp;rsquo;t go full retard.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You know why so many homesteads fail? It&amp;rsquo;s a really obvious issue, but no one talks about it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem is chickens. More precisely, the &amp;ldquo;start with some chickens&amp;rdquo; approach to homesteading.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DON&amp;rsquo;T start with chickens. Chickens will teach you the wrong lessons. Start with rabbits.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why rabbits and not chickens? Because when you get chickens, you&amp;rsquo;ll likely start buying chicken feed too. This will become your idea of what animal husbandry - and, by extension, homesteading - looks like. Put money in, get food out. Then, you&amp;rsquo;ll start thinking, crunch some numbers, and say &amp;ldquo;Wait a second - this homesteading thing is as expensive as buying food at the supermarket, only you have to work too!&amp;rdquo;. And then you&amp;rsquo;ll likely conclude that it&amp;rsquo;s all a fad, and walk away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Producers transmuters</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/animal-husbandry/farms/articles/red-velesov/producers-transmuters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/animal-husbandry/farms/articles/red-velesov/producers-transmuters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From a self-sufficiency standpoint, livestock can be divided into two categories:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Producers&amp;rdquo; - herbivores like cattle, sheep, goats, geese, rabbits and bees - and&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;transmuters&amp;rdquo; - omnivores like pigs, chickens, ducks, turkeys, pigeons and quail.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A short thread&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ideally, the bulk of a self-sufficient farmer&amp;rsquo;s livestock should be producers, as they convert a renewable resource - pasture - directly into food, saving the farmer a lot of work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Transmuters, on the other hand, require supplemental feed, and producing that feed is work.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;However, transmuters are particularly useful to the self-sufficient farmer&lt;br&gt;&#xA;who has to deal with a common problem - limited space.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Such a farmer can still achieve self-sufficiency by using much of his property to grow calorie-dense crops, to feed his transmuters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
