<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;3 Hindus feel besieged on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;3 Hindus feel besieged on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1980, October–1981, May: Godhra (Gujarat)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1980_October1981_May_Godhra_Gujarat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1980_October1981_May_Godhra_Gujarat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;51% Hindus, 46% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Gujarat: Madhavsingh Solanki, Congress Party, June 1980–August 1985&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A series of communal incidents which occurred over an almost one-year period took place in the city of Godhra (Gujarat). They resulted from a local rivalry between Sindhis (a deprived Hindu group from the Sindh region, which migrated to India after Partition) and Ghanchis (an Other Backward Classes [OBC] Muslim group). The first major incident occurred on 29 October 1980 when two street hawkers (one Sindhi and one Ghanchi Muslim) quarreled over the position of their handcarts. Sindhi and Ghanchi crowds rapidly gathered, each setting fire to shops and houses belonging to the other community. A family of five Sindhis was burned alive. On March 1981, further violence took place when the municipality allowed the Sindhi community to rebuild shops that had been destroyed, while the Muslims were formally denied permission to do the same. Attacks and counter-attacks took place until September. About ten lives were claimed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1980; August 13–14: Moradabad (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1980_August_1314_Moradabad_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1980_August_1314_Moradabad_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Religious composition of the population (as per the 2001 census): 50% Hindus, 49% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: V.P. Singh, Congress Party, June 1980–July 1982&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moradabad (Uttar Pradesh), a then Muslim-majority town, experienced a gruesome riot on August 13, the day of the Muslim festival of Id-ul-Fitr. The rising prosperity of the Muslim population within the brassware industry (because of its exports to the Middle-East) had created deep resentment among Hindu middlemen, particularly those who were refugees from East Pakistan. Tensions had also increased between Valmikis (a sub-caste of Dalits) and Muslims after the kidnapping of a young Dalit girl during a marriage ceremony by four Muslim youths on March 1980. On August 13, eighty thousand Muslims had gathered at the city’s Idgah to offer prayers. A pig disrupted the ceremony, an incident in which the police refused to intervene, leading the Muslims to think that the police had deliberately sent the pig. Stones were thrown and the police reacted by firing indiscriminately, killing several people during their prayers. A riot followed in which 50 persons lost their lives, including young children. The same evening, a Muslim crowd attacked a police station, killing two policemen and setting fire to the building. On August 14, a rumor circulated that the Muslims had attacked an entire police platoon. The Provincial Armed Constabulary (PAC) retaliated by beating ten men to death. A curfew was imposed from August 13 to September 10. Muslims suffered from intimidation by the police and the PAC (which colluded with Hindu goondas). Due to local-police involvement in the violence, paramilitary forces had to be deployed. The local administration proved totally inefficient and irresponsible. The death tally from this riot is still debated, but the Government recognized and paid compensation for 400 deaths. A Muslim group put the death toll at 2,500 while other sources estimated that 1,500 to 2,000 persons had lost their lives in the violence. Further rioting broke out at the end of October, in which 14 persons died. After much hesitation, Prime Minister Indira Gandhi eventually visited the town in October in order to appease the Muslim population. Following the Moradabad riot, violence between the PAC and Muslims also flared up in Allahabad, in August, claiming around ten lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1981; April 30–May 5: Biharsharif (Bihar)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1981_April_30May_5_Biharsharif_Bihar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1981_April_30May_5_Biharsharif_Bihar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;63% Hindus, 37% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Bihar: Jagannath Mishra, Congress (I), June 1980–August 1983&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A serious riot took place in Biharsharif (Bihar), a town that had a forty-eight percent Muslim population at the time. Due to the relatively large presence of Muslims, there are several cemeteries in the town. In early 1981, tensions arose between Muslims and Yadavs (a rising Hindu lower caste) because of a dispute in which Yadavs had attempted to claim land for themselves that was situated in a Muslim cemetery. On January 21, the Muslims realized that the Yadavs had gone ahead with the construction of a Hindu temple on the disputed site. Clashes erupted, but they were rapidly brought under control by the police. On August 30, a dispute between drunken Muslim and Hindu youths in the predominantly Muslim neighborhood of Gangandiwan sparked off a riot. Rumors spread that Muslims had &amp;ldquo;massacred&amp;rdquo; Gangandiwan’s few Hindu families. On May 1, a mob armed with guns and bombs attacked Alinagar - an area which had been exempted from the curfew imposed in other areas. One man and 14 women and children were killed. In the town of Biharsharif alone, twenty persons lost their lives. But the most important events took place in nearby villages such as Gulni where 13 persons, mainly women and children were killed on May 2 by a crowd armed with bombs and rifles. Villagers, mainly Dalits and Yadavs (OBCs), joined the mob, attacking Muslims in a village that had lived in communal harmony for years. Violence in the rural areas continued unabated for three days without any intervention from the police. The Congress state administration reacted slowly; Prime Minister Indira Gandhi had to come to the area on May 4. Calm was restored on May 5. Some reports pointed out that the RSS had taken advantage of the Yadav’s anger over the land dispute to trigger a riot. A local CPI (Communist Party of India) MLA reported that during the riots, RSS activists visited rural areas with loudspeakers, spreading a false rumor that two hundred Yadavs had been killed by Muslims in Biharsharif. The police also proved themselves to be incompetent and partial to the Hindus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1981; July 12–20: Hyderabad (Andhra Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1981_July_1220_Hyderabad_Andhra_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1981_July_1220_Hyderabad_Andhra_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;54% Hindus, 43% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Andhra Pradesh: Tanguturi Anjaiah, Congress Party, October 1980–February 1982&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fresh riots erupted in Hyderabad (Andhra Pradesh) and lasted for eight days. Forty people were killed and three hundred injured. The deaths were not attributed to mob violence but to isolated stabbings perpetrated by goondas in the small lanes of the city.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;***(Saksena, 1990: 191)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1982, February 15–18: Pune and Solapur (Maharashtra)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1982_February_1518_Pune_and_Solapur_Maharashtra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1982_February_1518_Pune_and_Solapur_Maharashtra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PUNE 80% Hindus, 9% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SOLAPUR 76% Hindus, 19% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Maharashtra: Babasaheb Bhosale, Congress Party, January 1982–February 1983&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Communal incidents took place in two cities, Pune and Solapur (Maharashtra), as a result of an aggressive VHP-led campaign that sought to awaken Hindus to the dangers of Islam, after the mass conversions that had been carried out at Meenakshipuram. Frightened Muslims adopted a low profile. On February 16, the VHP organized a procession through Pune, with the support of the Congress administration. It crossed Muslim neighborhoods, damaging Muslim shops and properties along the way. In the working-class town of Solapur, a VHP procession stopped near a mosque and shouted anti-Muslim slogans such as &amp;ldquo;Jalado Jalado Pakistan&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;Burn, Burn Pakistan&amp;rdquo;). Muslims there (not as passive as their coreligionists in Pune) retaliated by burning Hindu shops. Prompt action on the part of the administration brought the situation under control and limited the casualties.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1982; October 22–30: Baroda (Gujarat)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1982_October_2230_Baroda_Gujarat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1982_October_2230_Baroda_Gujarat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Religious composition of the population (as per the 2001 census): 85% Hindus, 11% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Gujarat: Madhavsingh Solanki, Congress Party, June 1980–August 1985&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Violence occurred in the communally sensitive city of Baroda (or Vadodara), Gujarat. Tensions began in September 1981 when nine persons lost their lives in a small-scale riot. From that point on, people lived in constant fear of communal troubles until October 1982 when large clashes eventually broke out. The underlying cause of the riots was the ever-present economic rivalry opposing Muslims and Kahars (a Hindu Scheduled Caste community) within the illicit liquor business. In addition, in 1982, the Hindu festival of Dussehra and the Muslim festival of Muharram (celebrated by Shias) coincided, further antagonizing the two communities. The stabbing death of a youth in the Navapura quarter on October 22 triggered off riots. Hindu and Muslim processions marching in the same street clashed. The police had to open fire and a curfew was imposed. A fresh bout of violence occurred on October 27 when a tazia procession (brandishing miniature mausoleums to celebrate Muharram), passing through a Hindu locality, discovered the dead bodies of two Muslims. Profiting from the social disorder and relying upon their close links with some police officers, Hindu criminal elements from the liquor industry ransacked Muslim shops. The stabbing of a Hindu on October 29 also led to violent police operations in Muslim areas. Engrossed in factional fighting, the Congress state administration proved unable to cope with the situation. Chief Minister M. Solanki did not visit Baroda until November 6, when Prime Minister Indira Gandhi requested him to do so. The violence claimed seven lives and left 55 injured. On December 13, a rumor that the city police commissioner (a man close to the BJP and RSS) had been removed by the state government, in response to pressures from Muslim leaders, sparked off student demonstrations, arson, and shop looting. Twelve persons died.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1982; September 29–October 2: Meerut (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1982_September_29October_2_Meerut_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1982_September_29October_2_Meerut_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Religious composition of the population (as per the 2001 census): 61% Hindus, 36% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: Sripat Mishra, Congress Party, July 1982–August 1984&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following the incidents of 1961, tragic communal riots occurred, once again, in the city of Meerut (Uttar Pradesh).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The atmosphere had become tense since January 1982 when the RSS chief, Balasaheb Deoras , visited the city. In September, Meerut felt the repercussions of the Ekatmata Yagna Yatra. On September 19–21, the VHP organized a meeting in Varanasi (Uttar Pradesh). A training camp was also held in Haridwar (Uttarakhand) in July. VHP volunteers subsequently came to the city of Meerut.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1983; February 18: Nellie (Assam)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1983_February_18_Nellie_Assam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1983_February_18_Nellie_Assam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Religious composition of the population in the district (as per the 2001 census): 48% Hindus, 51% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Assam: no Chief Minister between March 1982 and 27 February 1983&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A massive attack against Muslims took place in Nellie (Assam) in the Nagaon district and in other parts of the state during the February 1983 assembly elections.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The remote and deprived state of Assam is highly diverse and composite, the result of a long history of migration from the neighboring region of West Bengal. During the colonial period, the British encouraged the settlement of Bengali Muslim peasants to cultivate the land. With Partition in 1947 and the creation of Bangladesh (in 1971) - a poor and heavily populated state-Muslim migration to Assam intensified. In a situation where Assamese, tribals, Bengali Hindus, and Bengali Muslims lived side by side, forming a complex mosaic, Bangladeshi Muslim migrants were rapidly designated the scapegoats of a population suffering from its remoteness, its underdevelopment, and its lack of integration into the Indian nation. Agitation against &amp;ldquo;foreigners&amp;rdquo; crystallized around the voting issue: in a democratic system, Assam’s native citizens feared that they might become a minority in their own land.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1983; September 7–9: Hyderabad (Andhra Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1983_September_79_Hyderabad_Andhra_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1983_September_79_Hyderabad_Andhra_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;54% Hindus, 43% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Andhra Pradesh: N. T. Rama Rao, Telugu Desam Party (TDP), January 1983–August 1984&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a period of two days, the city of Hyderabad (Andhra Pradesh) was once again rocked by serious communal violence. The BJP and VHP were responsible for communal agitation in the city on the occasion of the Hindu festival of Ganesh Chaturthi. On September 7, a mentally handicapped Muslim leaving a mosque threw a stone at a Hindu temple. On September 8, a mosque on the premises of the Allwyn Metal Factory was desecrated by laborers from the trade union led by A. Narendra, a BJP MLA. Hindu idols were installed within the mosque and copies of the Quran were thrown into ablution tanks. The MIM (Majlis-e-Itthadul Muslimeen, Muslim party in Hyderabad), supported by other Muslim organizations (the Muslim League, the Tamir-e-Millat, the Jamaat-e-Islami, and the Amarat Millat Islamia) subsequently called for a bandh (general strike) on September 9. Although the Telugu Desam Party (TDP) chief minister, N. T. Rama Rao, did his best to dissuade them, the local Congress(I), eager to recover Muslim support, convinced the MIM leaders to maintain the bandh. The demonstration remained peaceful till MIM volunteers started coercing people to participate. A police officer fired, killing two young Muslims boys. After this event, isolated stabbing incidents began to take place in many sections of the city, but occurrences of mob violence were rare. Individual victims were killed in the narrow lanes of Hyderabad city. The city administration was reluctant to impose a curfew as this would have disturbed the Ganesh festival scheduled for September 10. As a result, the violence claimed 45 lives, according to official figures. Unofficial estimates put the actual death toll at 70 and the number of those injured at more than 200.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1984; July and September: Hyderabad (Andhra Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1984_July_and_September_Hyderabad_Andhra_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1984_July_and_September_Hyderabad_Andhra_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Religious composition of the population (as per the 2001 census): 54% Hindus, 43% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Andhra Pradesh: N.T. Rama Rao, Telugu Desam Party, January 1983–August 1984&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;N. Bhaskara Rao, Congress (I), August 1984–16 September1984&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Communal troubles occurred once again in the city of Hyderabad (Andhra Pradesh), which was becoming more and more sensitive (see chapter 4 in &amp;ldquo;Hindu–Muslim Communal Riots in India II (1986–2011)&amp;rdquo; by Violette Graff and Juliette Galonnier [2012]). On July 22, stones were thrown at a Hindu procession of Kali worshippers in the Muslim - majority area of Moghalpura. One person died in the fracas that followed. On July 29, a group of young men attacked a police station and stabbed passers-by. Riots subsequently erupted in five other parts of the city. Fifteen persons lost their lives. Further rioting took place in September, particularly on September 9 when young men from a Ganesh procession passing through the old city attacked and set fire to Muslim shops. Stabbing incidents took place in retaliation bringing the number of dead to twenty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1984; May 17–18: Bombay and Bhiwandi (Maharashtra)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1984_May_1718_Bombay_and_Bhiwandi_Maharashtra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1984_May_1718_Bombay_and_Bhiwandi_Maharashtra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bombay 67% Hindus, 19% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bhiwandi 44% Hindus, 51% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Maharashtra: Vasantrao Patil, Congress Party, February 1983–June 1985&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Riots raged in Bombay, Bhiwandi, Thane, Kalyan, and Bhayander (Maharashtra). Together, these riots are often referred to as the &amp;ldquo;Bombay–Bhiwandi riots&amp;rdquo;. They left a deep scar on India’s collective memory.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The communal atmosphere had been tense in the region since April 1984, when, for his birthday, the leader of the Shiv Sena (Army of Shiv, Maharashtrian Hindu nationalist organization), Bal Thackeray, decided to form a united Hindu front, called the Hindu Maha Sangh, with several organizations. A meeting of the Maha Sangh was held in Bombay on April 21, during which Thackeray delivered highly inflammatory speeches, referring to the Muslim community as a cancer, which needed to be excised. Vasant Dada Patil, Chief Minister of Maharashtra, paid no attention to the incident. Instead, he allowed the procession to proceed on the festival of Shiv Jayanti - for the first time since 1970 (the procession was banned at that time after having provoked communal riots). On May 13, the Urdu newspaper Akhbar-e-Alam distorted Bal Thackeray’s speech, thus propagating a rumor that he had insulted the Prophet. Muslims organized demonstrations. In response, the Shiv Sena called for a bandh in different areas of Bombay on May 16. Muslims counter reacted on May 17 by hoisting green flags and removing Shiv Sena’s saffron flags. Violence erupted in Bhiwandi and spread to Kalyan, Thane, and Bombay. People from outlying villages attacked the outskirts of Bhiwandi. Armed mobs with kerosene destroyed parts of the city. On May 19, twenty-seven persons, who had taken refuge at the farm of a rich Muslim businessman, were burned alive by a mob of about one thousand people. The police did not intervene. It was not a spontaneous eruption of crowd violence: the murders were perpetrated by well-armed Hindutva activists, hooligans, and goondas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1984; October 31–November 4: Delhi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1984_October_31November_4_Delhi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1984_October_31November_4_Delhi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;81% Hindus, 12% Muslims, 4% Sikhs&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Delhi: none, Delhi was then a Union Territory, not a state&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following the assassination of Prime Minister Indira Gandhi by her Sikh bodyguards, anti - Sikh pogroms occurred in Delhi, claiming 2,733 lives. (For further details, see, «Case Study on the Anti - Sikh Pogrom of October 31 to November 4, 1984, in New Delhi» by Lionel Baixas [2009].) Although this could not be qualified as an episode of Hindu–Muslim violence, this event left its mark on the Muslim community, which feared being targeted in the same manner. During the short period leading up to the December 1984 elections, rabidly pro-Hindu pamphlets were distributed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1985; March 18–25; April 15–29; 1986; July 9–14: Ahmedabad (Gujarat)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1985_March_1825_April_1529_1986_July_914_Ahmedabad_Gujarat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/3_Hindus_feel_besieged/1985_March_1825_April_1529_1986_July_914_Ahmedabad_Gujarat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;81% Hindus, 14% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Gujarat: Madhavsinh Solanki, Congress Party, June 1980–August 1985, Amarsinh Chaudhury, Congress Party, August 1985–December 1989&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A series of communal troubles erupted in the city of Ahmedabad (Gujarat), claiming more than 200 lives. The violence that engulfed Ahmedabad in February was not, at first, of a communal nature: it was linked, rather, to the anti-&amp;ldquo;reservation&amp;rdquo; protests of upper-caste Hindus against the implementation of quotas for the Backward Classes in the public and education sectors. On March 18, disturbances took on a communal cast when Muslim storekeepers refused to close their shops in response to a bandh call. In April, policemen retaliating for the death of a police head-constable helped rioters set fire to Muslim houses. On April 22, the police burned down the office of the newspaper Gujarat Samachar (which had been critical of their activities). Twenty Muslims were killed in shooting by police. The Indira Garib Nagar slum was attacked by an armed upper-caste Hindu mob with the police’s complicity on April 22. The unofficial toll rose to one hundred dead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
