<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/society/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/society/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On the passing of EO</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/society/articles/MT/2021-12-28_on-the-passing-of-e-o-wilson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/society/articles/MT/2021-12-28_on-the-passing-of-e-o-wilson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2021/12/28/on-the-passing-of-e-o-wilson/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the passing of E.O. Wilson&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;influence&#34;&gt;Influence&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;E.O. Wilson, one of the great biologists of the age, has fallen to the noose of the king, the black son of Vivasvān. He lived a long, productive, and eventful life, just 8 years shy of a century. He was a major influence on our scientific development. We learnt of kin and group selection and r- and K-selection from reading his classic tome, “Sociobiology: The New Synthesis” in our youth. The introduction to these concepts of the evolutionary theory kept brewing in our minds, and we kept thinking about the molecular consequences of the same. In the 13th summer of our life, we studied the immunoglobulin domain and the generation of antibody diversity in jawed vertebrates. It was then that first connections clicked into place. We realized that must be general evolutionary parallels between the immunological molecular machinery for self-non-self discrimination and the apparatus relating to kin-nonkin discrimination in social contexts. A few years later, we read John Maynard-Smith’s “Evolutionary Genetics”, which we were lucky to borrow shortly after its publication. By then, we were armed with some agility in calculus; thus, the mathematical framework provided by Maynard Smith allowed us to apprehend some key ideas of the selective process relating to the logistic growth curve and related issues. These also came together with the ideas of Pāṇini/Patañjali on linguistic systems and those of Shannon regarding the relationship between &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2018/12/29/1859-ce-and-beyond-some-reflections/&#34;&gt;entropy in statistical mechanics and linguistic strings&lt;/a&gt;. Finally, one fine evening it all came together, and we realized the foundations of understanding the imprints of the selective processes we first learnt of from Wilson’s book on the information in biological macromolecules. Exploring this story has kept us occupied to this date.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The puruSha and the superorganism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/society/articles/MT/2005-09-16_the-purusha-and-the-superorganism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/society/articles/MT/2005-09-16_the-purusha-and-the-superorganism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/09/16/the-purusha-and-the-superorganism/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;yat puruṣaṃ vyadadhuḥ katidhā vyakalpayan |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;mukhaṃ kimasya kau bāhū kā ūrū pādā ucyete ||&lt;br&gt;&#xA;brāhmaṇo.asya mukhamāsīd bāhū rājanyaḥ kṛtaḥ |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;ūrūtadasya yad vaiśyaḥ padbhyāṃ śūdro ajāyata ||&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently the ecologists Wilson and Hoeldobler claimed that group selection and not kin selection was the major force in the origin of eusociality. Eusociality fascinates us because in many ways it parallels our own societies though we are not eusocial ourselves. So when W and H claimed that eusociality is more likely an outcome by group selection rather than kin selection (as the standard model posits), I was puzzled and wondered what its full implications were. In fact W and H go as far as to suggest that the genetic relatedness seen in ant and bee colonies is a consequence rather than cause of eusociality. They further mused that kin selection may actually be disruptive rather than favorable to the emergence of eusociality because it would result in the formation of kin cliques that would war against other such cliques and reduce cohesion. So eusociality is seen in terms of group selection with all organisms of the eusocial group working as a superorganism and it is the superorganism that propagates itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enemies and their ilk</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/society/articles/MT/2004-08-12_enemies-and-their-ilk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/society/articles/MT/2004-08-12_enemies-and-their-ilk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/08/12/enemies-and-their-ilk/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;saMskR^ita terms for enemies have some interesting social connotations. Below we discuss some of these angles&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;sapatna- a rival or an enemy. In a strict usage related to rivals for the same woman or competing for lordship over the same object. The adjectival derivative sApatna could also mean children sharing only one common parent and thereby potential rivals due to lower gene-sharing that real sibs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;bhrAtR^ivya- a rival. Bears a connection with the word bhrAta, meaning brother. Members of the same brotherhood may have intense competition for lebensraum. Eg. duryodhana and yuddhiShThira&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Animal alliances</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/society/articles/MT/animal-alliances/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/society/articles/MT/animal-alliances/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;unusual&#34;&gt;Unusual&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1847143161824702549&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the plus sides of the otherwise deleterious picture-scrolling on twtr the volume of data it offers on unusual inter-species relationships between normally antagonistic species: cats and dogs; Felis catus and Lynx, chicken and cat; dog and cow etc. It brings to mind something viShNusharman had described in his tales of such unusual alliances overcoming svabhAva-vairam. People have debated if other animals have the same &amp;ldquo;emotions&amp;rdquo; as humans. We believe that these are evidence for them being on the same spectrum of emotions as humans with much overlap among phylogenetically closer organisms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Domestication</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/society/articles/MT/domestication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/general_biology/society/articles/MT/domestication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/2000797715924500571&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;pig-dog-cat&#34;&gt;Pig, dog, cat&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Objectively, a pig is more intelligent than a dog. Maybe a pig is more intelligent than a domestic cat, too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;pig &amp;gt; cat(?) &amp;gt; dog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yet dogs get more attention from humans. One can attribute this to 1. charisma &amp;ndash; probably, most people see dogs as more charismatic than a pig; 2. A dog connects emotionally more to humans than pigs &amp;ndash; they are primarily valued for this rather than just intelligence; 3. They cultivate a codependency with humans, which is definitely more than cats and likely also pigs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
