<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;hindu temples 2 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;hindu temples 2 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 PREFACE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/01_pre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/01_pre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PREFACE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A court order in 1986 threw open for Hindu worship the gates of the temple-turned-mosque at the Rāmajanmabhūmi at Ayodhya. Hindus were overjoyed, and started looking forward to the coming up of a grand Rāma Mandir at the sacred site. But they were counting without the stalwarts of Secularism in the Nehruvian establishment. It was not long before a hysterical cry was heard – “Secularism in danger!”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Marxist-Muslim combine launched a two-pronged campaign. On the one hand, they proclaimed that Muslims had destroyed no Hindu temples except those few which were stinking with hoarded wealth or had become centres of local rebellions, and that Islam as a religion was never involved in iconoclasm. On the other hand, they accused the Hindus of destroying any number of Buddhist, Jain and Animist shrines in the pre-Islamic days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 CHAPTER ONE THE DISPUTE AT SIDHPUR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/02_ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/02_ch1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER ONE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE DISPUTE AT SIDHPUR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Fourth Annual Report of the Minorities’ Commission submitted to the President of India through the Ministry of Home Affairs on April 19, 1983, carries an account of a dispute over the Jāmi‘ Masjid at Sidhpur in the Mehsana District of Gujarat. The account raises some significant questions about certain aspects of Islam as a religion and the character of Muslim rule in medieval India. We have to go to primary source materials in order to find satisfactory answers to these questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 THE STORY OF RUDRAMAHÃLAYA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/03_ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/03_ch2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER TWO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE STORY OF RUDRAMAHĀLAYA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to understand fully the meaning of what was exposed at Sidhpur and the strife it caused, we have to know what the Rudramahālaya was, how it came to be built at Sidhpur and how a Jāmi‘ Masjid was raised on its site and from its debris. The Report of the Minorities’ Commission provides some historical background. So does the Note from the Government of Gujarat. But the information is meagre and leaves a lot to be told. Both of them were dealing with a “communal problem” and were not expected to give a detailed history of Sidhpur, the Rudramahālaya and the Jāmi‘ Masjid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 MUSLIM RESPONSE TO HINDU PROTECTION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/04_ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/04_ch3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER THREE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MUSLIM RESPONSE TO HINDU PROTECTION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The protection provided by Siddharāja JayasiMha to Muslims and their places of worship was continued by his successors in Gujarat. The population of Muslims as well as their places of worship continued to multiply in several cities of Gujarat as is borne out by numerous inscriptions, particularly from Khambat, Junagadh and Prabhas Patan, dated before Gujarat passed under Muslim rule in the aftermath of Ulugh Khān’s invasion in AD 1299.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 CHAPTER FOUR THE MARXIST HISTORIANS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/05_ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/05_ch4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER FOUR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE MARXIST HISTORIANS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What was uncovered at Sidhpur only to be covered up again was verily&#xA;&lt;em&gt;the tip of an iceberg&lt;/em&gt; which remains submerged in hundreds of histories&#xA;written by Muslim historians, in Hindu literary sources which are slowly coming to light, in the accounts of foreign travellers who visited India and the neighbouring lands during medieval and modern times, and above all in the reports of the archaeological surveys carried out in all those countries which had been for long the cradles of Hindu culture. No systematic effort has yet been made by scholars to see the iceberg emerge from the dark depths and tell its own story in a simple and straight-forward manner. Rare is the historian or archaeologist who had related this vandalism to the theology of Islam based on the Qur’ān and the Sunnah of the Prophet. On the contrary, the subject has been politicised by the votaries of Secularism who become hysterical by the very mention of the untold story. Politicians in power have made and are making frantic efforts to suppress every tip of the iceberg which chances to surface in spite, of the conspiracy to keep it out of sight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 CHAPTER FIVE SPREADING THE BIG LIE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/06_ch5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/06_ch5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER FIVE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SPREADING THE BIG LIE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to the Marxist professors “what is really required is an investigation into the theory that both the Dera Keshav Rai temple and the Idgah were built on the site of a Buddhist monastery which appears to have been destroyed.” Thank God, they have suggested it only as a theory; elsewhere in their writings they have not been that cautious. In fact, they have gone out of their way in spreading the Big Lie that the Hindus destroyed many Buddhist and Jain temples and monasteries in the pre-Islamic past. They have never been able to cite more than half-a-dozen instances of dubious veracity. But that has sufficed for providing a vociferous plank in the “progressive” party line. “If the descendants of Godse,” writes the executive editor of a prestigious Marxist monthly, “think that every medieval mosque has been built after demolishing some temple, why should we stop at the medieval period? After all, Hindu kings had also got a large number of Jain and Buddhist temples destroyed. The KrishNa temple at Mathutā rose on the ruins of a Buddhist monastery. There are hundreds of such places (that is, Hindu temples built on the ruins of Buddhist and Jain places of worship) in Karnataka, Rajasthān, Bihār and Uttar Pradesh.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The author of the article did not think it necessary to quote some instances. The proposition, he thought, was self-evident. Herr Goebbles, too, never felt the need of producing any evidence in support of his pronouncements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 CHAPTER SIX THE EPIGRAPHIC EVIDENCE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/07_ch6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/07_ch6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER SIX&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE EPIGRAPHIC EVIDENCE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the history of Central Asia, Heinrich Zimmer writes: “During the sixth and early seventh centuries AD the whole tract was controlled by Turkish rulers, but in the course of the seventh, with increasing strength of the T’ang Emperors, China gained control. Finally, however, under the onslaught of Islam, from the eighth century to the tenth, both Buddhist and Manichaean as well as the Nestorian Christian culture and monuments of the region were destroyed.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 CHAPTER SEVEN THE LITERARY EVIDENCE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/08_ch7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/08_ch7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER SEVEN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE LITERARY EVIDENCE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Islamic literary sources provide far more extensive evidence of temple destruction by the Muslim invaders of India in medieval times. They also cover a larger area, from Sinkiang and Transoxiana in the North to Tamil Nadu in the South, and from the Seistan province of present-day Iran in the West to Assam in the East. As we wade through this evidence, we can visualise how this vast area, which was for long the cradle of Hindu culture, came to be literally littered with the ruins of temples and monasteries belonging to all schools of Sanātana Dharma-Bauddha, Jaina, Śaiva, Śākta, VaishNava and the rest. Archaeological explorations and excavations in modern times have proved unmistakably that most of the mosques, &lt;em&gt;mazārs, ziārats&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;dargāhs&lt;/em&gt; which were built in this area in medieval times, stood on the sites of and were made from the materials of deliberately demolished Hindu monuments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 CHAPTER EIGHT SUMMING UP</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/09_ch8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/09_ch8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER EIGHT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SUMMING UP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Starting with Al-Bilādhurī who wrote in Arabic in the second half of the ninth century, and coming down to Syed Mahmudul Hasan who wrote in English in the fourth decade of the twentieth, we have cited from eighty histories spanning a period of more than twelve hundred years. Our citations mention sixty-one kings, sixty-three military commanders and fourteen sufis who destroyed Hindu temples in one hundred and fifty-four localities, big and small, spread from Khurasan in the West to Tripura in the East, and from Transoxiana in the North to Tamil Nadu in the South, over a period of eleven hundred years. In most cases the destruction of temples was followed by erection of mosques, &lt;em&gt;madrasas&lt;/em&gt; and khānqāhs, etc., on the temple sites and, frequently, with temple materials. Allāh was thanked every time for enabling the iconoclast concerned to render service to the religion of Muhammad by means of this pious performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 CHAPTER NINE THEOLOGY OF MONOTHEISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/10_ch9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/10_ch9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER NINE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THEOLOGY OF MONOTHEISM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The destruction of Hindu temples at the hands of Islamized invaders continued for more than eleven hundred years, from the middle of the seventh century to the end of the eighteenth.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It took place all over the cradle of Hindu culture, from Sinkiang in the North to Tamil Nadu in the South, and from Seistan in the West to Assam in the East.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All along, the iconoclasts remained convinced that they were putting into practice the highest tenets of their religion. They also saw to it that a record was kept of what they prized as a pious performance. The language of the record speaks for itself. It leaves no doubt that they took immense pride in doing what they did.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 CHAPTER TEN THE PRE-ISLAMIC ARABS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/11_ch10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/11_ch10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER TEN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE PRE-ISLAMIC ARABS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Muslim theologians and historians present a pretty dark picture of pre-Islamic Arabia. Its people, we are told, were unrepentant pagans and polytheists unware of the Unity of God and the succession of his Prophets. They believed that Allāh, the one and only True God, stood in need of partners who could mediate between him and his creatures. Worse still, they gave daughters to Allāh while they preferred sons for themselves. They worshipped stones (&lt;em&gt;authān&lt;/em&gt;) and statues (&lt;em&gt;aSnām&lt;/em&gt;) and offered sacrifices to satans. They had had no Prophet (&lt;em&gt;Rasūl&lt;/em&gt;) and possessed no scripture (&lt;em&gt;Kitāb&lt;/em&gt;) of their own. Consequently, they were ignorant of the Last Day (&lt;em&gt;Qiyāmat&lt;/em&gt;), as also of Heaven (&lt;em&gt;Jannat&lt;/em&gt;) and Hell (&lt;em&gt;Jahannam&lt;/em&gt;). They revelled in blood feuds, and buried alive their female infants. Sons married their step-mothers, and the same man two or more uterine sisters. And so on, till the conviction grows on the readers or listeners that the pre-Islamic Arabs were despicable barbarians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 CHAPTER ELEVEN RELIGION OF PAGAN ARABIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/12_ch11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/12_ch11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER ELEVEN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RELIGION OF PAGAN ARABIA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Islamic sources do tell us that the pre-Islamic Arabs were&#xA;&lt;em&gt;mushriks&lt;/em&gt; (polytheists) “addicted” to worshipping numerous idols. But&#xA;they do not inform us as to what those idols symbolized. The Qur’ān&#xA;(2.257, 259; 4.52; 53.19; 71.21) mentions some idols but only to&#xA;denounce them. We reproduce below what Ibn Ishāq writes about them:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“They say that the beginning of stone worship among the sons of Ishmael was when Mecca became too small for them and they wanted more room in the country. Everyone who left the town took with him a stone from the sacred area to do honour to it. Wherever they settled they set it up and walked round it as they went round the Ka‘ba. This led them to worship what stones they pleased and those which made an impression on them. Thus as generations passed they forgot their primitive faith and adopted another religion for that of Abraham and Ishmael. They worshipped idols and adopted the same errors as the peoples before them. Yet they retained and held fast practices going back to the time of Abraham, such as honouring the temple and going round it, the great and little pilgrimage, and the standing on ‘Arafa and Muzdalifa, sacrificing the victims, and the pilgrim cry at the great and little pilgrimage, while introducing elements which had no place in the religion of Abraham. Thus, Kināna and Quraysh used the pilgrim cry: ‘At Thy service, O God, at Thy service! At Thy service, Thou without an associate but the, associate Thou hast. Thou ownest him and what he owns.’ They used to acknowledge his unity in their cry and then include their idols with God, putting the ownership of them in His hand…&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 CHAPTER TWELVE </title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/13_ch12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/13_ch12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER TWELVE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MONOTHEISM SPREADS TO ARABIA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Monotheism had infected the Jews some two millenia before the birth of Muhammad. Moses had sold them into slavery to Jehovah, a demoniacal Spirit masquerading as the one and only God.&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;¹&lt;/a&gt; Many books of the Bible tell the blood-curdling story of what the Jews did to themselves and to the others when goaded by this Gangster. The end result was their own ruination, and their dispersal as slaves and refugees in all directions. Meanwhile, the disease had spread to West Asia, Europe and North Africa in the form of Christianity. It had destroyed the Greco-Roman civilization as well as Germanic paganism, and spread darkness wherever it went. Now it was getting ready to engulf Arabia which had survived so far as an island of sanity in the midst of a surging sea of madness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 CHAPTER THIRTEEN MEANING OF MONOTHEISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/14_ch13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/14_ch13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER THIRTEEN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEANING OF MONOTHEISM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we shall see, the Allāh of the Qur’ān says again and again that he is not revealing anything new but only re-affirming what is already recorded in the earlier scripture, namely, the Bible. He is annoyed with the Jews in particular for their refusal to recognize Muhammad as a prophet when their own prophets were known to have spread the same message received from the same source. Muhammad, too, is pained that his people repudiate him without checking with the Jews and the Christians the truth of what he is proclaiming. Muslim theologians of later ages will deny that Muhammad learnt anything from the Bible. In their eagerness to invest Muhammad with an absolutely original inspiration, they will portray him as an illiterate (&lt;em&gt;ummī&lt;/em&gt;) who could neither read nor write. But we will better believe Allāh and his prophet rather than the latter-day Muslim theologians, and proceed to examine what the Bible says vis-a-vis other people’s gods and places of worship.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 CHAPTER FOURTEEN THE BIBLE APPEARS IN ARABIC</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/15_ch14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/15_ch14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER FOURTEEN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE BIBLE APPEARS IN ARABIC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Qur’ān can, without an exaggeration, be called the Bible in Arabic so far as its dominant theme is concerned. That dominant theme is monotheism with all its implications, of which the most important is iconoclasm. Our judgement is confirmed by the way the pagan Arabs responded to the Qur’ān.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Allah of the Qur’ān announced again and again that he was making his revelations available in the Arabic language so that the Arabs could have a scripture of their own.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The response from the Arabs, however, was far from positive. Biographers of the prophet inform us that the more the pagan Arabs came to know the Qur’ān the more hostile they became to it, till the man through whose mouth it was being conveyed left Mecca in total frustration. The only Arab audience which the Prophet could find was in Yathrib (Medina), the City of the Book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 CHAPTER FIFTEEN MUHAMMAD AND THE MECCANS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/16_ch15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/16_ch15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER FIFTEEN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MUHAMMAD AND THE MECCANS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Prophet had kept his mission concealed for three years after he received the first revelations. The Muslim brotherhood had functioned as a secret society. Ibn Ishāq gives a list of persons who had joined.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; “The advantage of the darkness for the first few years was great. The darkness saved it from being crushed at the outset. Ridicule and contempt could be more easily endured when some hundred persons were involved, than if the Prophet had been compelled to endure them by himself. It saved him, too, from the character of the eccentric sage (such as Waraqa and others had borne), investing him from his first public appearance with that of the leader of a party; it gave the Prophet time to secure over a reasonable number of people that influence which he could exercise to a reasonable degree.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 CHAPTER SIXTEEN THE PROPHET DESTROYS PAGAN TEMPLES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/17_ch16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/17_ch16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER SIXTEEN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE PROPHET DESTROYS PAGAN TEMPLES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Judaism and Christianity had equipped the Prophet of Islam with an exclusive god and a sectarian scripture which declared war on pagan Gods and their places of worship. The Jews and Christians in Arabia, descended from immigrants or native converts, also provided practical demonstration of how to proceed vis-a-vis pagan temples, whenever and wherever these two sects acquired political power, howsoever shortlived.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We do not know what the Christianized Arabs on the borders of the Byzantine Empire did to pagan places of worship; the sources are silent on the subject. It is a safe bet that they must have followed in the footsteps of their mentors in the Empire. Some information, however, is available on what happened in Yemen, the southern province of Arabia. Some years before the birth of Muhammad, Tubba‘, the Himayrite king of Yemen, had converted to Judaism under the influence of two rabbis from Yathrib (Medina). He used state-power for converting his people to the new creed. “Now Ri’ām,” reports Ibn Ishāq, “was one of the temples which they venerated and where they offered sacrifices and received oracles when they were polytheists. The two rabbis told Tubba‘ that it was merely a shayTān which deceived them in this way and they asked to be allowed to deal with it. When the king agreed they commanded a black dog to come out of it and killed it-at least this is what the Yamanites say. Then they destroyed the temple and I am told that its ruins to this day show traces of the blood that was poured over it.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The blood must have been that of the pagans who courted death in defence of the temple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 APPENDIX 1 MUSLIM DYNASTIES IN INDIA’S HISTORY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/18_app1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/18_app1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;APPENDIX 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MUSLIM DYNASTIES IN INDIA’S HISTORY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Muslim dynasties which figure in the history of India are divided, by modern historians of medieval India into two categories - Imperial and Provincial. Dynasties which ruled from Delhi/Agra are called Imperial Dynasties, whatever might have been the extent of their domain or power. On the other hand, dynasties which ruled independently of Delhi/Agra are labelled as Provincial Dynasties, even though some of them overshadowed the contemporary Imperial Dynasties in terms of territory controlled, or power wielded, or both.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 APPENDIX 2 WAS THE KA‘BA A ŠIVA TEMPLE?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/19_app2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/19_app2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;APPENDIX 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WAS THE KA‘BA A ŚIVA TEMPLE?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some years ago I read an article proposing that the Ka‘ba was a Śiva temple before it was converted into a mosque by Prophet Muhammad. The article cited a long hymn in Arabic addressed to Mahādeva who, according to the article, was the presiding deity of the Ka‘ba. The hymn, it was stated, had been composed in the reign of Vikramāditya of Ujjain in the first century BC.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 APPENDIX 3 MEANING OF THE WORD “HINDU”</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/20_app3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/20_app3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;APPENDIX 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEANING OF THE WORD “HINDU”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the present study we have used the expression “Hindu temples” to cover Brahmanical as well as Buddhist Jain, and Sikh temples. This sounds contrary to current usage in the world of scholarship as well as politics. But the history of the word “Hindu” supports our case. It was only in the nineteenth century that Western Indologists and Christian missionaries separated the Buddhists, the Jains, and the Sikhs from the Hindus who, in their turn, were defined as only those subscribing to Brahmanical sects. The missionaries invented another category, the Animists, which they employed in order to separate the tribals from the Hindus of their definition. It will, therefore, be worthwhile to survey the history of the word “Hindu”, and see what it has meant, at what stage, and to whom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 APPENDIX 4 QUESTIONNAIRE FOR THE MARXIST PROFESSORS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/21_app4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/21_app4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;APPENDIX 4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTIONNAIRE FOR THE MARXIST PROFESSORS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We return to the Marxist professors with whom we started.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have cited from eighty histories written by Muslims over a period of more than one thousand years. We have also cited several Islamic inscriptions which confirm what the historians say. The citations show how Hindu temples continued to be destroyed over a vast area and for a long time. We have added no “editorial comments” and given no “communal twist” to the events that took place. All along, we have kept to the actual language used by the Muslim historians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 BIBLIOGRAPHY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/22_bib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/hindu_temples_2/22_bib/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BIBLIOGRAPHY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Agrawala, V.S., &lt;em&gt;Masterpieces of Mathura Sculpture&lt;/em&gt;, Varanasi, 1965.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ahmad, Qeyamuddin (ed.), &lt;em&gt;Patna through the Ages&lt;/em&gt;, New Delhi, 1988.&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Alberuni’s India&lt;/em&gt;, translated by E.C. Sachau, New Delhi Reprint, 1983&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Annual Report of Indian Epigraphy&lt;/em&gt;, 1953-54, 1963-M, 1964-65, 1978-79&#xA;and 1980-81, New Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Archaeological Survey of India&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Annual Report&lt;/em&gt;, 1906-07 and 1911-12, New Delhi Reprint, 1990. Four&#xA;Reports Made During the Years 1862-63-64-65 by Alexander Cunningham, Varanasi Reprint, 1972.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arunachalam, M., &lt;em&gt;The Kalabharas in the Pantiya Country and their impact on the Life and Letters there&lt;/em&gt;, Madras, 1979.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
