<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;02 (B) For Social Uplift on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/02_B_For_Social_Uplift/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;02 (B) For Social Uplift on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/02_B_For_Social_Uplift/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Ch 28 Untouchability - The Curse And The Cure</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/02_B_For_Social_Uplift/01_Ch_28_Untouchability_-_The_Curse_And_The_Cure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/02_B_For_Social_Uplift/01_Ch_28_Untouchability_-_The_Curse_And_The_Cure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Religious perversion at the root – Historic call of the Dharmagurus – Violent approach recoils – Motivated propaganda of Harijan-non-Harijan confrontation – Special privileges for the needy of all castes – The “untouchables” excel many fronts – Work from the heart– Secret of success in Sangh.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AT the root of the malady of “untouchability” lies the belief among the common mass of people that it is part of dharma, and transgressing it would be a grave sin. This religious perversion is the chief reason why this pernicious practice has continued to stick to the popular mind till now in spite of dedicated efforts put in by a host of religious stalwarts and social reformers over centuries. Guru Nanak, Acharya Ramanuja, Basaveshwara, Shankar Dev, Swami Dayananda, Narayana Guru, Gandhiji and Veer Savarkar, to name only a few, have striven their utmost to eradicate this standing blot on Hindu society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Ch 29 Serving The Neglected Brethren</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/02_B_For_Social_Uplift/02_Ch_29_Serving_The_Neglected_Brethren/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/02_B_For_Social_Uplift/02_Ch_29_Serving_The_Neglected_Brethren/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Divisive policy of the British continues – Uplift through devotion to God – Lesson from foreign missionaries – Declare as Hindus in census – Their backwardness due to our lapse – Spirit of Karmayogi in serving– Questions and Answers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WE find a strange phenomenon in the Eastern regions of our country. Our Government regognises the existence of the “Christians” but not of the “Hindus”. The Government has classified all the “non-Christians” as “tribals” as distinct from Hindus.*&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Ch 30 Human Touch, the Great Solvent</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/02_B_For_Social_Uplift/03_Ch_30_Human_Touch_the_Great_Solvent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/02_B_For_Social_Uplift/03_Ch_30_Human_Touch_the_Great_Solvent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(*) Address to Coffee Planters and Industrialists&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tea planters, foreigners &amp;amp; natives, a contrast – Trust inherent goodness – First duty towards the poor – Example of Idinthakarai –“Heart” is important.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WE are assembled here to think out what solid contribution we can make towards the cause of resuscitation of our Dharma and our society, which is, I am sure, dearest and nearest to the hearts of us all. I shall give the example of the tea planters in Assam to make a few points clear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Ch 31 Call To Motherhood</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/02_B_For_Social_Uplift/04_Ch_31_Call_To_Motherhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/02_B_For_Social_Uplift/04_Ch_31_Call_To_Motherhood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Making the home, centre of Samskars – Morning chanting, dress, etc. – Toll of “modernism” – Heroic motherhood – Social aspect – Banish “loneliness” – Literacy campaign, training for employment, and Samskars, to needy sisters– Invoke spirit of Savitri.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OUR mothers have a special responsibility of rearing up the budding generations of our society. Now, what does “rearing up” really imply? Is feeding and clothing the children and sending them to schools, the only thing to be done? On the contrary, the essential aspect is to inculcate in them the right type of samskars such as devotion to duty, spirit of personal endeavour, love of the motherland and readiness for service to society. Our mothers have to attend to this aspect of character formation as their first duty. And for this purpose, they have to be mindful of the many little things, which go to fashion the young minds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 Ch 32 We And Our Students (*)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/02_B_For_Social_Uplift/05_Ch_32_We_And_Our_Students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/golvAlkar/bunch_of_thoughts_golwalkar/04_PART_THREE_-_THE_PATH_TO_GLORY/02_B_For_Social_Uplift/05_Ch_32_We_And_Our_Students/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three classes of people – Essence of education: man-making –Dedication to ideal – Teacher, the pivot – Right home atmosphere – Eschew wrong political leadership – For healthy unions – Role of press and publicity –A thorough reorientation needed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IT does not seem right to regard the students as community different from the rest of the society. The qualities of the people in general manifest in the younger folk, that only due to the immaturity, inexperience and preponderance of emotions in them; such qualities manifest themselves as an uncontrolled outburst. The general lack of training in codes of good behaviour, sense of uncertainty and insecurity in life resulting in a sort of frustration, want of any ideal to strive for and the none-too-edifying example of those who are projected as leaders and guides of the people, the crumbling down of the institution known as “home” are some of the causes contributing to the “ferment”, the disquietude and unbridled behaviour, which we name as indiscipline in the young folk, who constitute our students. One people – Three Faces Our people may be broadly classified into three major divisions: (a) Those who for generations have been ground down by penury, want of education and what is worst, social disabilities. Fortunately the Government has taken up the work of spreading education, at least of the primary stage, and the students from this segment are getting the advantage. These students need careful and loving attention conducive to inculcating good qualities and awakening their dormant abilities, for they have little background of proper bringing up. In a way theirs is a clean slate with the inevitable scratches dug into them by their hard life – deprived of the light of knowledge, of the happiness of wealth and of the sense of being equal partners in the building up of our national life. These are the hope of the future and have to be nurtured with special solicitude.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
