<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>al-jAhiz on hindus</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/articles/al-jAhiz_on_hindus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/articles/al-jAhiz_on_hindus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have already noted that Indians are pre-eminent in astronomy, mathematics (in which they have their own number system) and medicine. They possess extensive medical knowledge and have cures for the most terrible diseases. They create sculptures and paintings with which they adorn alcoves and niches. Chess, the noble game of strategy and cunning, is an Indian invention. Scimitars from Burma are used by them with great skill and dexterity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India new world crops</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/articles/india-new-world-crops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/articles/india-new-world-crops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Peanuts, Chilis, Corn, Cassava, Tomatoes, Potatoes, Guava, Sapota, Sitaphal, Chocolate, Papaya, Pumpkin, Pineapple, Sunflower, Sweet Potatoes, &amp;amp; certain bean varieties like Rajma are all from New World&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;travencore-tapioca&#34;&gt;Travencore Tapioca&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How did a tuber that has roots in Brazil finds its way to Kerala? Apparently, after a great famine hit erstwhile Travancore during the reign of Ayilyam Thirunal Rama Varma (1860 to 1880), the ruler adapted a number of measures to ensure that the people would not have to go through such an ordeal again. Vishakham Thirunal Rama Varma, the King&amp;rsquo;s younger brother, was also a keen botanist and that after a great deal of research it was he who introduced this starchy tuber in Travancore.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
