<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enclosures acts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/enclosures-acts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/enclosures-acts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Common land is owned collectively by a number of persons or by one person with others holding certain traditional rights, such as to allow their livestock to graze upon it, collect firewood, or cut turf for fuel. A person who has a right in or over common land jointly with others is called a commoner.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of the medieval common land of England was lost due to enclosure. In English social and economic history, enclosure was the process that ended traditional rights on common land formerly held in the open field system. Once enclosed, these land uses were restricted to the owner, and the land ceased to be for the use of commoners.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>German invasion genetics</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/german-invasion-genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/german-invasion-genetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1575921667833884672.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s explore the new genetic makeup of modern England and English descendants globally. This paper was in the works for a long time. Many Anglophiles promised it would prove a violent Anglo-Saxon replacement of the Iron Age British, but it does not prove this. It does, however, prove many other aspects of the AS migration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is the paper - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-05247-2&#34;&gt;The Anglo-Saxon migration and the formation of the early English gene pool - Nature&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>low-crime to hooliganism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/low-crime_to_hooliganism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/low-crime_to_hooliganism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UK was a low crime society then, confirmed by people who lived through those yrs on both good &amp;amp; bad (post war rationing). Lee Kuan Yew confirmed same &amp;amp; noted the changes for worse 40 yrs later. See Kynaston &amp;amp; BBC collection of peoples memories of 1950s.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was a different age and a different generation. After six exhausting years of bombings and privation, Londoners in the 1940s took great pride in themselves, were courteous and disciplined. Bomb sites were cleared, with the bricks neatly piled to one side and little make-shift gardens created. Perhaps the most impressive sight I came upon was when I emerged from the tube station at Piccadilly Circus. I found a little table with a pile of newspapers and a box of coins and notes with nobody in attendance. You take your newspaper, toss in your coin or put in your 10-shilling note and take your change. I took a deep breath - this was a truly civilised people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peasant-classes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/peasant-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/peasant-classes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rfhirst/status/1626380093261221889&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Medieval peasantries are often seen as amorphous blobs but in former ages hierarchy touched all levels of society, not just the elite. In Anglo-Saxon England there were (very broadly) three main classes of peasants, from highest to low: Geneatas, Cotsetlan and Geburas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Geneatas, &amp;ldquo;companions&amp;rdquo;, were the aristocrats of the peasantry. They were free from week-work, instead acting as their lord&amp;rsquo;s direct servants by escorting his guests, running for him errands, guarding his stables and so on. It was this class which most often owed militia service.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pirate every vs mogols</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/pirate-every_vs_mogols/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/articles/pirate-every_vs_mogols/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Henry Every may not be as famous as later pirates like Blackbeard or Bartholomew Roberts, but his brief career may have inspired many of them to first take up cutlass and set sail under Jolly Roger. During just two years prowling the seas, Every and his band captured roughly a dozen vessels and made off with tens of millions of dollars in booty. His exploits inspired songs, books and plays, including one called “The Successful Pyrate” that was performed on London stages for several years. Most astonishing of all and unlike Blackbeard and many others, he did it all without getting captured or killed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
