<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;1 Tiger Queens of the Silk Route 1206–1241 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/1_Tiger_Queens_of_the_Silk_Route_120612/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;1 Tiger Queens of the Silk Route 1206–1241 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/1_Tiger_Queens_of_the_Silk_Route_120612/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 It Takes a Hero</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/1_Tiger_Queens_of_the_Silk_Route_120612/1_It_Takes_a_Hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/1_Tiger_Queens_of_the_Silk_Route_120612/1_It_Takes_a_Hero/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ARENEGADE TATAR WITH THE KNIFE OF VENGEANCE HIDDEN in his clothes slowly crept toward the camp of Genghis Khan’s elderly mother, Hoelun. He sought revenge against Genghis Khan, who had annihilated the ancient Tatar clans, killed many of their warriors, married their women, and adopted their children, even changing their names to make them Mongol.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a military and political leader with many enemies, Genghis Khan lived in a well-guarded encampment where bodyguards had strict orders to kill anyone who crossed a precise point without permission. Hoelun, however, lived apart in her own camp, and although she now had ten thousand soldiers and their families assigned to her control, at her advanced age she let her youngest son take her part of the army out on missions with her eldest son, the khan, while she stayed home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 The Growling Dragon and the Dancing Peacock</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/1_Tiger_Queens_of_the_Silk_Route_120612/2_The_Growling_Dragon_and_the_Dancing_Pe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/1_Tiger_Queens_of_the_Silk_Route_120612/2_The_Growling_Dragon_and_the_Dancing_Pe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“WILL THEY COME? WILL THEY COME?” For the nomadic tribes of the Mongolian Plateau in the late winter and spring of 1206, that was the big question.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Weary of the constant feuding, bickering, and raiding, Genghis Khan had sent out messengers to convene a &lt;em&gt;khuriltai&lt;/em&gt;, a large political meeting or parliament of the steppes, with the purpose of getting allies and potential rivals alike to officially accept his leadership, thus allowing him to proclaim a permanent peace under a new government.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Our Daughters Are Our Shields</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/1_Tiger_Queens_of_the_Silk_Route_120612/3_Our_Daughters_Are_Our_Shields/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/1_Tiger_Queens_of_the_Silk_Route_120612/3_Our_Daughters_Are_Our_Shields/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE STEPPE ALONE LACKED THE RESOURCES THAT GENGHIS KHAN needed to keep his followers happy. Now that the people had peace, milk, and meat, they longed for something more: for &lt;em&gt;tangsuqs&lt;/em&gt;, those rare trinkets such as gems, golden and silver ornaments, and decorative baubles for their tents, horses, and themselves. In addition to the luster they provided, every item conveyed some spiritual property from its presumed place of origin, and the farther the &lt;em&gt;tangsuq&lt;/em&gt; traveled, the stronger this essence, and therefore its beneficial power, became. Seashells emitted the magical sounds of the ocean, gold radiated the warmth of the sun, and silver the cool of the moon. Iridescent peacock feathers reflected the rainbow, and wine instantly released a fog of laughter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Queens at War and Commerce</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/1_Tiger_Queens_of_the_Silk_Route_120612/4_Queens_at_War_and_Commerce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/1_Tiger_Queens_of_the_Silk_Route_120612/4_Queens_at_War_and_Commerce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WITH ALL THE SMALLER KINGDOMS SECURELY UNITED behind him and under the control of his daughters, and with an adequate, if not entirely amicable, alliance with the Tangut in control of the Gansu Corridor of the Silk Route, Genghis Khan could move and challenge one of the larger kingdoms. For the remainder of his life he would pursue two major operations: first, the North China campaign from 1211 to 1215, and then the Central Asian offensive against the Muslims from 1219 to 1224. His daughters played critically important, but different, roles in each of these two massive quests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
