<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Animal Intelligence on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Animal Intelligence on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Approaches</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/approaches/</guid>
      <description>Comparison to computer It is easy to think of the mind in relation to the body as being analogous to software being in relation to a computer. The state of a computer is ever changing - yes; and we can refer to specific things when necessary. Eg: &amp;ldquo;program X is running inside the computer, so it is presenting this output&amp;rdquo;.
Behaviorism Academic history This was a reaction to focus on internal states and feelings rather than environmental stimuli in western study of human psyche and behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behavior</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/behavior/</guid>
      <description>Output \ Actuation This involves basic muscle movements, often in complex patterns, resulting in more complex automatic behavior like walking, running, using hands and speaking.
Large areas of the brain are associated with the use of hands.
Degree of automation Behavior can be automatic or not, depending on the extant to which declarative memory is used; the latter class is called executive function, which involves planning, decision, error control. General aspects of cognition which underly this are considered elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General properties</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/general_properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/general_properties/</guid>
      <description>Associative nature of thought Thought about a certain concept is influenced strongly by (possibly weak) associations with other concepts.
Physiological reason Neurons which fire together wire together - they are highly social. Nature of human thought is associative.
Examples People, when asked to think about the past or future, tend to lean slightly back or forward. People when exposed to a crossword with polite words tend to exhibit more polite behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>