<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/math/history/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/math/history/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ancient archiology</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/math/history/articles/ancient-archeology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/math/history/articles/ancient-archeology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rattibha.com/thread/1569333446228557829?lang=en&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Did the ancients have any concept of archaeology?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most human societies have an explanation for objects that predate themselves. The Iroquois regarded archaic copper tools as lost objects from the spirit world, medieval peasants believed stone arrowheads and axes were made by elves, or lightning, and used them for protection. But beyond this, did any classical civilisation develop a systematic way of studying artefacts?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ancient Greeks split the study of the past into historia and archaiologia, the former being textual accounts of military and political events, and the latter being the study of origins through myth, story, objects and genealogies. Hero cults often excavated graves and used weapons and objects as votive offerings. Thucydides noted how graves on Delos were opened and the mortuary rituals carefully examined to prove the continuity of the Carian people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bourbaki dehistoricization</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/math/history/articles/bourbaki-dehistoricization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/math/history/articles/bourbaki-dehistoricization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One further point that may help connect the dots: the tweet from Kaushik Gangopadhyay makes this point that &amp;ldquo;liberals imagine a world without history&amp;rdquo;. This is indeed the heart of the matter, but this ahistoric approach is not restricted to liberals or marxists. The current mathematical tradition, as popularized by Bourbaki - is highly axiomatic and non-historic. This particular movement cuts across all histories - often even to western gods like gauss or euler. As Kaushik indicates, many of us prefer a historic approach to mathematics, and I believe that does make for better pedagogy, but that&amp;rsquo;s not the current fashion. The folks publishing at &amp;ldquo;Annals of Mathematics&amp;rdquo; and all these top places tend to be of the non-historical or axiomatic type for the large part.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
