<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Homeschooling गृहे शिक्षणम् on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/education/home_school/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Homeschooling गृहे शिक्षणम् on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/education/home_school/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Homeschooling- USA CA</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/education/home_school/usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/education/home_school/usa/</guid>
      <description>Groups and resources  A big list is available at Peach Blossom School site here.  County-wide support groups list here (they offer park days, social networks, cooperative activities, mom&amp;rsquo;s days). Classes, field trips pdf.   State wide  Homeschool Association of California - here, FB, yahoo.   Bay area  San Francisco Bay Area Gifted Homeschoolers - sitehere, talk by leader here -201804.    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homeschooling: FAQ गृहे शिक्षणम् - आक्षेपाः</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/education/home_school/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/education/home_school/faq/</guid>
      <description>Motivation and intro  People with narrow backgrounds (never having seen gifted and normal homeschooled kids, themselves products of &amp;ldquo;factory model&amp;rdquo; education) find it hard to appreciate the benefits of homeschooling, while finding it easy to see supposed downsides. Hence this section. Here we try to answer some common objections from our perspective. But, please see other objection lists below. Where possible we try to avoid repeating answers.:  NC. Unschooling FAQ अमृतवर्षिण्य् अत्र।    Socialization Objection: He has learn to fight and cooperate with other people (kids).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unschooling</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/education/home_school/unschooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/skills/education/home_school/unschooling/</guid>
      <description>Intro  Unschooling is an educational method and philosophy that advocates learner-chosen activities as a primary means for learning. &amp;ldquo;Unschooling is education whereby the learner determines what he learns (content, pace, depth), when he learns it (any age, or not at all), where his learns (home, community, online or school) and how he learns (self-taught, teacher-taught, facilitated, classroom, apprenticeship, online, correspondence, book, video, game, experiential, lecture, volunteering, project, job, or travel).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>