<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Reviews on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Reviews on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Old traps</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/reviews/old-traps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/reviews/old-traps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is Ancient DNA Research Revealing New Truths — or Falling Into Old Traps?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Gideon Lewis-Kraus&lt;br&gt;&#xA;January 17, 2019&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;सारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ancient DNA (like radio-carbon-dating earlier) has revolutionized archaeology research. It is prestigious and privileged over - say - skull measurements. Mass migrations are established.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Landscape is dominated by four well-funded, well-connected labs. Proprietary chemical reagents let them isolate and enrich ancient samples much more accurately and cost-effectively than other labs can. They run like a factory, with thousands on samples stored and processed. Fieldworkers are basically at their mercy (short time to review drafts) - and become junior collaborators.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A couple of David Reich&amp;rsquo;s papers on Vanuatu were suspiciously rushed through peer review (Nature and Current Biology), and made excessively bold conclusions (second wave snuffing out the first) relative to limited sample (initially just 3 ancients from 1 site, proxies instead of contemporary samples from Vanuatu). They were superseded by the Jena paper (500 years of ongoing traffic, rather than a decisive event) with better samples (19 ancient, lot of contemporary Vanuatuans) and more interdisciplinary collaboration.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-i&#34;&gt;PART I&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-the-ghosts-of-teouma&#34;&gt;1. The Ghosts of Teouma&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A faint aura of destiny seems to hover over Teouma Bay. It’s not so much the landscape, with its ravishing if boilerplate tropical splendor — banana and mango trees, coconut and pandanus palms, bougainvillea, the apprehensive trill of the gray-eared honeyeater — as it is the shape of the harbor itself, which betrays, in the midst of such organic profusion, an aspect of the unnatural. The bay, on the island of Efate in the South Pacific nation Vanuatu, is long, symmetrical and briskly rectangular. In the expected place of wavelets is a blue so calm and unbroken that the sea doesn’t so much crash on the land as neatly abut it. From above, it looks as though a safe harbor had been engraved in the shoreline by some celestial engineer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vish review</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/reviews/vish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/reviews/vish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A very interesting book with striking and memorable numbers and anecdotes. Examples -&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;the Vysya are known to have a high rate of prolonged muscle paralysis in response to muscle relaxants given prior to surgery.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;especially common in people with the last name O’Donnell, who descend from one of the most powerful royal families of medieval Ireland, the “Descendants of Niall”—referring to Niall of the Nine Hostages, a legendary warlord from the earliest period of medieval Irish history&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Regarding Iceland) &amp;ldquo;natural selection over the last century against people with more predicted education, likely because of selection for people who began having children at a younger age&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Singh and Thangaraj seemed to be threatening to nix the whole project. &amp;hellip; We sat together and came up with new names for ancient Indian groups.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Outside the science, he has his biases (which are anti-hindu, anti-conservative and at times counter-factual), and make him &amp;ldquo;signal&amp;rdquo; his &amp;ldquo;virtue&amp;rdquo;. Examples -&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
