<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;PART-2 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;PART-2 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CH I</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_I/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_I/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;consolidation-and-propaganda-in-the-andamans&#34;&gt;Consolidation and propaganda in the Andamans&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the first part of this narrative I have given an account, not of prisoner&amp;rsquo;s life and condition only but mainly that of the political convicts in the prison-house of the Andamans. The Story is brought down to the year 1914, The struggle, the courage, the tenacity of will, and the fight for principle of the political prisoners during the period, had their effect on other Hindu prisoners in that jail and had instilled into them the spirit of social and cooperative endeavour. They had gradually begun to realise the meaning and significance of words like ‘country’ ‘religion&amp;rsquo;, and ‘service&amp;rsquo; in relation to themselves and to the larger community of which they were also social units. The Mussulman Warder as also the Mussulman prisoner had each his copy of the Koran to read in the jail. And, sometimes they apparently read the Koran to put off their normal work. This facility was dented to their Hindu brethren in that jail. These had no religious books given them to read and understand. They could keep none of them themselves; and it was an offence to read them openly. Either the superior officer strictly banned them, or the lesser man-the Mussulman Jamadar - would not get them any copy of their religious scriptures. If a few of them even on a holiday gathered together sometime to read and hear the Ramayana of Tulsidas, the Muslim warder or Jamadar would suddenly disperse the assembly by force and loud abuse. I had seen these happenings myself, and several times, looking at the pictures in such a book, they denounced as indecent; and they regarded it as a religious duty not to allow prisoners to see and read such stuff. Not tolerating such interference and coercion, the political prisoners often carried the matter to the superior officers. And this knocking at the door resulted, in the long run, in the prisoners&amp;rsquo; freedom to keep a religious book. After his day&amp;rsquo;s work, from that time onwards, the prisoner could openly keep also a slate and pencil to con his alphabets and write them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH II</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_II/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_II/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Shuddhi&amp;rdquo; movement in the Andamans&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was sent to the Andamans in 1911, and I soon found out that some Hindu prisoners had been converted to Islam and assumed Muslim names after their transportation to the Andamans. And when I traced the genesis of this change, I found that the Hindus in that place never found it worth while to think of, and took it as a matter of course. What was there in it, they felt, that one should look into its origin or trace it to its cause? The Andamans were in fact under the supreme authority of the British people, and if at all Hindus were to be converted under that rule to any faith, that faith was Christianity and not Islam. Till 1857, both in prisons and in the armies, the ruling authorities had encouraged the spread of Christianity. But after the terrible catastrophe of that war of Independence, the British authorities seldom interfered with religion and did not encourage conversion. However, even today the Christian missionaries try to convert the so-called criminal tribes in India to their own faith. At least, they exert considerable influence over their lives and social habits. But I dare say, with all my knowledge and experience about it, that prisons are never utilised by the authorities to convert Hindu prisoners into Christians by propaganda or by any other similar influence. Sometime a Christian missionary comes there to offer a prayer. But none of the prisoners are compelled to attend that prayer. With very rare exceptions, no concealed or open effort, either official or non-official, is made throughout the Andamans to convert Hindus to Christianity. And no officer was found to use his influence in that direction. The exception was brought home to me in a strange manner. And I shall mention it in its due place. But I can bear out, by my fourteen years&amp;rsquo; experience, the fact that not even four examples can be quoted of forcible conversion of Hindus by Christian missionaries of that place. Nor was any temptation or bribe used by them for that purpose.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH III</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_III/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_III/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-world-war-1914-and-its-menace-to-the-andamans&#34;&gt;The World War (1914) and its menace to the Andamans&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reader must have gathered from the first Chapter of this section, how, we, political prisoners, were handicapped for news from India, and how, later on, that is, after my transportation to the Silver Jail, matters became easier for us to procure news from India and circulate it in the Andamans. Officers like Mr. Barrie spread among us canards from India to harass and frighten us at the start of our prison-life here, whereas after two years we gave him the correct news about the position in India, so that faked news found no soil to take root in these islands since that date onwards. I give here one or two very funny instances of how they tried to fool and frighten us then.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH IV (1914-1918)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_IV_1914-1918/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_IV_1914-1918/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;political-prisoners-again-flood-the-andamans&#34;&gt;Political prisoners again flood the Andamans!&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While these manoeuverings ofthe German submarine in the waters of the Andamans were in progress to attack the islands, I happened to receive a press-cutting from a friend which contained the heading &amp;ldquo;Mutiny at Meerut&amp;rdquo;, This cutting was thrown into my cell by a political prisoner employed as a writer in the office below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;About the month of May last, a plot was discovered in India to start a revolution with an army at Meerut rising in mutiny against the Government. Several arrests were made. Some were tried and sent to the gallows. As I read the headline, a thrill went through my heart and all over the body.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH IX</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_IX/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_IX/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-spread-of-hindi-in-the-andamans&#34;&gt;The spread of Hindi in the Andamans&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had begun my work to obtain for Hindi the status of the national language of India, and to popularise it by every means at my disposal from the year 1906 when I was in England. The members of the Abhinav Bharata in England repeated the pledge every night before they retired for sleep, lo &amp;lsquo;make India independent to weld her into one nation, to turn her into a republic, and last and the fourth, to make Hindi the national language of India and Devanagari the script in which it should be written.’&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH V</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_V/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_V/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fourth-strike-and-my-ill-health&#34;&gt;The Fourth Strike and my ill-health&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The misfortune to which I have referred at the end of the last chapter happened thus. There was a political prisoner among us by name Bhan Singh. He was a Sikh, and for skirmishing with his tindal and the petty officer, he was locked up in the cell and Mr. Barrie was sent for by the tindal and the petty officer combined. Mr. Barrie entered the cell and abused him, and the Sikh prisoner returned abuse for abuse. Mr. Barrie was enraged and signed to the petty officer and the tindal to give him a sound beating. Instantly, five of them entered his room with big sticks and began to belabour him. The prisoner did his best to resist the attack, but, being well- stricken in years, could not stand up to them. They felled him on the ground and bludgeoned him all night. The cries of the prisoner were heard all over the place, &amp;ldquo;I am undone, brothers, I am undone, save me&amp;rdquo;, yelled the prisoner. Four or five of the political prisoners who were nearest to him on the ground floor, alarmed and enraged by the cries, rushed out of their rooms for his rescue, and went up the chawl with anything as a weapon that they could lay their hands upon. Mr. Barrie was there to bar the entrance. When he saw these men running up the staircase, he quietly slipped from the place by another passage; of course, he had stopped the beating before he managed to leave the place. This incident I narrate here as it was faithfully reported to me by these political prisoners, and as confirmed by others. And they put it in writing for the information of the officers concerned therein. And this is what they had stated in their representation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH VI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_VI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_VI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-death-bed&#34;&gt;On Death-Bed&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While all these activities were carried on with zest during the later years of the war, I found my health completely shattered, as I wrote in the letter I had sent to my brother; and I was removed to the Hospital for rest and treatment. When my fever was ever hundred degrees on my body, and the dysentery had become very acute, the hospital Authorities began to attend to me with greater care and undertook regular treatment of my disease. Every prisoner when taken to the hospital does get some rest in that place, and, therefore, it was no wonder that I got it because when I went in I wan worse in health than any other prisoner. It was in the eighth year of my residence in this jail, that they gave me this relief. Otherwise whenever I was ill before, the only treatment for me was solitary confinement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH VII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_VII/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_VII/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;riots-in-punjab-and-gujarat-1919-1920&#34;&gt;Riots in Punjab and Gujarat. (1919-1920)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The war had ended and its reaction on India was just coming to a close, when news came in the Andamans about riots in Punjab and Gujarat. We were taken by surprise to read that news. In the tremendous upheaval of the great war and its repercussion on the world, nothing cataclysmic could happen in India. And now these riots - on a day after the fair, an uprising of sleepers awakened and struggling for commotion, after the tide had turned! Ahmedabad, Viramgaon, and Delhi and towns in the Punjab rioting, for what? Presently were drafted in this prison martial law convicts from the Punjab and Gujarat. No Muslim political convicts had yet been reported to the Andamans. But in this batch from Gujarat and Punjab there were a few Muslim political convicts as well. All of them had sentences passed on them which ranged from two years&amp;rsquo; rigorous imprisonment to transportation for life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH VIII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_VIII/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_VIII/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;amnesty-and-political-prisoners&#34;&gt;Amnesty and political prisoners&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Jail Commission had left the Andamans. There was no doubt in my mind that the members of the Commission were considerably impressed by the statement I had submitted, and the discussion I had with them. And I have reason to believe that they did not suggest my release because, though I had plainly put it to them that if the new reforms proved a success the revolutionaries would follow the path of peace, I had introduced many ifs and but&amp;rsquo;s to qualify that general proposition, and they were angered by them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH X</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_X/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_X/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;miniature-hindu-raj&#34;&gt;Miniature Hindu Raj&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I stepped into the Andamnnn there was in it, in prison and outside, what one may rightly call, Pathan Raj. Dressed in brief authority, the Pathan dominated the scone. It was overthrown, ns I Imvo described in thin story, hy the time that my stay in the prison had come nearly to an end. The Pathan raj was gone and Hindu Raj had taken its place. If that was no more than a span, this was no better than one and one-fourth that span. The capital of that Raj was the oil depot of the prison and an I have already mentioned before, I was its foreman and therefore the monarch of that Raj. I sat in my capital on a throne which was no other than the chair with a broken arm in front of that depot. Our story has been brought so far, and now we proceed in it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH XI I meet my family again</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_XI_I_meet_my_family_again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_XI_I_meet_my_family_again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;last-days-in-the-andamans&#34;&gt;Last days In the Andamans&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just about this time my younger brother paid me a visit in the Andamans. There was no hope then of my release from that place. My elder brother had continued to be failing in health. And, therefore, the first thought that struck us when we three met together was that perhaps that was the last meeting together of us three. For, the next time that such a permission would be granted to us would be only after the lapse of one year. And one year was such an interminable period for a person like my elder brother who had found himself so thinned in body and so gone down in health that it was hard to imagine he would last long. Every day was such a difficult day for that emaciated body to pull on with. As such I told my younger brother the bitterest truth in plain words. I said, “Bal, truth is always harsh but I am sure you are not so weak-minded and cowardly as not to face it with fortitude. I see, therefore, no reason to conceal it from you. On the other hand, the sorrow that comes with perceptible and slow steps is easier to bear than any calamity that comes down upon us with a sudden blow. Be prepared to hear the worst of us any day in the future. I don&amp;rsquo;t think we can pull on for a long lime now. Do not forget, however, that even the unexpected sometimes happens. Who know we may survive from this. But the chances are very remote for that. Take it that this is our last meeting together on this side of the world!” Every word that I uttered went like a burning brand to my heart. The face of Bal had completely darkened and his countenance fell. But he realised that words were like heart-beats, and harsh though they were, they were but echoes of truth. I had ultered them as the voice of my conscience, and he heard them intently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH XII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_XII/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_XII/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we alighted from the steamer and touched the port at Calcutta we were put in the lock up at the Alipore jail. The fear that I had felt on leaving Andamans in the morning had but proved too true. Myself and my brother were put in different cells. Wearing our prison-garments and holding our bedding under the arm-pit and our pots and pans in one hand, we were both marching together like thieves directed by our escort of sepoys, when my elder brother was directed along a side passage by the sepoy in charge, and I was taken in different direction by another. Then I felt that I and my brother were parted for good one from the other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH XIII</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_XIII/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_XIII/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;meeting-with-friends-from-the-andamans&#34;&gt;Meeting with friends from the Andamans&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This was my second visit to Yeravada Jail. First I was put there in 1910 and for the second time now 1923. In those days the prison was full of convicts sentenced in the Mulshi Satyagraha case. They came and they went, all of them political prisoners. Some were punished with whipping. Those who had remained behind used to tell me of their severe ordeal in the Yeravada jail. There were in it prisoners hailing from Sindh and Dharwar who had taken part in the Non-cooperation and the Khilafat movements. Hindus and Muslims, political convicts they were all of them. The most wonderful fact of them all was that I met there my friends from the Andamans whom the Government of India had ordered back to India. Sikhs of the Lahore case and several others on transportation for life to the Andamans I met in the prison. I was strictly forbidden from inter-course with any of them, though I managed secretly to see them, and it gave me as much joy as I would have felt to meet the members of my own family and my near relatives. With tearful eyes, we greeted one another. In the Andamans we had suffered together. Any one of us could have won freedom in a day by the betrayal of our friends, by giving away the secrets of our society, or by putting the noose round the neck of fellow convicts. But God had saved us from such evil temptation. We revolutionaries had stood our ground bearing tortures as painful as a row of elephants pricked in the head by the good of their rider. They stand rooted to the spot under its severest blows, so we stood up firm and unshaken, to all the mental and physical pain inflicted upon us. We could not take a step forward. We would not go a step backward, so we stood obstinately where we were planted. No doubt we were cornered and at bay. And all around us were hurled &amp;ldquo;slings and arrows&amp;rdquo; of misfortune. The newcomers - the non-cooperators and the Khilafatists looked down upon these seasoned soldiers, these fighters and revolutionaries, as sinners, because they were members of secret societies, and conspirators, fhe Non-co-operators and the Khilafatists had not seen even two years of prison-life. They were raw, vainglorious men, and they bragged of their suffering before those who had passed through ten years or more of transportation for life in the Silver Jail of the Andamans - the brave Sikhs who had never winced under the severest hardships! They vaunted of their worthless &amp;lsquo;Satyagraha&amp;rsquo; and of their short imprisonment for it before these terrorists and presumed to despise them!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH XIV</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_XIV/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/My_Transportation_to_Life/PART-2/CH_XIV/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Reader&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The story is told. The curtain is rung down on it. Two life- sentences have been run. And I have brought together my recollections of them within the cover of this book. They are narrated in brief outline to you; they are put together within the narrowest compass.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I came into this world, God sent me in it on a sort of life-sentence. It was the span of life allotted to me by Time to stay in this &amp;ldquo;prison-house of life.&amp;rdquo; This story is but a chapter of that book of life—a longer story not yet ended. As I completed this chapter as a dedication to my great worship of the ideal, so the book of life may end as a dedication to it without break or faltering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
