<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Hindu Pad-Padashahi on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Hindu Pad-Padashahi on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Intro</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/01_Intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/01_Intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Hindi version is fuller - &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/wg121/page/n85/mode/2up&#34;&gt;archive link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Author’s Foreword&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A New Era&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hindavi Swaraj&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A Nation Succeeds Shivaji&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A Royal Martyr&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A Royal Martyr Avenged&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Maharashtra Mandal&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Appearance of Bajirao on the Scene&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Forward to Delhi&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;9&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To Free The Hindu Seas&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;10&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nadirshah and Bajirao&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;11&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nana and Bhau&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;12&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On to the Indus&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;13&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hindu Pad-Padashahi&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;14&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Panipat&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;15&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Defeat that Vanquished the Victor as well&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;16&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Madhaorao, the Virtuous&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;17&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Panipat Avenged&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;18&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Civil War and Popular Revolution&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;19&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The English humbled&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;20&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Svai Madhaorao—The Peshwa of the People’s choice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;21&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Ideal&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;22&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Best Solution under the Circumstances&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;23&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Viewed in the Light of Ancient History &amp;amp; Modern&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;24&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Means : Maratha Warfare&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;25&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Empire fosters an all round Hindu revival&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;26&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A Debt of Love and Gratitude&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;27&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Curtain Falls&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;authors-foreword&#34;&gt;Author&amp;rsquo;s Foreword&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inspite of the fact that the first tss6vfer rapidly Yfecfedi’fig from us further and further, the indefatigable exertions 6f a band of Maratha scholars led by Messrs ‘Rajwade and others h&amp;amp;d thrown such a flood ofnew light on the Ivistory of the Hindu Empire Of Maharashtra that the “salient features 6f that rgv^’at movement have become far more clearly discernible to ws than they were to those who were constrained for want of better mearfs to view the history through the distorted and dim glt§s£s of foreign scholarship alofte. “But as the monumental material, consisting of Estate records, documents, original letters afvd contemporary narratives that the Maratha scholars have discovered and laid under contribution, is to a very great extent confined to the Marathi language and as no attempt excepting that of justice Ranade, has been made to rewrite, at least concisely, the history of Maharashtra in the light that these valuable researches throw on it, in a language that would place before the Non-Maratha scholars and readers the fruits of their laboufs, the Indian public, not to speak of that of any other nation, has still very dim, curious and even perverted notions regarding both the heroic principles that animated the Maratha movement as well as the far- reaching effects it had on the course of the larger history of the Indian people. In the absence of such a comprehensive work as would marshal-out all the detailSofthis history under a masterly review in this new light thrown o’n it, we had long intended to write at least a monograph,, a -small handbook that would pave a way to a large work and acquaint the Non-Maratha readers with the great message that the movement came to deliver, the outline of the momentous mission it strove to fulfil. In 1910 We had, just after finishing the Work we wrote on the history of the Sikhs but which was throttled even ih the hour of its birth by the ruthless shocks of Revolutionary struggle, even commenced such a handbook in the English language on the history of the Marathas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 A New Era</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/02_A_New_Era/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/02_A_New_Era/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was in the year 1627 that Shivaji was born. That year wad destined to be the beginning of an epoch on account of that birth. Before Shivaji was born, hundreds of gallant souls had fought and fallen martyrs in resisting the onslaughts of the Muhammadan foes and in defence of the honour of the Hindu race. Fighting as bravely as any of these martyrs and warriors who fell vanquished in the field before him. Shivaji was destined to win and create a wave of triumph which gathered in strength as it proceeded and carried the Hindu banner on its crest from glory to glory, from achievement to achievement, for a period of hundred years or so. The tide of Muhammadan conquest that followed the arms of Mahomed of Ghazni rolled down with irresistible force till all Hindusthan lay submerged under it. Shivaji was the first person to raise his head above it and to command, in his stern Maratha accents: Thus far shalt thou go; but no farther’ Till the appearance of Shivaji on the political scene, it could be roughly stated that from the Himalayas tot he seas - wherever the Hindu arms met those of the Muhammadans, before 1627, the Hindus were sure to lose, now because of the sudden disappearance or death of their leader, now through the treachery of a minister here or a general there - but somehow or other every decisive struggle was sure to prove disastrous to the Hindu flag. One has only to recall Dahi’s fate, Jayapal’s fights, Anangapal’s stand, Prithvi Raja’s fall, the black day of Kalingar Sikri, Devagiri or Talikota to convince one of the melancholy truth of the above statement. But the hand of Shivaji took hold, as if bodily, of this cursed destiny of our people and gave a right about-turn and set her there, facing our opponents as sternly as she did us till then. Never again had the Hindu flag to bend before the Muhammadan crescent. From the Himalayas to the seas, wherever the Hindu arms met those of the Muhammadans after 1627, the Hindus sure to win and the Muhammadans sure to lick the dust, whateviB be their strength or however tumultuous were their war of’ Allah-ho-Akbar!’—God be victorious! God doubtless proved victorious, but it was the Hindu God. After 1627, one findsGod definitely enlisted on the Hindu side—on the side of the image worshipper, and setting his face sternly against the irnagjll breaker; one has only to recall the capture of Sinhgad, thedefence of Pavankhind, the careers of Govindsingh, Band Bahadur, Chhatrasal, Baji Rao, Nana, Bhau, Malharrad’; Parasharampant, Ranjit Singh and other numerous Maratiif Rajput and Sikh generals who beat the Muhammadans wherever and as often as they met. This turn, so momentous andl!! triumphant, which the political fortunes of the Hindu took, was doubtless due as well to the great spiritual and national ideal which Shivaji and his spiritual preceptor Shri Ramdas placed before our race, as to the new strategical methods and the new weapons they introduced into the battlefield. Maratha warfare was asl truly an addition to the science of war as it was in vogue then among Hindus, as the Maharashtra Dharma was a new force! animating the dying spirit of the national life of the Hindu race.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Hindavi Swaraj</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/03_Hindavi_Swaraj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/03_Hindavi_Swaraj/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The youth rose in rebellion. He writes in 1645 A.D. to one of his compatriots severely protesting against the allegation of being faithless to the Shah of Vijapur, and appealed to superior morals by reminding him that the only faith they pledged was not to any Shah, but to God alone. Did he not in company of Dadaji, his guardian, and his comrades solemnly swear in the presence of God on the summits of Sahyadri to fight to a finish and establish ‘Hindavi Swaraj’, a Hindu-Pad- Padshahi in Hindusthan? ‘ God is on our side and He shall win!’&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 A Nation Succeeds Shivaji</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/04_A_Nation_Succeeds_Shivaji/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/04_A_Nation_Succeeds_Shivaji/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;‘God, we enter our last fight Thou dost know our cause is right Make us march now in thy light On to Victory ! Let us not thy wrath deserve In the sacred cause we serve Let us not from danger swerve Teach us how to die!!’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shivaji died in 1680 A.D. and Ramdas in 1681. They had achieved much, but much more had yet to be achieved. They two died, but even their death would not kill the movement they had brought into being. It was not based on the narrow and shifting foundation of an individual life. It had struck its roots deep into the life of the nation. This is one of the most important features of the history of the Marathas, which we wish to emphasise and impress on the mind of our non- Maratha readers. As it is, the life and work of Shivaji and Ramdas being more or less known outside Maharashtra, and the latter part of Maratha history being more or less unknown or but vaguely and confusedly known, the general readers of Indian or Hindu History feel that Shivaji and Ramdas were the first and the last of Maratha patriots who aimed at the establishment of Hindu-pad-padashahi and championed the cause of all Hindudom. Not only this but the general understanding of Maharashtra seems to be that the real history of the Marathas, not only began, but also ended with the life of Shivaji; all that follows is confusion worse confounded by selfish and demoralized struggle of stray adventurous bands of freebooters. Both these suppositions are utterly wrong. The fact is that the real greatness of Shivaji and Ramdas lay in the very fact that their movement, not only survived them long, but characters as able and patriotic, organizers and captains, heroes and martyrs, rose in hundreds and in an unbroken succession and fought for the same cause mightily, pressing towards the same goal of Hindu-pad- padashahi, and achieved such glorious results as would have dazzled the eagle eye of Shivaji himself. When Shivaji was crowned he had hardly a province under him, and yet it was a great achievement. But was it not an achievement, single and great, when his successors under Raghoba Dada entered Lahore and the Maratha horse pranced triumphantly on the banks of the Indus and a continental country lay at their feet? When Shivaji died, Aurangzeb still lived. It was not Shivaji but his Maratha Nation, that at last succeeded in burying down Aurangzeb and his anti-Hindu ambitions in a common grave at Ahmednagar. The seed that fell at Raigad had become so noteworthy on account of the imposing tree into which our Empire grew. Otherwise, it would have proved barren and been lost into the dust of oblivion like so many other seeds that never grew into fruitful trees. Shivaji ruled at Raigad; but the day was yet to come when his people would rule at Delhi. Nay, had not Dhanaji and Santaji, Balaji and Baji, Nana and Bhau, Malhrrao and Dattaji, Madhavrao and Parshurampant, Nana and Bapu risen, thought, fought and won his cause, the result that Shivaji achieved would have seemed so bald and unimposing as those of the founders of some small principalities, like the Patwardhan or the Bundela states, and could not have claimed such unparalleled and Pan-Hindu significance in the history of our Hindu race. Shivaji is great, because his nation proved worthy of his greatness, could grasp and press on his mission to ultimate success, could realise what he could merely hope, could accomplish what he could merely desire to. The death of Shivaji was the mere beginning of Maratha history. He founded a Hindu principality-it had yet to grow into a Hindu Empire. This was all done after the death of Shivaji. The real epic opens as soon as Shivaji, after calling into being the great forces that had to act it up, disappears from the scene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 A Royal Martyr</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/05_A_Royal_Martyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/05_A_Royal_Martyr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aurangzeb was himself mistaken in sounding the death of Mararashtra Dharma and the vitality it had breathed into the movement of Hindu Revival in Maharashtra. Like so many other movements, personal or parochial, he thought the Maratha movement too must have received its death-blow at the death of its able leader Shivaji and by the fact of his being succeeded by his brave but incapable son Sambhaji; so Aurangzeb thought h is opportunity had come. With the vast resources of an Empire at his command in men and money from Kabul to Bengal, he descended into the Deccan with an army estimated at about three lakhs of all arms. Even Shivaji had never to face such overwhelming forces at a stretch. Aurangzeb was not wrong in his calculations, for the whole of the weight of the Mogul Empire thus masterfully concentrated could have crushed a kingdom ten time as large as the new and disorganised Maratha state. To make any attempt to resist the Moguls yet more hopeless, the Marathas had for their leader a man quite incapable of guiding a great nation. In addition to this incapacity to lead, Sambhaji had a bad temper, and at times indulged in excesses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 The Royal Martyr Avenged</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/06_The_Royal_Martyr_Avenged/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/06_The_Royal_Martyr_Avenged/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The whole Maratha nation rose in arms to avenge the death of their king, whose misdeeds and mistakes were readily forgotten and forgiven in this his last greatest act of self- abnegation. They resolved, resourceless and penniless, to secure their national independence, and assembling together under the presidency of their leader Rajaram, the second son of Shivaji, solemnly swore to fight and die in defence of their Hindu faith and Hindu Rajya. were not forgotten after his death, but, on the contrary, became the living faith of a whole people. Rajaram, Nilo Moreshwar, Prahlad Niraji, Ramchandra Pant, Sankarji Malhar, Parashuram Trimbak, Santaji Ghorpade, Dhanaji Jadhav, Khanderao Dabhade, Nimbalkar, Nemaji Parsoji, Brahmins, Marathas, Prabhus, princes, and peasants—it was a nation that rose in arms against the Muhammadan foe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 Maharashtra Mandal</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/07_Maharashtra_Mandal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/07_Maharashtra_Mandal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While Aurangzeb, weighed down with the wreck of all his hopes and anti- Hindu ambitions, sank in a gloomy grave, the Marathas carried the war far and wide into the Mogul territories of Khandesh, Gondvan, Berar and even Gujarat. The release of Shahu, the formal recognition by the Mogul Emperor of the claims of the Marathas to Swaraj in Maharashtra proper and to Chowth and Sardeshmukhi over the six Subhas of the Deccan, as well as in the tributary states of Mysore and Travancore, strengthened the hands of the Marathas as never before, and gave them breathing time to put their house in order and dress their wounds of fierce party passions and the centripetal tendencies and interests and to constitute the Marathas into an organised whole, with all its inherent and perhaps inevitable weakness, gave so splendid an account of itself that the ‘Maharashtra mandal’ or the Maratha Confederacy actually became the Hindu-pad-padashahi and ruled, not in name but in fact, all over Hindustan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 The Appearance of Bajirao On the Scene</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/08_The_Appearance_of_Bajirao_On_the_Scene/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/08_The_Appearance_of_Bajirao_On_the_Scene/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Independent Maharashtra must lead the war of Hindu Independence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Who for Scotland’s king and law,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Freedom’s sword will strongly draw,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Freeman stand or freeman fall&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Let him on with me!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;By oppression’s woes and pains,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;By your sons in servile chains,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;We will drain our dearest veins,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;But they shall be free!!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Lay the proud usurpers low,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Tyrants fall in every foe,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Liberty’s in every blow,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Let us do or die!!!‘&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 Forward to Delhi!</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/09_Forward_to_Delhi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/09_Forward_to_Delhi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How thoroughly Baji Rao and his companions were brought up in the traditions of Shivaji and how closely they had studied the political policy and military strategy of that great leader, could best be seen both in the eloquent appeal, Baji Rao made to the Maratha leaders in the presence of Shahu, in which he expressly drew a telling comparison between the arduous circumstances under which Shivaji strove to carry the war of Hindu Liberation to the South and the relatively more favourable turn the events had taken since then, when his generation, instead of daring more in carrying the war to the north, sat doubting and deliberating as well as in the splendid campaigns against the Nizam, Bangesh and other mogul generals. The first thing he had to do was to humble the opposition of the Nizam who was the most capable of Muhammadan generals and statesmen of his time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 To Free The Hindu Seas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/10_To_Free_The_Hindu_Seas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/10_To_Free_The_Hindu_Seas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While the Marathas were thus carrying the War of Hindu Liberation into the very heart of the Mogul empire to free the Hindu land, they were no less strenuously striving to free the Hindu seas too, from the domination of the foreigners that threatened them from the West. They had very early realised that the safety of the Hindu empire was threatened as much by the European mercantile nations that visited their seas, as it was by the Moslems who had already made themselves masters of their lands. How thoroughly Shivaji and his generation were bent on checking and frustrating European ambition and greed on the western coast could best be seen in the clear rules and the line of policy enunciated in the famous treatise on ‘State Policy’ written by the distinguished Maratha leader and statesman. Ramchandra Pant, and issued for general information by the orders of the Maratha cabinet as a state document. Shiv aji strove as strenuously to free the coastline of all foreign domination as he could under the circumstances, and laid the foundation of a strong maratha navy, backing it up by a line of newly built and powerfully equipped sea fortresses, which were destined to defend and guard the freedom of the Hindu seas for a century to come.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Nadirshah and Bajirao</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/11_Nadirshah_and_Bajirao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/11_Nadirshah_and_Bajirao/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;But splendid as these successes in the Konkan were, the Maratha arms were prevailing elsewhere as splendidly. Bajirao after the conquest and stttlement of Gujarat, Malva and Bundelkhand and thus extending the power of the Hindu Empire up to the Chambal, was not likely to cry halt there for ever. His aim was a consolidated Hindu Empire that should embrace all Hindustan in its sweep. His anxiety was to see all the religious shrines of Hindus freed and cleansed from being polluted by the alien and faithless touch of the enemies of Hindu Dharma.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Nana and Bhau</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/12_Nana_and_Bhau/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/12_Nana_and_Bhau/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Baji Rao died. But the spirit he had infused in his people could not die. It braced them up to sterner efforts and greater achievements under their new leader Balaji, alias Nana Saheb- the son of Baji Rao, and Bhau Saheb-the son of Chimaji, the victor of Bassein. Although he was only 19, Balaji had already seen service under his father and proved to be capable of the leadership of a great people. Shahu, ever ready to recognise merit, did not hesitate to appoint the brilliant youth in his father’s place as the prime minister of the Maratha Empire. The ceremony of investiture was an imposing one. On the completion of it, a Royal letter of instructions was handed over by the Maharaja to the youthful minister signifying in a few inspiring sentences the very heart of the great idea that had ever been struggling itself to actulise in the mighty movements of Maharashtra. ‘Your father Baji Rao,’ wrote the king, ‘had served most faithfully and achieved mighty deeds. He aimed to extend the bounds of Hindu rule to the farthest limits of Hindustan. You are his son: realise your father’s ideal, achieve what he aspired to, and lead your horsemen beyond the walls of Attock!’&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 On to the Indus</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/13_On_to_the_Indus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/13_On_to_the_Indus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile Raghoba was dominating and shaping great events at Delhi. He helped Gaziuddin to assume the office of the Imperial Vazir. He forced the Emperor to cede Gaya and Kurukshetra to the Marathas. He personally advanced and occupied Mathura, Brindawan, Gadmukteshwar, Pushpavati, Pushkar and several other religious places of the Hindus : the sacred city of Benares, too, was entered and occupied and held by a strong Maratha detachment. Thus one of the most cherished dreams of the Hindu people was at last realized and Raghoba could proudly report to the Peshwa of having liberated and recovered almost all the holy sites and cities of Hindudom from the Moslem hands. The Hindu colours waving triumphantly over those sites and cities in north, that were so endeared to every Hindu heart by a thousand holy associations, supplied yet another moral justification of the claim of the Marathas to represent and lead the great movement of Hindu liberation and Hindu- pad-padshahi. The emperor too thought that he had enough of the Marathas and showed fight. As soon as the new Vazir Gaziuddin became cognisant of the emperor’s secret design against himself and the Marathas who had raised him to the office, he invited Holkar with 50,000 soldiers, who easily routed the imperial forces so thoroughly that the very ladies of the harem were left unprotected and fell in the hands of the Marathas. They, with Gaziuddin, entered Delhi, forced their way into the palace, dethroned the old emperor and seated a new one on his throne and, as if to render the vengeance of Nemesis poetically complete, named him Alamgir-II.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Hindu Pad-Padashahi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/14_Hindu_Pad-Padashahi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/14_Hindu_Pad-Padashahi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Soon after penning the letter, Raghunath Rao hastend back with his forces to the Deccan as the rainy season was imminent. It was, however, unfortunate that he had to do so and leave the newly conquered but weakly garrisoned provinces. A yet more fatal factor that was not satisfactorily dealt with was that Nazib- Khan, the most intriguing leader of the Pathani plot, was yet spared even after he was captured by the Marathas and in spite of the desire of almost all the Marathas to make him pay with his life for his treacherous dealing with Ahmedsha Abdally, in instigating him against the Maratha power. But that wily chief was a consummate actor. He offered numberless apologies, adopted Malharrao as his father and begged him to spare his penitent life as he would that of his son. Malharrao was ever anxious to adopt as his son all those who forfeited their lives as the enemies of the Maratha cause, pleaded so pressingly for Nazib, that Raghunath Rao had to give in against his will.+++(5)+++ It will soon be seen how Nazib spent his penitent life in fomenting most dangerous intrigues against those who had so foolishly spared it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 PANIPAT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/15_PANIPAT/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/15_PANIPAT/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Muhammdans could nest fail to realize the momentous meaning of these proceedings at Delhi. The mews spread like wild fire that the Marathas had crowned their prince as, the Emperor of Hindustan. Nazibkhan and other Mnhammadan leaders pointed at those events as justifying their fears and attempts to rouse the Muhammadans to the gravity of the situation. They loudly declared that the much dreaded Hindu- Pad-Padashahi—nay, as Nazib and Muhammadan zealots would deliberately have it—the Brahman padshahi +++(5)+++ had become an accomplished fact. Let every Muhammadan who was true to his Prophet strike against the forces of the Kafirs!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 The Defeat that Vanquished the Victor as well</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/16_The_Defeat_that_Vanquished_the_Victor_as_well/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/16_The_Defeat_that_Vanquished_the_Victor_as_well/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The loss was formidable, for, while Bhau along with the bravest that followed him was sustaining an unequal struggle round their national standard, the Marathas were getting completely routed all along the line, hotly pursued by the foes. Thousands fell dead. Thousands were made prisoners whom the next morning their furious victor made to stand in row after row and butchered in cold blood. The booty the Afghans got was also immense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Madhaorao, The Virtuous</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/17_Madhaorao_The_Virtuous/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/17_Madhaorao_The_Virtuous/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The enemies of Maharashtra, seeing it left practically leaderless by the death of Nanasaheb and expecting the Maratha Confederacy to collapse under the heavy blow it had to face at Panipat, rose and beset her on all sides. Haidar found the opportunity to usurp the Government of Mysore from the hands of his Hindu master and sovereign and to invade the Maratha territories from the south. The Nizam at Hyderabad had made feverish preparations to avenge his defeat at Udgir. The English strove to snatch as much as they could. Not only the Muhammadans in the North, but even the Rajputs and the Jats and several other principalities revolted against the Marathas each trying to feather their own nest as best as they could. To make the matter yet worse, the treacherous ambition of Raghunath Rao threatened to usher in a Civil war and divide the Maratha camp into hostile factions, precisely when their nation was likely to be overwhelmed by their foes and the cause of Hindu Independence it represented, fall with its fortunes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Panipat Avenged</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/18_Panipat_Avenged/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/18_Panipat_Avenged/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;‘To their benefactors the Marathas are grateful, to their enemies relentless. If they are insulted they will risk their lives to avenge themselves.’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—Hiuen Tsang&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Neither these domestic distractions, nor the treacherous civil wars, nor the rise of such new and dangerous enemies as Haidar and Tippu, could make the Marathas forget their duty to avenge the day of Panipat and inflict condign punishment on all those who dared to go against them there. For some time after the death of Nanasaheb, Holkar and Shinde were the two chief Maratha Sardars who kept guarding their national interests in the north as best as they could. When the civil troubles and intrigues of Raghoba could be fairly managed, Madhao Rao in 1769 determined to dispatch a punitive expedition to the north under the command of Binivale. All Maratha Generals in the north were ordered to join the force. Crossing the Narbada with a set purpose of resuming the direction and control of the Hindu Empire and of inflicting a crushing penalty on all those Indian principalities who had dared to pray for a work for the ruin of the Maratha power since 1761 the powerful Maratha army reached Bundelkhand, quelled the petty disturbances there and punishing the recalcitrant princelets and princes on there way, reached the Chambal without much serious opposition. The Jat showed fight and refused to hand over Agra and other forts he had usurped since the day of Panipat. Near Bharatpur a pitched battle was fought. The Jats contested the field as bravely as heroes do, but unable to hold long against the Maratha forces. They broke and fled leaving thousands of their comrades dead on the field and all their camp with elephants and horses and war material fell in the hands of the Marthas. Soon after their leader, Nababsing, sued for peace and returning all Maratha possession he held, paid in 65 lakhs of rupees to them, as his MCMttJaied tribute. Now the advancing Martha army marched forth towards the gates of Delhi, expecting their sworn enemy tfcere would put up some fight against them. But, the old fox that wily Najibkhan was again all humility and repentance, the wry news of the victorious march of the Marathas brought him to the camp as a supplicant for life. He retuned all his spoils in ffee Doab, smoothened the way of the Marathas to Delhi and would do anything for them, if but pardoned and allowed to live tfcar he might conspire once more against them as soon as a favourable opportunity presented itself. But this time nothing could likely to shield him from the vengeance of the Marathas had not Death himself intervened and shielded the author of Panipat from the wrath of the countrymen of those who had fallen there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Civil War and Popular Revolution</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/19_Civil_War_and_Popular_Revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/19_Civil_War_and_Popular_Revolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That a Madhao Rao, the hope of a whole people, should die young, while Raghoba, the curse of whole people, should survive a generation after him, is one of those events that make men doubt at times if God be really omnipotent as it is said to be.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The death of Madhao Rao was a great national calamity, but the survival of Raghoba was calamity even greater than that. No sooner was the childless Madho Rao succeeded in accordance with his wish and the nation’s will, by his younger brother Narayan Rao, than did Raghoba begin anew to hatch up bloody conspiracies against the young boy and those who supported him. He took the hired guard of the palace in his confidence and ordered them to surround and arrest the young Peshwa, which plan his demoniacal wife, Anandibai, replaced by inciting them to assassinate him altogether. On the 30th August 1773 the guards suddenly rose in mutiny and confronted Narayan Rao, clamouring insolently for pay. As soon as one of the faithful attendants of the Peshwa remonstrated with them, they drew their swords and killed him there and then. Alarmed, the young Peshwa hastened away from room to room, hotly pursued by the mutineers, till he reached Raghoba’s hall and throwing his arms round his waist piteously prayed that his life be spared. ‘Save uncle, save me, thy child: I will recognize three as my Peshwa and will ask no more than a few crumbs of bread for my maintenance.’ But the assassins were upon him. Raghoba disentangled himself from his clasp and the murderers fell upon the youth. Chaphaji Tilekar threw himself between the swords of the assassins and his master, and covering the body of Narayan Rao entreated the guards to spare their master. But murder was on them and the guards dealt strokes after strokes with their bloody swords and slew the young Peshwa along with the faithful Chaphaji who lay covering him unto death. Thereupon the mutineers proclaimed Raghoba as the Peshwa of Maharashtra and took possession of the palace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 The English Humbled</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/20_The_English_Humbled/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/20_The_English_Humbled/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As soon as the news of the capitulation of a great English army reached Calcutta, the English were so wild with rage as to make them utterly unscrupulous and refusing to sanction the treaty their Commander had at Vadgaon, signed, after the captured army had been allowed to pass back to Bombay by the Marathas, according to the treaty, they renewed hostilities with added zeal. In the meanwhile Raghoba, too, who would have in other states, been shot for high treason or betrayal, was so leniently treated as a prince would have been, abused that liberty and once more effected his escape and went over to the English camp. Then the war again grew furious. Goddard descended from Gujarat and marched on Bassein. He was opposed by Ramchandra Ganesh who contested the English advance with admirable pertinacity, fighting action after action against the foe whenever and wherever he could. He led his last assault with such magnificent courage and valour as to win admiration even from his foes. But unfortunately this gallant and skilled Maratha General, struck by a bullet, fell in the very thick of the fight and Goddard took Bassein in 1780. Encouraged by this success, the English thought of wiping out the stain that the surrender of their army at Vadgaon had left on their arms, by accomplishing the task of carrying the very capital of the Marathas which they had formerly so disgracefully failed to do. So the English advanced against Poona, aiming to browbeat Nana and his associates into surrender. But the matchless genius of that Maratha statesman had already woven a subtly dangerous net into which he threatened to entangle the English power all over India. He made Haidar promise to attack Madras, Bhonsle to invade Bengal and undertook himself to crush the English power at Bombay. Accordingly Haidar, with the aid of the French Government, achieved a signal success at Madras. Parashrambhau with 12 thousand men kept hanging around and harassing the flanks and the rear of the advance of the English forces towards Poona. While Nana, Tukoji Holkar, and Haripant Phadke faced the English with 30 thousand Maratha forces. General Goddard found himself as he advanced, in the same predicament as Col. Egerton did. He could not advance further unless he invited the fate of his predecessor and yet he had advanced far enough to render a march back as dangerous as it would be disgraceful. So standing where he was strengthened himself. But that too could not continue long. The vigorous and niosi harassing attacks the Marathas delivered against Captain Machay and Col. Brown while striving to carry supplies to Goddard made any further attempt to maintain communication with Bombay extremely risky and ruinous. At last even General Goddard, to his utter chagrin had to decide to drop the advance against the capital of the Marathas, and retire. As soon as the crest-fallen English army took a right- about-turn and began a march back, the Marathas led by Bhau and Tukoji Holkar closed upon the prey from all sides and in spite of the stubborn discipline and bravery of the English beat them so badly as to make their boastful Commander whose arrogance aspired to crown him with the honours of triumphant entry into the Maratha capital, thank his stars for having somehow been able to reach back Bombay alive, even though at the cost of leaving hundreds of his soldiers slain and strewn, marking the track of his return march with their corpses and almost all ammunition, guns, tents, and camp furniture, thousands of cannon shots and stores, thousands of bullocks abandoned and fallen in the hands of the triumphant Marathas. Thus twice did the English come audaciously forward to fight their way on to Poona; and twice had they to face the utter humiliation of retiring beaten and crest-fallen back to Bombay. Never did a boastful going out end in a more sadly disgraceful return home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Savai Madhaorao- The Peshwa of the People’s Choice</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/21_Savai_Madhaorao-_The_Peshwa_of_the_Peoples_Choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/21_Savai_Madhaorao-_The_Peshwa_of_the_Peoples_Choice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For Nana and Mahadji, the brain and the sword of Hindudom, meant on their Atalantian shoulders to bear the weight of the mightest of monarchies. Of all the best of statesmen and swordsmen, of Hastings and Wellesley, that England or France or Holland or Portugal sent out to India to conquer an Empire, none could outwit or oppose these with any great measure of success. Both of them had seen the palmiest days of the Hindu Empire. Both were trained in the principles and aims and traditions of their nation and its mission in the imperial school of the great Nanasaheb and Sadashivrao Bhau. Both had seen Panipat and survived it determined to carry on the mission of the heroic generation that lay slain on that gory field. They found their kingdom smitten by the civil war, on the verge of ruin, with a nonentity for its king, a lad for its Prime Minister and an ambitious and powerful European foe for its sworn antagonist. Yet they faced all odds with dauntless courage and an undimmed vision, quelled revolts and rebellions within the realm and with a mighty hand and unerring eye threw down and forced their foes, whether European or Asiatic to drink the cup of humiliation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 A SYNTHETIC REVIEW</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/22_A_SYNTHETIC_REVIEW/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/22_A_SYNTHETIC_REVIEW/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Go. Freedom, whose smiles we shall never resign. Go. tell the invaders, the Danes. ’Tis sweeter to bleed for an age at thy shrine Than to sleep but a minute in chains.’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—Thomas Moore&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ideal-an-all-india-hindu-empire-under-the-hegemony-of-maharashtra&#34;&gt;The Ideal An all-India Hindu Empire under the hegemony of Maharashtra&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our motive in undertaking the review of Maratha history was to bring out prominently, from a general confusion of details those events which, when cogently arranged, were most likely to enable us better to appraise and appreciate the value of the modern history of Maharashtra from a Pan-Hindu point of view and to correlate and fit it in comprehensive whole—the History of the Hindu nation itself—of which the first forms but a chapter, however glorious and momentous in itself it be. Therefore, it was necessary to narrate as briefly as possible the story of the Maratha movement and to ascertain the source, the spring, the motive power that propelled a whole people like that to struggle and strive and sacrifice, till they built a mighty Hindu Empire. As the first part of this history is better known outside Maharashtra and even better appreciated than the latter one which roughly may be taken to open from the rise of Balaji Vishwanath and the formation of the Confederacy and as scholars, like Ranade, had already done justice to the period it covered by presenting the activities of Shivaji’ and Rajaram’s generations in their true aspect, we have but very cursorily referred to a few events in that period and dealt in our sketch more fully—though not at all exhaustively—with the second part of the Maratha History, since it ceased to be Maratha History proper and assumed such magnitude as to cover and get essentially identified with Indian History itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 The Curtain Falls</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/23_The_Curtain_Falls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/marATha/post-peshva/articles/sAvarkar_VD/english/Hindu-pad-pAtshAhi/23_The_Curtain_Falls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have brought our review down to the battle of Kharda, 1795. All our remarks passed in the preceding chapters necessarily refer to this period under review. Ours has never been the intention of recounting and examining all the details of the Maratha movement, but only to bring out those which would enable us to ascertain the leading motive, the underlying principle, that inspired and informed it and ascertain, in that &amp;hellip; teal place in the history of our Hindu people. That &amp;hellip; lash is done. Yet the period from 1795 to 1818 when the Maratha Empire fell, is too tragic to be passed by without a sigh or tear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
