<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Computer architecture on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/computerArchitecture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Computer architecture on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/computerArchitecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Display</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/computerArchitecture/Display/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/computerArchitecture/Display/</guid>
      <description>Display screens Liquid Crystal displays tend to be more ergonomically friendly than CRT tube monitors.
Quality Image quality Display screens vary in image quality parameters: screen size, maximum resolution: SVGA (800 x 600), XGA (1024 x 768), SXGA (1280 x 1024), or UXGA (1600 x 1200), contrast ratio.
They also vary in refresh rate, in the case of images generated from projection, as in CRT monitors or projectors: low refresh rate results in flicker and eye strain - especially from typing distance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Input</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/computerArchitecture/Input/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/computerArchitecture/Input/</guid>
      <description>Gaming input Motion detection Microsoft Kinect detects hand motions at a certain optimum distance using a camera - no external devices are required.
Containment/ Size Computer case The case/ tower provides power-supply and cooling. Good cooling systems try to be noiseless - they rely on airflow or ensure that the fan speed is usually low.
Size Computer&amp;rsquo;s processing and storage components are sometimes fit into the monitor or under keyboard in case of a notebook computer, or in a small case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interfaces and networking</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/computerArchitecture/Interfaces_and_networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/computerArchitecture/Interfaces_and_networking/</guid>
      <description>Device interfaces Common standards are often used to connect a wide variety of device pairs.
Universal serial bus USB is currently most popular. USB 3 enables superior data-transfer speeds.
USB allows for a tiered star topology: so one can connect many devices to a particular device with a single usb wire branching out into many others. Power dissipation limits the extant to which this can be done.
USB Plugs USB wires have 4 (sometimes 5) terminals arranged in various shapes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Number storage formats</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/computerArchitecture/Number_storage_formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/computerArchitecture/Number_storage_formats/</guid>
      <description>Design factors Words and bits Suppose \(b\) bits are available to store a certain type of number: this is usally expressed in terms of multiples of words (collection of \(w\) bits). Because binary logic is used for addressing and processing, \(w\) is generally a power of 2. In old days, it used to be \(w = 2^2\), now 64 bit words are common.
Simplicity of computation logic Some representation formats require simpler and more efficient circuits for performing basic arithmetic operations than others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel computers</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/computerArchitecture/Parallel_computers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/computerArchitecture/Parallel_computers/</guid>
      <description>Architecture Possible 4 uses of multiple processing units were named by Flynn as single/ multiple instructions single/ multiple data-streams.
Communication Shared memory vs message passing architectures. Can use shared memory abstraction over message passing, vice-versa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Procurement and maintenance</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/computerArchitecture/Procurement_and_maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/computerArchitecture/Procurement_and_maintenance/</guid>
      <description>Maintenance Fan vent cleaning In case of a laptop, the fan-vent needs to be cleaned periodically. CPU temperature can be monitored in the GUI using common applications.
Battery If laptop is always connected, best to disconnect battery \chk.
Vostro 1000 disassembly procedure Remove panel above keyboard. Disconnect keyboard, wires to monitor, trackpad. Remove screws in the front and in the back. Remove the panel from above the keyboard.
Upgrades Understand needs In order to understand what needs to be change, it is good to understand resource limitations: is working memory low, or is the CPU too slow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Special computers</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/computerArchitecture/Special_computers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/computerArchitecture/Special_computers/</guid>
      <description>Pocket computers Components These devices are very compact, and often combined with specialized equipment like ability to connect to certain mobile phone networks, GPS, gyroscopes, compasses, cameras, flash led&amp;rsquo;s, accelerometers. Such components often make single function devices much less attractive.
Customizability The hardware customizability is often very limited; but communication interfaces (eg: bluetooth, card slots) enable expansion.
OS The operating systems used are often not easily switched; but may be upgradeable or hacked in minor ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage devices</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/computerArchitecture/Storage_devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/computing/computerArchitecture/Storage_devices/</guid>
      <description>Magnetic storage Unlike optical storage, magnetic storage is re-writable.
Bus interface While SCSI has a processor integrated into the controller, SATA makes greater use of the system processor to serve that function; the former is costlier.
Quality Hard disk drives differ mainly in speed, storage capacity, size, redundancy (RAID), error correction, shock resistance.
Best and economical Areal density doubling every two to four years since their invention. So, even 1TB is economical.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>