<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Coginition on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/cognition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Coginition on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/cognition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>01 Sensory perception</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/cognition/01_Sensory_perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/cognition/01_Sensory_perception/</guid>
      <description>Automated processing Sensory perception involves not only the sense organs, but also specialized circuitry in the brain. This is akin to input devices + software drivers in the case of computers.
Perception often involves attention, but all processing is non-explicit and non-verbal.
Signal sparsity The brain deduces most of what it knows from scant filtered signals.
Eyes keep moving around from nose to eye to lips etc.. So actual information observed is actually small, the brain does not know what is happening outside this small area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 Simulation and modeling</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/cognition/04_Simulation_and_modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/cognition/04_Simulation_and_modeling/</guid>
      <description>Aka vikalpa, vitarka, vichAra. Purpose could be amusement, prediction, evaluation, planning. It involves understanding, reasoning, empathy.
Understanding, theorizing This may or may not be probabilistic. It may or may not involve explicit formal reasoning.
This includes empathy.
Role of proability theory Facile and formal use of probability theory is a good idea. In any case, probability estimation in animal intelligence can be understood using the belief/ Bayesian interpretion of probability theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 Attention</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/cognition/05_Attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/cognition/05_Attention/</guid>
      <description>aka manas by Hindus. Attention control is akin to task scheduling in computers
Types Attention could be endogenous or exogenous (response to a loud noise). Endogenous attention is thought to involve frontal cortex and basal ganglia. Depending on whether it involves focusing sensors, attention is overt or covert.
Number of tasks Attention may be directed at a single or multiple tasks. Usually multitasking is accomplished by focusing on each task for a short period of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 Decision: evaluation and comparison</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/cognition/06_Decision_evaluation_and_comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/cognition/06_Decision_evaluation_and_comparison/</guid>
      <description>Making a choice is fundamental to behavior. It fundamentally involves comparison.
Reasoned vs automatic It may involve simulation, possibly with explicit verbal reasoning to various degrees.
Preset Preferences Decisions not involving explicit reasoning are made using set preferences. Some preferences are formed due to developmental environment; while some tastes are acquired consciously due to habit formation. Right from the womb, the human baby learns the rhythm of its mother&amp;rsquo;s language, the taste of food she ingests; and adapts its behavior upon being born.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 Affect</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/cognition/07_Affect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/biology/organism/animalIntelligence/cognition/07_Affect/</guid>
      <description>Aka emotion, vikAra.
Distribution over actions/ thoughts Emotion was defined by behaviorists in terms of probability distribution over responses (either to stimuli, or physical reactions/ sensations including in the brain) Eg: sadness increased certain type of responses; while others identify it purely with certain mental sensations or neurochemicals. One may extend this distribution to cover thoughts as well.
Modes of cognition/ operation On may draw an analogy with a computer which can operate in different modes; and whose computation and output distribution changes according to the mode.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>