<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;4 The Deccan and the South, 1400–1650 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/4_The_Deccan_and_the_South_14001650/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;4 The Deccan and the South, 1400–1650 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/4_The_Deccan_and_the_South_14001650/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 LINKS TO THE PERSIANATE WORLD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/4_The_Deccan_and_the_South_14001650/01_LINKS_TO_THE_PERSIANATE_WORLD/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/4_The_Deccan_and_the_South_14001650/01_LINKS_TO_THE_PERSIANATE_WORLD/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Timur raided north India in mid December 1398, Delhi’s poorer classes had little choice but to remain and face the devastation. But many of the city’s elites, well aware of the warlord’s prior conquests and possessing sufficient resources, hastily packed their things and escaped before the storm broke. Among these was Muhammad Gisudaraz (d. 1422), who would become the most famous Sufi shaikh of the Deccan plateau. His tomb in Gulbarga, then the Bahmani sultanate’s capital, remains today the Deccan’s most popular Sufi shrine.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 SUCCESSORS TO THE BAHMANI STATE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/4_The_Deccan_and_the_South_14001650/02_SUCCESSORS_TO_THE_BAHMANI_STATE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/4_The_Deccan_and_the_South_14001650/02_SUCCESSORS_TO_THE_BAHMANI_STATE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Bahmani court’s efforts to recruit talent from the Persian-speaking world came at heavy cost. As more so-called Westerners – ethnic Persians and Turks – arrived from across the Arabian Sea and acquired positions of influence, the kingdom’s native Muslims, the Deccanis, felt increasingly embittered and alienated. This class was descended from north Indian immigrants who, such as Gisudaraz’s parents, had settled in the Deccan from the 1320s, when the Tughluqs established Daulatabad as their empire-wide co-capital. Born in the Deccan, this class spoke indigenous languages in addition to an early form of Hindavi called Dakani. And, to a far greater extent than Westerners, they had adopted the plateau as their natural home. During their successful struggle against the Tughluq regime in Delhi, they had positioned themselves against north Indians. But after achieving independence from Delhi, their rivals became the Westerners, whom they viewed as interlopers who had been given preferential treatment by the court. The differences between the two groups were therefore both political and cultural. By the mid fifteenth century a de facto apartheid system had emerged. In Bidar’s Hall of Public Audience, Westerners attending court stood to the right-hand side of the throne and the Deccanis to the left. While on military campaigns, the two factions continuously clashed, each side blaming the other for insubordination, cowardice, even treason.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 POLITICAL AND CULTURAL EVOLUTION AT VIJAYANAGARA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/4_The_Deccan_and_the_South_14001650/03_POLITICAL_AND_CULTURAL_EVOLUTION_AT_VIJAYANAGARA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/4_The_Deccan_and_the_South_14001650/03_POLITICAL_AND_CULTURAL_EVOLUTION_AT_VIJAYANAGARA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long before Sultan Muhammad Quli Qutb Shah began planning the city of Hyderabad, royal patrons in the sprawling kingdom of Vijayanagara had already built the monumental temple complexes that, in popular imagination, remain iconic images of that state. In their metropolitan capital, kings regularly sponsored huge public processions and ceremonies taking place over several days that were enacted in elaborately built structures near their palaces or in the city’s temple complexes. Long chariot streets, tanks, multi-pillar halls and colonnades lining inner enclosure walls – all were prominent features of these complexes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 GUNPOWDER TECHNOLOGY IN THE DECCAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/4_The_Deccan_and_the_South_14001650/04_GUNPOWDER_TECHNOLOGY_IN_THE_DECCAN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/4_The_Deccan_and_the_South_14001650/04_GUNPOWDER_TECHNOLOGY_IN_THE_DECCAN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The drama that played out between Vijayanagara and its northern adversaries took place against the backdrop of a military revolution – or, as some historians would say, &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; military revolution.43 The term conventionally refers to the socio-political transformations that occurred in early modern Europe following the advent of large siege cannon capable of smashing the tall, vertical walls of medieval forts. It is widely assumed that such technologies and transformations first appeared in Europe and then diffused to the rest of the world in the early period of European colonialism, the sixteenth and seventeenth centuries. However, the presence of gun-ports built into the walls of forts at Bidar, Kalyana and Raichur indicate that as early as the 1460s cannon were being used defensively in the heart of the plateau. In the early 1470s the Bahmani minister Mahmud Gawan directed military operations in which he seems to have referred to the use of siege cannon. By the beginning of the sixteenth century, Portuguese merchant-soldiers who had just entered the Indian Ocean reported the presence of artillery in cities along India’s western coast. And in 1510, when Portuguese naval squadrons captured the strategic seaport of Goa from the sultan of Bijapur, they found the arsenal in that city well stocked with munitions, including adaptations of some of their own firearm technology that had been captured from a naval engagement several years earlier. In the decades preceding 1510, Bijapur’s military engineers in Goa had been assimilating firearm technologies from both Mamluk and Ottoman, as well as European sources. Indeed, Afonso de Albuquerque (d. 1515), the viceroy and mastermind of the Portuguese enterprise in the Indian Ocean region, was so impressed with the weaponry manufactured at Goa that he reported to the king of Portugal in 1513 that Muslim gunsmiths there were making firearms of higher quality than those produced in Germany, which the Portuguese had considered the finest anywhere. Albuquerque even sent to Lisbon one of these master gunsmiths, together with samples of heavy cannon made in Goa, with the idea that Portuguese engineers might learn munitions techniques from him.44 Such evidence of technologies moving from India to Europe instead of vice versa challenges the conventional image of Europe as the undisputed font of military technology in the early modern era, and of the rest of the world as its passive recipients.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 CULTURAL PRODUCTION IN THE GUNPOWDER AGE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/4_The_Deccan_and_the_South_14001650/05_CULTURAL_PRODUCTION_IN_THE_GUNPOWDER_AGE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/4_The_Deccan_and_the_South_14001650/05_CULTURAL_PRODUCTION_IN_THE_GUNPOWDER_AGE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As modernized forts began to appear across the plateau, the balance of military advantage tipped from attackers to defenders. Besieging armies found it difficult or impossible to seize reconstituted forts, which thereafter virtually ceased changing hands. For the first time since the emergence of the five sultanates in the early sixteenth century, the Deccan’s internal frontiers stabilized. As this occurred, the cultural production of the northern sultanates grew in quantity and became more differentiated in quality. For example, for the first seven or eight decades of their independent existence, the Deccan’s four principal sultanates used existing stocks of Bahmani and Vijayanagara coins, which remained in circulation during that period. But then, between 1578 and 1584 – shortly after the northern Deccan’s internal borders had stabilized – each of the region’s sultanates began minting its own coins, reflecting an awareness of, and a desire to express, their distinctive identities. A similar thing happened regarding architecture, art and literature produced after the mid sixteenth century.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 VIJAYANAGARA’S SUCCESSORS AND SOUTH INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/4_The_Deccan_and_the_South_14001650/06_VIJAYANAGARAS_SUCCESSORS_AND_SOUTH_INDIA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/4_The_Deccan_and_the_South_14001650/06_VIJAYANAGARAS_SUCCESSORS_AND_SOUTH_INDIA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After the Battle of Talikota, the peninsula south of the Krishna evolved along very different lines from those of the northern Deccan. Following Rama Raya’s disastrous defeat and death on the battlefield, his brother, Tirumala, rescued the imprisoned king, Sadaśiva – together with courtiers, government officials, the harem, military personnel and 1,500 elephants laden with treasure49 – and set out to relocate the capital in more secure territory. This was the fort of Penukonda, 200 kilometres south-east of their abandoned metropolis. But the disruptions caused by the shock of defeat had plunged the empire into a state of chaos that persisted for the next six years, during which Sadaśiva, the last Tuluva emperor, mysteriously died. Tirumala’s efforts to pick up the pieces of the stricken state were further stymied by domestic turmoil, including a bitter dispute with his nephew, Rama Raya’s son, over leadership of the Aravidu clan. By 1570, however, Tirumala felt sufficiently secure to crown himself the first Aravidu monarch of a reconstituted state of Vijayanagara, to be succeeded two years later by his son Śriranga I (r. 1572–85).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 CONCLUSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/4_The_Deccan_and_the_South_14001650/07_CONCLUSION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/india-persianate-age/4_The_Deccan_and_the_South_14001650/07_CONCLUSION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Between 1347 and 1565 Vijayanagara had often been at war with the Bahmani sultanate and the latter’s sixteenth-century successor states. Because the ruling houses of Vijayanagara and its northern neighbours adhered to different religious traditions, many modern historians have construed the Krishna as a civilizational frontier dividing the Deccan into a Muslim north and a Hindu south. In part, this idea is a legacy of historian Robert Sewell who, writing in 1900, first brought Vijayanagara’s history to the attention of the reading public. Sewell famously described that state as a ‘Hindu bulwark against Muhammadan conquests’,73 thereby contributing to an enduring trope of religiously defined territorial separatism in the plateau. Sewell’s book was published when India’s nationalist movement was in full swing, and when Indian historians were looking to the country’s past for evidence of successful states whose memory might mobilize British India’s population for the nationalist cause. Inasmuch as Indian nationalism for many meant Hindu nationalism, Sewell’s communalized characterization of Vijayanagara found a receptive audience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
