<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;व्रणः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/wound/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;व्रणः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/wound/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bone</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/wound/bone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/wound/bone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;6-8 weeks recovery.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bones heal best when loads are applied to them. Weight bearing activities through injured bones stimulates an increase in bone growth at injury sites and a subsequent increase in bone strength. This concept is why immobilizer boots are often used in ankle and foot fractures rather than plaster casts. Allowing patients to walk while protecting their healing bone allows the bony repair process to occur faster and more thoroughly than keeping weight entirely off of a fracture site.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>cartilage</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/wound/cartilage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/wound/cartilage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;detection&#34;&gt;Detection&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cartilage is also aneural – meaning that it has no nerve supply. Because of the lack of nerve endings, pain is generally not felt when cartilage is damaged until it has been worn down significantly. Pain is felt when faulty movement at the injury site has started to impact another tissue in the area, such as underlying bone or associated ligamentous tissue.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;healing&#34;&gt;Healing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cartilage is avascular - no blood supply. Very slow-healing. Nutrition to cartilage is maintained by fluid in the joints, which lubricates the tissue. The lubrication process occurs by a sort of flushing mechanism, when load is applied and then removed from the tissue repeatedly. Activities such as stationary cycling and walking that involve repeated smooth joint movement can promote this lubrication process without creating too much stress on injured cartilage tissue.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Inactivity has negative effects on joint cartilage. Lack of movement or of weight bearing can cause thinning of cartilage, making it susceptible to injury. Therefore – even fairly immediately after injury – exercises that encourage joints to move throughout their range of motion and that involve some degree of load bearing through the joint surfaces help cartilage to heal.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;maintenance&#34;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inactivity has negative effects on joint cartilage. Lack of movement or of weight bearing can cause thinning of cartilage, making it susceptible to injury.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dog bite</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/wound/dog-bite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/wound/dog-bite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;danger&#34;&gt;Danger&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dog packs instinctually attack and kill humans - within seconds. Hunger is NOT the cause, neither is provocation (evident from videos and live observation).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2025-07-02 bengaLUru &amp;ldquo;koDigehaLLi telecom layout&amp;rdquo; 68 yo healthy farmer killed. &lt;a href=&#34;https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/dog-attack-case-in-bengaluru-morning-walk-turns-tragic-neighbours-help-goes-in-vain-in/articleshow/122982655.cms&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2023-08-20 (Roughly) BengaLUru jAlahaLLi Air force camp, 7tyo Rajdulari Sinha, a retired schoolteacher, was killed by 10 dogs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2023-06-20 (Roughly) 9yo Kannur - rescued in time &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/NewsFirstKan/status/1671100040126033920&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.indiatvnews.com/news/india/kerala-9-year-old-mauled-by-stray-dogs-undergoes-treatment-in-kannur-2023-06-20-876986&#34;&gt;IN&lt;/a&gt;. Also 11 yo handicapped killed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2023-04-20 0yo in cradle, Ahmedabad - serious injury &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DeshGujarat/status/1649394164692312064&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2023-04-21 9yo, Kolar serious injury.&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opindia.com/2023/04/9-year-old-boy-attacked-by-stray-dogs-in-karnatakas-kolar-rescued-by-a-cop/&#34;&gt;OP&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MirrorNow/status/1649385372277940224&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;65+yo dead AMU 2023-04-16 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Mithileshdhar/status/1647480502444752903&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CNNnews18/status/1646363893235867649&#34;&gt;6yo almost-dead Nagpur 2023-04-13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4yo dead HYD 2023-02-23 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/porinju/status/1627912438376181761&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/virendra1137/status/1627935641064595457&#34;&gt;9yo almost-dead BLR 2023-01-28&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;12yo dead near house Boondi RJ &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opindia.com/2023/07/stray-dogs-maul-12-year-old-to-death-boondi-rajasthan/&#34;&gt;OP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Other collections: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dintentdata/status/1635563094079569920&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joint dislocation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/wound/dislocation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/wound/dislocation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Should be corrected (&amp;ldquo;reduced&amp;rdquo;) without surgery soon after dislocation. 6 hours in case of hip - femur dislocation. Else may damage surrounding blood vessels and nerves.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If some time has passed, surgical reduction may be required.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CT-scan help determine if there is an associated fracture or bone fragments in the joint.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligament tear</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/wound/ligament-tear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/wound/ligament-tear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ligaments attach bones to other bones. They generally have a more limited blood supply than either muscle or tendon – lengthening their healing time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ankle sprains and ligamentous tears in the knee (such as an Anterior Cruciate Ligament injury) are two common ligament injuries.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;severity-and-prognosis&#34;&gt;Severity and prognosis&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grade 1 - Small micro holes. No swelling, and small hemorrhage (bruising). Mild sprain.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Should recover 4–6 weeks later. It will be less painful after a week or two and walking should be fine.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Work back into high level exercises after 2/3 weeks and return to sport may take about 6–8 weeks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grade 2 - partial tear of ligament. The ligament recovers in 8–12 weeks. The ligament will have “healed” during this time.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;But if you wanna get back into running/football etc. then you’ll need to start higher level rehab at the 6–8 week mark to build up strength and confidence.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Full recovery back into your impact sport might take up to 4–5 months if you do the right rehab to stop it happening again.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grade 3 -  full tear of ligament. This can sometimes recover by itself but it does vary by location, nature of injury and the individual. There will normally be loads of swelling so will be important to assess function once inflammation has settled.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;I’ve known of people to live comfortably without a particular ligament, they don’t always warrant surgery. I myself have completely torn one of my ankle ligaments 4 years ago and I can run and play football without an issue.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;However, if the ligament (eg. ACL, MCL, ATFL) doesn’t recover and it causing instability, and you want to get back into your sport/hobby then surgery might be needed to repair the ligament.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Muscle</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/wound/muscle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/wound/muscle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Better vasculature than ligaments and tendons - so faster healing time - 2-4 weeks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nerve damage</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/wound/nerve-damage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/wound/nerve-damage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3-4 mm/day&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tendon tear</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/wound/tendon-tear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/wound/tendon-tear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tendons attach muscles to bones. Tendons generally have a more limited blood supply than muscles.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Healing can take up to 12 weeks. The injured tendon may need to be supported with a splint or cast to take tension off of the repaired tendon.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tendons tend to respond well to a particular type of tension. Eccentric activity, which means that a tendon is stressed while it is being lengthened, is particularly helpful for tendon remodeling after injury.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
