<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The successors of the kaunteya-s in the national memory of bhArata-s and bhoTa-s and related discursions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/2013-12-26_the-successors-of-the-kaunteya-s-in-the-national-memory-of-bharata-s-and-bhota-s-and-related-discursions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/2013-12-26_the-successors-of-the-kaunteya-s-in-the-national-memory-of-bharata-s-and-bhota-s-and-related-discursions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2013/12/26/the-successors-of-the-kaunteya-s-in-the-national-memory-of-bharata-s-and-bhota-s-and-related-discursions/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;.&#xA;-۩۞۩-۩۞۩-۩۞۩-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;indic-vs-han-influence&#34;&gt;Indic vs Han influence&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;western-presentation&#34;&gt;Western presentation&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now we shall take a detour into the history of a neighboring nation,&#xA;which shares close cultural links with our own, that in recent times has&#xA;been blithely swallowed by Han imperialism. Indeed, as though to mirror&#xA;the obliteration of this nation from the maps of the world, a certain&#xA;strand of modern white Tibetologists tend to attribute greater than&#xA;observed roles for the Han in the emergence of the Tibetan civilization.&#xA;These present the Indic role as a later one, coming in the form of the&#xA;Tantric state, which caused the Tibetans to lapse into a medieval la-la&#xA;land from which they were awakened into modernity by the successive&#xA;actions of the English and the Han conquerors under Mao Zedong. The role&#xA;of the Tibetan emperor (tsenpo) in aiding the Chinese invasion of the&#xA;Indian province of tirAbhukti after harShavardhana’s death is seen as&#xA;evidence for subservient alignment, right from the inception of the&#xA;Tibetan state, with the Han as opposed to the Hindu.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese incursion of 2013: Just the beginning?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/2013-04-25_chinese-incursion-of-2013-just-the-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/2013-04-25_chinese-incursion-of-2013-just-the-beginning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2013/04/25/chinese-incursion-of-2013-just-the-beginning/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hindus face three major civilizational threats – two from the Abrahamisms, the religions of peace and love, and one from the legalistic Han imperialism. The assault from the religion of love is primarily spear-headed by the leukosphere and is abetted by their internal allies in the form of the shava-sAdhaka-s within India. The onslaught from the religion of peace belongs to the whole umma, but the primary ghazis deployed against the Hindus come from remnants of the Mogol empire in the form of terrorist state of Pakistan, the terrorist state of Bangladesh, Malaysia and Indonesia. Many Hindus wrongly believe that the Han are not a civilizational enemy, but the conflict with them is a recent and unfortunate consequence of Marxism. As we stated before the Marxism and Westernism of the chIna-s is only a facade for the inner legalism, which has conferred identity to chIna policy since the days of the wall-building Chin Shi Huang. Per say Marxists are merely subversionist rabble who might by used by all the three civilizational enemies of ours. Some interlocutors have questioned, somewhat indignantly, as to how we could call our Asian neighbor and a hoary nation a civilizational enemy. The problem is these people, like many other Hindus, have not studied history too closely. Nor have they understood the essentiality of an uncompromising, maximalist Hindu realist position. To briefly reiterate, this position entails the total defanging of the religions of peace and love, along with the restoration of global paganism nourished by the benign light of bhArata. Of course this naturally includes restoration of the Tibetan, and other central Asian pagan traditions, which is in direct conflict with the Han rapacity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crispr clones</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/crispr-clones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/crispr-clones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1067286599845797888.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since everyone and their mother are talking about the birth of CRISPR Dong and CRISPR Ding I’m piling on with a couple of long threads.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m just saying a little bit about the science in case someone is interested but mostly the politics:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They disrupted the CCR5 gene which codes for a 7-transmembrane receptor protein for at least 5 signaling proteins called chemokines in the immune system. It is expressed on many cells of the immune system called white blood cells in lay language and is used as the receptor by HIV-1 one of the AIDS viruses. It might have been used in someway by the unrelated smallpox virus too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early-medical-thought</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/early-medical-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/early-medical-thought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;scientific&amp;rdquo; thought of a chIna warlord &amp;amp; intellectual Cao Zhi whose clan brought an end to the Later Han during a past epidemic that ripped through the late Han world. An e.g., of rationalism the recurs through diverse cultures in a rather similar form.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the twenty-second year of Jian-an (217 C.E.), the infectious disease roamed about, every family experienced the pain of death, and every household was mourning with sad outcry. Some families died out com- pletely, other clans perished altogether. People thought that the disease was caused by ghosts and spirits&amp;hellip;. This is because yin and yang are dis- located and hot and cold weathers missed their proper time. This is why disease comes about. And yet foolish people hang talismans to exorcise it, which is quite laughable.12&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geopolitics</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/geopolitics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/geopolitics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1639695934501076993.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;demographic-window&#34;&gt;Demographic window&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The more one looks, it seems the demographic window for chIna adventurism is rather limited &amp;ndash; whether they want to conquer Taiwan or invade India or even, for that matter, Mongolia in a lamaistic frenzy. The emperor has to move in his current term. So one can interpret his pact with the rUs as giving the space for just that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;india-as-pawn&#34;&gt;India as pawn&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The intention of the mahAmlechCha-led pa&lt;del&gt;nchanetraka-s is to force H as cannon fodder against the chIna-s. Yet we can see how, as predicted, the gardabhin-s are trying their best to foment trouble in bhArata with 1st responders. How does this square with the hope of using H as cannon fodder against the Han? The conspiracy theory goes thus: if H are left to themselves, they would dictate their own foreign policy &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;I chose when &amp;amp; how to react to the chIna incursions&amp;rdquo;. However, if they are weakened by the pa&lt;/del&gt;nchanetraka-backed 1st responders, it would both embolden the chIna-s to move against H &amp;amp; at the same time, make the H paradoxically more dependent on mahAmlechCha-s for assistance as the old rUs ally seems to have been drawn away by the new alliance with the Han. Thus, rather than fight the chIna-s directly, the mahAmlechCha &amp;amp; their allies would like to engineer a chIna-H clash that would weaken both &amp;ndash; a desired objective in their highly predictive geopolitical framework &amp;ndash; realism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Koxinga ghost dictation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/koxinga-ghost-dictation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/koxinga-ghost-dictation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1947164601772061120&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Heard from a Taiwanese gentleman that he took a ghost dictation from Sino-Japanese hero Koxinga (國姓爺 &amp;ndash; what complicated set of characters for the non-chIna!). It had a profound religious effect on him, and he gave up alcohol and straightened his life (private). He mentioned that Koxinga&amp;rsquo;s ghost sometimes possesses people in Taiwan and speaks through them like kabandha AtharvaNa. For others, he appears in dreams. He rolled the dictation into a locket and keeps it as an amulet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liu Ju</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/liu-ju/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/liu-ju/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Liu Ju ~940 CE:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The kingdom of India (Tianzhu天竺) is the kingdom of Shendu 身毒 of the Han [records], also called “the land of the brāhmaṇa” (bolouomen 婆羅門). Having the “Onion Mountains” (Karakorum-Pamir) to its northwest, it encompasses more than 30000 li.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;trnsl. by M. Deeg&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I guess mlechCha and other mlechCha-inspired H haters will feel offended by the name conferred by the chIna chronicler.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As Deeg observe,s there is some consistency in foreign accounts of bhArata from West &amp;amp; East: Whom do you think Pliny the elder is talking about? It is hardly a wonder that they want to &amp;ldquo;storm that fortress.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wuhan tackling</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/wuhan-tackling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/wuhan-tackling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;wuhan-return&#34;&gt;Wuhan return&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1605039835512655872&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The return of Wuhan to the motherland has animated little Galtons galore to carry a bit of water for the emperor. But their strategy does raise a number of possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, it does seem like they were either on the brink of a serious rebellion or an economic blizzard to let go of their earlier restrictions all of a sudden. This makes sense in light of their attempt at a landgrab in India &amp;ndash; a classic move to direct attention outwards. Then the legalist inner circle of the emperor perhaps thought that it is best to let disease run through for that would be the best way to distract from the possibility of a rebellion and automatically cause the people to panic about other things &amp;amp; increase their dependency on the rulers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xuanzang&#39;s record</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/xuanzang-record/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/proto-asian/sino-tibetan/china/articles/MT/xuanzang-record/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second section of Xuanzang&amp;rsquo;s record is systematic a Tang&amp;rsquo;s spy&amp;rsquo;s dispatch or the probing of a white indologist: Below are its subsections:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The names of India&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The general geographical situation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Measures of distance&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Measures of time&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Settlements and residences&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Outer appearance, clothes, and adornment&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hygiene and purity&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The writing system&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Official documents&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;General education and knowledge&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The four Vedas&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Teachers and scholars&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Buddhist learning and Buddhist institutions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The caste system&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The military system&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The legal system&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Etiquette and behavior&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Illness and medical care&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Death and funerary customs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Administration and taxation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Agriculture and products&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Food and drinks&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Utensils and tools for preparing and eating food&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Precious items and money&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Climate&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-translation from the Chinese by the sinologist Max Deeg.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
