<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Khitans and Mongols A</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/2023-05-24_khitans-and-mongols-a-story-of-deep-and-persistent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/2023-05-24_khitans-and-mongols-a-story-of-deep-and-persistent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2023/05/24/khitans-and-mongols-a-story-of-deep-and-persistent-connections-1/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Khitans and Mongols: A story of deep and persistent connections-1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While the Chingizid Mongols have long been the focus of students of medieval steppe history, studies over the past 50 years have been steadily contributing to the picture that they were heirs of a previously neglected and even now underappreciated power – the Khitans. The story of the Khitans before their meteoric rise to imperial power was until recently shrouded in the mists of history. This starts with their ethnicity and language. The Iraqi Arab historian Ibn al-Athīr (whose tomb was recently demolished by the al-Qaeda), writing in the 1200s in his al-Kāmil fī al-ta’rīkh records the Islamization of the Turks with almost perceptible glee. He first claimed that a horde of 100000-200000 “tents” of Turks were Islamized (evidently referring to the Qarakhanids, a branch of the Qarluk Turks). Then he mentions that a smaller band of 10000 “tents” were Mohammedanized, after which “only the Khitans and the Tatars remained infidels”. This evidently referred to the Khitans and the Mongols. Based on this, early historians took the Khitans to be another branch of Turks. However, starting from Rashid ad-Din, the physician-historian of Jewish origin, there has been the counter-proposal that they were Mongols. Starting about 70 years ago, this theory was revived and expanded by the Japanese Khitanologists, who proposed that they were a proto-Mongolic group. However, over the past 50 years, the evidence has been decisively building for the Khitans being a para-Mongolic people with a long history before their rise to imperial power. In the first of the notes on this topic, we shall consider some aspects of the timing of the Khitan-Mongol divergence and their prolonged interaction until the absorption of the former by the Chingizid Mongols.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1911-freedom</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/1911-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/1911-freedom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1608869568050790400.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;111 years ago, on 29/12/1911, Mongolia declared independence. A while ago, I made a thread on the topic. Since some readers back then commented on whom exactly Mongolia declared independence from, here&amp;rsquo;s a follow-up🧵 I was careful in writing that, back in 1911, the Bogd Khaan had declared independence from the Qing Empire – not from China – because from a Mongolian perspective, this point was and is a crucial distinction. It clashes with the Chinese interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avar khanate</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/avar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/avar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rattibha.com/thread/1510476770629275649?lang=en&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Origins of the Avar elite elucidated with ancient DNA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Less known than Attila’s Huns, the Avars were their more successful successors. They ruled much of Central and Eastern Europe for almost 250 years. They came from Central Asia in the 6th C AD, but their provenance was debated.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a new study, a multidisciplinary team analysed 66 individuals from the Carpathian Basin, covering the entire Avar period as well as the preceding era. The study included the eight richest Avar graves ever discovered, overflowing with golden objects. The earlier genomes were typical of west Eurasians and mostly overlap with the genetic profile of modern-day inhabitants of the region. But the Avars were completely different. Their DNA largely matched that of ancient populations that inhabited the Mongolian plateau.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indian imprints in Baikal</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/indian-imprints_in_baikAl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/indian-imprints_in_baikAl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1557356226844827648.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Ancient Indian Imprints in Siberia&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Approximately 4000 kilometers to the northeast of India lies Lake Baikal. Lake Baikal is the world&amp;rsquo;s largest freshwater lake by volume, containing 22–23% of the world&amp;rsquo;s fresh surface water. And around Baikal in the Republic of Buryatia lives the Buryat community. This community has centuries-old ties to Indian ethos through Tibetan Buddhism, Hinduism, and other linkages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Lokesh Chandra, in his article - Indian Culture in Transbaikalian Siberia, published in 1970, gives us a great glimpse into these ties. This thread is based on his writing and some other sources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ja Lama kAlachakra ritual</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/ja-lAma-kAlachakra-ritual/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/ja-lAma-kAlachakra-ritual/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To boost his spiritual power in the eyes of followers, from time to time, Ja-Lama visualized and merged with the powerful god Mahakala, one of the “eight terrible ones, defenders of the Buddhist faith.+++(4)+++ He was also prone to literal interpretations of Tibetan Buddhist mythology and iconography. After the victory over the Chinese at Kobdo, Ja-Lama performed a public tantra session for his warriors. It was scripted according to ancient Kalachakra texts and involved a sickle, skull cups, blood, and hearts ripped out from the chests of the enemies. During this ceremony, Ja-lama, in a trance, turned into wrathful Mahakala, using the blood and hearts of prisoners to fill his skull cup the way Mahakala was portrayed doing on sacred scrolls. When a representative of the Bogdogegen rode into the crowd and confronted Ja-Lama with orders from the Bogdo-gegen to stop the ritual, he was killed in the ensuing melee. By morning, mixed with blood and soil, the sparks of civic notions lay dead, sacrificed to the altar of faith and race.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mongke, buddhist, christian</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/mongke_buddhist_christian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/mongke_buddhist_christian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The process of encounter between Buddhism and the West was a slow one, perhaps extending back to Alexander the Great and certainly made more complex by Buddhism’s virtual eradication in its native home (northern India and Nepal) during several phases of Islamic conquest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Buddhist doctrine and texts, originally recorded in Pali and Sanskrit, were subsequently disseminated via large translation projects throughout Central Asia: northward into Tibet, Nepal, China, Japan, and Mongolia, and eastward into Bhutan, Cambodia, Korea, Thailand, and Vietnam. The first recorded contact between a European and “the Buddhocratic government of Tibet” occurred in a remarkable interfaith gathering at the Karakorum court of the Khans in May 1254 (Batchelor, 93).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin-myth</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/origin-myth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/origin-myth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mongol origin mythology, as described by the Chingizid historian Saghang Sechen:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, on the establishment of the external universe, the main support of everything, from the celestial sphere that generally supports the internal beings: if we discuss the establishment of the very first of these, the external material world, it was established by three sorts of mandala-s. In particular, these three maṇḍala-s were&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the mandala creating wind,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the maṇḍala of billowing water, and&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the mandala supporting earth.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first of these three, the mandala of wind: because of the colliding together and the moving this way and that way of the great winds from the ten directions in the primordial emptiness of the celestial sphere, there was established a mandala of wind, indestructible and having a bluish color termed “delicate” (i.e., the sky).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>qorchin-ongods</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/qorchin-ongods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/qorchin-ongods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1690406526559612928.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A bucket with the images of the ongod-s of the shamans of the Qorchin tribe of Mongols. They are the descendants of Chingiz Khan&amp;rsquo;s brother Qasar &amp;amp; his followers. At the time of the rise of the Tungusic lord Nurhachi who founded the Manchu empire, they broke away from their cousins to join the resurgent Tungus &amp;amp; were major factor in their dominance &amp;amp; power down to the battles with the Europeans in China &amp;ndash; the last blaze of Mongol prowess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transbaikal state</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/transbaikal-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/transbaikal-state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rattibha.com/thread/1522243790962106370?lang=en&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I was reminded to write about a long-forgotten but nonetheless remarkable event that had taken place during the Russian Civil War in Eastern Sibеria. A thread about the first (and last) Buddhist theocratic state in Trаnsbaikal and the man behind it:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The “Kudun theocratic state” was established in 1919, partly in opposition to the military conscription of Khori Вuryats into Grigory Semyonov&amp;rsquo;s forces. It was headed by Lubsan Samdan Tsydenov, a Buddhist monk born &amp;amp; raised in a small Transbaikal village.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
