<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;19 The Philosopher Kings A D 96-180 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/19_The_Philosopher_Kings_A_D_96-180/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;19 The Philosopher Kings A D 96-180 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/19_The_Philosopher_Kings_A_D_96-180/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 NERVA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/19_The_Philosopher_Kings_A_D_96-180/01_NERVA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/19_The_Philosopher_Kings_A_D_96-180/01_NERVA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WITH the assassination of Domitian the principle of heredity disappeared for a century from Roman monarchy. The Senate had never recognized inheritance as a source of sovereignty; now, after 123 years of submission, it reasserted its authority; and as in Rome’s beginnings it had chosen the king, now it named one of its own members princeps and imperator. It was an act of courage intelligible only when we remember that the vigor of the Flavian family was exhausted in that same generation which had seen the vitality of the Senate renewed by Italian and provincial blood.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 TRAJAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/19_The_Philosopher_Kings_A_D_96-180/02_TRAJAN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/19_The_Philosopher_Kings_A_D_96-180/02_TRAJAN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trajan received word of his accession while he was in charge of a Roman army in Cologne. It was characteristic of him that he went on with his work at the frontier and postponed his coming to Rome for nearly two years. He had been born in Spain of an Italian family long settled there; in him and in Hadrian Roman Spain arrived at political hegemony, as it had reached literary leadership in Seneca, Lucan, and Martial. He was the first in a long line of generals whose provincial birth and training seemed to give them the will-to-life that had gone from the native Roman stock. That Rome made no protest against this enthronement of a provincial was in itself an event and omen in Roman history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 HADRIAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/19_The_Philosopher_Kings_A_D_96-180/03_HADRIAN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/19_The_Philosopher_Kings_A_D_96-180/03_HADRIAN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-the-ruler&#34;&gt;1. The Ruler&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Probably we shall never know whether the most brilliant of the Roman emperors won his throne by amorous connivance or by Trajan’s conviction of his worth. “His appointment,” says Dio Cassius, “was due to the fact that when Trajan died without an heir, his widow Plotina, who was in love with Hadrian, conspired to secure him the succession.”12 Spartianus repeats the story.13 Plotina and Hadrian denied the rumor, which nevertheless persisted to the end of his reign. He settled the matter by distributing a generous donative among the troops.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 ANTONINUS PIUS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/19_The_Philosopher_Kings_A_D_96-180/04_ANTONINUS_PIUS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/19_The_Philosopher_Kings_A_D_96-180/04_ANTONINUS_PIUS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Of Antoninus there is no history, for he had almost no faults and committed no crimes. His ancestors had come from Nimes two generations before, and his family was one of the wealthiest in Rome. Reaching the throne at fifty-one, he gave the Empire the most equitable, and not the least efficient, government it would ever have.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He was the most fortunate man that ever wore a crown. We are told that he was tall and handsome, healthy and serene, gentle and resolute, modest and omnipotent, eloquent and a despiser of rhetoric, popular and immune to flattery. If we are to believe his adopted son Marcus we should have to reject him as “that faultless monster whom the world ne’er knew.” The Senate called him &lt;em&gt;Pius&lt;/em&gt; as a model of the milder Roman virtues, and &lt;em&gt;Optimus Princeps&lt;/em&gt; as the best of princes. He had no enemies and hundreds of friends. But he was not unacquainted with grief. His elder daughter died as he was setting out as proconsul to Asia; his younger daughter proved a dubious wife to Aurelius; and scandal accused his own wife of being as faithless as she was beautiful. Antoninus bore these rumors silently; and after Faustina’s death he established in her name and honor a fund for the support and education of girls and raised to her memory one of the loveliest temples in the Forum. He did not marry again, lest he mar the happiness and inheritance of his children, but contented himself with a concubine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 THE PHILOSOPHER AS EMPEROR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/19_The_Philosopher_Kings_A_D_96-180/05_THE_PHILOSOPHER_AS_EMPEROR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/3_THE_PRINCIPATE_30_B_C_-A_D_192/19_The_Philosopher_Kings_A_D_96-180/05_THE_PHILOSOPHER_AS_EMPEROR/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Antoninus, said Renan, “would have been without competition for the reputation of being the best of sovereigns, had he not designated Marcus Aurelius as his heir.”41 “If,” said Gibbon, “a man were called upon to fix the period in the history of the world during which the condition of the human race was most happy and prosperous, he would without hesitation name that which elapsed from the accession of Nerva to the death of Aurelius. Their united reigns are possibly the only period of history in which the happiness of a great people was the sole object of government.”42&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
