<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#43;लक्ष्मी-ताताचार्याः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/lakShmI-tAtAchAryAH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/lakShmI-tAtAchAryAH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;anantacharya&#34;&gt;anantAchArya&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Also called Anantarya and Anandalvan, was born in the year 1053 AD at Siruputtur (now called Kirangur) on the banks of the Kaveri.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Went to Srirangam to study the philosophy of Vishistadvaita at the sacred feet of Sri Ramanujacharya.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Went to Tirupati to perform &amp;lsquo;pushpa-kainkaryam&amp;rsquo; of Lord Srinivasa in fulfillment of Namm-Alwar&amp;rsquo;s burning desire as directed by Acharya Ramanuja.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Was the epitome of devotion unto the devotees of the Lord (Charama-Parva-Nishthaa).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tirumala-chikka-govindaraja-udaiyavar&#34;&gt;TIRUMALA CHIKKA GOVINDARAJA UDAIYAVAR&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Famous descendant of Ananthacharya who initially lived at Tirumala during the time of Krishnadevaraya and later moved to Mandya District in Karnataka. Outstanding scholar, who defeated many other reputed scholars in debate&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;King Krishnadevaraya was so pleased with the scholarship that he profusely honored Chikka Govindaraja Udaiyavar and gifted him six villages in the present Mandya District. Later, Chikka Govindaraj Udaiyavar migrated to Karnataka along with Sri Vaishnavas of 13 Gothras and began living there. Thus the Mandayam Sri Vaishnava Community came into being.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;dasha-vidya-chakravarti-alwar-swami&#34;&gt;DASHA VIDYA CHAKRAVARTI ALWAR SWAMI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Popularly known as Alwar Swami, was born in 1850&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Could give discourses not only in Kannada, Tamil and Telugu, but in Hindi, Urdu and Gujarati as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Established the Vivekollasini Sabha at Melkote for conducting Acharya Ramanuja&amp;rsquo;s Tirunakshatram annually in a grand manner.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Because of his mastery in so many arts and sciences, in one gathering of people, he was accorded the title &amp;lsquo;Dasha-Vidya-Chakravarthy&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;The Emperor of Ten Types of Knowledge&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tarkateertha-mahavidvan-lakshmithathacharya-swami&#34;&gt;TARKATEERTHA MAHAVIDVAN LAKSHMITHATHACHARYA SWAMI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Born in 1873 in Srimukha Samvatsara under the Uttarashada Nakshatra.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Composed many &amp;lsquo;pada bandhas&amp;rsquo; in Sanskrit and was an outstanding Teacher.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;During School vacations used to engage himself in land development for farming.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Could unravel many difficult riddles and technical complexities of language of the Shastras and explain them with clarity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;panditha-raja-sri-uve-alwar-tirumalai-iyengar-swami&#34;&gt;PANDITHA RAJA SRI U.Ve. ALWAR TIRUMALAI IYENGAR SWAMI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Born in 1905, his radiant personality and spiritual power attracted many disciples.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;His discourses in many Sabhas earned accolades for scholarship and brilliance and have become legendary.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Was conferred many titles such as &amp;lsquo;Pandita Raja&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Pandita Prakanda&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Vidya Vachaspati&amp;rsquo; etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sri-uveprof-ma-lakshmithathacharya-swami&#34;&gt;SRI. U.Ve.PROF M.A. LAKSHMITHATHACHARYA SWAMI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Born in the year 1936, Simha Masa, and Mula Nakshatra.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eldest son of Panditha Raja Sri. U.Ve. Tirumalai Iyengar Swami and Smt. Singamma.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Founder of Academy of Sanskrit Research in Melukote (later subject to hostile takeover)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Founder of samskriti foundation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ma-alwar&#34;&gt;MA ALWAR&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jIva-gosvAmI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/jIva-gosvAmI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/jIva-gosvAmI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Srila Jiva Goswami is an important figure in the Indian Philosophical world. He appeared in the 16th century. He studied almost all the major indian philosophies. All of his knowledge is visible in his works. He authored works on philosophy, poetry, linguistics etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He was an expert in sanskrit grammar. He studied almost all grammars that were present at that time and composed his own sanskrit grammar named Harinamamrit Vyakran which is a novel contribution to the realm of sanskrit grammar. He has made his unique prakriya to form words. He has authored a total of 3 works related to sanskrit grammar. Śrī Harināmāmṛta-vyākaraṇa, Sūtra-mālikā, Dhātu-saṅgraha are those three works. Regarding his scholarship on vedas he has authored two books Gāyatrī-vivritti and Gopāla-tāpanī-ṭīkā.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tirumalai anantALvAn</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/tirumalai-anantALvAn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/tirumalai-anantALvAn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://acharya.org/bk/pb/Anandazhvan/ThirumalaiAnanthalwan-ABiography.pdf&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THIRUMALAI ANANTHALVAN&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A Biography Originally in Sanskrit&lt;br&gt;&#xA;By Sri.U.Ve. Mahavidvan Purisai Srirangachariyar Swami&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sthalacarya Purusha&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Tamil Version and Introduction By Sri.U.Ve.TA.Krishnamacharya Vidvan &amp;amp; Siromani&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Head of the Dept.of Nyaya (Retd) S.V.Oriental College,Tirupati&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Translated in to English by Shri.T.C.A.Ramanujam Chief Commissioner of Income Tax (Retd.) Member-Income Tax Appellate Tribunal (Retd.) Advocate-Madras&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;0&#34;&gt;0&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-man-of-courage&#34;&gt;The Man of Courage&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The title was given by Ramanuja to Ananthalvan who accepted to go to Tirumalai and cultivate the flower garden-nandavanam to serve the Lord Venkatesvara.Thousand years back, Tirumalai was a deep forest. It was not congenial for human habitation. There were ferocious animals like tigers and leopards, snakes and various poisonous reptiles. Only Ananthalvan had the courage to come and cultivate the garden there. Ramanuja appreciated this and called him as Anpillai -i.e Courageous man. Hence the successors came to be called Anantha-anpillai. When we look at the main deity viz Lord Venkatesvara in the Garbhagriha we find the application of Pacchaikarpuram (Medicated Camphor) at the chin. There is an anecdote in this regard. Ananthalvan was digging the tank and his wife was helping him. She picked up the dug-up earth and put it away at a distance. She was in an advanced state of pregnancy and was finding this task very difficult. A brahmachari came to her rescue and asked her to give the pan to him so that he would dump it at a distance. When Ananthalvan saw his wife returning so quickly, he asked her and she told that a brahmachari was helping her to throw away the mud. Ananthalvan was angry with the interruption of the stranger and he threw the spade at him. It hit the chin and the blood oozed. When archakas opened the temple, they found that the Lord was bleeding at the chin.The archakas then applied pacchaikarpuram and the bleeding stopped. The practice still continues. Ananthalvan’s garden is in the left side of the temple where Ananthalvan breathed the last. Lord Venkatesvara every year on this day visits the place and offers special honour to the tree under which Ananthalvan expired. There is another important historical aspect in Ananthalvan Valitttirunamam. Malaiyil Venkatavarku Mamanar Valiye. That means let him live long, who is the father in law of Venkatesa. This gives a clue by which we can get the&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vallabhaH on puShTimArg_net</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/vallabhaH_on_puShTimArg_net/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/vallabhaH_on_puShTimArg_net/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Date of Birth: Eleventh day of the dark half of Chaitra month of V.S. 1535&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Place of Birth: in the forest named Champaranya in India.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Left the World: At the age of 52 on the day of Rathayatra in V.S. 1587 he entered into the river Ganga and one bright bundle of light merged into the Sun and disappeared from the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;family&#34;&gt;Family&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;His father’s name was Lakshman Bhatta and mother’s name was Sri Illammagaru. Born in Vellanateeya community of Brahmana which is regarded as yet a pious and well educated community of India, his gotra was Bharadvaja and Sutra Apastamba. His ancestors were in study of the Taittireeya Shakha of the Krshna Yajurved. He had two sons. The elder one named Shri Gopinathji and the younger named Shri Vitthalnathji (popularly known as Shri Gusaiji).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vangI-pura-pUrNaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/vangI-pura-pUrNaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/vangI-pura-pUrNaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;vangi purathu nambi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;sriramanuja-vangi-purathu-nambi-art&lt;br&gt;&#xA;emperumAnAr and vangi purathu nambi&lt;br&gt;&#xA;thirunakshathram: not known&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;avathAra sthalam: not known (potentially vangi puram which is his father’s native place or srIrangam where his father vangi purathu Achi might have lived after becoming maNakkAl nambi‘s sishya)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AchAryan: emperumAnAr&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;sishyas: siriyAthAn&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;vangi purathu Achi is a sishya of maNakkAl nambi. vangi purathu nambi is the son of vangi purathu Achi and he goes on to become a sishya of emperumAnAr.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>अन्नमाचार्ये ऽचिन्त्यः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/annamAchArye_achintyaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/annamAchArye_achintyaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;.. श्री- ..&lt;br&gt;&#xA;śrīhi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tāllapāka Annamāchārya&lt;br&gt;&#xA;-Sri Adviteeya Dixit&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article also quotes extracts from a similar article previously published in the journal ‘Sri Nirisimha Priya’- English edition dated May, June and July 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;affiliation&#34;&gt;Affiliation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;श्रीवेङ्कटाचलाधीशं&lt;br&gt;&#xA;श्रियाऽध्यासितवक्षसम्&#xA;श्रित-चेतन-मन्दारं&lt;br&gt;&#xA;श्रीनिवासमहं भजे&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“I worship Lord Srinivāsa, the Lord of Vênkatachala Hill, the Lord whose chest is the abode of Goddess Lakshmi, and the one who is the wish-yielding tree for those who seek refuge in Him!”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>इञ्जिमेडूद्भवो रङ्गनाथः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/injimeDUdbhavo_ranganAthaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/injimeDUdbhavo_ranganAthaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ahobilamutt.org/us/acharya/bio/42jeer.asp&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-avataram&#34;&gt;1. AvatAram&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This great AchAryan was born on Janury 21, 1879. It was Thai UttharAdam in a BahudhA+anya (Different in many ways) samvathsaram (year). A great assembly of MahA PurushAs like PutthankOttakam Swamy, GhOshtiUr Swamy were born in that year, some 122 years back.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;42nd Azhagiyasingar&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;His place of birth was an agrahAram established for Vedic scholars on the banks of Baahu nadhi (SeyyARu river) by the most revered Sixth Azhagiya Singar, HH SrivaNN SatakOpa Srishashta ParAnkusa YathIdhra MahA Desikan. This AchArya Saarvabhouman adorned the peetam of Ahobila Matam from 1499-1513 CE and entered into a cave in Ahobilam and never returned. He is said to be performing AarAdhanam to Sri Lakshmi Narasimhan inside that cave even today. The agrahAram was given the name of Nrusimhapuram by the Sixth Azhagiya Singar and later came to be known as InjimEdu. It has a Sannidhi for Lord VaradarAjan. Our AchAryan&amp;rsquo;s gOthram was BhAradhvAja Gothram. His father&amp;rsquo;s name was Sri AadhivarAhAcchAr Swamy. His son was given the name of the Lord of Srirangam, RanganAthan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
