<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Roman fall on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/roman_fall/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Roman fall on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/roman_fall/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alexandria library hypatia loss</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/roman_fall/alexandria-library-hypatia-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/roman_fall/alexandria-library-hypatia-loss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/archeohistories/status/1813622768065232926&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;origin-and-structure&#34;&gt;Origin and structure&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alexandria was founded in Egypt by Alexander the Great. However, it was his successor as Pharaoh, Ptolemy I Soter, who founded the Museum (Museum of Alexandria, Greek Mouseion, “Seat of the Muses”) or Royal Library of Alexandria in 283 BC. The Museum was a shrine of the Muses modeled after the Lyceum of Aristotle in Athens. The Museum was a place of study that included lecture areas, gardens, a zoo, and shrines for each of the nine muses as well as the Library itself. Historians have estimated that at one time the Library of Alexandria held over half a million documents from Assyria, Greece, Persia, Egypt, India, and many other nations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alexandria violence 5 CE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/roman_fall/alexandria-violence-5CE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/roman_fall/alexandria-violence-5CE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Religious and Intercommunal Violence in Alexandria in the 4th and 5th centuries CE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lauren Kaplow&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The fourth and fifth centuries CE were a time of vast social and religious change in the Eastern Roman empire. Going into this time period, Christianity had just begun to be an important player in imperial politics and religious policy, and by the mid-fifth century it had become clearly dominant. The power politics of cities changed as ecclesiastical appointees began to compete with comparable civil officials. The conflicts involved in divisive doctrinal debates spread and then receded. Alexandria, like all eastern cities, was not left unscathed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead fall</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/roman_fall/lead-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/roman_fall/lead-fall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;April 6, 2004: What is the history of lead poisoning?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This question of the week is just for fun and for those with an interest in toxicology history.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lead Poisoning and the Demise of the Ancient Roman Empire&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hence gout and stone afflict the human race;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Hence lazy jaundice with her saffron face;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Palsy, with shaking head and tott&amp;rsquo;ring knees.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And bloated dropsy, the staunch sot&amp;rsquo;s disease;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Consumption, pale, with keen but hollow eye,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And sharpened feature, shew&amp;rsquo;d that death was nigh.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The feeble offspring curse their crazy sires,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And, tainted from his birth, the youth expires.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(Description of lead poisoning by an anonymous Roman hermit,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Translated by Humelbergius Secundus, 1829)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maniots</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/roman_fall/maniot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/roman_fall/maniot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rattibha.com/thread/1500848163007217671?lang=en&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Did you know Greek Paganism survived well into the Medieval period? Let’s explore the Mani Peninsula, where the last worshippers of Zeus, Ares, and Apollo clung to the rocky cliffs. The Mani Peninsula is a craggy spur of the Peloponnese, Mani meaning “dry” or “barren.” The people of the peninsula lived in fortified villages and “house-towers,” most settlements were only accessible from the sea.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Maniots, claiming ancestry from the famed Spartans, lived as fierce warriors and pirates. The people of the isolated peninsula often engaged in blood feuds and stubbornly resisted any attempts at conquest from outsiders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rome fall date</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/roman_fall/rome-fall-date/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/roman_fall/rome-fall-date/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rome Didn&amp;rsquo;t Fall When You Think It Did&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Source: BY EDWARD J. WATTS OCTOBER 6, 2021 4:18 PM EDT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In September of 476 AD, the barbarian commander Odoacer forced the teenaged Western Roman emperor Romulus Augustus to resign his office. The Constantinopolitan chronicler Marcellinus Comes would write in the 510s that when “Odoacer, king of the Goths, took control of Rome” the “Western Empire of the Roman people … perished.” But no one thought this at the time. The fall of Rome in 476 is a historical turning point that was invented nearly 50 years later as a pretext for a devastating war. The fact that it has since become recognized as the end of an epoch shows how history can be misused to justify otherwise unpalatable actions in the present—and how that misuse can also distort the lessons future generations take from the past.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
