<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;addresses on bhakti-yoga on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/addresses_on_bhakti-yoga/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;addresses on bhakti-yoga on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/addresses_on_bhakti-yoga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>171 THE PREPARATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/addresses_on_bhakti-yoga/171_the_preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/addresses_on_bhakti-yoga/171_the_preparation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-preparation&#34;&gt;THE PREPARATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best definition given of Bhakti-Yoga is perhaps embodied in the&#xA;verse: &amp;ldquo;May that love undying which the non-discriminating have for the&#xA;fleeting objects of the senses never leave this heart of mine — of me&#xA;who seek after Thee!&amp;rdquo; We see what a strong love men, who do not know any&#xA;better, have for sense-objects, for money, dress, their wives, children,&#xA;friends, and possessions. What a tremendous clinging they have to all&#xA;these things! So in the above prayer the sage says, &amp;ldquo;I will have that&#xA;attachment, that tremendous clinging, only to Thee.&amp;rdquo; This love, when&#xA;given to God, is called Bhakti. Bhakti is not destructive; it teaches us&#xA;that no one of the faculties we have has been given in vain, that&#xA;through them is the natural way to come to liberation. Bhakti does not&#xA;kill out our tendencies, it does not go against nature, but only gives&#xA;it a higher and more powerful direction. How naturally we love objects&#xA;of the senses! We cannot but do so, because they are so real to us. We&#xA;do not ordinarily see anything real about higher things, but when a man&#xA;has seen something real beyond the senses, beyond the universe of&#xA;senses, the idea is that he can have a strong attachment, only it should&#xA;be transferred to the object beyond the senses, which is God. And when&#xA;the same kind of love that has before been given to sense-objects is&#xA;given to God, it is called Bhakti. According to the sage Rāmānuja, the&#xA;following are the preparations for getting that intense love.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>172 THE FIRST STEPS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/addresses_on_bhakti-yoga/172_the_first_steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/addresses_on_bhakti-yoga/172_the_first_steps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-steps&#34;&gt;THE FIRST STEPS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The philosophers who wrote on Bhakti defined it as extreme love for God.&#xA;Why a man should love God is the question to be solved; and until we&#xA;understand that, we shall not be able to grasp the subject at all. There&#xA;are two entirely different ideals of life. A man of any country who has&#xA;any religion knows that he is a body and a spirit also. But there is a&#xA;great deal of difference as to the goal of human life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>173 THE TEACHER OF SPIRITUALITY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/addresses_on_bhakti-yoga/173_the_teacher_of_spirituality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/addresses_on_bhakti-yoga/173_the_teacher_of_spirituality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-teacher-of-spirituality&#34;&gt;THE TEACHER OF SPIRITUALITY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every soul is destined to be perfect, and every being, in the end, will&#xA;attain to that state. Whatever we are now is the result of whatever we&#xA;have been or thought in the past; and whatever we shall be in the future&#xA;will be the result of what we do or think now. But this does not&#xA;preclude our receiving help from outside; the possibilities of the soul&#xA;are always quickened by some help from outside, so much so that in the&#xA;vast majority of cases in the world, help from outside is almost&#xA;absolutely necessary. Quickening influence comes from outside, and that&#xA;works upon our own potentialities; and then the growth begins, spiritual&#xA;life comes, and man becomes holy and perfect in the end. This quickening&#xA;impulse which comes from outside cannot be received from books; the soul&#xA;can receive impulse only from another soul, and from nothing else. We&#xA;may study books all our lives, we may become very intellectual, but in&#xA;the end we find we have not developed at all spiritually. It does not&#xA;follow that a high order of intellectual development always shows an&#xA;equivalent development of the spiritual side of man; on the other hand,&#xA;we find cases almost every day where the intellect has become very&#xA;highly developed at the expense of the spirit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>174 THE NEED OF SYMBOLS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/addresses_on_bhakti-yoga/174_the_need_of_symbols/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/addresses_on_bhakti-yoga/174_the_need_of_symbols/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-need-of-symbols&#34;&gt;THE NEED OF SYMBOLS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bhakti is divided into two portions. One is called Vaidhi, formal or&#xA;ceremonial; the other portion is called Mukhyā, supreme. The word Bhakti&#xA;covers all the ground between the lowest form of worship and the highest&#xA;form of life. All the worship that you have seen in any country in the&#xA;world, or in any religion, is regulated by love. There is a good deal&#xA;that is simple ceremony; there is also a good deal which, though not&#xA;ceremony, is still not love, but a lower state. Yet these ceremonies are&#xA;necessary. The external part of Bhakti is absolutely necessary to help&#xA;the soul onward. Man makes a great mistake when he thinks that he can at&#xA;once jump to the highest state. If a baby thinks he is going to be an&#xA;old man in a day, he is mistaken; and I hope you will always bear in&#xA;mind this one ideal, that religion is neither in books, nor in&#xA;intellectual consent, nor in reasoning. Reason, theories, documents,&#xA;doctrines, books, religious ceremonies, are all &lt;em&gt;helps&lt;/em&gt; to religion:&#xA;religion itself consists in &lt;em&gt;realisation&lt;/em&gt;. We all say, &amp;ldquo;There is a God.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Have you seen God? That is the question. You hear a man say, &amp;ldquo;There is&#xA;God in heaven.&amp;rdquo; You ask him if he has seen Him, and if he says he has,&#xA;you would laugh at him and say he is a maniac. With most people religion&#xA;is a sort of intellectual assent and goes no further than a document. I&#xA;would not call it religion. It is better to be an atheist than to have&#xA;that sort of religion. Religion does not depend on our intellectual&#xA;assent or dissent. You say there is a soul. Have you seen the soul? How&#xA;is it we all have souls and do not see them? You have to answer the&#xA;question and find out the way to see the soul. If not, it is useless to&#xA;talk of religion. If any religion is true, it must be able to show us&#xA;the soul and show us God and the truth in ourselves. If you and I fight&#xA;for all eternity about one of these doctrines or documents, we shall&#xA;never come to any conclusion. People have been fighting for ages, and&#xA;what is the outcome? Intellect cannot reach there at all. We have to go&#xA;beyond the intellect; the proof of religion is in direct perception. The&#xA;proof of the existence of this wall is that we see it; if you sat down&#xA;and argued about its existence or non-existence for ages, you could&#xA;never come to any conclusion; but directly you see it, it is enough. If&#xA;all the men in the world told you it did not exist, you would not&#xA;believe them, because you know that the evidence of your own eyes is&#xA;superior to that of all the doctrines and documents in the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>175 THE CHIEF SYMBOLS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/addresses_on_bhakti-yoga/175_the_chief_symbols/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/addresses_on_bhakti-yoga/175_the_chief_symbols/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-chief-symbols&#34;&gt;THE CHIEF SYMBOLS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two Sanskrit words, Pratika and Pratimā. Pratika means coming&#xA;towards, nearing. In all countries you find various grades of worship.&#xA;In this country, for instance, there are people who worship images of&#xA;saints, there are people who worship certain forms and symbols. Then&#xA;there are people who worship different beings who are higher than men,&#xA;and their number is increasing very rapidly — worshippers of departed&#xA;spirits. I read that there are something like eight millions of them&#xA;here. Then there are other people who worship certain beings of higher&#xA;grade — the angels, the gods, and so forth. Bhakti-Yoga does not condemn&#xA;any one of these various grades, but they are all classed under one&#xA;name, Pratika. These people are not worshipping God, but Pratika,&#xA;something which is near, a step towards God. This Pratika worship cannot&#xA;lead us to salvation and freedom; it can only give us certain particular&#xA;things for which we worship them. For instance, if a man worships his&#xA;departed ancestors or departed friends, he may get certain powers or&#xA;certain information from them. Any particular gift that is got from&#xA;these objects of worship is called Vidyā, particular knowledge; but&#xA;freedom, the highest aim, comes only by worship of God Himself. Some&#xA;Orientalists think, in expounding the Vedas, that even the Personal God&#xA;Himself is a Pratika. The Personal God may be a Pratika, but the&#xA;Pratikas are neither the Personal nor Impersonal God. They cannot be&#xA;worshipped as God. So it would be a great mistake if people thought that&#xA;by worshipping these different Pratikas, either as angels, or ancestors,&#xA;or Mahātmās (holy men, saints), etc., or departed spirits, they could&#xA;ever reach to freedom. At best they can only reach to certain powers,&#xA;but God alone can make us free. But because of that they are not to be&#xA;condemned, their worship produces some result. The man who does not&#xA;understand anything higher may get some power, some enjoyment, by the&#xA;worship of these Pratikas; and after a long course of experience, when&#xA;he will be ready to come to freedom, he will of his own accord give up&#xA;the Pratikas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>176 THE ISHTA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/addresses_on_bhakti-yoga/176_the_ishta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/vivekAnanda/volume_4/addresses_on_bhakti-yoga/176_the_ishta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ishta&#34;&gt;THE ISHTA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The theory of Ishta, which I briefly referred to before, is a subject&#xA;requiring careful attention because with a proper understanding of this,&#xA;all the various religions of the world can be understood. The word Ishta&#xA;is derived from the root Ish, to desire, choose. The ideal of all&#xA;religions, all sects, is the same — the attaining of liberty and&#xA;cessation of misery. Wherever you find religion, you find this ideal&#xA;working in one form or other. Of course in lower stages of religion it&#xA;is not so well expressed; but still, well or ill-expressed, it is the&#xA;one goal to which every religion approaches. All of us want to get rid&#xA;of misery; we are struggling to attain to liberty — physical, mental,&#xA;spiritual. This is the whole idea upon which the world is working.&#xA;Through the goal is one and the same, there may be many ways to reach&#xA;it, and these ways are determined by the peculiarities of our nature.&#xA;One man&amp;rsquo;s nature is emotional, another&amp;rsquo;s intellectual, another&amp;rsquo;s active,&#xA;and so forth. Again, in the same nature there may be many subdivisions.&#xA;Take for instance love, with which we are specially concerned in this&#xA;subject of Bhakti. One man&amp;rsquo;s nature has a stronger love for children;&#xA;another has it for wife, another for mother, another for father, another&#xA;for friends. Another by nature has love for country, and a few love&#xA;humanity in the broadest sense; they are of course very few, although&#xA;everyone of us talks of it as if it were the guiding motive power of our&#xA;lives. Some few sages have experienced it. A few great souls among&#xA;mankind feel this universal love, and let us hope that this world will&#xA;never be without such men.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
