<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>100 y storage</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/100y-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/100y-storage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://lil.law.harvard.edu/century-scale-storage/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you had to store something for 100 years, how would you do it?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Century-Scale Storage&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maxwell Neely-Cohen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lil.law.harvard.edu/&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the-building-by-the-plum-orchard&#34;&gt;The Building by the Plum Orchard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#hard-drives&#34;&gt;Hard Drives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the-cloud&#34;&gt;The Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#removable-media&#34;&gt;Removable Media&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#make-it-physical&#34;&gt;Make It Physical: Print and Rock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#dispersal&#34;&gt;Dispersal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#answers-and-non-answers&#34;&gt;Answers and Non-Answers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-building-by-the-plum-orchard&#34;&gt;The Building by the Plum Orchard&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the north side of downtown San Jose, tucked against a gentle curve in California State Route 87 and the Guadalupe River that it follows, sits a nondescript single-story off-white building with tinted windows. As of the time of writing this, signs exclaim that 99 Notre Dame Avenue is available for lease. The two adjacent lots are also empty and being used as parking lots, mostly as overflow for the municipal courthouse a few blocks away. Across the street the condos start, glassy and standardized, one pale red and cream and the next a mixture of aqua and silver, stretching to the sky for blocks east toward City Hall and south until you hit the looming corporate headquarters of Adobe Inc. The low building’s only active neighbor is a weightlifting and martial arts gym in the adjoining warehouse that gives no hint of what used to be built there. Otherwise it sits alone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Archival paper yt</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/archival-paper-yt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/archival-paper-yt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fAsr4-MT4zc&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[0:00] What makes a print archival and does that mean that the print will last forever?   [0:04] check out today&amp;rsquo;s video and you&amp;rsquo;ll find out [0:13]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;archival-paper&#34;&gt;Archival Paper&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Archival Paper [0:33] - they&amp;rsquo;re using archival paper and archival ink&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Archival paper means that the paper will last for   [0:41] many years think centuries&lt;br&gt;&#xA;before it starts  to break down and become brittle&lt;br&gt;&#xA;think about [0:46] a very old book that might be 100 200 years&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and if  you try to bend the sheet it will just break off   [0:53].&lt;br&gt;&#xA;that&amp;rsquo;s why acid-free and lignin-free are what  make paper considered archival&lt;br&gt;&#xA;because it&amp;rsquo;s the [0:59] acidity that&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s breaking down the paper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arnano sapphire nanoform</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/arnano-sapphire-nanoform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/arnano-sapphire-nanoform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arnano.fr/the-ultra-long-life-nanoform.html?lang=en&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A SOLUTION FOR LONG TERM SECURE PRESERVATION OF DIGITAL DATA&#xA;For any human organization (companies, institutions) the preservation of information or strategical documents due to their economic, juridical or patrimonial value is a major issue. Risks of loss of this information are increasing on very long-term.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to answer to this issue of conservation of digital information with high safety level, ARNANO developed a technology allowing « to reproduce » at a microscopic scale the documents on an extremely stable sapphire wafer. So it guaranties a very long life to the informations. The NANOFORM, sapphire wafer that can contain up to 10 000 A4 pages, is:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manuscript cost</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/manuscript-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/manuscript-cost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/satoverma/status/2012409628282544410&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1690s, if you were in Kashmir and wanted to procure a complete manuscript of Kashmiri recension of Mahabharata having ~1.1 lakhs shloka-s, what would be the price of it? We don&amp;rsquo;t need to hypothesize because there is a recorded sale of such a manuscript from 1682.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aurel Stein acquired a manuscript of Mahabharata from Kashmir in 1898. The text was written in Sharda script and it only contained a few parva-s as it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a complete manuscript. However, he found something quite interesting in the portion that he acquired.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Voyager golden record - ferris</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/voyager-golden-record_tim-ferris/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/backup/articles/voyager-golden-record_tim-ferris/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newyorker.com/tech/annals-of-technology/voyager-golden-record-40th-anniversary-timothy-ferris&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How the Voyager Golden Record Was Made&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Forty years ago, we sent a message to extraterrestrials—a collection of sights and sounds of life on Earth.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;By Timothy Ferris&lt;br&gt;&#xA;August 20, 2017&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We inhabit a small planet orbiting a medium-sized star about two-thirds of the way out from the center of the Milky Way galaxy—around where Track 2 on an LP record might begin. In cosmic terms, we are tiny: were the galaxy the size of a typical LP, the sun and all its planets would fit inside an atom’s width. Yet there is something in us so expansive that, four decades ago, we made a time capsule full of music and photographs from Earth and flung it out into the universe. Indeed, we made two of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
