<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Man, the Troglodyte and environment</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/MT/2005-12-24_man-the-troglodyte-and-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/MT/2005-12-24_man-the-troglodyte-and-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/12/24/man-the-troglodyte-and-environment/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;third-chimpanzee&#34;&gt;Third chimpanzee&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jared Diamond, a socialist American scientist wrote a book termed the “Third chimpanzee”. Here he highlighted the similarities between us and our cousins of the genus Pan, and the explosive spread of Homo in the recent past. There have been some recent works that allow us to exquisitely understand the transition from the ancestral condition, still recapitulated in many ways by the troglodytes and the gorillas to the derived condition seen in Homo. Homo is in many ways different from the other related apes. He is naked, his canines are reduced, he walks erect all the time in adulthood, having shed the undignified ambulation on the knuckles. The females of his species sexually signal to him with their inflated mammary glands and posteriors and he tends to observe reasonably long term pair formation with his mates. His big toe in unopposed, he is clumsy on trees compared to his cousins and much to his great pride he sports an enormous brain, that is unrivalled in the animal world. These changes appear to be quite a handful for a lineage that has been relatively conservative in its ways since the days Victoriapithecus that may be close to the ancestory of both the monkeys and apes, and the early apes such as Afropithecus, Heliopithecus and Otavipithecus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Founding fathers and other musings</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/MT/2005-12-23_founding-fathers-and-other-musings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/MT/2005-12-23_founding-fathers-and-other-musings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/12/23/founding-fathers-and-other-musings/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/1600/niall.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/320/niall.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/320/niall.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/1600/nurhachi.0.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/320/nurhachi.0.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/320/nurhachi.0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/1600/chingiz.2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/320/chingiz.2.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/320/chingiz.2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The results of recent chromosomal studies point to an interesting feature regarding the founding fathers of several nations. The biggest impact that has been uncovered to date appears to be that of Chingiz Kha’Khan, the founder of the great Mongol nation, who appears to have left behind 16 million male descendents in the modern world. More modestly the founder of the Manchu empire, the descendents of Chingiz Khan’s arch rivals the Jurchen, appears to have left behind 1.6 million descendents today. More recently it was noted that the legendary early Irish king, Uí Néill appears to have fathered a whole bunch of Irishmen such the McDonalds, McAlisters and McDougalls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#43;African Introgression</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/MT/african-introgression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/MT/african-introgression/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Studies in past 10 years that suggest two distinct introgression events in Africa with archaic: 1 before Af-non-Af split &amp;amp; 2. After the latter diverged. This means archaics were around in African until relatively recently.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interesting article studying several African groups in depth where the authors identify a possible archaic Homo which has introgressed into Africans independently of Neanderthals introgressing into the Eurasians. This is the network they reconstruct. Note the branch introgressing into the sub-Saharan Africans separated from other Homo sapiens more than 500 Kya. That is a deep split not long after the split of the sapiens lineage from neanderthal+denisova.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elite competition</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/MT/elite-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/MT/elite-competition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tressel.xyz/threads/1496304792578273284&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Article via @Rjrasva :https://t.co/HWd3vi2ew6&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It suggests that both dropping fertility &amp;amp; rise of navyonmAda are symptoms of the same problem of elite competition. However, IMO it neglects the important social contagion issue of navyonmAda &amp;ndash; paralleling other ekarAkShasa diseases&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The authors posit 2 systems of elite certification which they call &amp;ldquo;Prussian&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; rote learning &amp;amp; hard exams vs &amp;ldquo;Confucian&amp;rdquo;&amp;ndash; more subjective display of knowledge. They believe that navyonmAda has its roots the latter where it serves as means to beating the objective &amp;ldquo;Prussian&amp;rdquo; model which has been &amp;ldquo;gamed&amp;rdquo; by the elite wannabes.+++(4)+++ Indeed, the prAchya-s &amp;amp; to lesser degree the deshI-s have been at the forefront of gaming it to get into elite mlechCha institutions by cracking gate-keeping tests. When they do away with these tests, like demonitization it instantly nullifies the capital of the &amp;ldquo;Asians&amp;rdquo; to enter such institutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homo precursors</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/MT/homo-precursors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/MT/homo-precursors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1902237910952251693&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The development of a Hidden Markov model for population splits and rejoinings suggests that all modern sapiens are a 80:20% composite between two ancient Homo lineages that split from each other around 1.5 Mya! One of the lineages the (80% one) also gave rise to the Neanderthal-Denisovan lineage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This suggests that the 20% lineage was probably erectus, which split at some point from the heidelbergensis lineage, which could be the 80% one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inter specific competition</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/MT/inter-specific-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/MT/inter-specific-competition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2017/05/07/the-upper-story-in-a-few-pictures/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is interesting that it was almost as if the brain and testis of sapiens were protected against the genetic influence of Neanderthals. Not surprisingly, the Neanderthal variants contribute to depression &amp;amp; addiction in sapiens.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We had argued that the explosive parallel increases in brain size in the late lineages Homo was driven by interspecies conflict. They likely created lineage-specific genetic backgrounds wherein brain expressed alleles from other others would malfunction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Out of africa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/MT/out-of-africa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/MT/out-of-africa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;cave-art&#34;&gt;Cave art&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/2014864069941928122&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pretty old new cave art in the Indonesian far east from Liang Metanduno on Muna Island in southeastern Sulawesi. They date this to a minimum age of 67.8±3.8thousand years BP. This is well before the ~47-50 KYA emergence of modern H.sapiens out of Africa. Hence, could it be the Denisovans or late-surviving Indonesian erectus-like forms or an earlier extinct wave of sapiens?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The authors favor it being an extinct wave of sapiens. They also note it is close to the ~65 KYA  Madjedbebe evidence from northern Australia, which has been interpreted as evidence for the presence of an early pre-modern wave of sapiens that subsequently became extinct for unknown reasons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
