<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Caesar on druids</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/caesar_on_druids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/caesar_on_druids/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृत् - टिप्पनी&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Roman dictator Julius Caesar provides an account of the Druids in his Commentarii de Bello Gallico thusly (they were essentially the V1s of the Celts descending from the ancestral Corded Ware V1 progenitors from whom we also descend).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They are involved in divine matters, oversee public and private sacrifices, and interpret religious practices.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A large number of young men gather around them for the sake of learning,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and they are held in great honor among them.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;They are said to memorize a vast number of verses,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and some remain in training for as many as twenty years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impure-professions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/impure-professions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/impure-professions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Defiled Trades and Social Outcasts&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book presents a social and cultural history of &amp;ldquo;dishonorable people&amp;rdquo; (unehrliche Leute), an outcast group in early modern Germany. Executioners, skinners, grave-diggers, shepherds, barber-surgeons, millers, linen-weavers, sow-gelders, latrine-cleaners, and bailiffs were among the &amp;ldquo;dishonorable&amp;rdquo; by virtue of their trades. This dishonor was either inherited, often through several generations, or it arose from ritual pollution whereby honorable citizens could become dishonorable by coming into casual contact with members of the outcast group.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kennan - norway</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/kennan_norway/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/kennan_norway/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kristiansand, June 12 1974&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Norwegians, outwardly so simple, are not really that way at all, and their outlooks reveal some deformations that are positively weird. I was particularly struck this time with the anxious, fussy egalitarianism that seems to pervade political thought and to prevail in governmental practice. How is one to explain it?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Norwegian society comes closer than any other I know, closer even than the regular &amp;ldquo;Communist&amp;rdquo; societies, to the Marxist ideal of the classless society. A few people, very few, have some money and invest it, normally in shipping, but their style of life scarcely varies from that of all the others. I look in vain in the Kristiansand area for a single example of conspicuous affluence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Partiarchal Norse</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/patriarchal-norse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/patriarchal-norse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1516318103981932545.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christianization of Iceland in particular and Ancient Nordic societies more broadly was a complex and gradual process. It more or less rearranged the patriarchal rules — for example, prior to Christianization it was not considered necessary for men to get a woman’s consent before agreeing between themselves to marry her off. Christianization introduced the legal norm of actually ensuring the woman agrees to the marriage first. On the other hand, Christianization introduced an increased rhetoric of victim-blaming for rape that wasn’t as common previously. That’s just one example, the actual process of conversion is complex.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prussian army swelling</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/prussian-army-swelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/prussian-army-swelling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Faced with the mayhem generated by forced recruiting, the king changed tack and put an end to the practice inside his territories.53 In its place he established the sophisticated conscription mechanism that would come to be known as the &amp;lsquo;canton system&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An order of May 1714 declared that the obligation to serve in the king&amp;rsquo;s army was incumbent upon all men of serving age and that anyone fleeing the country in order to avoid this duty would be punished as a deserter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rjrasva on christianization</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/rjrasva_christianization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/rjrasva_christianization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;adalward&#34;&gt;Adalward&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/books/edition/The_Viking_Age/oBK_DwAAQBAJ?hl=en&amp;amp;gbpv=1&amp;amp;dq=glowing+with+fervor,+then,+adalward+entered+sweden&amp;amp;pg=PA403&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;29. Glowing with fervor, then, Adalward entered Sweden to preach the Gospel and in a short time led to the Christian faith all in Sigtuna and round about.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;He also secretly agreed with Egino, the most saintly bishop of Scania, that they should go together to the pagan temple called Uppsala&lt;br&gt;&#xA;to see if they could perhaps offer Christ&lt;br&gt;&#xA;some fruit of their labors there,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;for they would willingly undergo every kind of torture for the sake of destroying that house which was the seat of barbarous superstition.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For, if it were torn down, or preferably burned, the conversion of the whole nation might follow.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Observing that the people murmured about this design of the confessors of God,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;the most pious king Stenkil shrewdly kept them from such an undertaking,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;declaring that they would at once be punished with death and he be driven from the kingdom for bringing malefactors into the country,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and that everyone who now believed would quickly relapse into paganism,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;as they could see had lately been the case in Slavia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tacitus on manu tvAShTra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/tacitus_manu_tvAShTra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/articles/tacitus_manu_tvAShTra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(The Roman Tacitus writing about the Germanic peoples)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They celebrate with ancient songs, which is their only form of record and annals, that the god Tuisto, born from the earth, and his son Mannus, are the origin and founders of their race. To Mannus, they attribute three sons, from whose names the nearest tribes to the Ocean are called the Ingaevones, the central ones the Herminones, and the rest the Istaevones. Some, as is common with the liberty of antiquity, assert that more gods arose and that there are more names of peoples, including the Marsi, Gambrivii, Suebi, and Vandilii, and they claim these are the true and ancient names.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
