<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;1 Congress Decline on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/1_Congress_Decline/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;1 Congress Decline on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/1_Congress_Decline/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1961, October 3: Aligarh (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/1_Congress_Decline/1961_October_3_Aligarh_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/1_Congress_Decline/1961_October_3_Aligarh_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;57% Hindus, 41% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: C. B. Gupta, Congress Party, December 1960–October 1963&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After the Jabalpur riots, which badly shook the Indian leadership and the Prime Minister, Jawaharlal Nehru, further violence flared up in Aligarh (Uttar Pradesh), just before the 1962 general elections. The city is famous for the Aligarh Muslim University (AMU), whose students are predominantly Muslim and which has claimed minority status for years. During the student-union elections of October 1961, not a single Hindu student was elected. Muslims held a victory procession, provoking counter-demonstrations by activists from the BJS (Bharatiya Jan Sangh, Indian People’s Alliance) and the ABVP. A clash subsequently broke out between Muslim and Hindu students in a university hostel. A rumor that a Hindu student had been killed on campus sparked off violence in the city on October 3. University employees were assaulted by students from the town’s Hindu colleges. The riot claimed 14 lives, mostly Muslim.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1961, October 5–8: Meerut (Uttar Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/1_Congress_Decline/1961_October_58_Meerut_Uttar_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/1_Congress_Decline/1961_October_58_Meerut_Uttar_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;61% Hindus, 36% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh: C. B. Gupta, Congress Party, December 1960–October 1963&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Troubles also erupted in Meerut (Uttar Pradesh), after one Hindu student, a native of the town, was severely beaten by Muslim boys during clashes at the Aligarh Muslim University. Back in his hometown and supported by his father, a police officer, he led a procession of 150 supporters who targeted an old Muslim college and some Muslim-owned shops. Prominent members of the administration were present in the crowd and the police did nothing to intervene. The following day, an even larger Hindu procession gathered, threatening to enter a Muslim locality. Muslim residents rushed out of their houses, armed with lathis (sticks) - ready to defend their community. Instead of dispersing both the crowds, the police charged into the Muslim crowd. As a consequence, rioting broke out in several parts of the city. Violence lasted several days, claiming between 13 and 17 lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1961; February 4–9: Jabalpur (Madhya Pradesh)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/1_Congress_Decline/1961_February_49_Jabalpur_Madhya_Pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/1_Congress_Decline/1961_February_49_Jabalpur_Madhya_Pradesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Religious composition of the population (as per the 2001 census): 80% Hindus, 14% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Madhya Pradesh: K.N. Katju, Congress Party, January 1957 - March 1962&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first major-scale riot between Hindus and Muslims in post-Partition India erupted in the city of Jabalpur in the state of Madhya Pradesh. This riot was linked to the emergence of a small class of successful Muslim entrepreneurs who created a new economic rivalry between the Hindu and Muslim communities. The immediate cause of the violence, however, remains unknown. Two versions exist.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1964; March: Calcutta (West Bengal), Jamshedpur (Bihar), Rourkela (Orissa)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/1_Congress_Decline/1964_March_Calcutta_West_Bengal_Jamshedpur_Bihar_Rourkela_Orissa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/1_Congress_Decline/1964_March_Calcutta_West_Bengal_Jamshedpur_Bihar_Rourkela_Orissa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Calcutta 78% Hindus, 20% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of West Bengal: P. Chandra Sen, Congress Party, July 1962–March 1967&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jamshedpur 81% Hindus, 9% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Bihar: K. B. Sahay, Congress Party, October 1963–March 1967&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rourkela 84% Hindus, 9% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Orissa: Biren Mitra, Congress Party, October 1963–February 1965&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ghastly violence engulfed the cities of Calcutta (West Bengal), Jamshedpur (Bihar), and Rourkela (Orissa). These riots were part of a cross-national (affecting India, Pakistan and East Pakistan) chain of events: the theft of a relic hair of the Prophet Mohammed from the Hazratbal mosque in Srinagar (Kashmir) on December 27, 1963 provoked indignation in Pakistan and East-Pakistan (now Bangladesh). Protest marches and violence against the Hindu minorities took place in the cities of Khulna and Jessore (East Pakistan) on January 2 and 3, 1964. This led to retaliation against Muslims in Calcutta and in West Bengal, which in turn kindled events in Dacca and Naryangunj (East Pakistan), where minority communities (of Hindus, Christians, and Buddhists) were heavily targeted (although, ultimately, the holy relic was returned on January 4). According to the 1965 Report of the Indian Commission of Jurists on Recurrent Exodus of Minorities from East Pakistan and Disturbances in India thousands of Hindu families left East Pakistan and sought refuge in India after January 5. The Indian government arranged for special trains to deliver them to the states of Bihar, Orissa, and Madhya Pradesh where they were to be received. As these trains crossed through Indian towns, the narrative of the atrocities that Hindus had suffered in East Pakistan spread, triggering anti-Muslim riots. Jamshedpur (Bihar) and Rourkela (Orissa) were particularly affected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1967; August 22–29: Ranchi (Bihar)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/1_Congress_Decline/1967_August_2229_Ranchi_Bihar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/1_Congress_Decline/1967_August_2229_Ranchi_Bihar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;63% Hindus, 17% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Bihar: Mahamaya Pd Sinha, Jan Kranti Dal, March 1967–January 1968&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Troubles erupted between Hindus and Muslims in the towns of Hatia and Ranchi (Bihar). Rioting had already occurred in the district in 1964, following anti-Hindu violence in East Pakistan. The Raghubar Dayal Commission of Inquiry established that communal tensions (regarding the organization of the Hindu Ram Navami festival) had been rising since April 1964. The 1965 conflict with Pakistan had also reinforced suspicions about Indian Muslims. During the March 1967 general elections, the situation further degenerated because of the debate over the Urdu issue (the language commonly spoken by Muslims). A proposal to declare Urdu the second official language of Bihar weakened the ruling coalition and led to state-wide, anti-Urdu agitation on the part of the BJS, the RSS, and an organization called the Bihar Hindi Sahitiya Sammelan. Trouble erupted in Ranchi on August 22 after the brick-batting of an anti-Urdu student procession near Muslim Azad High School. The school was attacked and one Hindu was killed in retaliation. The Raghubar Dayal Commission of Inquiry reported 184 deaths in Ranchi - among them 164 Muslims and 19 Hindus. Violence spread, leading to arson, looting, stabbings, and large-scale rioting in the city itself as well as in nearby industrial towns, particularly Hatia, where 26 persons died (25 Muslims and one Hindu).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1968; March: Karimganj (Assam)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/1_Congress_Decline/1968_March_Karimganj_Assam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/1_Congress_Decline/1968_March_Karimganj_Assam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;47% Hindus, 52% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Assam: B. P. Chaliha, Congress Party, December 1957–November 1970&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Violence flared up in the district of Karimganj (Assam) after an argument erupted between Hindu and Muslim teenagers, merely over a cow. An existing local rivalry between Hindu and Muslim smugglers constituted the underlying cause of the riots. Other accounts noted that violence had broken out the very day that the CPI (Communist Party of India) organized a massive demonstration of tea workers - which included 1,500 Muslim laborers. That appeal to communal sentiments was designed to break the workers’ unity. The violence claimed 41 Hindu lives and 41 Muslim lives according to some sources but only seven lives according to others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1969; September 18–24: Ahmedabad (Gujarat)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/1_Congress_Decline/1969_September_1824_Ahmedabad_Gujarat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/1_Congress_Decline/1969_September_1824_Ahmedabad_Gujarat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Religious composition of the population (as per the 2001 census): 81% Hindus, 14% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Gujarat: Hitendra K. Desai, Congress Party, October 1965–May 1971&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dramatic riots occurred in Ahmedabad (Gujarat) and in adjacent districts in September. Communal tensions had been rising since the Indo–Pak war of 1965, during which Gujarat’s Chief Minister’s plane was shot down. Anti-Pakistan feelings rapidly transformed into anti-Muslim resentment. Incidents multiplied from mid-1968 onwards. In June 1968, the Muslim organization Jamiat-Ulema-i-Hind organized a conference of Gujarati Muslims. This was followed by an RSS mass rally held the 27–29 December, and attended by the leader Guru Golwalkar . In January, an All Gujarat RSS Camp was held in Ahmedabad and included two thousand volunteers. On March 10 1969, Muslim protests took place in the city in which several policemen were injured after a Hindu policeman allegedly insulted the Quran during an altercation with a Muslim rickshaw-driver. On August 21, Muslims demonstrated against the arson attack on the Al-Aqsa Mosque in Jerusalem. On September 4, a Muslim policeman was alleged to have kicked the Hindu holy book of Ramayana while searching for a Hindu pandit (scholar of Hindu sacred texts) during a religious ceremony. Two days later, a Hindu Dharma Raksha Samiti (HDRS, Committee to Defend Hindu Religion) was formed. On September 15, a victory procession was organized by the BJS to celebrate the punishment of the Muslim police officer. On September 14 and 16, the MP (Member of Parliament) and BJS leader, Balraj Madhok , made a series of inflammatory speeches (the Modak lectures).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1970; May 7–8: Bhiwandi (Maharashtra)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/1_Congress_Decline/1970_May_78_Bhiwandi_Maharashtra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/3_decline/1_islamic-assault/articles/riots/hindu-muslim-riots_1947-86/1_Congress_Decline/1970_May_78_Bhiwandi_Maharashtra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;44% Hindus, 51% Muslims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of Maharashtra: Vasantrao P. Naik, Congress Party, December 1963–February 1975&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dreadful communal disturbances occurred in the state of Maharashtra in the towns of Bhiwandi, Jalgaon, and Mahad during this period. Since 1969, the situation in the Muslim-majority town of Bhiwandi had been tense. In October, Hindu leaders received anonymous letters threatening imminent revenge for the 1969 Ahmedabad riots. Publication of these letters in the press and an ensuing series of provocative speeches by communal organizations contributed to the escalating hate campaign. Adding to the uneasiness, the religious festivals of Muharram (Shia) and Holi (Hindu) coincided in March 1970.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
