<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;02 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;02 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/00/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/00/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;preface&#34;&gt;PREFACE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THIS book with a companion volume that treats of the Roman Catholic and Greek Orthodox missions is an attempt to describe the chief events connected with the history of Christianity in Japan. It labours under the disadvantage of dealing with occurrences so close at hand that it is difficult to see them in their right perspective and so to judge of their comparative importance. It is, however, easier now than it will ever be again to gather materials such as are needed for the earlier chapters of such a book, and the completion of the first half-century of organised Protestant missions in Japan presents a suitable occasion for looking back upon what has happened within that period.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 WAITING BEFORE THE CLOSED GATES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/01_WAITING_BEFORE_THE_CLOSED_GATES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/01_WAITING_BEFORE_THE_CLOSED_GATES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AT the middle of the nineteenth century Japan was a hermit nation. Three hundred years had passed since it had first been visited by Europeans. Almost immediately after merchants found their way thither, Roman Catholic missionaries began those labours that at one time seemed likely to result in the speedy winning of Japan to their Church. Then came an era of bitter opposition that resulted in the apparent extirpation of Christianity. All Europeans were driven from the land except as the Dutch merchants were allowed to have a trading post on the tiny island of Deshima, which thus became the one point of contact between Japan and the West.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 THE OPENING OF THE GATES 1853-1859</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/02_THE_OPENING_OF_THE_GATES_1853-1859/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/02_THE_OPENING_OF_THE_GATES_1853-1859/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AT last the time had come for Japan to he drawn forth from its long seclusion. The way in which this was accomplished by Commodore Perry has often been described, and here we need concern ourselves with only such particulars as have a direct connection with our subject.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When it became known that the United States was fitting out an expedition to Japan, great interest was aroused among those who hoped that among its results would be the opening of the land to the Gospel. One young man, Jonathan Goble, joined the force of marines for the purpose of gaining such knowledge of Japan as would help in future attempts at its evangelisation. During the last part of the outward voyage he had an opportunity to begin missionary work by instructing a Japanese who was one of a crew of shipwrecked sailors picked up by an American ship and sent to China. When Commodore Perry offered to take these sailors to their own country, only one of them accepted the offer. The sailors gave him the nickname &amp;ldquo;Sam Patch,&amp;rdquo; by which he was known to foreigners through the remainder of his life. In the account of the expedition Commodore Perry says:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 THE ESTABLISHMENT OF MISSIONS IN JAPAN 1859-1873</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/03_THE_ESTABLISHMENT_OF_MISSIONS_IN_JAPA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/03_THE_ESTABLISHMENT_OF_MISSIONS_IN_JAPA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EARLY in 1859, the Mission Board of the American Episcopal Church appointed Rev. John Liggins and Rev. C. M. Williams, both of whom were missionaries in China, to open work in Japan, &amp;ldquo;requesting them to remove to that empire, and to enter upon the missionary work there immediately after receiving these instructions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Mr. Liggins learned of this appointment, he was already in Japan, whither he had gone to recover from the effects of a fever and from injuries inflicted by a Chinese mob. He arrived at Nagasaki, May 2, 1859. This was two months before the provisions of the treaty permitted residence; but through the assistance of the United States Consul he secured permission to remain, and obtained a house in which to live. He was soon joined by Mr. Williams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 JAPANESE ARGUMENTS AGAINST CHRISTIANITY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/04_JAPANESE_ARGUMENTS_AGAINST_CHRISTIANI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/04_JAPANESE_ARGUMENTS_AGAINST_CHRISTIANI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IN 1868, there was circulated in Kyushu a pamphlet that may well be given in full, as it shows how the Japanese looked upon the missionaries and their religion. It also narrates from a different point of view some of the events described in previous chapters.*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;nagasaki-pamphlet&#34;&gt;Nagasaki pamphlet&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TALES OF NAGASAKI—THE STORY OF THE EVIL DOCTRINE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-roman-catholic-religion&#34;&gt;The Roman Catholic Religion&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At a village named Oura, near Nagasaki,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;the French built a church, and five or six priests took up their residence there.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;They gave wages of a hundred or two hundred &lt;em&gt;rios&lt;/em&gt; annually&lt;br&gt;&#xA;to about twenty Japanese readers&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and sent them out in the disguise of traders or travelling students to Hirado, Shimabara in Hizen, to Fukabori and to Amakusa.&#xA;To the poor they gave money,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and to the superstitious they exhibited prodigies in order to proselytise them,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;or worked upon their feelings by conventicles.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(A conventicle is a meeting of both sexes at night in a secret chamber for pleasure.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 PLOUGHING AND SEED-SOWING 1873-1882</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/05_PLOUGHING_AND_SEED-SOWING_1873-1882/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/05_PLOUGHING_AND_SEED-SOWING_1873-1882/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE year 1873, was a turning-point in the history of Christianity in Japan. The attitude of the Government suddenly changed. We have already seen that, on February 19th, orders were issued for the removal of the edicts against Christianity. There were other signs of increased freedom. A few newspapers had been established, and in one of these that was published in Kobe there appeared, in April, an article written by a young man who was then a student in America, and who at a later date became one of the most efficient pastors in Japan, Paul Sawayama. The most remarkable thing about this article, which, after criticising Shintoism, Buddhism, and Confucianism, urged the introduction of Christianity, is that such sentiments could be published and freely circulated in Kobe less than two years after Mr. Ishikawa had been arrested for having Christian books in his possession, and but five months after his death in prison.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 RAPID GROWTH 1883-1888</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/06_RAPID_GROWTH_1883-1888/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/06_RAPID_GROWTH_1883-1888/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WE have now reached the time when the growth of the Protestant churches and the eagerness of the people to learn about Christianity were such as to arouse the highest hopes of the missionaries, and to excite the wonder of the whole Christian world. Many persons were led to ask the old question with a tone that implied an affirmative answer: &amp;ldquo;Shall a nation be born in a day?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Though there is no one point that specifically marks the beginning of this period of rapid growth, the year 1883 has usually been considered as opening a new chapter in the history of the Protestant churches. This is partly because it was the year when important conventions were held, and partly because it saw the beginning of a series of revivals that exerted a powerful influence upon the Christians, and through them upon unbelievers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 THE PERIOD OF RETARDED GROWTH 1889-1900</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/07_THE_PERIOD_OF_RETARDED_GROWTH_1889-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/07_THE_PERIOD_OF_RETARDED_GROWTH_1889-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JAPAN is a country of sudden changes. The bright prospects that gave rise to the hope that the country would be speedily evangelised were soon clouded over. Missionaries are usually optimists, and it seemed to most of them that the storm would quickly pass and the sun would then shine out as brightly as before. In the correspondence of the period now to be reviewed the hopes of the writers frequently find expression in such words as, &amp;ldquo;The worst is over,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;The reaction has spent its force,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Things are looking brighter than they have for a long time,&amp;rdquo; etc. Yet a full decade must pass ere there would be any very marked improvement, and even then the rate of apparent progress would be much slower than it had been before the reaction set in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 THE OPENING OF THE TWENTIETH CENTURY 1901-1903</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/08_THE_OPENING_OF_THE_TWENTIETH_CENTURY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/08_THE_OPENING_OF_THE_TWENTIETH_CENTURY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ALTHOUGH the system of dating years from the birth of Christ had not become common even among the Christians of Japan, so much was said in Western journals about the transition from the nineteenth to the twentieth century that the Japanese could not fail to be affected by the thought that a new chapter in the world&amp;rsquo;s history was being opened. In Great Britain and America various forms of religious activity were inaugurated under the name of &amp;ldquo;twentieth century forward movements,&amp;rdquo; and we have already seen that the Conference of Protestant Missionaries, held in Tokyo, had recommended co-operation with the Japanese Christians in special evangelistic efforts to be begun in 1901. A committee was chosen by the missionaries to join with one appointed by the Japanese Evangelical Alliance in making the necessary arrangements. While most of the churches and Christian workers united in the movement, those commonly known as &amp;ldquo;liberal&amp;rdquo; were excluded by the rules that the Alliance adopted. These rules led to considerable criticism, not only by those that held liberal views, but also by some others who thought it unwise to shut out any that were willing to join such efforts as were proposed. Some of the methods adopted were either new or had hitherto been used only by such organisations as the Salvation Army. It was necessary in the first place to prepare the Christians by arousing their zeal and securing their active participation in the movement; then public attention had to be secured and the people brought together that they might hear the Gospel. In the neighbourhood of the place where meetings were to be held, striking placards were posted to advertise the services. Notices of the meetings were inserted in the newspapers and special letters of invitation were sent to persons that were thought most open to Christian influences, Sometimes there was a house to house visitation. For an hour or two before a meeting was to commence, companies of believers marched through the streets, carrying banners and lanterns, singing Christian hymns, and distributing printed invitations to the meeting. The younger members of the church were the most active in these processions; but pastors, evangelists, missionaries, business men, and others did not consider it beneath their diginity to fall into the ranks and take a part in gathering an audience. Whether or not those critics were right who thought these methods led people of the better class to despise Christianity, and so did as much harm as good, it is certain that Christianity once more secured the attention which it had largely lost and that large audiences were gathered. Though some had feared that only a noisy rabble would be brought together, the audiences listened quietly to what was said and the meetings were seldom disturbed in any way. The addresses were usually simple and direct. Many preachers who had before delighted in giving learned dissertations upon themes that perhaps had but slight relations to Christ&amp;rsquo;s teaching now found out the power that there is in the earnest and plain teaching of the Gospel, Near the close of each meeting, those that were willing to express a desire to learn more about the Christian religion were asked to sign papers giving their names and residences. These papers were distributed among the churches so that the persons might be visited in their homes. It was customary to have a second service for those that wished to remain after the large audience had been dismissed. It must be remembered that a large proportion of those brought into the meetings had hitherto heard little or nothing of Christianity, and so these second meetings were much different from those that are held after evangelistic services in Christian lands. Many of those that remained did so from curiosity or with but very slight thought of Christianity as having personal claims upon them. Many, too, of those that signed the papers had no eager desire for further information. It was unfortunate that the use of the words &amp;ldquo;enquirers&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;seekers&amp;rdquo; for such persons led many in Christian lands and some in Japan itself to have exaggerated ideas of what was being accomplished. In Tokyo, after a campaign of about six weeks, the number of those enrolled as &amp;ldquo;converts and seekers&amp;rdquo; was over five thousand. Reports for the whole country were not obtained, but the statistics of this &amp;ldquo;forward movement&amp;rdquo; for the year 1901 showed that, so far as the efforts of 376 churches were concerned, there had been an attendance of 322,245 at the meetings, with 15,440 enquirers and converts,* and 1,181 baptisms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 JAPAN IN WAR AND IN PEACE 1904-1909</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/09_JAPAN_IN_WAR_AND_IN_PEACE_1904-1909/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/09_JAPAN_IN_WAR_AND_IN_PEACE_1904-1909/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IN February, 1904, Japan again found herself engaged in war; this time with one of the nations of Christendom. Among some of the Buddhists there was at first an inclination to utilise the enmity of the people against Russia as a means for exciting a similar feeling against Christianity; but this attempt met little encouragement, being frowned upon by the Government and by leaders of national thought, who saw how important it was that Japan should preserve the good opinion and, if possible, have the moral support of Western nations, especially of England, with which it was in alliance, and of America, whose friendship at such a time would be of great value. It was doubtless such reasons that led Count Katsura, the Prime Minister, to invite a missionary, Rev. W. M. Imbrie, D.D., to call upon him and hear some things that it was desirable to have brought to the attention of the people of America, whither the missionary was about going on a furlough. The interview lasted nearly two hours, and the account that Dr. Imbrie wrote of it was afterwards submitted to the Prime Minister for his certification to its correctness. Among other things Count Katsura said in combating the arguments that Russia would be likely to use in seeking to prejudice Americans in her favour were the following:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 PAST, PRESENT, AND FUTURE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/10_PAST_PRESENT_AND_FUTURE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/10_PAST_PRESENT_AND_FUTURE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HALF a century has elapsed since Japan was re-opened to missionary effort. The preceding chapters have narrated the more prominent events connected with the development of Japanese Christianity in those five wonderful decades. In addition to what has been related, there have been many ways in which Christianity has helped Japan to become what it is at the present day. Indeed, there is good reason for saying that, directly and indirectly, Christianity has been the chief force in effecting the changes that have taken place, so that a pamphlet written by Dr. W. E. Griffis is justified in bearing the title: &amp;ldquo;Christ the Creator of the New Japan.&amp;rdquo;* In that pamphlet Dr. Griffis says:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 INDEX</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/11_INDEX/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/kokutai/reject-christ/articles/otis-cary/02/11_INDEX/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ainu, 181, 246&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ajiki, 128&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alexander, Rev. T. T., 263&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;American Board Mission, 13, 70, 77, 78, 97, 107, 109, 139, 192, 254-259, 265, 266, 280, 311, 333&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;American Episcopal Mission, 41, 45, 46, 78, 79, 106, 137, 145, 152, 191&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;American Society of Friends, Mission of, 180&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ando Taro, 202, 295&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Andrews, Rev. W. R., 269, 295&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Annaka, 114, 117, 128, 139&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aomori, 105, 106&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arima, 86, 98&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Army, 221, 249-252, 292, 319-326&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
