<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/iraq-wars/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/iraq-wars/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Americans in Iraq: how is the going?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/iraq-wars/MT/2004-11-27_americans-in-iraq-how-is-the-going/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/iraq-wars/MT/2004-11-27_americans-in-iraq-how-is-the-going/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/11/27/americans-in-iraq-how-is-the-going/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With Bush firmly in power, we need to see how things are going for the Americans in Iraq. I recently heard from some Americans and also Hindus that the events in Fallujah vindicate the famous “fly-paper” theory that has been making rounds on the net. The Americans believe their victory in Fallujah was a sign that it is working. They believe that Fallujah attracted all the Shahids of the Dar-ul-Islam who poured in for action and got extirpated like moths in the fire. The Hindus chimed in that the lure of Fallujah might divert Ghazis from their usual pre-occupation of Kaffr-Kush in Moslem-occupied territories of India and allow them to be cleared by the Anglospheric hordes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The new American crusade</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/iraq-wars/MT/2004-05-24_the-new-american-crusade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/iraq-wars/MT/2004-05-24_the-new-american-crusade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/05/24/the-new-american-crusade/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the crusades are raging in Irak, the discerning Americans are divided as to whether the invasion was a good idea or not. This does not matter too much because most American citizens are thoroughly misinformed by their media and politicians and have an imperfect idea about what all this is about.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the war in Irak was correctly parsed by the Moslems as being a holy war waged by the Christians. With all the Christian missionaries trying to save souls (including the Korean mercenaries of the cross-planting division) there is no wonder that the Momeen are getting so excited. As Huntington had elegantly explained Islam is bloody within and without. So there is no surprise that Iraq has turned into a real bloody mess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Americans in Fallujah</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/iraq-wars/MT/2004-05-17_americans-in-fallujah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/iraq-wars/MT/2004-05-17_americans-in-fallujah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/05/17/americans-in-fallujah/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The American war machine under their not so intelligent Emperor easily achieved the conquest of Mesopotamia. The great Yankie Emperor now sat on the throne of Baghadad (albeit in a brief secret visit) emulating his predecessors like Hulegu the grandson of Chingiz and Timur-i-lang. However, his predecessors really conquered Iraq with all its tribes and factions, and did not restrict themselves to a one demonized leader. The notorious decapitation strikes of the Americans, and the capture of Saddam the Sot, and the killings of his successors was presented to the American people as a great victory. Surely, Americans did not get the kisses and hugs their emperor and his court promised them on the fall of Saddam. The court blamed it on elements of the previous regime. Of course the astute did not get as impressed as some of the sadly ill-informed voters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>American theory of operation Iraqi flypaper</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/iraq-wars/MT/2003-09-16_american-theory-of-operation-iraqi-flypaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/afro-asiatic/semitic/arab/articles/iraq-wars/MT/2003-09-16_american-theory-of-operation-iraqi-flypaper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2003/09/16/american-theory-of-operation-iraqi-flypaper/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many Americans are very satisfied with the conquest of Iraq, or at least they made to feel so by the government. They explain that the conquest of a vast stretch of land like Eye-rack has cost them very little in terms of men (probably even the great conquerors of yore like Timur and Huelegue may have lost a few more, but they conquered larger swaths of land). Halliburton or whoever has already gotten to go ahead with the pumping. Odai and Qosai have been given their subterranean resting places. But somehow the “peaceful, prosperous, secular Iraq” with the Iraqis singing paens of Pax Americana is not yet there. To add to this Emperor Bush adds that all is fine and he just asked the Moslems “to bring ’em on”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
