<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;११ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/11/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;११ on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/11/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The object and mirror image</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/11/2005-11-29_the-object-and-mirror-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/11/2005-11-29_the-object-and-mirror-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/11/29/the-object-and-mirror-image/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We had assembled for the gathering- me, durmukha, maireyapayin,&#xA;mUlApasmara, vAta vyAdi, mlechCha sundarI, kavargA, harir-bArava all&#xA;sahakuTumba. Glad to have escaped the tIkShNa hima we settled down to&#xA;reel out the yarns. The conversation drifted to the journey that we had&#xA;made with kalashajA to the hills in central India, where apparently&#xA;bhasmasura had placed his hand on his head. kalashajA’s mother had&#xA;provided us with the contact of a pious brAhmaNa woman who was civil&#xA;servant in those regions held by the Dravidian tribes. kalashajA, me,&#xA;the muni and my bhima-like clansman bhojanapriya set out on the&#xA;expedition. We were picked up at the forbidding station of Pipariya in&#xA;the late evening by her attendents and taken to her home. We enjoyed the&#xA;best food that night as though we were enjoying the bhogas of indra’s&#xA;svarga. The state servants of India truely enjoyed immense opulence at&#xA;public expense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kartik died mysteriously</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/11/2005-11-28_kartik-died-mysteriously/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/11/2005-11-28_kartik-died-mysteriously/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/11/28/kartik-died-mysteriously/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kartik was a clever guy, who held a degree master’s degree in physics&#xA;from a reputable university. He was considered cool by all his friends:&#xA;he rode a flashy bike, he spoke with a crisp American accent despite his&#xA;origins in a village in Tamil Nadu, he had a lot of hair on his head, he&#xA;wrote excellent code in a few languages, he knew all about cars and&#xA;electronic goods, he spoke about American cinema, TV and games with an&#xA;air of expertise, he made small talk on things like baseball and&#xA;American football, he was reasonably handsome, he knew of all key places&#xA;in the city, he was an expert on food, his knowledge and expertise with&#xA;software was widely sought after and he got along well with Whites. His&#xA;parents and aunts doted upon him. Many extraordinary girls, some endowed&#xA;only with beauty, others endowed with both beauty and intelligence of&#xA;the order of Hayastanika sought his company much to the jealosy of many&#xA;of his co-ethnics. He had no sadness in life and enjoyed life on earth&#xA;as though he was dashadyau sporting in indra’s benevolence. Many thought&#xA;that few people were blessed by indra in his game of dice as he was. He&#xA;was considered by many co-ethnic girls as the ideal man, much like the&#xA;yuva worth an eko mAnuSha AnandaH described in taittirIya brAhmaNa.&#xA;Kartik’s mAmAshrI was a hardworking and intelligent man who had faced&#xA;many natural calamities in his life. As a result he was more circumspect&#xA;and a dour personality. When people met him we felt a certain respect&#xA;for his composure that he retained despite the numerous calamities faced&#xA;in his life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rAkShasi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/11/2005-11-19_rakshasi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/11/2005-11-19_rakshasi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/11/19/rakshasi/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Long after the cell phone had exploded violently we lay unable to make&#xA;sense of what happened in the daze of the blast. We then saw that figure&#xA;moving like dhumAvati. It was laughing loudly and had all manifestations&#xA;of alakShmi. We longed for the lengthy conversations with the muni. We&#xA;marched through beaten path of the evil turuShka sultan with the low sun&#xA;beating down upon. Having reached an appropriate bend we made our&#xA;offerings of savitar and varuNa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>daNDaka kShUraka</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/11/2005-11-09_dandaka-kshuraka/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/11/2005-11-09_dandaka-kshuraka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/11/09/dandaka-kshuraka/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The daNDaka kShuraka attack was made. That led to further trouble in the troubled area. The oShadhi-vanaspati was ravaged- that brought the bank balance down to zero. The dagda ratha caused havoc. An year after the event there were only ruins. As we were passing by them we noticed the passage of fate. The yakShiNi passed by but did not descend. Instead she merely hovered around and said the following:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The appearance of the kR^ityA and chetaka…</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/11/2005-11-07_the-appearance-of-the-kritya-and-chetaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/11/2005-11-07_the-appearance-of-the-kritya-and-chetaka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/11/07/the-appearance-of-the-kritya-and-chetaka/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Everyone knows well how the bharadvAja yavakri met his end due the&#xA;kAshyapa’s spells.”&lt;br&gt;&#xA;We had fallen back from suvargaM lokaM. We then started walking along&#xA;the great path, when we saw a ratha similar to that of our ally of&#xA;utkIla’s clan. We turned around to see the ratha, when we sensed someone&#xA;was coming in front of us. We turned and were surprised to see a&#xA;beautiful woman, dressed very formally. On such a desolate day, at such&#xA;an hour and time it was very unusual to see such a woman coming out from&#xA;such familiar territory down such a familiar path. The woman passed us&#xA;and we glanced her smile a sinister smile. Having passed behind us she&#xA;vanished. Through our third eye we realized that it was not a woman but&#xA;the kR^ityA. We then saw the chetaka attempting to bite at the kavacha&#xA;but failed to do so. Then the chetaka lobbed a tIkShNa kShurika at us&#xA;through the kavacha and then vanished.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The drinking of soma in svarga</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/11/2005-11-04_the-drinking-of-soma-in-svarga/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/bhRguH/dvitIyajanmani_bhRguH/chyavanaH/ApnavAna/aurvaH/jamadagniH/MT_charitram/2005/11/2005-11-04_the-drinking-of-soma-in-svarga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/11/04/the-drinking-of-soma-in-svarga/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Briefly we were awarded the freedom by the grace of the great indra, who is greater than all (vishvasmAd indra uttaraH). We scored two great victories against the dasyus and brought back booty even as our empire was under fierce assaults. Verily indra bore us aid as we locked in combat with two dasyus and we overthrew them after the vajra entered our weapons and shattered theirs. We also made a strong thrust against the third front to bring the fort within striking distance. The spear of skanda relieved us from the pUtanA grAhi and we were placed in the midst of our rejoicing bands. We quaffed soma effused with thickened sweet milk, ate choice spreads and delighted in svarga as dyutAna in the days of yore. But we were told, like for yayAti, the elevation to svargo lokaH was not a permanent feature and we could be sent back to the midst of the rAkshasIs anytime. But then all have stated that one should enjoy svarga when you can. We looked forward to the performance of the great dhUrta kalpa with the 6th day of the moon to please the senAni.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
