<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A geopolitical roundup</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/2024-11-10_a-geopolitical-round-up-vijayavijaya-and-related-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/2024-11-10_a-geopolitical-round-up-vijayavijaya-and-related-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2024/11/10/a-geopolitical-round-up-vijayavijaya-and-related-issues/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A geopolitical round-up: Vijayavijaya and related issues&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In earlier accounts, we have detailed how the Mahāmleccha Deep State had engineered the uccāṭana of Vijaya-nāma-vyāpārin. In a dramatic reversal of fate, the Picchilaka made a comeback against all odds to retake the śvetālaya of the Mahāmleccha-s and, barring some extreme event will be re-crowned Mahāmleccheśvara. Thus, the story of the Nāriṅgapuruṣa has come to fit the classical and timeless tale of the triumph of the hero – something which prompted the mythologist Campbell to coin the phrase a hero with a thousand faces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking back at the</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/2023-06-02_looking-back-at-the-goroga-attacks-and-forward-at-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/2023-06-02_looking-back-at-the-goroga-attacks-and-forward-at-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2023/06/02/looking-back-at-the-goroga-attacks-and-forward-at-geopolitical-developments/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looking back at the goroga attacks and forward at geopolitical developments&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An acquaintance recently asked us if we remembered the famous goroga+++(=anthrax)+++ attacks in the mahāmleccha lands. We had to confess that they were hardly the top thing on our mind, though we had repeatedly thought of those attacks at the beginning of the pandemic. He said that he had seen a recent presentation on it by the journalist Harivana+++(=Greenwald)+++, who had helped the momentous revelations of Himaguha see the light of day. He wondered if we might rethink our position on the Wuhan disease after seeing it. We told him that while the Wuhan corruption had become a matter of personal faith for many, we did think there was something of a “conspiracy” with regard to the goroga incident. Harivana is not a good guy from the H perspective but has exposed mleccha evildoing on several occasions. Hence, we went and watched Harivana’s presentation on the goroga scare and felt the urge to put down a few words regarding that sordid episode which we experienced from close quarters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geopolitical summary</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/2022-03-31_geopolitical-summary-march-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/2022-03-31_geopolitical-summary-march-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2022/03/31/geopolitical-summary-march-2022/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Geopolitical summary: March 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-autumn-dawn&#34;&gt;The autumn dawn&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the 40th day of the autumn of 2016 CE dawned, the mahāmleccha left-liberals were sunning themselves in the last rays of the setting Ardhakṛṣṇa. He was the hero of the age for them, a veritable yuganātha, who had reified all they had stood for. The left-liberal biologists (the majority of them are such) celebrated his manifold vibhava-s by naming no less than 14 newly discovered organisms, from a fungus to a dinosaur-age lizard, after him. His pakṣa rested in the content surety that he would be succeeded by yet another of their chosen ones, the old Ṣiḍgapatnī, who had caused their hated antagonist, al-Qadhdhāfī of barbara-prathamonmatta extraction, to be meet his end by being skewered through his arse by their ghāzī allies on the North African sands. His reign had also seen the execution of at least 10 varṇa-kopa-s, following up on the Neocon-backed efforts of his predecessors, the mahāduṣṭa-s Guccaka and Vakrās, and the Ṣiḍga before him. It was hoped that the Ṣiḍgapatnī who had overseen many of those operations would continue the tradition without any break with financial backing from duṣṭa Sora and others. After all, they had propped up Vijaya-nāma-vyāparin as a strawman to demolish and overthrow the hastipakṣa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran and the Terrorist state of Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-01-21_iran-and-the-terrorist-state-of-pakistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-01-21_iran-and-the-terrorist-state-of-pakistan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/01/21/iran-and-the-terrorist-state-of-pakistan/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ascendency of USA came as a result of it literally being the “New World”. The natives of the land stretching from the cold reaches of Canada to the Southern tip of Patagonia, had only used up all the megafauna of the land leaving behind much of the mineral, forest and aqueous wealth for their White successors to plunder. Unlike Eurasia which had been denuded by thousands of years of high intensity metal and horse age human colonization, the Americas still had much to be used. The intense conflict between the two Germanic sibs Germany and England ensured the decline of England and Europe allowing the white colonists of USA to take leadership of the Leukosphere. Spain had overdone its colonial enterprise resulting in its decline. The distance of the Americas from Eurasia allowed it to be insulated from the tumultous convulsions that periodically rack Eurasia. While outwardly a strong democracy, at its heart lay dictators like the famous Edgar Hoover who ensured that the dissenting elements, both ideological and racial, which might weaken the country were eliminated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law and order in mlechCha desha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-08-31_law-and-order-in-mlechcha-desha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-08-31_law-and-order-in-mlechcha-desha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/08/31/law-and-order-in-mlechcha-desha/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The land of the mlechChas is in krau~ncha dvIpa is renowned for its orderliness arising from the maintenance of law and order. However, when the chakra of indra and vAyu+++(=Hurricane)+++ struck the land it was striking to note that the law and order collapsed rapidly. The state largely lost control and the dire circumstances resulted in an intense human competition and lawlessness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This did not seem to be case in bhArata despite the similar strike by the manyu of indra. The lawlessness appears to be of a different kind in bhArata from mlechCha desha. One wonders if this is because of svabhAva of the concerned people or the social inequalities between the kR^iShNavarNas and shvitinchyas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-president-race</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/2024-president-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/2024-president-race/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1708317694078959856.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The eagerness with which mainstream media declared Nikki Haley as a winner in both debates is striking. Her performance was pretty patchy esp in the 2nd one. Yet she was somehow the &amp;ldquo;winner&amp;rdquo;. The GOP establishment &amp;amp; media badly want her to emerge as the prime alternative to Trump.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is v.clear that the neocons, a limb of the deep state with tangled connections that underlie &amp;ldquo;neo-Occidental civilization&amp;rdquo;, have decided to prop her up. The MSM has been a domain of the neocons since the rise of guchchaka &amp;amp; mahAduShTa-vakrAs. That&amp;rsquo;s what we are seeing here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025&#43; trump actions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/2025-trump-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/2025-trump-actions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;city-vs-empire&#34;&gt;City vs Empire&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The clash between the imperial court running the nAri&lt;del&gt;NgapuruSha and gardabha-run oligarchic city states &amp;ndash; megalopolises is beginning to shape up among the mahAmlechCha. This also fits the Spenglerian pattern well of the clash between the Caesar (nAri&lt;/del&gt;Nga run by his controls) and the megalopolitan oligarchs backing the gardabha-s.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;distraction&#34;&gt;Distraction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/2009497466853367950&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The mahAmlechCha situation is heating up: nAri~Nga and anUpa&amp;rsquo;s actions are driving up unrest at home while building armies for war outside. Possibly, the idea is to trigger some wars so that the internal ferment is distracted and they can proceed with their internal agenda. But the internal ferment could end their electoral hopes before they achieve success in the wars.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contra Rus</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/contra_rus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/contra_rus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cognitive bias can deeply eclipse IQ and common sense. This is amply visible in the navyonmatta as well as the classical pretonmatta &amp;ldquo;army/law enforcement worshiper&amp;rdquo; elite among the mahAmlechCha. In contrast, a significant fraction of the common folks among them get this point with regards to the rUs. Putin&amp;rsquo;s speech today vs piNDaka&amp;rsquo;s navyonmatta backers&amp;rsquo; priorities exemplifies this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epstein files</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/epstein-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/epstein-files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hidden-hand&#34;&gt;Hidden hand&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Benveniste files provide a unique window into the mAhAmlechCha elite and their satellites that many had suspected. What it still does not answer clearly is how he got all his wealth and connections in the first place. There are some others today like that (apart from field-specific phenomena like Robert Trivers), and once one sees the thread, the hidden hand becomes visible. Idiots on the H pakSha don&amp;rsquo;t know how dangerous it is to say too much of it in public.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foreign scientists</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/foreign-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/foreign-scientists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1636549709568376836.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a common belief among many mlechCha-s that somehow they are doing a oneway favor to the foreigners they are &amp;ldquo;training&amp;rdquo;. What they don&amp;rsquo;t get is some of the most important scientific discoveries made in the US in the past &lt;del&gt;30 years were due non-pa&lt;/del&gt;nchantraka foreigners Those discoveries in turn have gone on to provide employment for legions of mlechCha-s researchers who would take much longer to reach where they are on their own.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hindu affinity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/hindu-affinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/hindu-affinity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; However, if one looks at world surveys, the opinion among the people towards India tends to be delta positive in the Anglosphere (apart from places like rUs or Israel). Thus, despite the old enmities and new support for anti-H activities there will be some level of affinity between the India and the Anglosphere.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now it is true that in the past the &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; or the Rs had a more negative opinion of H than the left or the Ds. But what people should realize is that there has been a shake up in the ground in US politics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kennedy on decline</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/decline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/decline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2025&#34;&gt;2025&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;comparisons&#34;&gt;Comparisons&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the American empire completes 249 years one could compare it to other hegemons. First, to clarify, we believe it was born as a hegemon because at birth itself, it defeated the British empire. Hence, we can see it as an empire from its inception.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The British empire can be mapped from the conquest of Jamaica from the Spanish in 1655 to 1947, when it lost India and the circum-India states shortly thereafter = 292 years&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We can place the Spanish empire between 1521 (the conquest of the Aztecs) and its 1898 rout by USA=  377 years.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The start and end of the Portuguese empire are a little murkier, but we could say it lasted between the conquest of Goa in India and the loss of its many African possessions: 1975 - 1510 = 465 years.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;French empire ~1605 gain of Canadian possessions to the 1962 fall of Algeria: 1962 - 1605 = 357 years&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Russian empire: 1547 Ivan the Terrible becomes Tsar to tsar Putin (present)= 478 years&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a comparison, the Hindu empires within the subcontinent are generally short lived:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maturation to navyonmAda</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/maturation-to-navyonmAda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/maturation-to-navyonmAda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1551304824188182528.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the late 1990s and early 2000s, one of my mistaken geopolitical inferences was that the political system in USA had developed genuine resistance to socialism. My understanding of pathogenic meme complexes has since vastly improved, and the mistake seems foolish in hindsight.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;rise&#34;&gt;Rise&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When ShiDga +++(Bill)+++ became mlechCharAT a band of ideologues penetrated the mlechCha deep state apparatus. They started off aligned with the gardabhins +++(Dem)+++ &amp;amp; were aligned with tech &amp;amp; deeply committed to projects related to the marusthala &amp;amp; destruction of the Rus. It seems they let ShiDga keep keep busy with his maithuna even as they tested out their agenda in bhagadattapura, against the Serbs &amp;amp; with Yeltsin. We all know who was the man who put a stop to the last of these projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Afghanistan strategy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/us-aghAnistAn-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/MT_lekhAH/us-aghAnistAn-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The great divergence between the deepstate &amp;amp; the American masses is that the former want to keep playing Great Game 2. This urge comes from superpower realism which holds that no overtly heathen power should arise that might even marginally rival the Occidental Xtian leukosphere. The only place where such a possibility exists in the modern world in the Indian subcontinent (Some might barge in saying: what about chIna? We say that even if chIna-s might have some heathen remnants, their power is not visibly or consciously heathen. More over the incident of the chInese younger bro of Jesus has made the occident wary of shift in center of gravity; then there is Galtonism; then there is dysfertility). Hence, the biggest issue for the deep state is to degrade &amp;amp; for a subset ultimately dismantling H power in the subcontinent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
