<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/language/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/language/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bouba-kiki</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/language/articles/bouba-kiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/language/articles/bouba-kiki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threads-web.vercel.app/threads/1606639090862260224&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a new study, out in Attention Perception and Psychophysics, @ananyapassi and I have cool insights to share about a fascinating cross-modal association called the Bouba-Kiki effect. Consider the shapes below: which shape would you call a Bouba? 1/n &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/jt0iwYW2ky&#34;&gt;https://t.co/jt0iwYW2ky&lt;/a&gt; Vote on it before you go any further!! Which shape would you call a Bouba?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re like most of our participants, you would have call the rounded shape on the left as a &amp;ldquo;Bouba&amp;rdquo; and conversely, the angular shape on the right as a &amp;ldquo;Kiki&amp;rdquo;. But why does this strange association occur between shapes and words? Such effects may have driven the evolution of language, and of course are interesting aspects of perception and the brain in their own right, so scientists have always been curious about how these effects arose. This effect was first noticed by Kohler in 1965, and called the baluba/takete effect and was later popularized by Ramachandran and Hubbard in 2001, who claimed that this effect arises because our mouth makes an rounded shape when we utter &amp;ldquo;Bouba&amp;rdquo; and an angular shape when we utter &amp;ldquo;Kiki&amp;rdquo;. So the widely accepted explanation for why humans show a Bouba-Kiki effect is that it is due to the sensorimotor association between mouth shape and the associated sounds made by our mouths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
