<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;3 Alternative Representations and Realities on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/3_Alternative_Representations_and_Realities/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;3 Alternative Representations and Realities on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/3_Alternative_Representations_and_Realities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/3_Alternative_Representations_and_Realities/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/3_Alternative_Representations_and_Realities/10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Virtuous Clientelism&amp;rdquo;: The Southern Question Resolved?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Simona Piattoni *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Much has changed in Italy in recent times, but the &amp;ldquo;Southern Question&amp;rdquo; still remains central to Italian political and economic life. Even though the institutions that had been created after the war to promote southern development have been dismantled and the parties that championed state intervention in the South have disappeared, it is commonly believed that an economic, political, and possibly cultural gap between North and South still exists. Such a gap today finds its expression in new concerns and a new language.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/3_Alternative_Representations_and_Realities/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/3_Alternative_Representations_and_Realities/11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Il Caso Sciascia: Dilemmas of the Antimafia Movement in Sicily&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Peter Schneider and Jane Schneider *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Among the ways that the &amp;ldquo;Southern Question&amp;rdquo; discourse in Italy stigmatizes the regions south of Rome is by drawing attention to their reputation for organized crime and political clientelism. The recent anti-crime and anti-corruption efforts of the Italian judiciary, however, demonstrate unequivocally what has long been suspected: that leaders of the national political regime that governed Italy from the end of the Second World War until the fall of the Berlin Wall not only tolerated mafia, &lt;em&gt;camorra&lt;/em&gt;, and &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;ndranghetta&lt;/em&gt;; but, largely as a clientelistic trade-off for safe electoral majorities, these leaders were also in various ways complicitous with organized crime. Thanks in no small part to this complicity, by the late 1970s criminal organizations had vastly expanded both their role in the global narcotics traffic and their presence in Northern Italy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/3_Alternative_Representations_and_Realities/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/3_Alternative_Representations_and_Realities/12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Re-writing Sicily: Postmodern Perspectives&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Robert Dombroski *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In December 1983, a literary conference devoted to the theme of &amp;ldquo;Writing Sicily&amp;rdquo; was held in the Sicilian city of Syracuse (Siracusa). Its purpose was to examine the different ways contemporary Sicilian writers conceived of and represented their native homeland as a locus of social and existential meaning. The choice of Sicily as theme was not accidental, for among all the regions of Italy the island is believed to possess a unique cultural landscape, defined and sustained by the numerous civilizations and ethnicities it has hosted throughout the centuries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/3_Alternative_Representations_and_Realities/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/schneider_southern_italy/3_Alternative_Representations_and_Realities/9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Casting Off the &amp;ldquo;Southern Problem&amp;rdquo;: Or the Peculiarities of the South Reconsidered1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*John A. Davis *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-new-agenda&#34;&gt;The New Agenda&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is hardly surprising that the South should figure as one of the central themes in the revisionist agenda around which Italian historians are currently rethinking Italy&amp;rsquo;s path to the twentieth century. Central to that agenda is a questioning of the teleological assumptions that linked the collapse of liberal Italy and the rise of fascism to the failings of modernization in Italy (cf. Davis 1994, Pezzino 1993a, Romanelli 1991).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
