<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;03 CONCLUSION on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/03_CONCLUSION/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;03 CONCLUSION on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/03_CONCLUSION/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>17 Converting the Missionary</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/03_CONCLUSION/17_Converting_the_Missionary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/03_CONCLUSION/17_Converting_the_Missionary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;IL missionaries do not preach or baptize. They avoid pastorlike roles. Rather, SIL believes that the most effective way to evangelize indigenous peoples is to translate the New Testament into their language. Since SIL also believes that the Bible is literally the word of God, then, it is reasoned, the Bible should be able to speak for itself. So my daily activities among the Pirahãs were mainly linguistic, trying to figure out the language well enough to do a good translation of the New Testament. As I progressed, I would work on translating sections and test my translations with different people in the village. In free times during the day, I would often talk to people about my faith and why it was important to me. There was no more to my missionary activity than this, typical for SIL members.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Epilogue Why Care about Other</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/03_CONCLUSION/18_Epilogue_Why_Care_about_Oth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/amazon/articles/everett_piraha/03_CONCLUSION/18_Epilogue_Why_Care_about_Oth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cultures and Languages?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T&lt;/strong&gt;he Hans Rausing Endangered Languages Project is housed at the School of Oriental and African Studies (SOAS) of the University of London. The project is funded by a donation of £20 million from Lisbet Rausing, the daughter of Hans Rausing. The goal of the project is to document languages from around the world that are in danger of extinction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why would anyone give £20 million sterling to study languages spoken mainly by powerless tribal people in parts of the world that are, to put it lightly, off the beaten tourist trails? After all, one could easily make the case that languages come and go and that their disappearance, or their spread, or the emergence of new languages, is governed by the forces of natural selection. A dying tongue is an inconvenience for those who need to learn a new language because their own is no longer viable, but little more than that. In fact, if one believes that the Tower of Babel was either literally a curse or merely symbolic of some human problems, reducing the number of spoken languages and homogenizing or “globalizing” human languages could be viewed as a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
