<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Elite competition</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/elite-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/articles/elite-competition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Crises of Elite Competition in the East and West&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Malcom Kyeyune and Marty MacMarty&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article originally appeared in American Affairs Volume V, Number 4 (Winter 2021): 156–70.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;culture-wars&#34;&gt;Culture wars&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whatever one thinks of today’s culture wars, it is hard to deny that the various barbarians currently rattling the gates were, in some sense, created by the failure of the prior generation to live up to its promises. Old center-left bromides about growing the economy by endlessly expanding higher education now ring hollow. Retreads of the Reagan program today serve as a stale punchline rather than a serious attempt at politics. The pathologies displayed by both the modern center‑left and center-right—trying to solve the crisis of education through more education, or adding more free-market Reaganism to combat the fallout from free-market Reaganism—clearly point to an exhaustion of imagination. Yet if the center is intellectually depleted, the radicals are hardly any better, as they increasingly promise not imaginative social change but promote ever more brazen schemes to secure dwindling resources for their own clients, as seen by the Left’s focus on student loan forgiveness, a program directed squarely at the urban postcollegiate class. The retreat by much of the Right into localism or an exclusive focus on personal virtue is a tacit admission that individuals simply have to look out for themselves, an equally empty response.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
