<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Celibacy advantage</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/celibacy-monk-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/celibacy-monk-advantage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Celibacy -its surprising evolutionary advantages – new research&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why would someone join an institution that removed the option of family life and required them to be celibate? Reproduction, after all, is at the very heart of the evolution that shaped us. Yet many religious institutions around the world require exactly this. The practice has led anthropologists to wonder how celibacy could have evolved in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some have suggested that practices that are costly to individuals, such as never having children, can still emerge when people blindly conform to norms that benefit a group – since cooperation is another cornerstone of human evolution. Others have argued that people ultimately create religious (or other) institutions because it serves their own selfish or family interest, and reject those who do not get involved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dating and automobile</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/dating-and-automobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/dating-and-automobile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;dating-only-as-old-as-the-automobile&#34;&gt;Dating only as old as the automobile&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dating is mainly a twentieth-century phenomenon. You&amp;rsquo;d be surprised to learn that the history of dating is no older th the automobile.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One book on the demise of courtship is aptly titled From Front Porch to Back Seat.12 The automobile took young couples and courtship away from their families. While providing what seemed to be exciting new freedoms, it had disastrous consequences for marriage. Chaperones and the family courting circle were abandoned in the early twentieth century for the thrill of the automobi the “independence” provided by the dating revolution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homo  genetic-heritability</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/homosexuality-genetic-heritability-level/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/homosexuality-genetic-heritability-level/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.rattibha.com/thread/1231291946846441472&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aat7693&#34;&gt;This study&lt;/a&gt; has changed my opinion on homosexuality w.r.t environmental influence. On the basis of a study with a sound sample size of 477,000 people–the contribution of all genetic heritability was estimated to be 8 to 25% of variation in female &amp;amp; male same-sex sexual behavior. This means at least 70% of the sexual activity with the same sex cannot be explained by genetics, hence showing a strong env. influence influencing people to do this. Meaning, society pushing LGBTQ agenda is making people with NO genetic basis for this show the trait.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mark Baker Learning</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/mark-baker-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/mark-baker-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1422895893255163907.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thread by @GuruAnaerobic on Thread Reader App – Thread Reader App&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Guru doesn&amp;rsquo;t usually talk about sex, dating women or the BS term of being a &amp;lsquo;player&amp;rsquo; - those twitter accounts are dumb and mostly set up by average looking shallow men. However, lack of &amp;lsquo;success&amp;rsquo; with the opposite sex is a concern for some young men. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found out:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was at school I had no real interest in girls; I was quite happy talking about UFOs, ghosts and science. I was very active, playing football during break or British bulldog, &amp;lsquo;he&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;home&amp;rsquo;. Most of my friends had no experience with girls. It&amp;rsquo;s after I left school that I started to get attention from the opposite sex; this was quite shocking as I had little of it at school. It felt good, so I went with the flow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>trans-propaganda - apotemnophilia</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/trans-propaganda_apotemnophilia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/trans-propaganda_apotemnophilia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1624443564884123652.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the 90s, Dr. Robert Smith, a surgeon at Falkirk Royal Infirmary, performed leg amputations on two men. Both men were perfectly healthy but suffering from apotemnophilia, a psychiatric condition involving the desire to have healthy limbs amputated. Sufferers claim not to feel whole with four limbs and obsess over having their unwanted body parts chopped off. Smith argued the surgeries were life-saving, claiming the patients would commit suicide otherwise. Apotemnophiles, like auto-gyne-philes, will insist that there is no erotic element, but it was later discovered that one of the men Smith operated on ran an amputee fetish website.+++(4)+++ Upon investigation, the hospital deemed the procedures unethical; Smith was banned from mutilating healthy bodies, and the ethically dubious experiment ended.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USA LGBT Trends 2022</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/usa-lgbt-trends_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/reproduction/Sexual_vs_asexual/Sexual/mating-behavior/articles/usa-lgbt-trends_2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1531264150231470080.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The LGBT share among young Americans tripled in the last decade to 21%. Trans &amp;amp; non-binary identification may be up as much as 1000%. My new @CSPICenterOrg &lt;a href=&#34;https://cspicenter.org/reports/born-this-way-the-rise-of-lgbt-as-a-social-and-political-identity/&#34;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; shows that this is, as @billmaher suggested, shaped by social trends. Data from @GSS_NORC shows that LGBT identification has been diverging from same-sex behavior. LGBT identity has risen 11 points among Americans under 30 since 2008, but same-sex behavior has only risen 4 points. For example, bisexuals are close to half the LGBT total, and predominantly female. But the GSS shows that the share of bisexual women with exclusively male partners in the previous 5 years increased from 13% in 2008-10 to 55% in 2018-21.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
