<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;4 EPILOGUE The Secrets of History on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/4_EPILOGUE_The_Secrets_of_History/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;4 EPILOGUE The Secrets of History on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/4_EPILOGUE_The_Secrets_of_History/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A NOTE ON TRANSLITERATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/4_EPILOGUE_The_Secrets_of_History/A_NOTE_ON_TRANSLITERATION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/4_EPILOGUE_The_Secrets_of_History/A_NOTE_ON_TRANSLITERATION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FIFTEENTH-CENTURY MONGOLIAN HISTORY HAS BEEN ONE of the most confusing times for scholars because of the difficulty of establishing a clear timeline. The chronicles using the animal cycle of years are often difficult to correlate with one another or with the modern calendar. The best chronology available has been published in Mongolian in three comprehensive volumes by Professor B. Baljinnyam, and whenever possible I rely upon his dates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;English-speaking scholars use many different ways of transliterating classical and modern Mongolian names and words. The correct title for the founder of Mongolia is Chinggis Khan, pronounced CHIN-gis, but by tradition it is rendered in English as Genghis Khan. Generally, I use the spelling that is easiest for the reader rather than adhering to only one system. For example in the name Qaidu Khan, the &lt;em&gt;Q&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Kh&lt;/em&gt; represent the same guttural sound. I use the &lt;em&gt;Qaidu&lt;/em&gt; spelling solely because the reader can find more additional information on him under that spelling; yet, for his daughter Khutulun, more can be found using the &lt;em&gt;Kh&lt;/em&gt; spelling. For the same sound I use only an &lt;em&gt;h&lt;/em&gt; as in the common spelling &lt;em&gt;Manduhai&lt;/em&gt; (rather than &lt;em&gt;Mandukhai&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Manduqai)&lt;/em&gt;, because it better approximates the pronunciation of &lt;em&gt;Man-du-HI&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SELECTED BIBLIOGRAPHY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/4_EPILOGUE_The_Secrets_of_History/SELECTED_BIBLIOGRAPHY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/hunnic/mongol/articles/weatherford-jack/queens/4_EPILOGUE_The_Secrets_of_History/SELECTED_BIBLIOGRAPHY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abu-Umar-I-Usman. &lt;em&gt;Tabakat-I-Nasirir: A General History of the Muhammadan Dynasties of Asia&lt;/em&gt;. Translated by H. G. Raverty. London: Gilbert &amp;amp; Rivington, 1881.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Al-Din, Rashid. &lt;em&gt;Rashiduddin Fazullah’s Jami’u’t-Tawarikh: Compendium of Chronicles&lt;/em&gt;. Translated by W. M. Thackson. Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Department of Eastern Languages and Civilizations, 1998.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;———&lt;em&gt;The Successors of Genghis Khan&lt;/em&gt;. Translated by John Andrew Boyle. New York: Columbia University Press, 1971.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Andrews, Peter Alford. &lt;em&gt;Felt Tents and Pavilions: The Nomadic Tradition and Its Interaction with Princely Tentage&lt;/em&gt;. London: Melisende, 1999.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
