<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>bhaTTa jayanta the paippalAdin</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-04-21_bhatta-jayanta-the-paippaladin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-04-21_bhatta-jayanta-the-paippaladin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/04/21/bhatta-jayanta-the-paippaladin/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have always felt a close affinity to bhaTTa jayanta, the great scholar&#xA;from kashmIra. He lived in the 800-900s of CE and was associated with&#xA;the dictatorial king shankaravarman who kalhaNA describes as a corrupt&#xA;despot. kalhaNa informs us of his lack of education and culture by&#xA;stating that this king spoke only apabhramsha, a language fit for&#xA;drunkards (I told our Hindi teacher these very words, which she has not&#xA;forgotten since :-), I hear) . Some how I have felt a unity with&#xA;jayanta, though we are separated by space and time yet resonate. We have&#xA;some biographical information about him from his son’s notes and his own&#xA;personal allusions. He was of the clan of the bharadvAjas and his&#xA;ancestors were from the vanga country in the east. Then, from vanga they&#xA;migrated to kashmIra during the 600s. His clan followed the paippalAda&#xA;shAkha of the atharva veda and were ardent shrauta ritualists. The one&#xA;of his ancestor’s shakti-svAmin, a worshipper of kumAra, was appointed&#xA;as an officer in the court of the great lalitAditya. Hailing from this&#xA;long line of brahminical scholars, jayanta was not surprisingly a boy&#xA;genius. At the age of ten he composed a comentary on pANini, which was&#xA;so lucid that he acquired the title of nava vR^ittikAra even before he&#xA;had completed his education. He subsequently went on to master the&#xA;atharva veda and its rituals, various dharma shAstras, and various&#xA;tantras. His personal deity was rudra, but he was clearly a smArta&#xA;rather than sectarian. He soon became a great exponent of nyAya and came&#xA;up with the concept that every thing that is “knowable” should also be&#xA;formally definable. As the brahman is ultimately knowable it must be&#xA;formally definable, unlike the advaita view that is knowable but&#xA;indefinable. He then went on to build nyAya as the core philosophical&#xA;system, and believed that the whole system of shAstraic interpretation&#xA;should rest on nyAya rather than advaita. He developed the concept of&#xA;the atomic nature of sense perception. However, throughout he voiced his&#xA;firm support for the importance of vedic ritualism over sectarian&#xA;streams like shaiva and vaiShNava matas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>dAlbhya dArbhya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/MT_lekhAH/dAlbhya_dArbhya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/AngIrasaH/prajAH_khyAtyAH/bharadvAjaH/bhAradvAjaH/articles/MT_lekhAH/dAlbhya_dArbhya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oocities.org/somasushma/dalbhya.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;History of the rise and fall of the dAlbhyas&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The pravara section of the bodhAyana shrauta sUtra informs us that the dAlbhyas or dArbhyas are bhAradvAjas of the harita branch. They were famous figures of the kuru-pa~nchAla realm in terms of ritual and war. While originally brahmins, they appear to have repeatedly transmuted to kshatriyas and rulers when the opportunity availed itself.+++(5)+++ Their first major figure was rathavIti (rathitara) dAlbhya who became a powerful monarch and was tutor and patron of the astronomer shyAvAshva atreya.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
