<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;3 The Disruptive Genome on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/3_The_Disruptive_Genome/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;3 The Disruptive Genome on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/3_The_Disruptive_Genome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>10 The Genomics of Inequality</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/3_The_Disruptive_Genome/10_The_Genomics_of_Inequality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/3_The_Disruptive_Genome/10_The_Genomics_of_Inequality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Great Mixing&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The American melting pot began to swirl almost as soon as Christopher Columbus arrived in 1492. European colonists, their African slaves, and the indigenous Americans were from populations whose ancestors had been isolated from each other for tens of thousands of years. Within a few years of meeting they began mixing, founding new populations that today number in the hundreds of millions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Martín Cortés “el Mestizo” belonged to one of the first of those populations. He was born within four years of the start of the 1519 military campaign in which his father, Hernán Cortés, led just five hundred soldiers to overthrow the Aztec Empire that dominated Mexico. His mother, “La Malinche,” was one of twenty female captives given over to the Spanish after a battle and she first served as an interpreter before becoming the mistress of Hernán Cortés. The Spanish quickly invented a term for the people of combined European and Native American ancestry who emerged from unions like this. “Mestizo” comes from the Spanish word &lt;em&gt;mestizaje,&lt;/em&gt; which in English means miscegenation—the mixing of different “racial” types. To maintain their status in the social hierarchy, the Spanish and Portuguese set up a &lt;em&gt;casta&lt;/em&gt; system in which people of entirely European ancestry (especially those born in Europe) had the highest status, while people who had even some non-European ancestry had lower status.+++(4)+++ This system collapsed under the demographic inevitability of admixture; within a few centuries people of entirely European ancestry were either an extreme minority or gone, and it was no longer feasible to limit power to those with entirely European ancestry.+++(4)+++ Following the independence movements of the nineteenth and early twentieth centuries, mixed ancestry became a source of pride in South and Central America. In Mexico, it defines national identity.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 The Genomics of Race and Identity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/3_The_Disruptive_Genome/11_The_Genomics_of_Race_and_Identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/3_The_Disruptive_Genome/11_The_Genomics_of_Race_and_Identity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;fear-of-biological-difference&#34;&gt;Fear of Biological Difference&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I started my first academic job in 2003, I bet my career on the idea that the history of mixture of West Africans and Europeans in the Americas would make it possible to find risk factors that contribute to health disparities for diseases like prostate cancer, which occurs at about a rate 1.7 times higher in African Americans than in European Americans.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This particular disparity had not been possible to explain based on dietary and environmental differences across populations, suggesting that genetic factors might play a role.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 The Future of Ancient DNA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/3_The_Disruptive_Genome/12_The_Future_of_Ancient_DNA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/articles/reich_who-we-are/3_The_Disruptive_Genome/12_The_Future_of_Ancient_DNA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Second Scientific Revolution in Archaeology&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first scientific revolution in archaeology began in 1949, when the chemist Willard Libby made a discovery that would transform the field forever and win him the Nobel Prize eleven years later.1 He showed that by measuring the fraction of carbon atoms in ancient organic remains that carry fourteen nucleons instead of the more common twelve or thirteen, he could determine the date when the carbon first entered the food chain. On earth, the radioactive isotope carbon-14 is mostly formed through the bombardment of the atmosphere by cosmic rays, maintaining the proportion of all carbon atoms of this type at a level of about one part per trillion. During photosynthesis, plants pull carbon out of the atmosphere and change it into sugar. From there, it gets integrated into all the other molecules of life. After a living thing dies, half the carbon-14 atoms decay into nitrogen-14 within 5,730 years. This means the fraction of all carbon atoms in ancient remains that have fourteen nucleons decreases in a known way, enabling scientists to determine a date for when the carbon entered a living thing as long as the date is less than about fifty thousand years ago (beyond that, the fraction of carbon-14 is too low to make a measurement).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
