<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Geopolitics on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Geopolitics on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Euro-colonist</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/anti-euro-colonist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/anti-euro-colonist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spanish, Dutch &amp;amp; Portuguese were always in fear of a Japanese invasion into their colonies like when Hideyoshi threatened to invade Spanish Philippines. In 1630&amp;rsquo;s some Filipinos messaged the Japanese to liberate them from the Xtian Spanish tyranny &amp;amp; in response the Tokugawa began preparing for an invasion as they decided to clear Philippines of the Xtians as it was being used as a base to try &amp;amp; smuggle missionaries to Japan. Just then Shimabara rebellion broke out &amp;amp; these plans were shelved as one of the pushers for invasion at the court also died.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Leukosphere conflict</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/anti-leukosphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/anti-leukosphere/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../../kokutai/reject-christ/&#34;&gt;Rejection of Christianity&lt;/a&gt; is considered separately.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A very useful article on the contrast between the modernization of Japan &amp;amp; the West &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amerika.org/globalism/religion-and-the-case-of-capitalism-richard-l-rubenstein/&#34;&gt;http://www.amerika.org/globalism/religion-and-the-case-of-capitalism-richard-l-rubenstein/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The black ships of USA arrived and threatened Japan in 1853. The shogunate had to accept humiliating terms - open more ports for trade and shelter, unequal trade agreements, allow barbarians to live by their laws in Japan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;meiji-restoration&#34;&gt;Meiji restoration&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Japan recognized its inferiority. People led by samurai from the border provinces of satsuma, choshu, (also hizen, tosa).  led a movement to modernize and strengthen Japan. They rallied around the Meiji emperor, demanded that the shogunate end. Others wanted modernization to happen, while retaining the shogunate and the older system. The former won.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Overt civil war was avoided by the advice of the likes of ???, who warned that a full blown civil war would be exploited by the barbarians, as had happened in India and China.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The shogun (himself from the same miTo province as the great influencer Aizawa Seishisai) resigned, and after a few skirmishes, the shogunate ended in 1868. An oligarchy led by Satsuma and Choshu samurai took over.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Haihan Chiken (1871): Samurai caste system and the feudal system were abolished. This was done in the emperor&amp;rsquo;s name, so opposition was small. 280 Daimyo domains were replaced with prefectures.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This went remarkably smoothly, with some daimyo explicitly requesting it, and others complying. [&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Rjrasva/status/640489349344325632&#34;&gt;T1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Rjrasva/status/640490060413030400&#34;&gt;T2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Rjrasva/status/640490671590240256&#34;&gt;T3&lt;/a&gt;] The daimyo bade their sAmurai to transfer the loyalty to national patriotism and the emperor.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 million samurai lost income.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A mission visited USA and Europe to try renegotiate trade humiliations (blocked by the British). They decided that the prussian model was the best. This was adapted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In ~1895, the emperor issued an edict to correct for the western fad, and reemphasize core Japanese values.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-chinese-war&#34;&gt;First Chinese war&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;causes-of-defeat&#34;&gt;Causes of defeat&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Not taking Japan seriously.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the Chinese mind, this neighbor was so insignificant that there was little point in conducting a thorough assessment of its military strength and capabilities&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Japan, by contrast, knew China well. Had set up a great spy network.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chinese disunity.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Revenue minister did not finance the navy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Admiral Ding Ruchang had poor relations with his officers, in part because he came from the north&amp;hellip; Because of these regional loyalties and prejudices, the authorities in Peking could not concentrate their forces.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bad administrative system.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Poorly organized navy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;General Ye Zhichao, China’s point man in Korea, lied about his “exploits,” while, in fact, he and his demoralized men trekked 250 kilometers in six days to flee the marauding Japanese.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;outcomes&#34;&gt;Outcomes&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It ceded Taiwan to Japan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The booty of war from China boosted Japanese state coffers, nearly 90 percent of which was spent on military build-up.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Later, manchu rule overthrown.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;korean-independence&#34;&gt;Korean independence.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Japan forcibly opened trade with Korea.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chinese influence on the vassal state of Korea was heavy. China itself was fast decaying due to European infestation. The dangers of Korea following suit were high. Modernization proposals were rejected and pro Japanese reformists were suppressed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;So, Japanese freed Korea from Chinese influence by force (1895). Japan captured Liaodong peninsula, Taiwan and Pescadores islands, and got much recompensation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;fight-with-the-rus&#34;&gt;Fight with the Rus&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Russians collaborated with anti Japanese Koreans, captured Liaodong, the pro Japanese Korean government was overthrown. China bowed to the Russians. Boxer rebellion was quelled by both.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Japanese allied themselves with the British, to ensure that they sided with the Japanese in the event of conflict with the Rus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Diplomatic efforts to keep the Rus at bay failed - the Rus were just buying time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Japan declared war, attacked and sunk Rus ships (even those from the Baltic fleet), won the land war, invaded Sakhalin. The Qing sided with the Japanese.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Japan annexed Korea.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;manchu-invasion&#34;&gt;Manchu invasion&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Republic of China was founded in 1912, following the Xinhai Revolution which overthrew the Qing Dynasty. Its leaders Sun Yat Sen and Chiang Kai Shek were methodist christians. Regional warlords held sway. In 1930-s Communist Party started a rebellion.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Japan invaded Manchuria in 1931 and established the puppet state of Machukuo. It create factories and made many investments.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Triggers:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Securing the north</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/secure-north/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/secure-north/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;annexation-of-hokkaido&#34;&gt;Annexation of Hokkaido.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Japanese settlers started moving into Hokkaido in the 15th Century and gradually pushed the Ainu north. They brought infectious diseases and so Ainu populations fell. &amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;post-meiji-motives&#34;&gt;Post Meiji Motives&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;rdquo; … The development of Japan&amp;rsquo;s large northern island had several objectives: First, it was seen as a means to defend Japan from a rapidly developing and expansionist Russia. Second … it offered a solution to the unemployment for the former samurai class … Finally, development promised to yield the needed natural resources for a growing capitalist economy.&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Russian christianization threat [&lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/whUzAwA.jpg&#34;&gt;A1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/Jcb2gWC.jpg&#34;&gt;A2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/o9N3OhW.jpg&#34;&gt;A3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.ca/books?id=693IrDhcT8sC&amp;amp;pg=PA134&amp;amp;dq=on+uruppu+mogami&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0CCYQ6AEwAGoVChMI8dy1l4jWxwIVyn6SCh0zIQyh#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=on%20uruppu%20mogami&amp;amp;f=false&#34;&gt;GB&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heathen traditions that have some organization tend to do better at holding back the unmadas (e.g. shinto, ourselves, taoism etc). The more unorganized seem easy prey as illustrated by the Nagas, Mizos, Africa etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;colonisation&#34;&gt;Colonisation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ainu land was redistributed to Japanese farmers. Ainu language was banned and children put into Japanese schools. Japanese names became compulsory.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The ainu population was small to begin with + disease + intermarriage + discrimination means they were wiped out as a distinct group in short order.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
