<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AI-cuneiform-translation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/AI-cuneiform-translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/AI-cuneiform-translation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://bigthink.com/the-future/ai-translates-cuneiform/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;New AI translates 5,000-year-old cuneiform tablets instantly&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like combining Google Translate with a time machine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Translation isn’t simply a matter of swapping one word for a corresponding word in another language. A high-quality translation requires the translator to understand how both languages string thoughts together and then use that knowledge to create a translation that maintains the linguistic nuances of the original, which native speakers effortlessly understand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kissinger meaning</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/kissinger-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/kissinger-meaning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;# The Meaning of History&#xA;Reflections on Spengler, Toynbee and Kant&#xA;by Henry A. Kissinger&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;table-of-contents&#34;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Introductory Note&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Argument (Introduction and Summary)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;History-as-Intuition (Spengler)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;History-as-an-Empirical-Science (Toynbee)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;History and Man&amp;rsquo;s Experience of Morality (Kant)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Sense of Responsibility&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Appendix&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bibliography&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introductory-note&#34;&gt;Introductory Note&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An introduction to an undergraduate honors thesis may seem presumptuous, but I believe that its inordinate length and unorthodox method require an explanation. As a general reason, the length is due to the fact that I did not realize the implications of the subject when I started to work on the thesis. As it grew, I have made several efforts to cut it down, such as omitting the chapters I had written on Hegel and Schweitzer. Since this still did not succeed in reducing this thesis to a more manageable size I have pointed out, at the end of this introductory note, those portions which I believe to be the nucleus of my analysis and which may be considered my honors thesis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rAjvADe lament</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/rAjvADe-lament/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/rAjvADe-lament/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dharmadispatch.in/culture/the-heartbreaking-anguish-of-rajwade-a-tragic-epilogue&#34;&gt;https://www.dharmadispatch.in/culture/the-heartbreaking-anguish-of-rajwade-a-tragic-epilogue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;rajwades-notes-on-history-research-and-writing&#34;&gt;Rajwade’s Notes on History Research and Writing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The desire, the machinery and the fruit; or the desire, the body and action are the three divisions of activities of the human society. To write history is to describe these divisions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The method of writing history which is considered scientific in Europe is considered equally so in India. Whether the history is political, religious, social or economic or whether it is of a single notion such as learning, wars, culture, Dark Ages, evil thoughts, or whether it is of the controlling agency which gives rise to these notions, the method of writing it faithfully and scientifically must be the same in all countries and at all times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruler religious affiliation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/ruler-religious-affiliation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/ruler-religious-affiliation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/Ravilochanan86/status/1812903854029365304&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: mostly ravilochana&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;good-signals&#34;&gt;Good signals&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;self-declarations&#34;&gt;Self declarations&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unambiguous declarations and initiations clearly indicate religious affiliation. Examples&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;kRShNadevarAya in Amukta-mAlyada declares himself to be a shrIvaiShNava. Krishnadevaraya declares that he holds other deities as inferior to Vishnu in his works.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kapilendea Gajapati in Puri inscription. As did most of the Gajapati incl Purushottama, Narasimha, Anangabhima etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;clear-sectarian-partonage-bias&#34;&gt;Clear Sectarian partonage bias&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Chola kings built shrines for Sharabha and Lingodbhava (latter in the place of Vishnu in Shiva temples), they were very much showing that they held Vishnu to be inferior.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TS kRShNa confusions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/TS-kRShNa-confusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/TS-kRShNa-confusions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thread by @Ravilochanan86 on Thread Reader App – Thread Reader App&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;vikrama-pandya&#34;&gt;Vikrama Pandya&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As usual, hypocrisy and tangential statements are only used by Krishnan here. It has become his practice to deny actual facts and uphold fantasies as history. Let us look at his claims here:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;he thinks that Nilakantha Sastri is the only source for Vikrama defeating Kafur.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;He even claims that Lilatilakam, a 14th century text, is based on Sastri!!! Talk about baseless claims!! -2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>udaya kumAr</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/udaya-kumAra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/society/history/meta/articles/udaya-kumAra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rerecording history: Bengaluru&amp;rsquo;s Inscriptions 3D Digital Conservation Project helps preserve millenia-old stone inscriptions&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FOR 54-year-old P.L. Udaya Kumar, fieldwork means locating ancient stone inscriptions and scanning and deciphering them. This is what Udaya Kumar, who heads the Bengaluru-based Inscriptions 3D Digital Conservation Project, set out to do on a Saturday morning in early February. Udaya Kumar was informed by a contact residing in Chikkabanavara on the northern outskirts of Bengaluru that he had discovered two stone inscriptions in a eucalyptus grove. Udaya Kumar reached the spot along with two young researchers, R. Yuvaraju and M.N. Madhusudhan, who are part of the inscriptions project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
