<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;muslim separatism on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;muslim separatism on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 CHAPTER I THE TWO BEHAVIOUR PATTERNS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/01_ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/01_ch1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER I&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;THE TWO BEHAVIOUR PATTERNS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Pakistan and Bangladesh are their fixed deposits. Those are Islamic states. No one else can lay a claim on them. India is a joint account. Plunder it as much as you please.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This is how Shri Shiva Prasad Roy, a very perceptive Bengali writer, has summed up the present situation in what is described as the Indian subcontinent now a days but what has been known as Bharatavarsha since time immemorial.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 CHAPTER II THE NATIONAL TERRITORIAL TRADITION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/02_ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/02_ch2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER II&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;THE NATIONAL TERRITORIAL TRADITION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The perspective of &lt;em&gt;The Tragic Story of Partition&lt;/em&gt; by Shri H.V. Seshadri is set by what the learned author has written in his short but succinct Preface. He says: “In the [past] one thousand years many parts of our country had been ruled by the Muslims and then by the British, but the nation had never compromised, in principle, its sovereignty over any part of the motherland. As a result, our nation had never ceased to strive for throwing out the aggressors and liberate those parts. And history tells us that ultimately it did succeed in freeing the entire land from the clutches of foreign invaders. However, for the first time, Partition conceded the moral and legal right to them over certain parts of the country and declared an ignominious finale to the one thousand years old heroic struggle for freedom. Thus it was an act of humiliating surrender on the point of principle. The usual interpretation of Partition, however, does not utter a word about this aspect. Even while conceding Partition to be a tragedy, it is sought to be made out as the only practical way out then available - as the inevitable price for achieving freedom.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 CHAPTER III THE NATIONAL HISTORICAL TRADITION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/03_ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/03_ch3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER III&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;THE NATIONAL HISTORICAL TRADITION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Partition of India which the national leadership conceded in principle in 1947 was a gross violation of the national territorial tradition which had always cherished the whole of Bharatavarsha as a single and indivisible Hindu homeland. But what was still more serious, it was also a flagrant betrayal of the national historical tradition which had never accepted the consolidation of any foreign conquest in any part of Bharatavarsha as a settle fact, final for all time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 CHAPTER IV THE BUSINESS OF BLAMING THE BRITISH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/04_ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/04_ch4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER IV&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;THE BUSINESS OF BLAMING THE BRITISH&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Problems have to be solved first at the level of thought before we can hope to solve them at the level of things. Hindu society has got to do some hard thinking in order to find an effective and lasting solution of the problem posed by Islam.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ISLAM AND HINDU SOCIETY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Islam came to India as a fully developed ideology of an aggressive and self-righteous imperialism. It tormented Hindu society for several centuries. It should have been demolished and dispersed when its imperialist hold was broken at last, after a long struggle. But it was allowed to survive and its inherent aggressiveness was not tamed. Hindu society had meanwhile deceived itself into believing that Islam was just another religion and, therefore, entitled to reverence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 CHAPTER V THE FRUSTRATION OF ISLAM IN INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/05_ch5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/05_ch5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER V&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;THE FRUSTRATION OF ISLAM IN INDIA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Long ago, some 12 or 13 years before Partition, I had a chance to pass by a meeting of Muslims in Delhi. The chaste Urdu and the weighty voice of the man making the speech at the moment, made me stand and stare. It was a bearded mullah wearing a fez. He was narrating some history which was new for me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The mullah mentioned several dates on which some decisive battles had been fought and won by the armies of Islam. I was not familiar with the names of the heroes and generals who had led those armies. But I knew the names of the countries which, according to the mullah, had been conquered and converted &lt;em&gt;en masse&lt;/em&gt; to Islam in rather short spans of time - Arabia, Palestine, Syria, Iraq, Egypt, Algeria, Tunisia, Morocco, Iran, Khorasan, Turkistan and so on. There were repeated references to swords and spears and horses and hoofs and countless clashes in which human blood had flowed copiously. In between, some one from the audience stood up and shouted &lt;em&gt;‘nāra-i-takbīr’&lt;/em&gt;. And the whole assembly roared back &lt;em&gt;Allāh-o-Akbar&lt;/em&gt; with full-throated frenzy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 CHAPTER VI ISLAMIC ATAVISM RENAMED MUSLIM REVIVALISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/06_ch6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/06_ch6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER VI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;ISLAMIC ATAVISM RENAMED MUSLIM REVIVALISM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“He stayed for a good time in Medina,” writes Jablani, “and returned to Mecca in 1731, a little before the start of the Hajj season. Of course, he spent the whole month of Ramzan there and its last ten days in seclusion (&lt;em&gt;itikat&lt;/em&gt;) in the sacred Mosque. During those hours of seclusion many secret truths were made clear to him and he was duly apprised of some difficult problems. Once he saw in a dream that he was the maintainer of the world - &lt;em&gt;Aaim-uz-Zaman&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 CHAPTER VII JOURNEY FROM JIHÃD TO JEE-HUZÛRÎ</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/07_ch7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/07_ch7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER VII&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;JOURNEY FROM &lt;em&gt;JIHĀD&lt;/em&gt; TO &lt;em&gt;JEE-HUZŪRĪ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“It is obvious to your exalted self that the alien people from distant lands have become the rulers of territories and times, and the traders and vendors of goods have attained the rank of sovereignty. They have destroyed the dominions of the big grandees and the estates of the nobles of illustrious ranks, and their honour and authority have been completely set at naught… As soon as the land of Hindustan is cleared of the alien enemies and the efforts of these people [the Wahabis] result in the achievement of their objective, the ranks and offices of the state and government would be handed over to the seekers [of these], and the roots of their power and sovereignty would be strengthened.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 CHAPTER VIII NATIONAL RESURGENCE REVILED AS HINDU REVIVALISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/08_ch8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/08_ch8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER VIII&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;NATIONAL RESURGENCE REVILED AS HINDU REVIVALISM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maharshi Dayananda Saraswati (1824-1883) was speaking at a meeting in Calcutta when some stones were thrown at him by some members of the audience disgruntled by his criticism of Hindu orthodoxy. He remained calm and self-possessed. He appealed for a patient hearing in the following words: “The British Government has guaranteed freedom of speech to all of us. Why should I be deprived of that freedom? Please! Let me say what I want to say. Those who disagree with me will also have their turn.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 CHAPTER IX LOSS OF PRIVILEGES PORTRAYED AS PRIVATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/09_ch9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/09_ch9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER IX&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;LOSS OF PRIVILEGES PORTRAYED AS PRIVATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A British scholar and civil servant, W.W. Hunter, wrote the book, The Indian Musalmans: Are They Bound in Conscience to Rebel against the Queen?, which was published in 1871. It was reviewed by Alfred Lyall who was soon to succeed as the Lieutenant Governor of the North West Province (later on known as U.P.). Lyall had warned that “what Hunter had said will be overheard by Indian Muslims; they will be encouraged to think of themselves as ‘an oppressed people or a persecuted sect’.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 CHAPTER X THE SEPARATIST SEWER POLLUTES THE NATIONAL MAINSTREAM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/10_ch10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/10_ch10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER X&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;THE SEPARATIST SEWER POLLUTES THE NATIONAL MAINSTREAM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is one chapter in the history of our freedom movement against British imperialism which has caused considerable confusion. This chapter opened with the signing of the Lucknow Pact in December 1916, and closed with the withdrawal of the first Non-Cooperation Movement by Mahatma Gandhi in February 1922. Many politicians and historians have looked back wistfully to those ‘wonderful days of Hindu-Muslim unity’ when the Indian National Congress and the All-India Muslim League held their annual sessions in the same city and at the same time, passed similar anti-imperialist resolutions, and raised similar slogans. Few political scientists have cared to interpret correctly and consistently the detailed documentation which has been available for quite some time regarding the motives of the Muslim League and, later on, of the Mullahs in making a common cause with the Congress. It looks like a wilful refusal to face facts which sound unsavoury.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 CHAPTER XI THE BEHAVIOUR PATTERN PATENTED BY ISLAM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/11_ch11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/11_ch11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER XI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;THE BEHAVIOUR PATTERN PATENTED BY ISLAM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On August 4, 1920, Mahatma Gandhi had written as follows in his &lt;em&gt;Young India&lt;/em&gt;: “My advice to my Hindu brethren is: Simply help the Mussalmans in their sorrow in a generous and self-sacrificing spirit without counting the cost and you will automatically save the cow… &lt;em&gt;Islam is a noble faith&lt;/em&gt;. Trust it and its followers. We must hold it a crime for any Hindu to talk to them about cow-protection or any other help in our religious matters, while the &lt;em&gt;Khilafat&lt;/em&gt; struggle is going on.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 CHAPTER XII PLEA FOR A HISTORICAL PERSPECTIVE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/12_ch12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/12_ch12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHAPTER XII&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;PLEA FOR A HISTORICAL PERSPECTIVE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shri H.V. Seshadri has taken &lt;em&gt;The Tragic Story of Partition&lt;/em&gt; to its fatal finale in 1947. Each of his chapters is packed with facts, insights, and interpretations such as make his book a substantial contribution to the large literature on this controversial subject. The only drawback in this otherwise well-documented study is the frequent absence of dates on which the books from which he has quoted were published, and the statements of leaders he has cited were made. Some of the statements credited to some national leaders leave the impression as if these leaders were able to see the precipice towards which our people were being pushed. Absence of dates on which these statements were made, helps in hiding the habit of our leaders to feel wise by hindsight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 APPENDIX ISLAMIC MANIFESTO FOR INDIA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/13_app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/muslim_separatism/13_app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;APPENDIX&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;ISLAMIC MANIFESTO FOR INDIA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is old. It is new. It is an enduring theme on which the Ulama and the Sufis of Islam thrive.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is a rueful review of an opportunity lost in the past. It is a fond dream about a future fulfilment. It is a fanatic faith to fight for in the present.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Borrowing a metaphor from the &lt;em&gt;Communist Manifesto&lt;/em&gt; of Karl Marx, the theme can be summarised as well as sloganized as follows: “We, the Ulama and the Sufis of Islam, disdain to hide our aim. We stand for a full and final conquest of India by Islam. Muslims of India unite! You have nothing to lose but your minority complex. You have a whole subcontinent to gain!”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
