<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Anti-Foreignism &amp; Western-Learning on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/aizawa_seishisai/Anti-Foreignism_Western-Learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Anti-Foreignism &amp; Western-Learning on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/aizawa_seishisai/Anti-Foreignism_Western-Learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>0</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/aizawa_seishisai/Anti-Foreignism_Western-Learning/0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/aizawa_seishisai/Anti-Foreignism_Western-Learning/0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Foreword and Acknowledgments ix&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Prologue: Looking Backward 3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 The Civilized and the Barbarian 17&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Civilization: Where Confucian Ritual Obtains 18&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Japan: A Land of Splendid Barbarians 22&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Innate Japanese Superiority: The Rise of Kokugaku 30&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Excellence of Western Barbarians 40&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Mito Synthesis: Japan as Middle Kingdom 51&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3 Knowledge and Hatred of the West 58&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Road to National Isolation: Misconceptions of Sakoku 58&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Aizawa&amp;rsquo;s View of Christianity: Conquest Without Warfare&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Threat from the North: Russia 76&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Threat from the South: Spain and (New) England 86&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Western Learning and Confucian World View 97&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4 Aizawa and his New Theses 100&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Prologue: Looking Backward</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/aizawa_seishisai/Anti-Foreignism_Western-Learning/1_Prologue_Looking_Backward/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/aizawa_seishisai/Anti-Foreignism_Western-Learning/1_Prologue_Looking_Backward/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the second lunar month of 1825 the Edo bakufu ordered officials in coastal areas except Nagasaki to attack on sight and drive away all Western ships, whether or not clearly identified as Dutch. In the following month Aizawa Seishisai (1781-1863), a Confucian scholar of Mito Learning,&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; composed a polemical tract entitled New Theses (Shinron) justifying that policy. These events mark a great divide in early-modern Japanese history: Even though the Expulsion Edict was revoked in 1842, bakufu authority and legitimacy after 1825 hinged on maintaining national isolation (sakoku), conceived of as an inviolable law of the land. This in turn meant being willing and able to perform joi, or the expulsion of Western barbarians by force. In this study, which serves as an introduction to the English translation of New Theses, I show how this idea of armed expulsion evolved during the Edo period and try to explain why bakufu leaders adopted it as the guiding principle of Japanese foreign policy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 The Civilized and the Barbarian</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/aizawa_seishisai/Anti-Foreignism_Western-Learning/2_The_Civilized_and_the_Barbarian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/aizawa_seishisai/Anti-Foreignism_Western-Learning/2_The_Civilized_and_the_Barbarian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;chapter two&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Civilized and the Barbarian&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Explaining the bakumatsu slogan &amp;ldquo;Expel the barbarians&amp;rdquo; (jōi) seems simple enough. The Japanese are civilized and are superior to Western barbarians; Western ships approaching Japan are to be driven off by force. But this simplicity is beguiling. The concepts of &amp;ldquo;civilization&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;barbarism,&amp;rdquo; as applied to peoples and nations, underwent important changes during the Edo period. Roughly speaking, early in the period, Japanese thinkers saw Ming dynasty China as representing civilization in contrast to Japan which they considered a barbarian state. Since Europeans were largely out of sight and mind, they escaped ready categorization. And in any case, these categories were cultural, having little to do with military force. But by the nineteenth century, Tokugawa thinkers claimed that their nation had surpassed Ch&amp;rsquo;ing dynasty China as the center of world civilization, and they reviled Westerners as barbarians who should be expelled militarily. Only after tracing how the concepts of civilization, barbarism, and expulsion evolved during the Tokugawa period will we properly understand Aizawa&amp;rsquo;s joi rhetoric in New Theses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Knowledge and Hatred of the West</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/aizawa_seishisai/Anti-Foreignism_Western-Learning/3_Knowledge_and_Hatred_of_the_West/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/aizawa_seishisai/Anti-Foreignism_Western-Learning/3_Knowledge_and_Hatred_of_the_West/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE ROAD TO NATIONAL ISOLATION: MISCONCEPTIONS OF &amp;ldquo;SAKOKU&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1838, Takano Chōei and his colleagues in Western Learning were apprehensive about how the bakufu would treat a Western ship they mistakenly assumed was approaching Japan. In fact, the bakufu had already driven away the vessel in question (named the Morrison) one year before. Chōei, however, believed that the eminent English Sinologist, Robert Morrison, was commanding the ship and was repatriating Japanese castaways. And he distrusted Morrison&amp;rsquo;s motives:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Aizawa and His New Theses</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/aizawa_seishisai/Anti-Foreignism_Western-Learning/4_Aizawa_and_His_New_Theses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/aizawa_seishisai/Anti-Foreignism_Western-Learning/4_Aizawa_and_His_New_Theses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, students of Western political history consider the separation of church and state to have been an important step in the formation of modern European nations. The textbooks tell us that Machiavelli&amp;rsquo;s views on government were modern, as opposed to medieval, in that he distinguished the ruler&amp;rsquo;s personal morality as a private individual from his public responsibilities as a head of state: For the prince, reprehensible personal conduct was often praiseworthy statecraft. After Machiavelli, Western rulers for the most part would exclude ethics and religion from the affairs of government; and as a result, the nation-state in modern Europe became a purely secular institution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Epilogue: Looking Ahead</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/aizawa_seishisai/Anti-Foreignism_Western-Learning/5_Epilogue_Looking_Ahead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/aizawa_seishisai/Anti-Foreignism_Western-Learning/5_Epilogue_Looking_Ahead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1855, Ikebe Tōzaemon, a samurai from Yanagawa domain, shrewdly appraised the political position held by Tokugawa Nariaki, former daimyo of Mito and the then advisor to the bakufu on coastal defenses. Nariaki had been an avid exponent of joi since 1825.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He advanced such views before anyone else in the realm; [now] he cannot bring himself to act on them. You might say he has climbed to the peak of a steep mountain. He cannot go up any further, but he cannot back down either. 1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 New Theses</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/aizawa_seishisai/Anti-Foreignism_Western-Learning/6_New_Theses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Trans-eurasian/japan/geopolitics/articles/aizawa_seishisai/Anti-Foreignism_Western-Learning/6_New_Theses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-prefatory-remarks&#34;&gt;1 Prefatory Remarks&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Note: In the translation that follows, the glosses were written by Aizawa himself.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our Divine Realm is where the sun emerges&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It is the source of) the primordial vital force (yuan ch&amp;rsquo;i) sustaining all life and order. Our Emperors, descendents of the Sun Goddess, Amaterasu, have acceded to the Imperial Throne in each and every generation, a unique fact that will never change. Our Divine Realm rightly constitutes the head and shoulders of the world and controls all nations. It is only proper that our Divine Realm illuminates the entire universe and that our dynasty&amp;rsquo;s sphere of moral suasion (kōkwa) knows no bounds. But recently the loathsome Western barbarians, unmindful of their base position as the lower extremities of the world&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; have been scurrying impudently across the Four Seas, trampling other nations underfoot. Now they are audacious enough to challenge our exalted position in the world. What manner of insolence is this?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
