<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Poisons on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/poisons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Poisons on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/poisons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cannabis</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/poisons/cannabis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/poisons/cannabis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1465167895969865738&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1465167895969865738&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There was discussion on cannabis legalization where one side felt it was safer than smoking tobacco &amp;amp; the other it was triggering mental illness &amp;amp; dangerous behavior. Just posting some stuff which is mostly common knowledge but apparently those in that argument did not seem to know. Just parking that bAlabodhana here in case someone else is interested.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First for some anatomical background: There is this part of the mammalian brain shown in red in the below pic where much of the action that concerns us happens. It&amp;rsquo;s called the striatum. There is a key signaling pathway that occurs in the neurons in that structure mediated by a neurotransmitter called dopamine shown below. It is type of compound called catecholamine (if you recall your school chemistry, you will see those groups). It signals between neurons by binding to a receptor which is on the membrane of the receiving neuron &amp;amp; it activates a signaling cascade inside the cell which involves a key enzyme called AKT1 which adds phosphate groups to other proteins. This cascade is activated by delta-9-tetrahydrocannabinol the major active compound in cannabis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Misc</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/poisons/misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/poisons/misc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;98% pure Sodium Nitrite इति जलेन मिश्रितं २० निमेषेषु घातयति।  असकृद् वान्तिनिरोधकेन साकं प्रयुज्यते। Antidote:  Methylene-blue.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Produce additives</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/poisons/produce-additives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/poisons/produce-additives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pesticides, ripeners, preservatives, colorants are commonly added.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;spices&#34;&gt;Spices&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The only masala powders that I buy are from MTR. An acquaintance from Food safety had once commented that MTR is the only one which can pass food safety tests. Rest pay for their certificates&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ravi&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;fruits&#34;&gt;Fruits&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;india&#34;&gt;India&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mango and sapoTa in bhArata are heavily sprayed with artificial ripeners and insecticides. Mango is sprayed even when a flower, as insects lay eggs even in flowers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ripeners</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/poisons/ripeners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/poisons/ripeners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;calcium-carbide&#34;&gt;Calcium carbide&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dipping mangoes in 2% sodium carbonate solution for 12 hr can be used to remove arsenic residues from the calcium carbide ripened mangoes prior to their consumption.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;detection&#34;&gt;Detection&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mango fruit starts to get black patches in 2 to 3 days due to the usage of calcium carbide for ripening of Mango fruit. Traces of white color powder arsenic traces are found on the mango fruit; if Calcium Carbide is applied, there will be traces of arsenic powder white powder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sugar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/poisons/Sugar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/poisons/Sugar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=da1vvigy5tQ&#34;&gt;YT Sarah Hallberg.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;non-necessity&#34;&gt;Non-necessity&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not necessary as a nutrient - body can manufacture it from carbohydrates as needed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In healthy foods (eg. fruits), it is an unavoidable ingredient.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;as-poison&#34;&gt;As Poison&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In modernly common contexts, sugar is a poison.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Further complications include: higher blood pressure, higher trglyceride levels, lower HDL cholesterol levels, higher LDL cholesterol levels (aka&#xA;metabolic syndrome), thence leading to both type 2 diabetes and heart disease (surprise!).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are also observations leading to speculation about its role in the increased incidence of cancer with western diet/ lifestyle: insulin promotes tumor growth!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trans-fats</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/poisons/Trans-fats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/phenes/health/food/poisons/Trans-fats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;structure&#34;&gt;Structure&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unrefined fats include double bonds in the carbon chain, which lead to a molecular structure which is not a straight chain. Upon hydrogenation, single bonds are formed in place of double bonds, with a strong preference for the formation of trans-hydrocarbon backbone rather than cis-bonds. Such molecules have a more linear structure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hydrogenated-oil&#34;&gt;Hydrogenated oil&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Partial hydrogenation changes a fat’s molecular structure (raising its melting point and reducing rancidity), but this process also results in a portion of the changed fat becoming trans fat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
