<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/vijayanagara/3_Late/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/vijayanagara/3_Late/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Feces of Pigs</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/vijayanagara/3_Late/articles/feces_of_pigs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/vijayanagara/3_Late/articles/feces_of_pigs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tmarathas-account&#34;&gt;TMarathas account&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1534167885500882945.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As per contemporary Maratha Bakhar of Rakshas Tagadi (Talikota), and Rayavacakamu, a contemporary eye-witness epilogue, the grand war between Vijaynagar and Deccan Sultanate Alliance started due to &lt;del&gt;CASTE&lt;/del&gt; issues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The emissary of Adilshahi Empire had visited the Vijaynagar court. It has to be noted that original great Bijapur City had been ruined by Vijaynagar&amp;rsquo;s armies (WITHOUT permission of the Samrat) just few years ago and tensions were always present. Even though Adilshahi Emperor respected Vijaynagar Samrat, his noblemen had not forgotten anything.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kRShNarAja on maisUru-electrification</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/vijayanagara/3_Late/articles/kRShNarAja_on_maisUru-electrification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/vijayanagara/3_Late/articles/kRShNarAja_on_maisUru-electrification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was only in 1882 that electric light was first used on a commercial scale in London, and it was another ten years before the possibility of utilising electric power at a distance from the generating station was accepted as a safe and paying undertaking. In Mysore we are exceptionally favoured in respect of sources of power to be put into harness, and in the genius of our administrators, who have seized upon the opportunity to make this power of the utmost value to the State. Compare with the dates that I have just given you the date of 1894, on which Sir K.C. Sheshadri Iyer first took up the question of the harnessing of the Cauvery Falls at Sivasamudram, and you will see that Mysore was not behind the times. In fact when in 1902 the transmission line from the Cauvery Falls to the Kolar Gold Fields, 93 miles long, and operating at 35,000 Volts, was put into service, it was the longest high voltage transmission line in the whole of Asia and the second or third longest in the world! The success of that undertaking is an eloquent testimony to the boldness of spirit, the farsightedness and the statesmanship of those who were responsible for it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kRShNarAja_25-yrs-letter</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/vijayanagara/3_Late/articles/kRShNarAja_25-yrs-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/vijayanagara/3_Late/articles/kRShNarAja_25-yrs-letter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;8th August 1927.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;On this day, when I complete the twenty fifth year of my reign, I send my loving greetings to each one of my dear people, with a heart full of solicitude for their happiness. With unceasing effort I shall, while life lasts, endeavour to promote their welfare and prosperity, and I pray that God may give me light and strength to achieve this, the supreme object of my life and rule.&#xA;Krishnaraja Wadiyar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shauqi - insolent envoy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/vijayanagara/3_Late/articles/shauqi_insolent-envoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/vijayanagara/3_Late/articles/shauqi_insolent-envoy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Sanjay Subrahmanyam&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The work in question is the &lt;em&gt;Fath Nāma- i Nizām Shāh&lt;/em&gt; (“Account of the Nizam Shah’s Victory”), and its author, Hasan Shauqi, remains quite obscure. He appears to have been active in the later sixteenth and early seventeenth centuries, and he is briefly mentioned by some other poets from the mid- seventeenth century as their predecessor. &amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The scene then shifts to the &lt;em&gt;darbār&lt;/em&gt; of Ramraj, where a conversation is in progress. The Vijayanagara ruler brings in his &lt;em&gt;wazīrs&lt;/em&gt; to prepare for the fight against the Nizam Shah. Having first praised the courage and intelligence of Husain, Ramraj then unveils his plan. It has been weighing on Ramraj that while the whole world calls him a king, only this “Turk” denies him such a tribute. Ramraj now cynically provokes the religious sentiments of the &lt;em&gt;wazīrs&lt;/em&gt; against the Nizam Shah, saying that he does not acknowledge the Vedas or Puranas, only the Quran. The &lt;em&gt;wazīrs&lt;/em&gt; become enthusiastic about the prospect of war, and say:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
