<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Native roots on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Native roots on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 The Road to Tuktoyaktuk</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/01_The_Road_to_Tuktoyaktuk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/01_The_Road_to_Tuktoyaktuk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;America ends at Tuktoyaktuk. There the land yields to the Arctic Ocean and the polar ice cap. Except for a few distant islands, human habitation stops. The frozen world beyond Tuktoyaktuk belongs to the seal-hunting polar bears that eternally wander the ice, and to the small herds of caribou and wild musk oxen that inhabit the most northern islands of the earth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The treeless, nearly barren Tuktoyaktuk Peninsula juts hesitantly from the Canadian mainland into the cold Arctic waters, but for most of the year the ice covering the land of frozen bogs and lakes looks much like the ice covering the ocean. The only landmarks separating Tuktoyaktuk Peninsula from the Arctic Ocean are the scattered pingos, the small, round ice volcanoes that poke up out of the earth like ruptured navels. In contrast to the frozen sea, the frozen land also serves as home to a band of nine hundred native Inuvialuit who built their village around a rocky bay at the base of the peninsula.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Pyramids on the Mississippi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/02_Pyramids_on_the_Mississippi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/02_Pyramids_on_the_Mississippi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A climber ascending the worn slope of the great pyramid sees the river plain slowly stretching out to the horizon. The top of the pyramid soars a hundred feet in the air, the equivalent of a ten-story building, and provides the highest viewpoint on the plain. Unlike the pointed top of the Egyptian pyramid, this truncated pyramid is capped by a massive field large enough to host a football game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Women \(and a Few Men\) Who Led the Way</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/03_Women_and_a_Few_Men_Who_Led_the_W/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/03_Women_and_a_Few_Men_Who_Led_the_W/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Mississippi River has one of the least dramatic sources of any great river in the world. The Ganges and the Mekong thunder down from the Himalayas, the Amazon begins at a glacier high in the Andes, the Nile starts in the headwaters of Lake Victoria and in the highlands of Ethiopia, over a mile above sea level, and the Rhine begins in the snowy Swiss Alps. Even the Missouri River splashes to life among the dramatic peaks of the Rockies, and the Ohio begins in the rolling mountains of Appalachia. The Mississippi River gently gurgles out of Lake Itasca in north central Minnesota. At a mere 1,475 feet above sea level, even its birth occurs as a gentle, seemingly insignificant event.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Firestorm</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/04_Firestorm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/04_Firestorm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thick birch forests cover much of south central Canada. Seen from a distance in the moonlight, the thin, straight birch trees, clustered tightly together, look as dense as the plains of elephant grass in northern Guinea, or the bamboo jungles of southern China. By growing close together, the birch, which appears to be a rather fragile tree, easily chokes out other trees and bushes by denying them a chance to get sunlight and grow. They leave no room for interlopers. Occasionally a single tall pine or fir juts up from a birch grove that invaded after it had already grown too tall to shield from the sun. The tall fir stands like a bear rearing up on its haunches, surrounded by baying dogs. The birches cannot kill the tall tree in their midst, but they surround it so densely that none of its seed will ever take root and spring to life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 The Tree in American History</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/05_The_Tree_in_American_History/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/05_The_Tree_in_American_History/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eureka, the largest town along northern California’s redwood coast, boastfully displays a love of ornate wood in its multicolored gingerbread houses. Built during the late Victorian era and the early twentieth century, when the jigsaw first came into prominent use in home decoration, the exteriors drip with carved wood that the builders nailed onto every balustrade, window, door, and porch. Rococo wooden embellishments so completely cover whatever they decorate that an onlooker can scarcely decide just what architectural function it obscures. The same building could just as easily be a home, a funeral parlor, a restaurant, a boutique, an insurance office, a museum, or a boardinghouse, and at some point in its life cycle, it may have been any of those.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 Hunting</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/06_Hunting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/06_Hunting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the shore of the Arctic ocean near Tuktoyaktuk, two old Inuvialuit hunters gather driftwood to build a fire and heat a kettle of water for making tea. They share a lunch of fresh caribou meat and &lt;em&gt;muktuk,&lt;/em&gt; the blubber taken from the sides of the beluga whale. They warm the caribou leg in the fire, and then cut off chunks of it, still dripping with blood. They alternate bits of caribou with fatty slices of muktuk, which has a rubbery consistency somewhat resembling that of squid or a chicken gizzard. It tastes distinctly of the ocean and leaves a fatty coating on the inside of the mouth. By contrast the fresh blood of the caribou tastes sweet, and the soft flesh has a flavor milder than beef and without a wild or gamy aroma.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 How the Fur Trade Shaped the American Economy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/07_How_the_Fur_Trade_Shaped_the_American/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/07_How_the_Fur_Trade_Shaped_the_American/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New York City has defined the twentieth century. Sometimes a place so dominates an epoch that the time becomes forever associated with that place, as New York has been with the twentieth century. Seemingly every major event of the century began in New York, ended in New York, passed through New York, or was financed in New York.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In an era when the world focused on the North Atlantic, New York City ruled the transatlantic world. Europe had several major ports, but they all traded with New York, which served as the shipping, communications, and air link between Europe and America. Radio and television grew up in New York during the twentieth century, and the city controlled the international arts and publishing world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 Beads and Buildings</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/08_Beads_and_Buildings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/08_Beads_and_Buildings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a bright summer evening, a small boat leaves Yellowknife harbor to take a group out for a picnic on the Great Slave Lake, in the heart of the Canadian north. Yellowknife, with a population of only 13,500, serves as the capital of the Northwest Territories, a jurisdiction as large as India and five times the size of Texas. The Dene and Inuit constitute a majority of the territory’s people, but the small total of only fifty thousand gives the territories fewer residents than some universities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 Corn, Cotton, and Tobacco</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/09_Corn_Cotton_and_Tobacco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/09_Corn_Cotton_and_Tobacco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most common way to see Pueblo Grande is from the air, not because it lies in a remote and inaccessible place, but because it lies near the end of a runway of Sky Harbor International Airport in the middle of Phoenix, Arizona. Thousands of passengers fly directly over it each day without noticing it. The ruins appear directly beneath the airplane almost as soon as the wheels lift off from the pavement at the east end of the runway.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 The Trade in Indian Slaves</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/10_The_Trade_in_Indian_Slaves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/10_The_Trade_in_Indian_Slaves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the Santa Barbara Mission, before the sun rises and before the noisy traffic begins the daily commute down the mountain to work in the town below, a visitor can almost hear the whispered groans of the thousands of Chumash who lie buried in unmarked graves in the mission graveyard. The mission exudes an eerie quiet in the early-morning stillness. The night fog recedes back toward the ocean after providing the meager moisture for the imported trees and plants that suck droplets of mist from the damp night air. The lingering fog obscures the rising sun, making it hard to tell exactly when day begins, but gradually light descends and the rays mop up the air to reveal a spectacular view of the town and ocean below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Fishing for Food and Profit</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/11_Fishing_for_Food_and_Profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/11_Fishing_for_Food_and_Profit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life on earth thrives where land and water meet—along the coasts of the oceans, the banks of the rivers, and the shores of the lakes. This holds true for terrestrial as well as marine life. Nowhere does this abundance of marine and terrestrial life show more vividly and dramatically than along the Pacific coast of southeastern Alaska, British Columbia, and Washington. The trees lap up the moisture of the perpetual fog, and in turn the trees nourish a variety of birds and animals. The larger mammals live in the water, where whales migrate in great herds among thousands of otters, sea lions, and seals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Guerrillas and Warriors</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/12_Guerrillas_and_Warriors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/12_Guerrillas_and_Warriors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Each year on the last weekend of September, the Dakota host the Mah-kato Powwow for all nations at Dakota Wokiksuye Makoce, the Land of Memories Park, just south of Mankato, Minnesota. For three days the singing groups drum and sing on the side while the people dance in an eternal circle. Between dances, elders and whole families step forward to host meals for all participants in honor of one of their members, to record a family event, or to thank the assembled people for some favor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 America’s Patron Saint</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/13_Americas_Patron_Saint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/13_Americas_Patron_Saint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Macon, Georgia, lies a little too far south of Atlanta to be a suburb, and yet a little too close to be a full city in its own right. It enjoyed a brief prosperity during the cotton days before the Civil War, and the perpetual poverty since then has preserved its handful of antebellum homes clustered on a hilltop overlooking the downtown area.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Across the tiny Ocmulgee River from downtown Macon, a poor district sprawls along the river. Small wooden houses with rickety old porches lie interspersed with cement-block houses sealed with air conditioners plugged into their windows. The small communities cluster around convenience stores that offer the coolest reprieve of any spot in the blistering and seemingly eternal summer of Georgia. The poverty of Macon has an anonymous and hard-to-identify quality—neither urban nor rural, not completely black but certainly not completely white; not hopeless, yet with no apparent remedy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Americanization of the English Language</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/14_Americanization_of_the_English_Langua/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/14_Americanization_of_the_English_Langua/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WOJB radio broadcasts daily across the Ojibwa territory of northern Wisconsin. The station originates from Lac Coutre Oreilles Reservation, just sixty miles south of what the Ojibwa call Lake Gitchee Gumi, which we know as Lake Superior, the largest freshwater lake in the world and a traditional focal point of Great Lakes Ojibwa culture and mythology. The nonprofit station operates as one of the most important Indian stations in the nation, and one of the few native stations to broadcast east of the Mississippi River.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 The Naming of North America</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/15_The_Naming_of_North_America/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/15_The_Naming_of_North_America/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seattle points toward America’s future. For a long time after its founding, Seattle must have seemed like the end of America, tucked far away in the northwest corner, accessible only by ship up the Pacific Coast or by arduous trek overland. The Northern Railroad reduced the isolation by connecting Seattle to St. Paul on the Mississippi River, and thus with the remainder of the United States. Seattle became the connecting port for people and supplies between Alaska and the lower forty-eight states; it served as warehouse and general store for the Yukon Gold Rush. It became a major point of exchange between the western United States and western Canada, and it was the United States’ closest port to Japan, Korea, and northern Asia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 North America’s Inca Historian</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/16_North_Americas_Inca_Historian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/16_North_Americas_Inca_Historian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most records of the early life of North America’s natives derive from archaeological excavations of mute objects and signs of human remains: bones, tools, weapons, marks of fenceposts in the soil, and art. Some wampum and pictographic texts have been preserved, and much information has been transmitted orally, but the oral tradition offers little information about the Indian nations that have disappeared leaving no one to pass on the spoken histories. We have no written records of these Indians that allow us to hear their own voices and explain to us their values, concepts, and beliefs. We can only piece together such cultural knowledge from the patches of information that we obtain from one source and the shreds of evidence from another.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Intellectual Mining</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/17_Intellectual_Mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/17_Intellectual_Mining/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Arkansas River twists across the state of Arkansas and through eastern Oklahoma. Barges chug down it carrying agricultural goods, coal, and the petrochemical products of Oklahoma’s lucrative oil industry. In this setting, the prosaic name of the Pocola Mining Company sounds little different from hundreds of other companies started in this century to tap the rich natural resources of Oklahoma. Most of them disappeared with little interest to anyone other than the Internal Revenue Service, and a few of them grew into fabled multimillion-dollar fortunes that financed the skyscrapers, mansions, and magnificent art collections of Tulsa, Oklahoma City, and Bartlesville.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Mixed-Blood Nation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/18_Mixed-Blood_Nation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/18_Mixed-Blood_Nation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lower Fort Garry overlooks Manitoba’s Red River, which flows north to form the broad Lake Winnipeg. The fort rises up on a lonely, quiet stretch of the river, not too far from the geographical center of the North American continent. If one drew a large X on a map of North America, running one line from northern Quebec to Baja California in Mexico, and the other from Florida to the northwestern tip of Alaska, the lines would intersect in southern Manitoba, near Lower Fort Garry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 The White Roots of Peace</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/19_The_White_Roots_of_Peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/19_The_White_Roots_of_Peace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Hiawatha Wampum survives as the oldest constitution in North America, perhaps the oldest in the world. The edges of the beaded belt have frayed slightly, but the skilled hands that made the purple and white beads from whelk shells, carefully tied each bead into its place. The Hiawatha Belt signifies the union of the nations of the Haudenosaunee, the Iroquois League, founded approximately six hundred years ago by Deganawidah and Hiawatha.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About the Author</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/About_the_Author/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/americas/articles/weatherford-jack/native-roots/About_the_Author/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jack Weatherford’s previous books include &lt;em&gt;Tribes on the Hill&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Indian Givers.&lt;/em&gt; His studies of Native Americans on both continents and their bridge building between the Old and New Worlds have taken him to fifty countries around the globe, and his works have been translated into five languages. He is an anthropologist at Macalester College in St. Paul, Minnesota.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
