<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Electric-vehicle-grifters</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/articles/electric-vehicle-grifters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/articles/electric-vehicle-grifters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Biden and the Media Are Electric-Vehicle Grifters&lt;br&gt;&#xA;If the president succeeds, global emissions will be 0.18% lower.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;By&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Holman W. Jenkins&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 18, 2023 6:23 pm ET&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Joe Biden drives a Cadillac Lyriq during a tour at an auto show in Detroit, Sept. 14, 2022.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I pestered a senior Biden climate official a few months ago about the counterintuitive argument that green handouts won’t reduce fossil-fuel consumption, he surprised me by finishing my sentence. The only real solution is for governments “to put a price on carbon,” he said, and speculated Democrats and Republicans might break the ice with a carbon-related import tax.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy addicion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/articles/energy-addiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/power/articles/energy-addiction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, we need leaders capable of abandoning the kind of thinking that worships more technology as the only solution capable of repairing the damage caused by previous technologies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the last word should go to Ivan Illich, a great prophetic voice. The philosopher warned a half-century ago that unlimited and clean energy might appear to be the solution, but deliver its own problems. &amp;ldquo;Even if nonpolluting power were feasible and abundant,&amp;rdquo; he wrote, “the use of energy on a massive scale acts on society like a drug that is physically harmless but psychically enslaving.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
