<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;28 The Growth of the Church A D 96-305 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/28_The_Growth_of_the_Church_A_D_96-305/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;28 The Growth of the Church A D 96-305 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/28_The_Growth_of_the_Church_A_D_96-305/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 THE CHRISTIANS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/28_The_Growth_of_the_Church_A_D_96-305/01_THE_CHRISTIANS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/28_The_Growth_of_the_Church_A_D_96-305/01_THE_CHRISTIANS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THEY met in private rooms or small chapels, and organized themselves on the model of the synagogue.1 Each congregation was called an &lt;em&gt;ekklesia&lt;/em&gt;—the Greek term for the popular assembly in municipal governments. Slaves were welcomed, as in the Isiac and Mithraic cults; no attempt was made to liberate them, but they were comforted by the promise of a Kingdom in which all could be free. The early converts were predominantly proletarian, with a sprinkling of the lower middle classes and an occasional conquest among the rich. Nevertheless, they were far from being the “dregs of the people,” as Celsus would claim; they lived for the most part orderly and industrious lives, financed missions, and raised funds for impoverished Christian communities. Little effort was made as yet to win over the rural population; these came in last, and it was in this strange way that their name &lt;em&gt;pagani&lt;/em&gt; (villagers, peasants) came to be applied to the pre-Christian inhabitants of the Mediterranean states.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 THE CONFLICT OF CREEDS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/28_The_Growth_of_the_Church_A_D_96-305/02_THE_CONFLICT_OF_CREEDS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/28_The_Growth_of_the_Church_A_D_96-305/02_THE_CONFLICT_OF_CREEDS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It would have been surprising if, in the multitude of relatively independent centers of Christianity, subject to different traditions and environments, there had failed to develop a diversity of customs and creeds. Greek Christianity in particular was destined to a flood of heresies by the metaphysical and argumentative habits of the Greek mind. Christianity can be understood only in the perspective of these heresies, for even in defeating them it took something of their color and form.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 PLOTINUS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/28_The_Growth_of_the_Church_A_D_96-305/03_PLOTINUS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/28_The_Growth_of_the_Church_A_D_96-305/03_PLOTINUS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Moreover, Celsus was out of step with his time; he asked men to behave like gentlemen skeptics when they were withdrawing from a society that enslaved so many of them into a mystic world that made every man a god. That consciousness of supersensible powers which is the foundation of religion was prevailing universally over the materialism and determinism of a prouder age. Philosophy was abandoning the interpretation of that sense experience which is the realm of science, and was devoting itself to a study of the unseen world. Neo-Pythagoreans and Neoplatonists developed Pythagoras’ theory of transmigration, and Plato’s contemplation of the Divine Ideas, into an asceticism that sought to sharpen spiritual perception by starving the physical senses, and to reclimb by self-purification the steps by which the soul had been degraded from heaven into man.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 THE DEFENDERS OF THE FAITH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/28_The_Growth_of_the_Church_A_D_96-305/04_THE_DEFENDERS_OF_THE_FAITH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/28_The_Growth_of_the_Church_A_D_96-305/04_THE_DEFENDERS_OF_THE_FAITH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Church now won to its support some of the finest minds in the Empire. Ignatius, Bishop of Antioch, began the powerful dynasty of the post-apostolic “Fathers,” who gave a philosophy to Christianity, and overwhelmed its enemies with argument. Condemned to be thrown to the beasts for refusing to abjure his faith (108), Justin composed on his way to Rome several letters whose hot devotion reveals the spirit in which Christians could go to their death:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 THE ORGANIZATION OF AUTHORITY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/28_The_Growth_of_the_Church_A_D_96-305/05_THE_ORGANIZATION_OF_AUTHORITY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/articles/durant_caesar_and_christ/5_THE_YOUTH_OF_CHRISTIANITY_4_B_C_-A_D_325/28_The_Growth_of_the_Church_A_D_96-305/05_THE_ORGANIZATION_OF_AUTHORITY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Church might be excused for condemning Origen: his principle of allegorical interpretation not only made it possible to prove anything, but at one blow it did away with the narratives of Scripture and the earthly life of Christ; and it restored individual judgment precisely while proposing to defend the faith. Faced with the hostility of a powerful government, the Church felt the need of unity; it could not safely allow itself to be divided into a hundred feeble parts by every wind of intellect, by disloyal heretics, ecstatic prophets, or brilliant sons. Celsus himself had sarcastically observed that Christians were “split up into ever so many factions, each individual desiring to have his own party.”68 About 187 Irenaeus listed twenty varieties of Christianity; about 384 Epiphanius counted eighty. At every point foreign ideas were creeping into Christian belief, and Christian believers were deserting to novel sects. The Church felt that its experimental youth was ending, its maturity was near; it must now define its terms and proclaim the conditions of its membership. Three difficult steps were necessary: the formation of a scriptural canon, the determination of doctrine, and the organization of authority.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
