<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Cochran Gregory on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/cochran_gregory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Cochran Gregory on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/cochran_gregory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IJA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-06-20_ija/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-06-20_ija/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.wordpress.com/2012/06/20/ija/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IJA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;last-stands&#34;&gt;Last stands&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everyone has heard of famous last stands, such as Thermopylae, the&#xA;Alamo, or the French Foreign Legion at Camerone. They are memorable&#xA;partly because they are rare – generally, soldiers surrender when all is&#xA;lost, assuming that their enemies give them a chance to do so.  Even&#xA;Spartans, products of a lifetime of military training, could surrender,&#xA;as shown at Sphacteria in the Peloponnesian War.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So an army that routinely executed last stands – one that always refused&#xA;to surrender, that kept fighting until eliminated by firepower or&#xA;starvation – would be anomalous. It’s hard to imagine, but it’s easy&#xA;to remember: that’s what the Imperial Japanese Army was like in World&#xA;War Two.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wizard War</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-06-10_wizard-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-06-10_wizard-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.wordpress.com/2012/06/10/wizard-war/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wizard War&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Partly because it has some interesting examples of thick and thin&#xA;problems, but mostly because it’s so damn much fun, I’m going to talk&#xA;about &lt;em&gt;The Wizard War&lt;/em&gt;, by R. V. Jones.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reginald Jones (Ph.D. Oxford, 1934) was one of the first scientists to&#xA;work for an intelligence service. He investigated German radio&#xA;navigational systems and developed various methods of interfering with&#xA;them, which often involved projecting the German’s next move in the&#xA;electronic war. He was one of the developers of ‘chaff’, and also&#xA;served as an expert consultant on the development of German rocketry –&#xA;mainly the V-2.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enigma</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-03-15_enigma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-03-15_enigma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.wordpress.com/2012/03/15/enigma/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enigma&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Western Allies, in World War II, ran the most successful&#xA;intelligence effort in history. They did well against the Japanese,&#xA;frequently making partial decrypts of JN-25, the main fleet code, along&#xA;with lots of useful traffic analysis, etc.+++(4)+++  They did better still&#xA;against the Germans: most of the regime’s operational orders were sent&#xA;using the Enigma coding machine, and by 1942 the Allies were routinely&#xA;decoding three-rotor Enigma messages, used by the German Army and the&#xA;Luftwaffe, the same day.+++(5)+++ They not only knew which cards the Germans&#xA;were holding – they usually knew what the Germans were &lt;em&gt;thinking&lt;/em&gt; about&#xA;those cards.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gauge Transformation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-02-23_gauge-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-02-23_gauge-transformation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.wordpress.com/2012/02/23/gauge-transformation/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gauge Transformation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a reader pointed out, you don’t need to to have a flypaper memory to&#xA;be a physicist. There you can go a long way with a few basic facts and&#xA;a long chain of mathematical reasoning. You can see that the equation&#xA;of state is going to go soft when things turn relativistic, and suddenly&#xA;the star collapses. Whee!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But many subjects are not like that. Understanding, to the extent that&#xA;it is possible at all, requires mastery of many facts. Consider&#xA;Barbarossa, the invasion of the Soviet Union. More than three million&#xA;Germans invaded, with hundreds of thousands of motor vehicles and even&#xA;more &lt;em&gt;horses&lt;/em&gt;. The Germans had the initiative and were tactically&#xA;superior: the Russians had greater numbers and resources, if they could&#xA;survive long enough to bring them into play. The Germans had to win&#xA;quickly, if they were to win at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>War in the East</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-02-02_war-in-the-east/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/military/articles/cochran_gregory/2012-02-02_war-in-the-east/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://westhunt.wordpress.com/2012/02/02/war-in-the-east/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;War in the East&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The books generally say that biological warfare is ineffective, but then&#xA;they would say that, wouldn’t they? There is reason to think it has&#xA;worked, and it may have made a difference.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;german-assault&#34;&gt;German assault&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, it was spring 1942, and the Germans were on a roll.&#xA;Timoshenko had attacked from an already-established bridgehead across&#xA;the Donets (the Izium salient) with about 750,000 men. He made a bad&#xA;choice, since the Germans had already begun concentrating their forces&#xA;for a planned southern offensive. After some initial Soviet gains, the&#xA;Germans brought in Luftwaffe reinforcements and achieved air&#xA;superiority. The 1st Panzer army counterattacked and cut off much of the&#xA;Russian forces, who lost a quarter of a million prisoners (according to&#xA;Beevor), many dead and wounded, and most of their armor. There was a&#xA;huge hole in the front, and the Germans advanced towards Stalingrad.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
