<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Nixey darkening age on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Nixey darkening age on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 THE INVISIBLE ARMY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/01_THE_INVISIBLE_ARMY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/01_THE_INVISIBLE_ARMY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘Behold, I give unto you power to tread on serpents and scorpions, and over all the power of the enemy,’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Luke 10:19&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Satan knew how to tempt St Antony. One day, in a far corner of the Roman Empire, in Egypt, this prosperous young man caught the attention of the Evil One when he did something that was at the time very unusual. Aged about twenty, Antony walked out of his house, sold his possessions, gave all his land away and went to live in a pigsty.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 BATTLEGROUND OF DEMONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/02_BATTLEGROUND_OF_DEMONS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/02_BATTLEGROUND_OF_DEMONS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘My name is Legion: for we are many,’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mark 5:9&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This period was, for the later Church, an age of heroes. In those days the great giants of the Church still walked the earth; this was a time when St Augustine might go to speak to St Ambrose or write a letter to St Jerome. Many of their names, even today, are well-known. We have heard of the emperor Constantine, of St Martin and of St Antony – or at least of his monastery. We might even know the occasional humanizing detail about them: that Constantine founded Constantinople; that (less appealingly) he boiled his wife in a bath. We might well know that Augustine had an overbearing mother; or that as a young man he wished for God to make him chaste – but not yet.1 This is a period that can seem familiar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 WISDOM IS FOOLISHNESS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/03_WISDOM_IS_FOOLISHNESS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/03_WISDOM_IS_FOOLISHNESS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘Utter trash,’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the Greek intellectual Celsus evaluates the Old Testament&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In early AD 163, some of the most glamorous figures of second-century Rome gathered in a distinctly unglamorous-looking room. These people were not the merely rich, they were something that in those days was considered far more chic: they were the empire’s intellectual elite. Eminent philosophers, scholars and thinkers could be glimpsed among the gathering crowd.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In front of this illustrious group, however, was one rather less distinguished guest: on a large board at the front of the room, tied fast by ropes around each limb, was one doubtless rather distressed-looking pig.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 SMALL NUMBER OF MARTYRS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/04_SMALL_NUMBER_OF_MARTYRS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/04_SMALL_NUMBER_OF_MARTYRS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;‘ON THE SMALL NUMBER OF MARTYRS’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘Don’t you see the beauty of this pleasant weather?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;There will be no pleasure to come your way if you kill your own self,’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a Roman official addresses a would-be martyr&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Christian myth, the persecution began with Nero. He, it was said, was ‘the first of the emperors to be the declared enemy of the worship of Almighty God’.1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Few people, Christian or otherwise, had expected Nero to be a good thing. His breeding alone augured against it. His father, Domitius, had once, while driving his chariot through a village, run over and killed a young boy for fun. When another nobleman reprimanded him, Domitius turned and gouged out the man’s eye. Nero’s mother, Agrippina, was little more promising: a society beauty, in AD 54 she had murdered her third husband, the emperor Claudius, by poisoning him with his favourite food of mushrooms at a family dinner. Not even Nero’s own father had high hopes for his offspring. When he was born, Domitius remarked sanguinely that ‘any child born to himself and Agrippina was bound to have a detestable nature and become a public danger’.2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 THESE DERANGED MEN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/05_THESE_DERANGED_MEN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/05_THESE_DERANGED_MEN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘Because they love the name martyr and because they desire human praise more than divine charity, they kill themselves,’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pseudo Jerome&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the middle of the baking August of AD 111, as his ship rounded the foot of the Peloponnese in suffocating heat, Pliny the Younger looked little like the diabolical Roman governor of legend. The statue of Pliny in his hometown of Como shows him as a man with matinee-idol charms: a sternly square jaw set off by a sensuous mouth, a sensitive faraway gaze and lustrous curls. If Pliny was so dashing (which, given that he was then a middle-aged bureaucrat seems improbable) then on that day he was very unlikely to have been looking his best. He was hot, he was flustered and he was very late.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 MAGNIFICENT BUILDING</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/06_MAGNIFICENT_BUILDING/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/06_MAGNIFICENT_BUILDING/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE MOST MAGNIFICENT BUILDING IN THE WORLD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘He that sacrificeth unto any god, save unto the Lord only, he shall be utterly destroyed,’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exodus 22:20&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the end of the first century of Christian rule, the Colosseum still dominated Rome and the Parthenon towered above Athens. Yet when writers of this period discuss architecture, these aren’t the buildings that impress them. Instead, their admiration is drawn by another structure in Egypt. This building was so fabulous that writers in the ancient world struggled to find ways to convey its beauty. ‘Its splendour is such that mere words can only do it an injustice,’ wrote the historian Ammianus Marcellinus.1 It was, another writer thought, ‘one of the most unique and uncommon sights in the world. For nowhere else on earth can one find such a building.’2 Its great halls, its columns, its astonishing statues and its art all made it, outside Rome, ‘the most magnificent building in the whole world’.3 Everyone had heard of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 TO DESPISE THE TEMPLES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/07_TO_DESPISE_THE_TEMPLES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/07_TO_DESPISE_THE_TEMPLES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘The weakness of paganism as a religion is manifest . . . it was bound in the end to give way to a higher creed,’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gilbert Grindle, &lt;em&gt;The Destruction of Paganism in the Roman Empire&lt;/em&gt;, 1892&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This new Christian era began with a vision, and a declaration of liberty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In October AD 312, the emperor Constantine saw one of the most famous visions in the history of Europe. One day, so the story goes, not long before a forthcoming battle against his imperial rival, Maxentius, Constantine happened to look up into the sky at noon while praying. What he claimed to see would blaze out across the centuries. For above the sun, Constantine saw a cross of light. And next to it were the words: ‘Conquer by this.’1 Constantine and his army, aided by the religion of the Prince of Peace, went on to win the battle. Constantine’s conversion to the faith – so it was said – was now assured.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 HOW TO DESTROY A DEMON</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/08_HOW_TO_DESTROY_A_DEMON/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/08_HOW_TO_DESTROY_A_DEMON/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘He completely demolished the temple belonging to the false religion and reduced all the altars and statues to dust,’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Life of Martin&lt;/em&gt;, 14.6&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The pages of history might overlook this destruction, but stone is less forgetful. Go to Room 18 in the British Museum in London and you will find yourself in front of the Parthenon Marbles, taken from Greece by Lord Elgin in the nineteenth century. The astonishingly lifelike statues are, today, in a sorry state: many are mutilated or missing limbs. This, it is often assumed, was the fault of Lord Elgin’s clumsy workmen or fighting during the Ottoman occupation. And indeed some of this was – but not all. Much was the work of zealous Christians who set about the temple with blunt instruments, attacking the ‘demonic’ gods, mutilating some of the finest statuary Greece had ever produced.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 THE RECKLESS ONES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/09_THE_RECKLESS_ONES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/09_THE_RECKLESS_ONES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘For the wisdom of this world is foolishness with God,’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians 3:19&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They called them the ‘&lt;em&gt;parabalani&lt;/em&gt;’ – ‘the reckless ones’.1 At first, the name had been a compliment. Under the scorching heat of the Alexandrian sun, in this city at the crossroads of busy trading routes, someone needed to carry away the bodies of the sick and the weak – not to mention the merely unsavoury poor – and do so swiftly, to protect everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 TO DRINK FROM THE CUP OF DEVILS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/10_TO_DRINK_FROM_THE_CUP_OF_DEVILS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/10_TO_DRINK_FROM_THE_CUP_OF_DEVILS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘We, if wise, shall take from heathen books whatever befits us and is allied to the truth, and shall pass over the rest,’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;St Basil, &lt;em&gt;Address&lt;/em&gt;, IV&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Near the beginning of Umberto Eco’s novel &lt;em&gt;The Name of the Rose&lt;/em&gt;, an erudite medieval abbot turns to a monk who has just arrived in his monastery in Italy. ‘&lt;em&gt;Monasterium sine libris&lt;/em&gt;,’ he declaims, in Latin, naturally, ‘&lt;em&gt;est sicut . . . hortus sine herbis, pratum sine floribus, arbor sine foliis&lt;/em&gt;.’ A monastery without books is like a garden without herbs, a meadow without flowers, a tree without leaves. The abbot continues this explanation (or, less charitably, exposition) of monastic life in the vernacular. His order of monks, the Benedictines, he explains, ‘growing up under the double command of work and prayer, was light to the whole known world, depository of knowledge, salvation of an ancient learning that threatened to disappear in fires, sacks, earthquakes, forge of new writing and increase of the ancient’.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 TO CLEANSE THE ERROR OF DEMONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/11_TO_CLEANSE_THE_ERROR_OF_DEMONS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/11_TO_CLEANSE_THE_ERROR_OF_DEMONS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘Stay clear of all pagan books!’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apostolic Constitutions 1.6.1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Alexandria, towards the end of the fifth century, a Christian chronicler named Zachariah of Mytilene entered the house of a man and found that he was ‘sweating and depressed’. Zachariah instantly knew what was wrong: this man was struggling with demons. Zachariah knew too where these demons were coming from: the man had some documents containing pagan spells in his house. ‘If you want to get rid of the anxiety,’ the man was now told, ‘burn these papers.’ And so he did. He took his works and, in front of Zachariah, set light to them. The encounter concludes with a homily being read to the man who had now been cleansed of his ‘demons’ – not to mention of part of his library.1 As the pious Zachariah makes very clear, he did not consider that he has harmed this man by forcing him to burn his papers. He had not bullied him, or acted cruelly towards him. Quite the reverse: he had saved him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 *CARPE DIEM*</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/12_CARPE_DIEM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/12_CARPE_DIEM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let the girl with a pretty face lie supine, let the lady&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Who boasts a good back be viewed&lt;br&gt;&#xA;From behind . . . The petite should ride horse . . .&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the Roman poet Ovid advises on positions for lovemaking, &lt;em&gt;Ars Amatoria&lt;/em&gt;, 3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘&lt;em&gt;Imperium sine fine&lt;/em&gt;’ – ‘Empire without end’.1 That, so the poet had said, had been Rome’s aim as it had sought to push itself forwards, outwards, onwards into new countries, new continents and new worlds. But the Christianity that had taken it over was, according to its preachers, no less ambitious. As the world’s first century of Christian rule drew to a close and the fifth century opened, the effects of this conquest were everywhere to be seen. In Italy, Gaul, Greece, Spain, Syria and Egypt, temples that had stood for centuries were falling, shutting, crumbling. Brambles began to grow across disused ruins, as the mutilated faces of gods looked on silently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 FORSAKE THE WAY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/13_FORSAKE_THE_WAY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/13_FORSAKE_THE_WAY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THEY THAT FORSAKE THE WAY OF GOD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘Then will the tragic actors be worth hearing, more vocal in their own catastrophe;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;then the comic actors will be worth watching, much lither of limb in the fire;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;then the charioteer will be worth seeing, red all over on his fiery wheel;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;then the athletes will be worth observing, not in their gymnasiums, but thrown about by fire,’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tertullian, reflects on the pleasures of Judgement Day, &lt;em&gt;De Spectaculis&lt;/em&gt;, 30.5&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 OBLITERATE JOY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/14_OBLITERATE_JOY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/14_OBLITERATE_JOY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TO OBLITERATE THE TYRANNY OF JOY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘For the eye of God always sees the works of a man and nothing escapes him,’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Sayings of the Desert Fathers, Gelasius, 6&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you had travelled to the great cities in the eastern empire, to Alexandria and to Antioch, in the fourth and fifth centuries, then long before you came to a city itself you would have seen them. At dawn, they emerged from caves in the hills and holes in the ground, their dark robes flapping; their faces gaunt and pale from hunger, their eyes hollow from lack of sleep. As the cocks began to crow, while the city beyond was still slumbering, they gathered in the monasteries and hills beyond and,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 MERCIFUL SAVAGERY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/15_MERCIFUL_SAVAGERY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/15_MERCIFUL_SAVAGERY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘There is no cruelty in regard for God’s honour,’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;St Jerome, Letter 109.32&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It had all seemed so simple: render unto Caesar what is Caesar’s. Render unto God what is God’s. As the fourth century drew to its close and the fifth century opened, caveats were added, complications brought to bear. What, asked some of the most powerful preachers, if God and Caesar both laid claim to the same thing? Well, said the great thinkers of the first Christian century, in that case God took precedence. As Augustine put it, if God’s law diverged from Roman law then the Heavenly City and its inhabitants were compelled ‘to dissent, and to become obnoxious to those who think differently’.1 Everything – man, law, and even bureaucracy – was now to give way to God. Or rather, to His Church. And if this meant some sticky moments on earth then so be it, for, argued another aggressive Christian cleric, the greatest wrong that one could do was not to disobey the law but to disobey God. ‘It is better to be deprived of empire, than to become guilty of impiety.’2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 A TIME OF TYRANNY AND CRISIS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/16_A_TIME_OF_TYRANNY_AND_CRISIS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/16_A_TIME_OF_TYRANNY_AND_CRISIS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘Moreover, we forbid the teaching of any doctrine by those who labour under the insanity of paganism,’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Justinian Code 1.11.10.2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The philosopher Damascius was a brave man: you had to be to see what he had seen and still be a philosopher. But as he walked through the streets of Athens in AD 529 and heard the new laws bellowed out in the town’s crowded squares, even he must have felt the stirrings of unease.1 He was a man who had known persecution at the hands of the Christians before. He would have been a fool not to recognize the signs that it was beginning again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Notes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/17_Notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/17_Notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;prologue-a-beginning&#34;&gt;PROLOGUE: A BEGINNING&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1.Coptic pilgrims’ chant, quoted in Kristensen (2013), 85.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-an-ending&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION: AN ENDING&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1.Athanassiadi (1993), 4; Marinus, &lt;em&gt;Life of Proclus&lt;/em&gt;, 26.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;em&gt;PH&lt;/em&gt;, 124.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;em&gt;PH&lt;/em&gt;, 117C; Olympiodorus, &lt;em&gt;Commentary on the First Alcibiades&lt;/em&gt;, quoted in Cameron (1969), 15.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4.C. Th., 16.4.4.2, dated 16 June 388.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;em&gt;AGT&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6.&lt;em&gt;PH&lt;/em&gt;, 119.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;7.&lt;em&gt;PH&lt;/em&gt;, 42.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;8.Palladas, 10.90 and 10.82.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;9.The precise criteria for a triumph varied; the stipulation of thousands dead was, for a time, one of them. Deciding when a triumph had been won was usually more an art than a science. See Beard (2007).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Index</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/18_Index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/articles/nixey_darkening-age/18_Index/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Acropolis, Athens ref1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Acts of John&lt;/em&gt; ref1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Acts of Paul and Thecla&lt;/em&gt; ref1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aeschylus ref1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Agrippina ref1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alban, St ref1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alexander the Great ref1, ref2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alexandria ref1, ref2, ref3, ref4, ref5, ref6, ref7, ref8, ref9&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Great Library ref1, ref2, ref3, ref4, ref5, ref6&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Great Lighthouse ref1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Musaeum ref1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;zoo ref1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amantius ref1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ambrose, Bishop of Milan ref1, ref2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ambrose of Alexandria ref1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ammianus Marcellinus ref1, ref2, ref3, ref4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Antioch ref1, ref2, ref3, ref4, ref5, ref6&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
