<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;1 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;1 on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 TENDENCY IN ENGLISH HISTORY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/1/01_TENDENCY_IN_ENGLISH_HISTORY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/1/01_TENDENCY_IN_ENGLISH_HISTORY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is a favourite maxim of mine that history, while it should be scientific in its method, should pursue a practical object. That is, it should not merely gratify the reader&amp;rsquo;s curiosity about the past, but modify his view of the present and his forecast of the future. Now if this maxim be sound, the history of England ought to end with something that might be called a moral. Some large conclusion ought to arise out of it ; it ought to exhibit the general tendency of English affairs in such a way as to set us thinking about the future and divining the destiny which is reserved for us. The more so because the part played by our country in the world certainly does not grow less prominent as history advances. Some countries, such as Holland and Sweden, might pardonably regard their history as in a manner wound up. They were once great, but the conditions of their greatness have passed away, and they now hold a secondary place. &amp;amp; B&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 ENGLAND IN THE EIGHTEENTH CENTURY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/1/02_ENGLAND_IN_THE_EIGHTEENTH_CENTURY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/1/02_ENGLAND_IN_THE_EIGHTEENTH_CENTURY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was in the eighteenth century that the expansion of England advanced most rapidly. If therefore we would understand the nature of that expansion, and measure how much it absorbed of the energy and vitality of the nation, we cannot do better than consult the records of the eighteenth century. Those records too, if I mistake not, will acquire new interest from being regarded from this point of view.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I constantly remark, both in our popular histories and in occasional allusions to the eighteenth century, what a faint and confused impression that period has left upon the national memory. In a great part of it we see nothing but stagnation. The wars seem to lead to nothing, and we do &amp;ldquo;not perceive the working of any new political ideas. That time seems to have created little, so that we can only think of it as pros- perous, but not as memorable. Those dim figures George I. and George II., the long tame administra-&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 THE EMPIRE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/1/03_THE_EMPIRE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/1/03_THE_EMPIRE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LECTURE III The expression &amp;quot; Colonial Empire &amp;quot; is familiar to us, and yet there is something strange in the juxtaposition of words. The word Empire seems too military and despotic to suit the relation of a mother-country to colonies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two very different kinds of colonisation. First there is a kind which may be called natural, in the sense that it has manifest analogies in the natural world. &amp;ldquo;Colonies are like fruits which only cling till they ripen,&amp;rdquo; said Turgot. Colonisation, say others, is like the swarming of bees ; or it is like the marriage and migration to another house of the grown-up son. And no doubt history furnishes us with real examples of such easy and natural colonisa tion. The primitive migrations may often have been of this kind. In the first chapters of European history, in the earliest traditions of Greece and Italy, which show us the Greco-Italian branch of the Aryan family in the act of occupying the territory whichLECT. in THE EMPIRE 45 was afterwards to be the scene of its greatness, we see this easy process going on under the influence of primitive ideas. We read of the institution called ver sacrum, by which all the children born in one spring would be dedicated to some deity, who was supposed to accept emigration in lieu of sacrifice ; ^ the votaries accordingly, when they grew up, were driven across the frontier, and sometimes they settled and founded a city on the spot where an animal accidentally overtaken on the journey, in whom they saw a guide sent by the god, had chanced to stop. From such a sacred animal we are told that some cities, e.g. Bovianum and Picenum, received their name.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 THE OLD COLONIAL SYSTEM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/1/04_THE_OLD_COLONIAL_SYSTEM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/1/04_THE_OLD_COLONIAL_SYSTEM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I REMARKED that ancient Greek colonisation, com pared with the modern system, might be called in a certain sense the natural system. And yet the modern system might be represented as natural also. The Greeks regard the State as essentially small, and infer that a surplus population can only be accommo dated by founding another State. But is there any thing necessarily unnatural in the other view, that the State is capable of indefinite growth and expan sion &amp;ldquo;J The ripe fruit dropping from the tree and giving rise to another tree may be natural, but so is the acorn spreading into the huge oak, that has hundreds of branches and thousands of leaves. If Miletus among its daughter-cities may remind us of the one, England expanding into Greater Britain resembles the other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 EFFECT OF THE NEW WORLD ON THE OLD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/1/05_EFFECT_OF_THE_NEW_WORLD_ON_THE_OLD/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/1/05_EFFECT_OF_THE_NEW_WORLD_ON_THE_OLD/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a former lecture I pointed out how much unity is given to the history of England in the eighteenth century, how all the great wars of that time are shown to belong together and fall into a connected series, if you remark the single fact that Greater Britain during that period was establishing itself in opposition to Greater France. And I have since proceeded further in the same train of reflection, by remarking that during the eighteenth and seven- teenth centuries it is not England and France only that have great colonies, but Spain, Portugal, and Holland also. You will, I think, find it very helpful in studying the history of those two centuries, always to bear in mind that throughout most of that period the five states of Western Europe all alike are not properly European states but world-states, and that they debate continually among themselves a mighty question, which is not European at all, and which the student with his eye fixed on Europe is LECT. V EFFECT OF THE NEW WOULD ON THE OLD 91 too apt to disregard, namely, the question of the possession of the New World.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 COMMERCE AND WAR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/1/06_COMMERCE_AND_WAR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/1/06_COMMERCE_AND_WAR/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;] Competition for the New World between the five western maritime States of Europe : this is a formula which sums up a great part of the history of the seventeenth and eighteenth centuries. It is one of those generalisations which escape us so long as we study history only in single states.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Much would be gained if the student of history would look at modern Europe as he has already the habit of looking at ancient Greece. Here he has constantly before him three or four different states at once—Athens, Sparta, Thebes, Argos, not to mention Macedonia and Persia, and is led to make most instructive comparisons and most useful reflections upon large general tendencies. This is entirely owing to the accident that Greece was not a State but a complex of States, which fact our historians do not perceive clearly enough to conclude, as in con sistency they ought, that they ought not to write a history of Greece at all, but separate histories ofLECT. yi COMMERCE AND WAR 115 Athens, Sparta, etc. Let me ask those of you who know Grecian history to apply to these Western States the mode of conceiving to which you have accustomed yourselves. You have been in the habit of thinking of a cluster of States gathered round a common sea, which is studded with islands, and which has on the other side of it large territories imperfectly known and inhabited by strange races. You have thought of all these States together, and not merely of each by itself ; you have traced the general results produced upon the Hellenic world as a whole by all the intricate play of interests between the several Hellenic city-states. Now the five States we have in view—Spain, Portugal, France, Holland and England—were ranged in like manner on the North-Eastern shore of the Atlantic Ocean, and had in like manner a common interest in what that Ocean contained or hid. If the States seem to you so large, the Ocean so boundless, and the settlements so scattered that you cannot bring them into one view, make an effort, bring them into the same map, and draw the map on a small scale. But your great effort must be to raise your head above the current of mere chronological narrative, to apply a fixed principle to the selection of facts, grouping them not by nearness in time, nor by their personal biographical connection, but by the internal affinity of causation. This great struggle of five States for the New World differs from the struggles of those old Greek States in thisj that it is not isolated. It was superinduced by the discovery of Columbus upon other struggles, 116 EXPANSION OF ENGLAND leot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 PHASES OF EXPANSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/1/07_PHASES_OF_EXPANSION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/1/07_PHASES_OF_EXPANSION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The object I professed to set before myself in these lectures was to present English history to you in such a light that the interest of it instead of gradually diminishing should go on increasing to the close.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will perceive by this time in what way I hope to do this. It is impossible that the history of any State can be interesting, unless it exhibits some sort of development. Political life that is uniform has no history, however prosperous it may be. Now it appears to me that English historians fail in the later periods of England, because they have traced one great development to its completion, and do not perceive that, if they would advance further, they must look out for some other development. More or less consciously, they have always before their minds the idea of constitutional liberty. This idea suffices until they reach the licvolution of 1688, perhaps even until they reach the accession of the LECT. VII PHASES OF EXPANSION 139 House of Brunswick. But after this it fails them. Not that development ceases in the English Con stitution at that point, nor even that to the political student it becomes less interesting. But it begins to be gradual and quiet ; the tension is relaxed ; dram atic incident henceforth must be looked for elsewhere. Our historians are not sufficiently alive to this. It may be true that George III.&amp;rsquo;s use of royal influence attained in an insidious way objects similar to those which the Stuarts tried to reach by prerogative or by military force. But when Wilkes and Home Tooke, Chatham and Fox are brought forward to play the parts of Prynne and Milton, Pym and Shaftesbury, the interest of the reader grows languid. He seems to have before him the feeble second part of some striking story. Those parliamentary strug gles which in the seventeenth century were so intense, seem, when repeated in the eighteenth, to have something conventional about them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 SCHISM IN GREATER BRITAIN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/1/08_SCHISM_IN_GREATER_BRITAIN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/kentum/germanic/english/USA/articles/expansion_of_england_seel/1/08_SCHISM_IN_GREATER_BRITAIN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As objects change their outline when the observer changes his point of view, so the history of a state may be made to take many forms. The outline I have given of English history in the seventeenth and eighteenth centuries is very different from that with which we are familiar, because I have taken a point of view from which many things seem great that before seemed small, and many small that seemed great, while some things are now outline that were shading, and others are shading that were outline. And yet most people think of history as if its outline were quite fixed and unalterable. Details, they think, may be more or less accurate, more or less vivid, in this historian or in that, but the framework must be the same for all historians. In reality it is just this framework, the list of great events which children learn by heart, that is unfixed, unstable, alterable, though it seems made of cast-iron. For what makes an event great or little 1 Is the acces-LECT, viii SCHISM IN GREATEE BRITAIN 165 sion of a king necessarily a great event? At the moment it seems great, but when the excitement it causes has subsided, it may appear to have been in the history of the country no event at all. This principle consistently applied would produce a re- volution in our ideas of history. It would show us that the real history of a state may be quite different from the conventional, since all or many of the events that have passed for great may be really unimportant, and the truly important events may be among those which have been slightly or not at all recorded. We must have then a test for the historical im- portance of events, and to apply this test will be a principal part of the historian&amp;rsquo;s task. Now what test shall we apply 1 Shall we say, &amp;quot; The historian should make prominent those events which are interesting i&amp;quot; But surely an occurrence may be inter- esting biographically, or morally, or poetically, and yet not interesting historically. Shall we say then, &amp;quot; He is to give to events the importance they were felt to have at the moment when they happened ; he is to revive the emotion of the time &amp;ldquo;1 I maintain that it is not the business of the historian, as we so often hear, to put his reader back in the past time, or to make him regard events as they were regarded by contemporaries. Where woidd be the use of this&amp;rsquo;? Great events are commonly judged by contemporaries quite wrongly. It is in fact one of the chief functions of the historian to correct this contemporary judg- ment. Instead of making us share the emotions of the passing time, it is his business to point out to us 166 EXPANSION OF ENGLAND lect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
