<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/sikh-confederacy/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/sikh-confederacy/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gulab Singh&#39;s Role 1st war</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/sikh-confederacy/articles/gulAb-singh-role_in_first-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/sikh-confederacy/articles/gulAb-singh-role_in_first-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication-info&#34;&gt;Publication info&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Raja Gulab Singh&amp;rsquo;s Role in the First Anglo-Sikh War&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Author(s): Bawa Satinder Singh&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Department of History, The Florida State University, Tallahassee.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Source: Modern Asian Studies, Vol. 5, No. 1 (1971), pp. 35-59&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Published by: Cambridge University Press&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;article&#34;&gt;Article&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;The man whom I have to deal with, Golab Singh, is the greatest rascal in Asia.&amp;rsquo; - 1 Sir Henry Hardinge, Governor-General (GG), to his wife Emily, Hardinge  Papers (HP), vol. 6, 2 March 1846, MSS in the private papers of Lady Helen  Hardinge, Penshurst, Kent, England.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Islam suppression in multAn</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/sikh-confederacy/articles/islam-suppression_in_multAn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/sikh-confederacy/articles/islam-suppression_in_multAn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Sikh rule in Multan as described by Alexander Burnes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this city, which held for upwards of 800 years so high a Mahommedan supremacy, there is now no public ‘numaz&amp;rsquo;; the true believer dare not lift his voice in public. The &amp;lsquo;Eeds&amp;rsquo; and the Mohuram pass without the usual observances, and the “Ullaho Acbar&amp;rsquo; of the priest is never heard; the mosques are yet frequented, but the pious are reduced to offering up their orisons in silence. Such has been the state of things since Mooltan fell in 1818, and yet the number of Seiks is confined to that of the garrison, from four to five hundred men. The Mahommedans, who amount to about 40,000 souls, suffer no other inconvenience from their new masters, who afford every protection to their trade. The Seiks excuse themselves, by alleging that they have not inflicted, in retribution, one fourth of their own sufferings at the hands of the Mahommedans.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mirzA-mohammed on bandA-execution</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/sikh-confederacy/articles/mirzA-mohammed_on_bandA-execution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/persons/sikh-confederacy/articles/mirzA-mohammed_on_bandA-execution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On this day [of their arrival] I went to the Salt Market to witness the event and accompanied them from there to the Imperial Fort. Of the people of the city there were few who did not come to see the humbling of those rebels. Large crowds gathered in every lane and market such as had seldom appeared before. The Muslims were in a happy and festive mood. Yet many of those ill-fated ones [the Sikhs], who had come as prisoners in this condition, insisted on standing fast by their villainy. There was no sign of humility and submission on their faces. Rather most of them, riding on the camels&amp;rsquo; backs, kept singing and reciting melodious verses. If any one in the lanes and bāzār reminded them of the cruelties they had committed, which brought them to this condition, they gave immediate and manly retorts, and attributed their capture and humiliation to the doings of fate. If any one told them that they would now be executed, they replied,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
