<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bhima Koregaon myth</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/bhIma-koregaon-myth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/bhIma-koregaon-myth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;the last battle of the Anglo-Maratha war was fought at Koregaon village on the banks of Bhima river near Pune. The battle marked the firm hold of the British Empire in India. The British erected an obelisk at the battle ground in the memory of the dead. It has 49 names, 22 of them are identified by their ‘nak’ suffix as Mahars.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;It was&amp;hellip; used by the first batch of Mahar leaders such as Gopal Baba Walangkar, Shivram Janba Kamble and even Ramji Ambedkar, B.R. Ambedkar’s father, when pleading the British for the restoration of Mahar recruitment in the British army when it was stopped in 1893. The stoppage of Mahar recruitment was a consequence of the Indian uprising of 1857, after which the British reassessed their recruiting strategies to include only those from ‘martial races’ in the army.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Babasaheb Ambedkar painted the Battle of Bhima Koregaon as the battle of Mahar soldiers against their caste oppression in Peshwa rule, he was creating a pure myth. As myths are required to build movements, he perhaps saw its necessity then.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Many Dalit organisations recently formed a joint front to observe the 200th anniversary of this battle as a campaign to launch an attack on the new Peshwai, the rising Brahmanic rule of the Hindutva forces.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Circustance: &amp;ldquo;Before the battle of Koregaon on January 1, 1818, the Peshwas had been reduced to weaklings by the earlier two Anglo-Maratha wars. As a matter of fact, the Peshwa Bajirao II had fled Pune and was attempting to attack Pune from outside.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://thewire.in/caste/myth-bhima-koregaon-reinforces-identities-seeks-transcend&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-battle&#34;&gt;The battle:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Peshwa’s army comprised 20,000 cavalry and 8,000 infantry, out of which around 2,000 men, divided into three infantry parties each comprising 600 Arabs, Gosains and soldiers, mounted the attack. The majority of the attackers were Arabs, reputed to be the finest among the Peshwa soldiers. The Company troops comprised 834 men, including around 500 soldiers of the 2nd Battalion of the 1st Regiment of Bombay Native Infantry, which was manned predominantly by Mahar soldiers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Peshwa army ultimately withdrew, fearing the arrival of a larger British force led by General Joseph Smith.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Non-mAhar-ness. &amp;ldquo;Although there is no record of their exact number, it is obvious that all of them were not Mahars. Even going by the casualties, the majority of those died in the battle (27 out of 49) were not Mahars.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;motives&#34;&gt;Motives&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Did they want the Peshwa’s Brahmanic rule to triumph? The fact is that they simply fought as soldiers for their masters, as the Dalits did for theirs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;They took caste as a natural order and their oppression as the fate that they had to meekly endure. Therefore, there was no question of any resistance to caste, leave apart physical war against them. Contrary to such myths of bravery, there is no evidence of any militant resistance the Dalits ever posed against the Brahmanic oppression.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hoysala garuDa-s</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/hoysala-garuDas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/hoysala-garuDas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Concept of Garuda Lenkas is so unique to Karnataka &amp;amp; India, Only tradition close to this is Bushido Cult of Samurai Still many of us dont know about this unique tradition of Service, Bravery, Valour &amp;amp; Sacrifice. Esp Agrahara Bachahalli ,the epicentre of this tradition of Garuda Lenkas - Actually two different entities. Garudas who were literally shadow of the king and Lenkas being the shadow of Garudas. The concept was &amp;quot; If object does not exist, then shadow does not exist&amp;quot;. Garudas were literally shadow of Hoysala Kings. The Tradition Meant that if the master dies of any reason, so does the shadow of the master.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>info-gathering-backwardness - rjrasva</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/info-gathering-backwardness_rjrasva/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/info-gathering-backwardness_rjrasva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;japan&#34;&gt;Japan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meiji was not the 1st great reform, the 1st great reorganization was during the tang when they felt threatened by the tang &amp;amp; reorganized the state on Tang model with modifications where needed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Japanese residents of Korea sent back reports of Mongol conquest of China soon after it happened, so the Japanese were aware of the Mongol threat.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;shogunate ordered hayashi gaho to compile a detailed record of the manchu conquest of china after interviewing chinese merchants &amp;amp; ming loyalist refugees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jaswant Singh - armed</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/jaswant-singh_armed-citizenry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/jaswant-singh_armed-citizenry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A &amp;lsquo;defending of India&amp;rsquo; has to start with an understanding of the debilitating consequences of that great disarming of India, post-1857. That disarming was an act of retribution, of revenge against all Indian males in the then British India.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was not just the physical action of stripping Indian males of arms; it was a psychological wounding, a moral crippling of India and that for the first time in memory. Until a consolidation of British power in India in 1858, all Indian males carried arms, this was de rigueur, for personal arms were both a male adornment and a physical and psychological support.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>khanwa-battle</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/khanwa-battle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/khanwa-battle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1636649186878803971.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thread by @prathgodbole&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On 16 March 1527 was a very interesting battle in Indian history. Battle of Khanwa (Rajasthan), between Rana Sanga and Babur. Babur won but it was quite close. Short 🧵 on the campaign and battle-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In April 1526, Babur won at the 1st battle of Panipat, defeating Ibrahim Lodi and capturing Delhi and then Agra. While these armies fought, Rana Sanga was intervening in the Gujarat sultanate in a civil war. By the time it ended, Babur had taken Delhi. This triggered a race between Rana Sanga and Babur to seize the remains of the sultanate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pAnIpat chiefs</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/pAnIpat-chiefs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v2/defence/military/articles/pAnIpat-chiefs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: TW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to the manuscript &amp;lsquo;Bakhar of Panipat&amp;rsquo; written in 1761, there were 418 chiefs who died in the third battle of Panipat. Out of these 208 were on the Maratha Side while 210 were with the Afghans. The manuscript also mentions the names of these chiefs and after a close According to the manuscript &amp;lsquo;Bakhar of Panipat&amp;rsquo; written in 1761, there were 418 chiefs who died in the third battle of Panipat. Out of these 208 were on the Maratha Side while 210 were with the Afghans. The manuscript also mentions the names of these chiefs and after a close inspection it&amp;rsquo;s fair to say that although almost all chiefs on the Maratha Side were &amp;lsquo;Maratha&amp;rsquo;(with the exception of some 10 odd who were Rajput, Muslim and Kannadiga), the Afghans had a significant presence of Rajputs, Khatiawadis, etc. About 31% or 66 of the chiefs killed on the Afghan side were Hindus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
