<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;nehruism genesis on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;nehruism genesis on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00 FOREWORD BY PHILIP SPRATT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/00_for/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/00_for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FOREWORD BY PHILIP SPRATT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why is there so much puzzlement about the politics of Jawaharlal Nehru? As Goel reminds us, and every newspaper reader can recall, he himself frequently says that he agrees in principle with the Communists. Why is he not taken at his word?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We do not take him at his word, because he says and does many other things, and so we do not realise how closely the relevant parts of his policy accord with this particular avowal. When I read the articles in this book, I was quite surprised. He is a very much more faithful Communist than I had realised.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01  FIRST PREFACE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/01_pre1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/01_pre1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FIRST PREFACE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The eighteen chapters of this book appeared originally as eighteen installments of a series written by &amp;lsquo;Ekaki&amp;rsquo; in the weekly Organiser, New Delhi, from June 5 to October 9, 1961. The nineteenth chapter, &lt;em&gt;Choosing Between USA And USSR&lt;/em&gt;, was contributed by me to the Diwali 1962 issue of the Organiser which came out soon after the first wave of Chinese invasion on October 20, 1962. They have been reprinted with a few minor changes here and there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02  SECOND PREFACE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/02_pre2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/02_pre2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SECOND PREFACE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is a reprint with minor changes, mostly in language, of an old one published from New Delhi in December 1963 under the title &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;In Defence of Comrade Krishna Menon&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;. That book, in turn, was compilation of a series of my articles which appeared under the same general title in the New Delhi weekly, Oganiser, from October 1961 to October 1962. The book carried a Foreword and a Preface as well. The Foreword was written by Mr. Philip Spratt.&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; In the Preface I detailed the activities of the Society for Defence of Freedom in Asia (SDFA) which our group had organised in 1952 for informing the people of Asia in general and India in particular about the character of Communism as a far more formidable imperialism than that which the Asian people had fought in the recent past.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03  ONE IN SEARCH OF A CULPRIT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/03_ch01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/03_ch01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ONE&lt;br&gt;&#xA;IN SEARCH OF A CULPRIT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The communist and fellow-travelling press and platforms in this country are busy building up and defending India&amp;rsquo;s Defence Minister, Mr. V.K. Krishna Menon, in the face of what the leftists describe as &amp;ldquo;an upsurge of rightist reaction&amp;rdquo;. Krishna Menon himself struts about with an air of injured innocence, and frequently dons the mask of a much misunderstood martyr whose services to the nation have not been properly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04  TWO A PILGRIM TO THE SOVIET PARADISE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/04_ch02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/04_ch02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TWO&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A PILGRIM TO THE SOVIET PARADISE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first job is to find out how Pandit Nehru has looked at the Soviet Union and the creed of Communism all through these years. For purposes of this investigation we have chosen five basic books written by him, namely &lt;em&gt;Soviet Russia&lt;/em&gt; (1929), &lt;em&gt;Glimpses of World History&lt;/em&gt; (1934), &lt;em&gt;An Autobiography&lt;/em&gt; (1936), &lt;em&gt;Unity of India&lt;/em&gt; (1941), and &lt;em&gt;Discovery of India&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;(1946). All these books, except the first and the fourth, have been&#xA;reprinted many times and still constitute the basic reading for anyone who wants to understand Pandit Nehru. We shall take these books one by one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05  THREE HISTORIAN WITH COMMUNIST GLASSES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/05_ch03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/05_ch03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THREE&lt;br&gt;&#xA;HISTORIAN WITH COMMUNIST GLASSES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pandit Nehru&amp;rsquo;s second book, &lt;em&gt;Glimpses of World History&lt;/em&gt;, was first published in India in 1934 and later on in England in 1939. The second edition which was &amp;ldquo;revised and, to a considerable extent, rewritten&amp;rdquo;, carried a foreword from Krishna Menon who was mainly responsible for getting it published in England. Krishna Menon says: &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Glimpses of World History&lt;/em&gt; is no mere narrative of events, valuable as the work is in this respect, but also a reflection of the author&amp;rsquo;s personality.&amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06  FOUR AN INDEFATIGABLE SOVIET ENTHUSIAST</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/06_ch04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/06_ch04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FOUR&lt;br&gt;&#xA;AN INDEFATIGABLE SOVIET ENTHUSIAST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have seen in the foregoing chapter that Pandit Nehru held up the &amp;ldquo;Soviet experiment&amp;rdquo; up to 1934 as being of special interest to India because-in his opinion &amp;ldquo;conditions in this country [India] are very much the same as in Russia before the Revolution&amp;rdquo;. What were the similarities? First of all, Russia before the Revolution was a backward country as India was in 1934. Secondly, Russia before the Revolution had a huge language and minorities problem, the same as we had in India in 1934. Russia had solved both these problems. India might, he argued, very well learn a lesson from her.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07  FIVE AN INCURABLE SOVIET-ADDICT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/07_ch05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/07_ch05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FIVE&lt;br&gt;&#xA;AN INCURABLE SOVIET-ADDICT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If we contemplate the several varieties of Soviet-addicts, we can classify them into three clear-cut categories.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the first place, we have those dupes who believe that all the dreams which mankind has ever dreamt have become physical reality inside the Soviet Union. These people can talk and write endlessly about the miracles that have materialised in Soviet society. But no one can ever involve them into a discussion based on known facts. Faced with facts, they either denounce you in the choicest terms of communist swearology or simply turn away their faces and get back into their trance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08  SIX AN APOLOGIST FOR SOVIET SINS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/08_ch06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/08_ch06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SIX&lt;br&gt;&#xA;AN APOLOGIST FOR SOVIET SINS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An ordinary apologist for Soviet sins always points out the &amp;ldquo;progressive character of Soviet foreign policy&amp;rdquo; whenever he is faced with an overwhelming evidence of Soviet crimes in the domestic sphere. And he generally turns towards &amp;ldquo;Soviet achievements at home&amp;rdquo; whenever he finds that a defence of Soviet foreign policy at some point is a somewhat more difficult job. But Pandit Nehru is no ordinary apologist. He does take the first turn and tries to draw people&amp;rsquo;s attention towards Soviet foreign policy whenever the ugliness of the domestic Soviet scene becomes too obvious even to his indoctrinated &amp;ldquo;insight&amp;rdquo;. But whenever it comes to defending the defects in Soviet foreign policy, he comes out as quite an extraordinary apologist. In fact, Soviet foreign policy has been his one permanent fixation all through these nearly thirty-five years during which he has worshipped at the altar of Communism. This will become more than amply evident when we take up his foreign policy in the later part of this series. Just now we are analysing his various books for finding out his basic beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09  SEVEN A PERSISTENT PRO-SOVIET SPEAKER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/09_ch07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/09_ch07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SEVEN&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A PERSISTENT PRO-SOVIET SPEAKER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pandit Nehru&amp;rsquo;s admirers are prepared to admit that he was influenced by communist thought to quite an extent before he became the first Prime Minister of independent India in August 1947. But they maintain (of course, in a purely &lt;em&gt;a priory&lt;/em&gt; fashion) that since that event his sense of responsibility as leader of a major democracy has considerably diluted his devotion to purely theoretical questions, and developed in him a sense of proportion regarding the Soviet Union.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10  EIGHT A DEVOTED DISCIPLE OF STALIN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/10_ch08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/10_ch08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EIGHT&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A DEVOTED DISCIPLE OF STALIN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The question may be asked that if Pandit Nehru was not very important in the Congress organisation so long as Mahatma Gandhi and Sardar Patel were alive, how did he come to dominate the organisation within a very short time after Sardar&amp;rsquo;s death, and to swing the country fast towards his Soviet Fatherland. An answer to this question needs an analysis of the character of our nationalism during our struggle with British imperialism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11  NINE A FELLOW-TRAVELLER OF SOVIET FOREIGN POLICY-1</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/11_ch09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/11_ch09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NINE&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A FELLOW-TRAVELLER OF SOVIET FOREIGN POLICY-1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Gita has laid down a profound principle in the following words: &amp;ldquo;The person is characterised by his credo. Whatever is a person&amp;rsquo;s credo, that he is.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And a person&amp;rsquo;s credo can be identified not so much in the words he speaks or writes as in the actions that flow freely out of him. The speaker or the writer who fails to act in terms of the faith he propounds in his speeches and writings is no more than a sophist who may be successful with some people or for some time but who is sure to be found out sooner or later. The tragedy of a sophist is that his own words fail to sink into the inner recesses of his being and inspire his actions in life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12  TEN A FELLOW-TRAVELLER OF SOVIET FOREIGN POLICY-2</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/12_ch10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/12_ch10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TEN&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A FELLOW-TRAVELLER OF SOVIET FOREIGN POLICY-2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ever since Pandit Nehru visited the United States of America for the first time in 1949 and the U.S. Administration discovered that it was impossible to have a free and frank discussion with him regarding concrete policies, a horde of U.S. specialists and psychologists have been in and out of India for a &amp;ldquo;fuller understanding of Jawaharlal Nehru, India&amp;rsquo;s man of destiny&amp;rdquo;. They have studied his life story exhaustively and brooded for years over his least little idiosyncrasy. And, by now, they are unanimous in their &amp;ldquo;analysis&amp;rdquo; that he is an extremely touchy person who will never brook any affront to his sense of self-respect. The U.S. State Department has, therefore, been deputing its topmost experts in public relations to his court at New Delhi, and there has been no end of their kowtowing before this king of independent India. But in spite of all their endeavours, the U.S.A. has been singularly unsuccessful with him. Every now and then he gets irritated with the U.S.A. and starts shouting against U.S. policies so that even his loyal lobbymen in the U.S.A., such as Chester Bowles, Cooper, Walter Reuther etc., are shocked and have to hang their heads in a confession of defeat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13  ELEVEN A FELLOW-TRAVELLER OF SOVIET FOREIGN POLICY-3</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/13_ch11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/13_ch11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ELEVEN&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A FELLOW-TRAVELLER OF SOVIET FOREIGN POLICY-3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An year or so before Sardar Patel&amp;rsquo;s death in December 1950, there was a serious rift between him and Prime Minister Nehru on questions concerning the foreign policy of India. The Sardar did not like the way in which our foreign affairs were being conducted. He felt that our foreign policy was too servile to the Soviet camp in spite of the violent hostility which that camp had all along shown towards the Government of independent India. But he could not or did not review this policy in terms of any alternate international analysis of his own. Pandit Nehru, on the other hand, pointed out repeatedly that the general direction of India&amp;rsquo;s foreign policy after the attainment of independence was not new but only an application of the principles enunciated in the various foreign policy resolutions which the Congress had passed in pre-independence days. The Sardar was exasperated. And he made a. public statement that he had never read a single foreign policy resolution of the Congress. He added that these resolutions were passed always and unanimously more in order to avoid controversy over what was an academic issue for enslaved India than to denote any decisive national attitudes towards international politics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14  TWELVE A FELLOW-TRAVELLER OF SOVIET FOREIGN POLICY-4</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/14_ch12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/14_ch12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TWELVE&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A FELLOW-TRAVELLER OF SOVIET FOREIGN POLICY-4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shri D.G. Mohan Rao, a friend from Warrangal, who has been reading this series, writes: &amp;ldquo;There is confusion to know exactly what is Ekaki&amp;rsquo;s name to write about either Shri Nehru or Krishna Menon. Ekaki collected only the &amp;lsquo;yes&amp;rsquo; quotations of him-Nehru. But Nehru tells sometimes &amp;rsquo;no&amp;rsquo; also about communists. The theory and the way of collecting only &amp;lsquo;yes&amp;rsquo; quotations in Nehru&amp;rsquo;s praise of communism does not underline the psychology in perfect way because there are so many other &amp;rsquo;no&amp;rsquo; quotations also in Shri Nehru&amp;rsquo;s warnings against communists.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15  THIRTEEN A FELLOW-TRAVELLER OF SOVIET FOREIGN POLICY-5</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/15_ch13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/15_ch13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THIRTEEN&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A FELLOW-TRAVELLER OF SOVIET FOREIGN POLICY-5&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Subhas Chandra Bose and Jawaharlal Nehru have always been associated in our intelligentsia&amp;rsquo;s mind as leftists and socialists who are supposed to have stood for the same sort of ideals during the days of our struggle against foreign rule or at least upto 1939 when Bose was ousted from the Indian National Congress by &amp;ldquo;Sardar Patel&amp;rsquo;s rightist clique&amp;rdquo;. The intelligentsia is also aware that at no time did Pandit Nehru have a soft corner for Bose whom he increasingly came to suspect as a sympathiser of Fascism and Nazism. And it is also widely known that Bose had nothing but contempt for Pandit Nehru whom he saw as a spineless soap-box orator.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16  FOURTEEN A FELLOW-TRAVELLER OF SOVIET FOREIGN POLICY-6</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/16_ch14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/16_ch14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FOURTEEN&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A FELLOW-TRAVELLER OF SOVIET FOREIGN POLICY-6&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main plank of Congress propaganda after independence has been that it drove out the British by means of non-violent non-cooperation and brought freedom to the country. The Congress refers with particular pride to the policies it pursued during the Second World War period, particularly after the Quit India Resolution was passed in Bombay in August 1942. To put it simply, we are asked to believe that British imperialism in India got frightened because some Congressmen in some parts of the country pulled down some telephone poles and broke a number of letter-boxes before they were herded into British jails.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17  FIFTEEN A FELLOW-TRAVELLER OF SOVIET FOREIGN POLICY-7</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/17_ch15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/17_ch15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FIFTEEN&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A FELLOW-TRAVELLER OF SOVIET FOREIGN POLICY-7&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hitler got defeated in the Second World War. Therefore, everyone can now shout: &amp;ldquo;Hell, thy name is Hitler.&amp;rdquo; So if anyone says today that at least in so far as Hider&amp;rsquo;s relations with the Soviet Union were concerned after Molotov signed a Non-Aggression Pact with Ribbentrop in August 1939, his record was absolutely unimpeachable, he should be committing the most horrible crime. For, the Soviet Union won the War along with her Western allies. And no sane person is supposed to find faults with those who are successful. After all, the one sure sign of insanity is that one refuses to swallow the current surges of public opinion without a fistful of salt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18  SIXTEEN A FELLOW-TRAVELLER OF SOVIET FOREIGN POLICY-8</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/18_ch16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/18_ch16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SIXTEEN&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A FELLOW-TRAVELLER OF SOVIET FOREIGN POLICY-8&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I draw towards the end of this series, I have a second letter saying that I have not at all succeeded in establishing my case about Prime Minister Nehru&amp;rsquo;s communist leanings. Mr. Tolo Panjabi from Bombay thinks that the &amp;ldquo;tone and trend&amp;rdquo; of my arguments is &amp;ldquo;most regrettable and deliberately misleading&amp;rdquo;, and that my description of Fascism as the &amp;ldquo;last-ditch battle of nationalism against communism&amp;rdquo; shows where my &amp;ldquo;sympathies are&amp;rdquo;. He refers to the imperialist record of Fascist Italy in Africa to prove his point. And then in a bid to defend Pandit Nehru, he goes on, &amp;ldquo;I wonder how he would explain the policy of Mr. Nehru on such matters as Goa, Kashmir, Algeria, and &lt;em&gt;de jure&lt;/em&gt; transfer of French occupied territories in India. Let him not tell us that a conflict between India and Portugal will not embarrass Western countries and delight Russia, or the occupation of a part of Kashmir and establishment of American bases there serves the interests of Russia. Certainly, the Russians are not such naive goblins as would allow such a thing to happen through one of their stooges. I dare him to analyse Mr. Nehru&amp;rsquo;s role in Belgrade in the light of his far-fetched arguments.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19  SEVENTEEN A PROMOTER OF THE COMMUNIST PARTY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/19_ch17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/19_ch17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SEVENTEEN&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A PROMOTER OF THE COMMUNIST PARTY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the Soviet Union denounced Pandit Nehru in 1948 as a puppet whom &amp;ldquo;American imperialism&amp;rdquo; was trying to prop up in place of the old &amp;ldquo;paper tiger&amp;rdquo;, President Chiang Kai-shek of China, the Western nations, particularly the United States of America, had proclaimed immediately that Pandit Nehru was the &amp;ldquo;bulwark of democracy in Asia&amp;rdquo;. But the Korean War was hardly half through when it was widely realised in the West that at least in the field of international politics Pandit Nehru was no friend of the West, and that his sympathies, whenever and wherever they became manifest, were always and all along with the communist camp. The West has, however, been bewitched by Pandit Nehru on another count. He seems to it to be the &amp;ldquo;only person who understands the dynamics of the modern world&amp;rdquo; in a &amp;ldquo;surging sea of superstition and primitivism that is India&amp;rdquo;. Western statesmen and scribes have floated another myth also about him, namely that whatever the policies he pursues in the sphere of international politics, &amp;ldquo;at least inside India he is not prepared to tolerate Communism&amp;rdquo;, and that &amp;ldquo;he is fighting the Communist Party of India tooth and nail&amp;rdquo;. And in support of this new illusion, Western writers have been quoting his record of resistance to communist violence during 1948-50.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20  EIGHTEEN SAPPERS AND MINERS OF COMMUNISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/20_ch18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/20_ch18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EIGHTEEN&lt;br&gt;&#xA;SAPPERS AND MINERS OF COMMUNISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An ideology can be taken to have triumphed when those whom it declares to be its enemies start speaking its language. Communism has already passed that test and arrived at a stage when its thought-categories have acquired an almost universal adherence. Let us sample some of the more basic communist slogans and see how strongly and systematically they have seeped into the thought and language of the present-day intelligentsia in every corner of the world. In the process, we shall also discover how the human mind can be manipulated to a point where any amount of objective data fails to have any impact on it, and where superstitions of the silliest sort become its entire stock-in-trade.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21  NINETEEN CHOOSING BETWEEN USA AND USSR1</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/21_ch19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/articles/goel_sitArAm/nehruism_genesis/21_ch19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NINETEEN&lt;br&gt;&#xA;CHOOSING BETWEEN USA AND USSR&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Communist China&amp;rsquo;s aggression along our Himalayan frontier has once again posed before the nation the problem of finding friends against foes in a dangerous and divided world. The nation had faced this problem at first when Pakistan signed a military pact with the United States of America, and started talking tough in the context of her self-chosen controversy over Kashmir. During those days, at least, it was seriously apprehended by the Indian people at large that Pakistan might mount an aggression against India from a position of superior military strength. The same people now fear that a militarily mightier China may choose any day to convert isolated border incidents into an all-out war.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
