<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Materials on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/materials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Materials on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/materials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aluminium</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/materials/aluminium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/materials/aluminium/</guid>
      <description>Doesn&amp;rsquo;t rust and corrode like mild steel! But expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blocks</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/materials/blocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/materials/blocks/</guid>
      <description>Popular choices : Fire baked bricks, concrete blocks, fly ash blocks (low weight, high carbon footprint)
Mud blocks  Environmentally friendly. Made at site by mixing cement, mud and water and then pressing into blocks before curing.  Hollow Clay blocks  Good insulation Can be brittle - careful while making holes - drill, don&amp;rsquo;t hammer.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glass</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/materials/glass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/materials/glass/</guid>
      <description> 4mm often used for windows.  Toughened glass  12mm toughened glass very hard to break. Can sit on it. Oft used for window canopies. 16mm to 20mm glass is used for walkways.  Cost  With installation and silicone (2020): Rs 550 per sqft. Additional cost for metal supports: approx Rs 100. With installation (2019): Rs 280-600 per sqft.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polycarbonate</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/materials/polycarbonate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/materials/polycarbonate/</guid>
      <description>Cons  Degrades with time and exposure to sunlight.  Compact clear  Prone to scratches if used outside house. 2019 Bengaluru price  GE Sabic Lexan - around 38 Rs (besides gst) per mm per sqft, 105 for 3mm per sqft. Local manufacturer - around 5 Rs less.    Embossed  no scratch problem. Lets 90+% of light through. 2019 Bengaluru price  GE Sabic Lexan - around 37 Rs (besides gst) per mm per sqft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steel</title>
      <link>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/materials/steel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>file:///storage/emulated/0/notesData/notes/materials/steel/</guid>
      <description>Cost (2020)  MS grill with installation - ~ 450/sqft Highly finished door (hollow?) steel - Rs 700/sqft (IndiaMart) - Rs 14.7k.  Mild steel (MS)  Aka Carbon steel rusts when exposed to air and moisture. This iron oxide film is active and accelerates corrosion by forming more iron oxide. stiff and strong exhibit ferromagnetism (i.e. they are magnetic). This means they are extensively used in motors and electrical appliances.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>