<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Memorization on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/learning/articles/memorization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Memorization on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/learning/articles/memorization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Memorization: Neuroimage report 2016</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/learning/articles/memorization/memorization_neuroimage-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/learning/articles/memorization/memorization_neuroimage-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We studied a group of verbal memory specialists to determine whether intensive oral text memory is associated with structural features of hippocampal and lateral-temporal regions implicated in language processing. Professional Vedic Sanskrit Pandits in India train from childhood for around 10 years in an ancient, formalized tradition of oral Sanskrit text memorization and recitation, mastering the exact pronunciation and invariant content of multiple 40,000–100,000 word oral texts. We conducted structural analysis of gray matter density, cortical thickness, local gyrification, and white matter structure, relative to matched controls. We found massive gray matter density and cortical thickness increases in Pandit brains in language, memory and visual systems, including i) bilateral lateral temporal cortices and ii) the anterior cingulate cortex and the hippocampus, regions associated with long and short-term memory. Differences in hippocampal morphometry matched those previously documented for expert spatial navigators and individuals with good verbal working memory. The findings provide unique insight into the brain organization implementing formalized oral knowledge systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sci Am Hindu memorization report</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/learning/articles/memorization/sci-am-hindu-memorization-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/learning/articles/memorization/sci-am-hindu-memorization-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ‘Sanskrit effect’ and how rigorous memorising helps the memory&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(It is also important to realise that one need not attach any special power to Shukla Yajurveda as a brain enhancer)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Considerable excitement has been triggered through email and social media across India due to a recent “observation” reported by one Dr James Hartzell in the journal Scientific American. This neuroscientist has coined the term “The Sanskrit effect.” He writes that memorising Vedic mantras increases the size of brain regions associated with cognitive function such as memory (both short-term and long-term). He writes in his report that Indian tradition holds that rigorously memorising and reciting mantras enhances memory and thinking. In order to test this idea, Hartzell (and his colleagues from the University of Trento in Italy) teamed up with Dr Tanmay Nath and Dr Nandini Chatterjee Singh of the National Brain Research Centre (NBRC) at Manesar in Haryana. They chose to study 42 volunteers — 21 professionally qualified Sanskrit Pandits (aged around 22) who have been trained full-time daily for 7 years (total of over 10,000 hrs) in their childhood reciting the Shukla Yajurveda. These Pandits were recruited from Vedic Pandit schools in Delhi. As control, they chose 21 age-matched males, students from a nearby college.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
