<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Organizations on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Organizations on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BJP</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/bjp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/politics/id-practice/hindutva/orgs/bjp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The BJP has grown out of the Golwalkar worldview, and in theory it swears by the “integral humanism” of Deendayal Upadhyaya (ca. 1965). Of this system, the name is the most important thing, as it amounts to a modern reformulation of the word Dharma. However, the party’s undeniable evolution, while modernizing its economic views and its PR, has mostly meant its growing away from ideology altogether.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In 1922, the Hindu Mahasabha was created as a guardian of Hindu interests. In 1951, tainted by the murder of the Mahatma by one of its members, it was replaced by the Jan Sangh, which was never tempted to stray from its Hindutva ideology by a stint in power. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://centreright.in/2014/08/the-modi-governments-hindu-agenda/#.U_Ndlj2x3Ua&#34;&gt;KE&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Earlier history and downfall post-independence - &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2009/01/18/have-the-hindus-given-up/&#34;&gt;MT08&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In 1977 it merged in the Janata Party, and in 1979, it was refounded as the BJP. For some years, the BJP was controlled to some extent by the RSS, which itself was ideologically unimaginative and stagnant, but at least somewhat principled. Because of its growth and its recruitment in modernized sections, however, the BJP moved ever farther out of the RSS ambit. By the time it came to power (1998), its ties to its mother organization had thinned sufficiently for taking initiatives that were unthinkable a few years earlier. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://centreright.in/2014/08/the-modi-governments-hindu-agenda/#.U_Ndlj2x3Ua&#34;&gt;KE&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
