<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GK anantAchAr</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/grAma-keshavAchArya-anantAchArya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/grAma-keshavAchArya-anantAchArya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1536737458129235968.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had no idea that just an hour from my parents’ home in Bengaluru near Nelamangala, there was a dreamland full of Hindu art treasures with a close link to Amar Chitra Katha, my favorite comic series. So indebted to @Ramyarohini for motivating me to visit Omthara Kala Kuteera. Until Ramya made me aware, I credited Anant Pai solely for the success of Amar Chitra Katha. Looks like there has been a big omission and you will know that when you visit Omthara. GK Ananthram is the brain behind Amar Chitra Katha. Only after he pestered his boss Mirchandani he got the budget to publish the comic series in Kannada which became a runaway hit. Impressed, the publishers (India Book House) decided to publish ACK in English &amp;amp; other languages. Anant Pai who ran Indrajal comics was then brought in to run ACK in the late 1960s and the rest is history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>guNDappa on rAman</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/guNDappa_on_rAman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/guNDappa_on_rAman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. C. V. Raman: A Personal Tribute&#xA;This two-part tribute was published in December 1970 and January 1971 on the pages of Public Affairs, a monthly journal published by the Gokhale Institute of Public Affairs. —Editors&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was my good fortune to receive many marks of personal kindness from the late Dr. C. V. Raman. On the human side, he was as admirable and lovable as he was eminent as a scientist. He was a kindly, sympathetic man — despite occasional barbs of irony and invective darting out for those who deserved them. On such occasions, the disinterested third party would laugh as at the peeve of a good child. The barb had no venom in it. And the barb was soon followed by the balm of generous friendliness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kAdanteti-ANDavan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/kAdanteti-ANDavan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/kAdanteti-ANDavan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Srimad Kadanthethi Andavan Sri Srinivasa Ramanuja Maha Desikan&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Birth star: Avani Mulam&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thaniyan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;śrīmach-chrīvāsa-yogi-pravara sakaruṇāpāñga sangāta-bhañgāt&lt;br&gt;&#xA;vedānta-dvandva-vidyā-madhura-salaharī-chancharīkayamāṇaḥ&lt;br&gt;&#xA;tenāchāryeṇa ranga-prabhu-caraṇa-yuge datta-rakshā-bhara-śrīḥ&lt;br&gt;&#xA;śrīmach-chrīvāsa-rāmāvaraja-muni-maṇis santataṁ śreyase syāt&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Srimad Kadanthethi Andavan Sri Srinivasa Ramanuja Mahadesikan was born in 1829 CE in the sashti-samvatsara year of Virodhi in the Tamil month of Avani under the star of Mulam, in a village called Kadanthethi, just south of the river Kaveri. His parents Srimathi Janaki Ammal and Sri Raghunathachar named the child Sri Varada Vedantachar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kAshinAdhuni-vishvanAtha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/kAshinAdhuni-vishvanAtha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/kAshinAdhuni-vishvanAtha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dharmadispatch.in/culture/a-tribute-to-kviswanath-the-last-of-the-masters&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Tribute to K.Viswanath: The Last of the Masters&lt;br&gt;&#xA;An appreciation of the art, craft and legacy of K.Viswanath, one of the greatest masters of Indian cinema&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I offer a hundred thousand salutations to the donor who extended his hands to guard the flame of pure traditional classical music which was fluttering under the assault of the typhoon of Western music,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;says a visibly touched Shankara Sastri, moments before he begins the ultimate concert of his life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kedAranAtha-dAsaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/kedAranAtha-dAsaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/kedAranAtha-dAsaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.rattibha.com/thread/1629138930963566594&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While we remember Neel Ratan Sarkar, BC Roy, today we hv completely forgotten the person responsible for decrease in maternal death rate of Indian women. Sir Kedarnath Das. For this he designed a long curved obstetric forcep, known as &amp;lsquo;Bengal forcep&amp;rsquo;. Today&amp;rsquo;s his birthday (Feb 24)&amp;hellip; He was born in Kolkata 156 years ago today. Losing his mother at a young age inspired him to study medicine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At that time, Simpson forcep was used to deliver Indian children. But in reality it was seen that often a deep wound form in the vagina, which in many cases resulted in mothers&amp;rsquo; death. Dr. Das showed that stature of Indian women is smaller than their European counterpart. Simpson forceps were created in Britain keeping European women in mind. So using it on comparatively smaller Indian women is causing their death.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>keralapura-kRShNamUrti</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/keralapura-kRShNamUrti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/keralapura-kRShNamUrti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: PrexA article and YT talk.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;K Krishnamoorthy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: This is the transcript of a lecture delivered under the auspices of Gokhale Institute of Public Affairs and Prekshaa Pratishtana, as part of a lecture series titled Exemplars of Indian Wisdom from Karnataka.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I offer my heartiest greetings to everyone present here. As a student of Sanskrit literature and Indian aesthetics, I feel elated to speak on the life and works of K Krishnamoorthy. I owe my knowledge of aesthetics entirely to Śatāvadhānī R Ganesh. Ganesh feels the same about Krishnamoorthy. In this manner, I am a small part of a great vidyāvaṃśa. I take this opportunity to express my sincerest gratitude to these two extraordinary scholars whom I consider as vaṃśarṣis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>khaptaDa-guruH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/khaptaDa-sachchidAnanda-sarasvatI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/khaptaDa-sachchidAnanda-sarasvatI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;bisht-article&#34;&gt;Bisht article&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nepal: The Recluse Khaptad Baba&#xA;January 1, 2020&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Originally a doctor, he meditated for 50 years in Nepal’s icy, isolated Himalayan foothills&lt;br&gt;&#xA;BY KAPIL BISHT, NEPAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;KHAPTAD BABA (February 10, 1880-May 9, 1996),&lt;br&gt;&#xA;IF HE were still around, would have loved the fact that few people know of him today. He cherished solitude and anonymity, which is was why he chose to live in Khaptad, a wilderness in the Himalayan foothills of west Nepal. The area is 460 miles by road, then two days walk from Kathmandu—but it feels separated by centuries, not miles, from the rest of Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kRShNa-deshika</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/kRShNa-deshikaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/kRShNa-deshikaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Overview on Sri Ranganatha Temple and Swamiji:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sri Ranganatha Temple is located in Pomona, New York. Five Full-Time priests and two Voluntary priests ( part-time ) work diligently to ensure that all religious services are offered to the Deities and to the complete satisfaction of the Devotees. The dedication shown by all the priests is the essence of the temple. One such priest, not only built the temple by accepting the path of surrender, but also became a Sannyasi to propagate the concept of Absolute Surrender to Lord Sri Krishna. Sri Krishna Desika Yati Jeeyar Swami renounced material life and is now living in simplicity, Swamiji has become more dedicated towards the temple and its patrons. I had the opportunity to speak to Swamiji himself and asked him a few questions regarding Hinduism and his outtake on its principles. Following a simple lifestyle, Swamiji continues to inspire many patrons and devotees who come to the temple daily. Leaving all of his luxuries, including his family, Sri Krishna Desika Yati Jeeyar Swami lives a simple but worthwhile life in order to help devotees attain salvation and seek a passageway towards Vaikuntam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mAnavaLLi-rAmakRShNa-kavi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/mAnavaLLi-rAmakRShNa-kavi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/mAnavaLLi-rAmakRShNa-kavi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://sriramv.com/2010/12/28/the-life-and-works-of-manavalli-ramakrishna-kavi/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This was not the caption of the lecture of Dr CN Premlatha at the Music Academy. This took place on the 16th of December. The actual title (I think) said the Manuscripts of Manavalli Ramakrishna Kavi, whom, in the interests of Carpal Tunnel Syndrome I will refer to as MR Kavi. Dr Premlatha comes from the Sri Venkateswara Oriental Research Institute, Tirupati.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is very rarely that anyone sheds tears during a lec dem. But on that day, the life of MR Kavi had everyone, ranging from the oldest member TK Govinda Rao, down to the youngest, weeping freely. MR Kavi was born in 1866 in Nungambakkam, Madras. He acquired an MA in Telugu and Sanskrit from this University here though the college where he did his graduation is not identified with certainty. Some have it as Madras Christian while others say it was Pacchaiyappa’s. At the age of 16 he wrote a poem titled Mrgavati and was given the suffix of Kavi. He worked for some time at the Government Oriental Manuscripts Library (GOML) and was later a Private Secretary at the Wanaparthi Estate. He began collecting manuscripts and one of his discoveries was the Abhinava Bharati. In 1916 he stayed at Nidadavolu Venkatarao’s home and copied the Natyasastra and a commentary on it while there. In 1916 he was Assistant Curator at the GOML. In 1940 he became a Reader at the SVORI and continued there till 1951.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Periyav AchchAn piLLai</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/periyav-AchchAn-piLLai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/periyav-AchchAn-piLLai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://acharya.org/ac/spvp/pvpv.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sri Periyavaccan Pillai Vaibhavam&#xA;srImatkrushNasamAhvAya namO yAmunasoonavE |&#xA;yatkadAkshaikalakshyANAm soolapa: srIdharas sathA ||&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Salutations to that Srimatkrishnar (Sri Periyavaccan Pillai) who is the son of Yamuacharya, and to whose followers (those who are the target of his grace) Sridhara is always easily attained).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sri Periyavaccan Pillai (PVP) was born in the sarvajith year (1167), in the month of avani in Krishnashtami Rohini. He was born to Yamunacharya and Nacciyaramman, in the town of Sanganalloor near Thiruvelliyankudi (in Tanjore district). He was born as the amsam of Lord Krishna and was named as Sreekrishnar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>phillauri-shraddhA-rAma</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/phillauri-shraddhA-rAma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/phillauri-shraddhA-rAma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.rattibha.com/thread/1676962523512475649&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do you know the most famous Arti &amp;ldquo;Om Jai Jagdeesh Hare&amp;rdquo; was written by a Punjabi Hindu Brahmin, Shraddha Ram Phillauri? Pandit Shraddha Ram was born in 1837 at Phillaur (Jullundur district), During the 1857 war, he was 19 years old,&amp;amp; he began to preach the Mahabharata in public&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He asked Hindus to follow the ritual of purification,apply tilak on their foreheads, and greet each other with ‘Jayati Hari’  (Victory to the Gods). It is said that when Maharaja of Kapurthala was about to convert to Christianity, Shraddha Ram ji persuaded him not to do so.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>praNavAnanda</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/praNavAnanda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/praNavAnanda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://thepaperclip.in/the-swami-the-spy/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Swami, The Spy&#xA;Authored by Barun Ghosh (@barunghosh)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of us have enjoyed the spy thrillers of the Cold War period like the James Bond stories. While Ian Fleming was giving shape to Bond, an Indian Swami travelled across the remote Himalayas regions conducting real-life espionage. Barun Ghosh writes on his remarkable life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Born in 1896 in a small village of the West Godavari district of Andhra Pradesh, Pranavananda was named Kanakadandi Venkata Somayajulu (KVS). After completing his schooling, he attended the Dayanand Anglo Vedic College in Lahore (now known as Government Islamia College). &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>purI nishchalAnanda-sarasvatI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/purI-nishchalAnanda-sarasvatI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/purI-nishchalAnanda-sarasvatI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1744387292201091584.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A thread those who don&amp;rsquo;t know what Puri Shankaracharya ji has done. &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Do you know that the present Jagadguru Shankaracharya ji had left his home and hearth in 1960 after taking a pledge to adopt the Sanyas order at 17? It is also worth mentioning that he actively participated in the meeting held on 7 November 1966 right in front of the Indian Parliament. Even before the commencement of the above meeting, Shri Gavananda Hariji had received three hours of advice and guidance from him on the main issues of that meeting. He fought hard for cow protection and was arrested along with Swami Karpatriji Maharaj and other sadhu santh to save Cows. They all were kept in jail for 52 days.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While the Jagadguru was leading the national movement at the birthplace of Ram Ji, Ex-PM Narshhima Rao formed the Ramalaya Trust the main objective of which was to build both a mosque and mandir at the same place to create Hindu-Muslim bhaichara. Only puri Jagadguru Shankaracharya disagreed and refused to approve it and faced death threats.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While traveling to Nepal 22 years ago, upon observing the conditions there, Jagadguru immediately realized that Nepal would not remain a Hindu state for a long time and that a major threat was looming for the king. Nepal king died within a short time and Nepal fell into the hands of communists. Jagadguru organized a huge rally at Jagannath Puri along with many sadhus, santh and general public. The objective of this rally was to see Nepal once again emerging as a Hindu power. It had a tremendous impact in some other states of India and a few days later he visited Nepal to address a religious gathering&#xA;organized by some eminent persons and organizations. more than two lakh people participated in that . This step taken by Jagadguru to restore its Hindu nation again. From then demonstration for monarchy is going on in nepal.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For preservation of Ram Setu Puri Shankaracharya toured across India starting from China border night up to Rameswaram. At pandharpur, Maharastra, as many as five thousand devotees prayed to lord Pandharnath for the bridge-protection. The Jagadguru also carried on the movement for the bridge at Rameswaram a long with one hundred fifty devotees representatives of his. In this connection he also got in touch with the Govt. of srilanka and the UNO.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Here the proof Jagadguru Shankaracharya Nischalananda Saraswati re-converted the tribals of Odisha.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jagadguru had taken immense pains to organize the “Save Ganga” conference with the sole objective of protecting the mystical sanctity of its sacred waters – a conference which saw the participation of representatives from seven states.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Do you know when Dalai Lama was all set in Delhi to convert millions of Hindus to Buddhism on receiving the news jagadguru rushed to Dharamshala and in a press-interview advised the Lama that he would be better off carrying out his project. Jagadguru made it clear in clear words that the Lama would not arrogate to himself the role of the maker of India&amp;rsquo;s destiny. On this Lama sent his chief messenger to meet Acharya. The messenger promised that the conversion program would be stopped immediately. &lt;a href=&#34;https://tibet.net/press-statement-his-holiness-the-dalai-lama-has-no-plans-of-conversion-of-hindus-to-buddhism/&#34;&gt;DL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yet another cow protection incident During the J B Patnaik Ex-CM, a huge conference of Muslims was to be held in Brahmabarda, Orissa. On that occasion, thousands of cows were to be slaughtered for food in Brahmabarda, a Hindu dominated area. On receiving the news, Jagatguru immediately came into action and announced that if the conference would be held in Brahmabarda, not a single cow would be put to the knife and all mandatory Will take vegetarian food. The government relented and Acharya&amp;rsquo;s sacred wish was respected. All the cows were distributed among the nearby villages. The conference was filled with vegetarian ethos from the beginning till the end. Thus the Jagadguru has been keeping himself busy over the years for the proper preservation of the Hindu manbindus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Apart from all this, Jagadguru has been giving important discourses for the last few years to bring about an ideological revolution among the public at large. With this objective in mind, he has been visiting renowned educational institutions of India, delivering lectures on &amp;ldquo;Science without Veda (knowledge), &amp;ldquo;Destruction in the name of development&amp;rdquo; and other such topics of vital importance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jagadguru has also written more than 130 books. Considering zero as an ideological number, gurudev wrote an entire book titled Swastika Mathematics. Needless to add, the book easily attracted the attention of leading scientists and mathematicians of Oxford and Cambridge. +++(नैवम्। )+++ This unique mathematical treatise had such an impact on businesses around the world that some mathematicians and scientists had to visit the Govardhan mutt in Puri to learn more about the subject.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;16 years ago in 2008, on the Pausha Purnima day, the Gurudev started “Sandhya-Vandan” (Evening worship) on the sea-shore in grateful adoration of the samudra devta. Furthermore, in the huge gathering of devotees that gathers on the seashore every Pausha Purnima Day, Gurudev keeps on awakening everyone to do his little bit to wipe out in to the burning problems facing the Nation. A kindred programme is also carried out at Ganga Sagar every Makar Sankranti Day in the evening hours. Plans are afoot to carry out such programmes at Kanya Kumari and Rameswaram as well in the new future.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In Rastrotkarsh Abhijan tour of Rajasthan in November 2016, CM Vasundhara Raje Scindia arrived to see him. Pujyapad advised him not to close the cow shed at Pathmeda, as it was the responsibility of the govt land. The man who runs the cowshed is doing very good work for cow protection. He promised to take necessary steps for the protection of cow progeny. Later in January 2017, Rajasthan Govt. Passed an order to legalize the cowshed running for charitable purposes. In this way the lives of lakhs of cows were saved from reaching the slaughterhouses.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;kanchi-defence&#34;&gt;Kanchi defence&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Shankaracharya of Puri went from city to city, from Jammu to Bhopal, rousing Hindus against the arrest of the Shankaracharya of Kanchi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RAghavAchAryaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/rAghavAchAryaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/rAghavAchAryaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;8 सितम्बर 1952 को उत्तर प्रदेश के हमीरपुर जिलान्तर्गत विरखेड़ा ग्राम में जन्म ।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;श्रीराम संस्कृत महाविद्यालय जानकीकुण्ड, चित्रकूट (उ.प्र.) में संस्कृत व्याकरण का प्रारम्भिक अध्ययन।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1970 से 1981 तक वाराणसी में वेदान्त विषय का अध्ययन, भारत के मूर्धन्य विद्वान श्रद्धेय श्री श्रीराम पाण्डेय एवं श्री पारसनाथ द्विवेदी जी के चरणों में बैठकर किया।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;सन् 1981 में वेदान्त विभाग में सर्वाधिक अंक प्राप्त कर सम्पूर्णानंद विश्वविद्यालय, वाराणसी से स्वर्ण पदक त्रय प्राप्त किये।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;सन् 1981 में अखिल भारतीय संस्कृत वाक्पटुता प्रतियोगिता में वेदान्त विषय में अखिल भारतीय स्वर्ण पदक प्राप्त किया।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;सन् 1983 में जगद्‌गुरू श्री शालिग्रामाचार्य जी महाराज ‘अग्रपीठाधीश रैवासाधाम से विरक्त दीक्षा ग्रहण की ।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;आपने 25 फरवरी 1984 को रैवासापीठ के पीठाधिपति के पद को सुशोभित किया।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;देश में लुप्त होती वेदाध्ययन की परम्परा को पुनर्जीवित करने के लिए आपने रैवासापीठ में वेद विद्यालय एवं संस्कृत विद्यालय की स्थापना की ।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;विशाल गौशाला की स्थापना कर पंचगव्य उत्पादों के माध्यम से गोवंश को स्वावलम्बी बनाने का श्रेष्ठ प्रयास निरन्तर कर रहे है।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;धर्म जागरण के कार्यक्रमों में अखिल भारतीय स्तर पर प्रवास कर सनातन धर्म का प्रचार-प्रसार कर रहे है।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;विश्वहिन्दु परिषद् में केन्द्रीय मार्गदर्शक मण्डल सदस्य एवं विश्व हिन्दु परिषद् में रामजन्म भूमि उच्चाधिकार समिति सदस्य के दायित्व का निर्वहन।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;पूर्ववर्ती भाजपा सरकार में राजस्थान संस्कृत अकादमी के अध्यक्ष पद के दायित्व का निर्वहन करते हुये पूरे प्रदेश में वेदाश्रमों की स्थापना की। आज राजस्थान प्रदेश में 1000 से अधिक विप्र बटुक अध्ययनरत है ।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;रैवासा वेद विद्यालय के 2 दर्जन से अधिक विद्यार्थी भारतीय सेना में धर्मगुरू (RT JCO) के पद पर अपनी सेवाएँ दे रहे है तथा भारत के विभिन्न महानगरों में वैदिक कर्मकाण्ड के माध्यम से भारतीय संस्कृति एवं सनातन धर्म का सम्पोषण कर रहे है। निःशुल्क नेत्र शिविरों के आयोजनों का संचालन आपके द्वारा होता रहा है।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;आप के सहयोग से रैवासा पीठ के भक्तों द्वारा प्राथमिक चिकित्सा केन्द्र एवं उच्च माध्यमिक विद्यालय का निर्माण करवा कर राजस्थान सरकार को सुपुर्द किया। राज सहयोग एवं श्रीजानकीनाथ बड़ा मंदिर ट्रस्ट के सहयोग से रैवासा ग्रामवासियों के लिए पीने के पानी की एक लाख ली. क्षमता वाली टंकी का निर्माण करवा कर ग्राम पंचायत रैवासा को सुपुर्द किया।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rAjagopAla-sharmA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/rAjagopAla-sharmA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/rAjagopAla-sharmA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://thedharmadispatch.substack.com/p/honoring-the-vedic-stalwarts-in-our?utm_source=substack&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;preface&#34;&gt;Preface&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Honoring the Vedic Stalwarts in Our Midst: Vidvan Ghanapati Rajagopala Sarma&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A profile of Ghanapati Rajagopala Sarma, a true Vedic stalwart in our midst. This is a translation of Shatavadhani Dr. Ganesh&amp;rsquo;s brilliant portrait of this eminent Vedic Pundit and scholar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ONE OF THE AGELESS GEMS in the cinematic universe of K. Viswanath is the memorable scene from Swarnakamalam featuring an aged Ghanapati and a haughty bureaucrat. In less than four minutes, Viswanath brings alive the tragic history of the downfall of the Vedic culture in the very land it was birthed. It is an excruciating scene executed not in a revolutionary or reactionary manner but in a spirit of pure Sattva. It also accomplishes several things at the same time. It exposes the enduring thrall of the psychological colonisation of the Hindu mind. The bureaucrat who humiliates the Ghanapati is one of the most powerful symbols of the ugliness called Nehruvianism. In fact, he is the very creation of the corrosive Nehruvian state. Like Nehru, he is haughty because he’s petty. But this is no ordinary pettiness. It is a pettiness imbued with spite, which actively seeks to annihilate all that is noble, lofty, and virtuous. And thus, there’s no better — or worse — form of annihilation than reducing a Ghanapati to a beggarly status.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RAjasthAna sudarshanaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/rAjasthAna-sudarshanaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/rAjasthAna-sudarshanaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.shrisidhdataashram.org/hi/about-us/shri-guru-maharaj&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;अनन्त श्रीविभूषित इन्द्रप्रस्थ एवं हरियाणा पीठाधीश्वर स्वामी सुदर्शनाचार्य जी महाराज का प्रादुर्भाव 27 मई 1937 को राजस्थान की पावन अवनी में सवाई मण्डलान्तर्गत पाड़ला ग्राम में एक सम्पन्न कृषक ब्राह्मण परिवार में हुआ।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;बीरवान बलवान के होत चिकने पात&amp;rdquo; इस कहावत को सार्थक करते हुए अनन्त श्रीविभूषित इन्द्रप्रस्थ एवं हरियाणा पीठाधीश्वर स्वामी सुदर्शनाचार्य जी महाराज जो कि बहु मुखी प्रतिभा के धनी, धार्मिक भावनाओं से ओतप्रोत थे, उन्होंने सर्वप्रथम मेंहदी पुर बालाजी के प्रसिद्ध मंदिर के महन्त श्री गणेशपुरी का सान्निध्य प्राप्त कर मानव कल्याण की कामना से लोकहित कार्यो में अपना ध्यान लगाते हुए अपनी आध्यात्म पथ की यात्रा की शुरूआत की,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;तथा इसके बाद व्रज वसुन्धरा के पावन वृन्दावनधाम में खटलेश स्वामी गोविन्दाचार्य महाराज से दीक्षा एवं शिक्षा ग्रहण कर सारस्वत नगरी काशी में भी वेदादि शास्त्रों का गहन अध्ययन किया।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rAjvADe vishvanAthaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/rAjvADe-vishvanAthaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/rAjvADe-vishvanAthaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dharmadispatch.in/culture/&#34;&gt;https://www.dharmadispatch.in/culture/&lt;/a&gt; by sandeep&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Remembering Vishvanath Kashinath Rajwade: The Maharashtra Historian Extraordinaire&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WE HAVE ALMOST A DAILY ACCOUNT of the degeneration of Maharashtra in our own time: the latest being the arrest of a sitting minister not to mention the vice-ridden life of something called Aryan Khan. The descent has been as swift as it is appalling.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In fact, it is shocking how much the descent has actually been normalized when we contrast it with the conditions that prevailed in the state just eighty years ago. Or roughly, four generations ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAligrAma dhanurdAsa yatiH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/sAligrAma-dhanurdAsa-yatiH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/sAligrAma-dhanurdAsa-yatiH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;parivarah&#34;&gt;parivAraH&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maternal great grandson of Karpangadu venkatacharyar swamy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;viraktih&#34;&gt;viraktiH&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was an IT person abroad. Had 2 kids with a vaDakalai shaThamarShaNa family wife.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Disagreement over vedAdhyayana led to break up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;shriranga-vasah&#34;&gt;shrIranga-vAsaH&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was a cook in shrIrangam.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;saligrama-vasah&#34;&gt;sAligrAma-vAsaH&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The (relatively) young dhanurdAsa-yati (AchArya of @sankIrtaH ) started caring for the rAmAnuja shrine in sAligrAma village (R supposedly stayed there).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Seems to have degenerated to ruins frequented by prostitutes, dogs and such. He got the villagers to agree to let him care for it, and build some 3 rooms. The land is, as per records, titled as &amp;ldquo;smashAna&amp;rdquo; (though it&amp;rsquo;s an ASI recognized 1k year old site etc.). He&amp;rsquo;s trying to get it separated from the cemetary (which might&amp;rsquo;ve been an usurpation case) so that he can build a fence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SekkiLAr aDi-pODi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/sekkiLAr_adi-podi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/sekkiLAr_adi-podi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Chekizhaar Adi Podi&amp;rsquo; Dr. T.N.Ramachandran (1934-2021): A Tribute&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Aravindan of svarAjya&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. T.N.Ramachandran (1934-2021) showed how to fight the forces which want to harm Dharma, and do this in a way that the fight itself becomes spiritual sadhana.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was an evening in some year of the 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some Tamil scholars of Kanyakumari district were having a meeting in our house. The agenda of the meeting was a book titled Thirukural, Saiva Siddhanta and Bible: A Comparative Study. The book, written by one Deivanayagam, was being published by the International Tamil Research Institute, Chennai. The book claimed that not only the Thirukural but the entire Saiva Siddhanta had their roots in the Bible which was brought to India by St. Thomas. Needless to say, this was more fanaticism than scholarship even though the book had pretensions of the latter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ShaNmukha-sharmA on karapAtrI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/shaNmukha-sharmA_on_karapAtrI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/shaNmukha-sharmA_on_karapAtrI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The life of Śrī Karapātri Swāmi is an amalgamation of practice, propagation, and principle of Dharma, Bhakti, and Advaita Jñāna with the power of tapas, Dēśa Bhakti, scholarship, and sacrifice It is the duty of every Bhāratīya to reminisce this great soul every morning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;dispassion-towards-mundane-and-concern-for-motherland&#34;&gt;Dispassion towards mundane and concern for Motherland&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Born into the Ojha family replete with illustrious scholars on Sunday Śrāvaṇa Śuddha Vidiya in Batani on the banks of River Sarayu. Haranārāyaṇa (Given name before becoming a renunciate) demonstrated high intellectual capacity right from childhood. Though he was given admission into higher classes, he expressed interest to study Sanskrit, which the overjoyed father arranged. He had dispassion that arose out of pure discrimination towards the worldly aspects right from beginning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>shrIdhara-dushyanta-2015</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/shrIdhara-dushyanta-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/shrIdhara-dushyanta-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.livemint.com/Sundayapp/zsEBJDUoFd9l7xM7x12kcM/In-the-beginning-was-the-word.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the beginning was the word&lt;br&gt;&#xA;13 min read Updated: 23 May 2015, 11:35 PM IST Samanth Subramanian&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;young-crop&#34;&gt;Young crop&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The last decade has seen a surge in young people taking up the traditional arts of upanyasam and harikatha discourses on Hindu scriptures&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Figuring out which of Dushyanth Sridhar’s two lives is the alternate one is not necessarily simple. It might be the one in which he is a product manager at Tata Consultancy Services Ltd, creating PowerPoint decks, dialling into conference calls, and fretting about software.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surapura kRShNaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/surapura-kRShNaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/surapura-kRShNaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ದಿನಕ್ಕೊಬ್ಬ ಮಾಹುಲಿ ವಿದ್ಯಾಸಿಂಹಾಚಾರ್ಯರ ಶಿಷ್ಯರ ಪರಿಚಯ :-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;೨) ಪಂ ಕೃಷ್ಣಾಚಾರ್ಯ ಸುರಪೂರ (ನಾಸಿಕ) :-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ಸುರಪೂರ ಮನೆತನದಲ್ಲಿ ರುಕ್ಮಿಣೀಬಾಯಿ ವಿಠಲಾಚಾರ್ಯ ದಂಪತಿಗಳಲ್ಲಿ ಜನಿಸಿದಂಥ ಇವರು ಪರಮಪೂಜ್ಯ ೧೦೦೮ ಶ್ರೀ ಸತ್ಯಧ್ಯಾನತೀರ್ಥರಿಂದ ಅನುಗೃಹೀತವಾದ ಶ್ರೀ ಸತ್ಯಧ್ಯಾನ ವಿದ್ಯಾಪೀಠದಲ್ಲಿ ಪೂಜ್ಯ ಮಾಹುಲಿ ಗೋಪಾಲಾಚಾರ್ಯರರಲ್ಲಿ ಪ್ರಾಥಮಿಕ ತರ್ಕ, ವ್ಯಾಕರಣ, ಸಾಹಿತ್ಯ ಗ್ರಂಥಗಳನ್ನು ಅಧ್ಯಯನ ಮಾಡಿ, ನಂತರ ಪೂಜ್ಯ ಮಾಹುಲಿ ವಿದ್ಯಾಸಿಂಹಾಚಾರ್ಯರಲ್ಲಿ ಸಮಸ್ತ ವೇದಾಂತ ಗ್ರಂಥಗಳನ್ನು ಅಧ್ಯಯನ ಮಾಡಿ, ವಿದ್ಯಾಸಿಂಹಾಚಾರ್ಯರು ಮುಂಬೈ ಮಹಾನಗರದಲ್ಲಿ ಪರಮಪೂಜ್ಯ ೧೦೦೮ ಶ್ರೀ ಸತ್ಯಪ್ರಮೋದತೀರ್ಥರ ಸನ್ನಿಧಿಯಲ್ಲಿ ನಡೆಸಿದಂಥ ಪ್ರಥಮ ಶ್ರೀಮನ್ನ್ಯಾಯಸುಧಾಮಂಗಳದಲ್ಲಿ ತಮ್ಮ ಸುಧಾಮಂಗಳ ನೆರವೇರಿಸಿ ಪಂಡಿತರಾದವರು ಸುರಪೂರ ಕೃಷ್ಣಾಚಾರ್ಯರು.&#xA;ಸಾತ್ವಿಕರಾದ, ಸದಾಚಾರನಿಷ್ಠರಾದ ಇವರು ಅನೇಕ ವರ್ಷಗಳ ಕಾಲ ನಾಸಿಕ ಕ್ಷೇತ್ರದಲ್ಲಿದ್ದು ಅನೇಕ ಶಿಷ್ಯರನ್ನು ಪಡೆದು, ಪ್ರಕರಣಗ್ರಂಥಗಳು, ಶ್ರೀಮನ್ನ್ಯಾಯಸುಧಾ, ಶ್ರೀಮದ್ಭಾಗವತ ಮೊದಲಾದ ಗ್ರಂಥಗಳನ್ನು ಪಾಠಮಾಡಿ, ಮನೆಯಲ್ಲಿಯೇ ವಿದ್ಯಾರ್ಥಿಯನ್ನು ಇಟ್ಟುಕೊಂಡು ಸುಧಾದಿ ಗ್ರಂಥಗಳ ಪಾಠಮಾಡಿ, ಉತ್ತಮ ವಾಗ್ಮಿಗಳಾಗಿ, ಸ್ತೀಯರಿಗೆ ಶ್ರೀ ಹರಿಕಥಾಮೃತಸಾರ ಮೊದಲಾದ ಪಾಠ ಹೇಳಿ, ತಮ್ಮ ಶಿಷ್ಯರಿಂದ ಸುಮಾರು ಆರು ಕೋಟಿ ಶ್ರೀರಾಮಮಂತ್ರದ ಜಪ ಮಾಡಿಸಿ ಶ್ರೀ ಮಹಾಸ್ವಾಮಿಗಳ ಸನ್ನಿಧಿಯಲ್ಲಿ ಸಮರ್ಪಣೆ ಹೋಮ ಮಾಡಿಸಿ, ಪಾಠಪ್ರವಚನ ಮಾಡ್ತಾ, ಬಂದ ಅತಿಥಿಗಳಿಗೆ ಉತ್ತಮ ವ್ಯವಸ್ಥಾಪಕರಾಗಿ, ಅನೇಕ ಪ್ರಶಸ್ತಿ ಪುರಸ್ಕೃತರಾಗಿ, ಸುವರ್ಣಪದಕ ವಿಜೇತರಾಗಿ, ಅನೇಕ ಸಂಘ ಸಂಸ್ಥೆಗಳಿಂದ ಮಾನಿತರಾಗಿ, ಎಲ್ಲರಿಗೂ ಪ್ರೀತಿಪಾತ್ರರಾಗಿ,  ಅನೇಕ ಸ್ವಾಮಿಗಳ ಗುರುಗಳ ಅನುಗ್ರಹಕ್ಕೆ ಪಾತ್ರರಾಗಿದ್ದಾರೆ. ಅಂಥ&#xA;ಕೃಷ್ಣಾಚಾರ್ಯರು ಇವತ್ತು ನಮ್ಮ ಜೊತೆಗೆ ಇಲ್ಲ ಅಂತನ್ನೋದೇ ದುಃಖದ ಸಂಗತಿ.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>svAminAthAryaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/svAminAthAryaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/svAminAthAryaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/GhorAngirasa/status/1103333097452462080&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An anecdote by the late Ki. Va. Jagannathan on his legendary guru, shrI U. Ve Swaminatha Iyer, who literally knocked on thousands of home doors in TN to obtain the sangam manuscripts in precarious states, decipher &amp;amp; publish them in printed form before they could be lost forever.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since he is in the position of an AcArya, it is not wrong to pay reverence to him as a mANuSya-matsyadeva who revived the veda from the ocean-bed. shrI Ki. Va Ja&amp;rsquo;s anecdote gives an insight into his character as well. A picture of U. Ve Sa reading his obtained manuscripts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tirukkudantai-ANDavan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/tirukkudantai-ANDavan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/tirukkudantai-ANDavan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Srimad Thirukkudanthai Andavan Sri Vedanta Ramanuja Mahadesikan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Birth Star: Panguni Pusam (Pushyam)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thaniyan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;śrīmad vedānta rāmānuja-muni karunā-labdha vedānta-yugmaṁ&lt;br&gt;&#xA;śrīmad śrīvāsa yogīśvara guru-padayor-arpita svātma-bhāraṁ&lt;br&gt;&#xA;śrīmad śri rañganāthāhvaya muni-krupayā prāpta mokśāśramaṁ taṁ&lt;br&gt;&#xA;śrīmad vedānta rāmānuja-munima-paraṁ samśraye deśikendraṁ&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Translation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;His father was a parama-ekanti  and had the full blessings of his acharya. He used to visit Srimad Andavan Periashramam in Srirangam regularly to participate in the parayana-ghoshtis (assembly of scholars chanting  Vedic mantras) for all major Sri Vaishnava festivals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TirukurunguDi sudarshanaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/tirukurun-guDi-sudarshanaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/tirukurun-guDi-sudarshanaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;brahmacharya&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the age of 26 they started looking .!&#xA;Just now he resigned his job.&#xA;Both he and his brother having strict aahaara niyama shika and  12 Pundra.&#xA;So even at the time of IT job no one is ready to give them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;**Quitting a Top IT firm in Chennai at 35, Sudharsan has returned to Azhagiya Nambi Divya Desam to perform lifetime service **&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last week, this section featured a story on a long time resident of Thiruvallikeni quitting a corporate job in his early 40s to return to his hereditary home in Vaanamaamalai Divya Desam where he is currently performing Madapalli service at the Thothadri Nathan temple. This story is about another Thiruvallikeni resident, who aged only 35, has quit a high paying IT job after over a dozen years in the sector and returned to Thiru Kurungudi to take up service as a  Sannidhi Paricharakar at less than one tenth the IT salary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TiruvahIndra-pura-devanAthaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/tiruv-ahIndra-pura-devanAthaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/tiruv-ahIndra-pura-devanAthaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Born in 1925. sri http://U.Ve thiruvaheendrapuram Devanathachar, the acharya through who&amp;rsquo;s help samveda was saved from getting lost.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time in 1960, just 10 ashtabrahmana adhyayis (one who has learnt all 8 brahmanas of kauthuma samaveda) in Tamilnadu and just 20 across India were there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of them is Srirangam Saamam Swamy (sri U. Ve thiruvaheendrapuram Devanathachar.) He was a legendary teacher who taught samveda all his life and now  due ti his efforts around 100 students and prasishyas of his are ashtabrahmana adhyayis.&#xA;He was instrumental in keeping karnaparampara of the shakha&amp;rsquo;s brahmanas. Without him and Kanchi matha Murali Krishna shrauti family, Samaveda Brahmana might&amp;rsquo;ve been lost in adhyayana parampara.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TotAdri shrInivAsaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/totAdri-shrInivAsaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/totAdri-shrInivAsaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://prtraveller.blogspot.com/2025/05/vaanamaamalai-thothadri-srinivasan.html&#34;&gt;Vaanamaamalai Thothadri Srinivasan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back to the roots&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From Tier 1 IT company to Madapalli Cook at a historical  remote Divya Desam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjCSZL0zH61UBdSAY9aNYQSmVVztB4PhBulErhXU190ghQkPfeh4BRgpxMyTsvG8gRBIdLl9mUG9OUnHpOzWal3xtIuFvwqEYbX2IOCXv0OSVeFhvT-3W6dycxhDmBDBfwnQDNEszkRWWxnAEGndZtoiaU6lwiwhOqYfcHAzeJ9JEATb5nWZMriIrBbG5_f/s1397/thothadri%20srinivasan.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjCSZL0zH61UBdSAY9aNYQSmVVztB4PhBulErhXU190ghQkPfeh4BRgpxMyTsvG8gRBIdLl9mUG9OUnHpOzWal3xtIuFvwqEYbX2IOCXv0OSVeFhvT-3W6dycxhDmBDBfwnQDNEszkRWWxnAEGndZtoiaU6lwiwhOqYfcHAzeJ9JEATb5nWZMriIrBbG5_f/s320/thothadri%20srinivasan.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjCSZL0zH61UBdSAY9aNYQSmVVztB4PhBulErhXU190ghQkPfeh4BRgpxMyTsvG8gRBIdLl9mUG9OUnHpOzWal3xtIuFvwqEYbX2IOCXv0OSVeFhvT-3W6dycxhDmBDBfwnQDNEszkRWWxnAEGndZtoiaU6lwiwhOqYfcHAzeJ9JEATb5nWZMriIrBbG5_f/s320/thothadri%20srinivasan.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is past 1am on Wednesday (May 7) night. 47 year old Thothadri Srinivasan (Nambi) is still at the Madapalli at the Thothadrinathan Divya Desam in Nanguneri and he brings Dosai Thaligai to be presented to Deivanayagan following the Horse Vahana procession on the 8th day of the Chitrai Brahmotsavam.  Shortly after, he is at the moolavar Sannidhi for the Thaligai presentation at the Artha Jaama Pooja. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VenkaTeshaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/venkaTeshaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/venkaTeshaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://prtraveller.blogspot.com/2024/09/dr-venkatesh-thiru-kudanthai-upanyasakar.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Temple, Travel and Sport&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Wednesday, September 25, 2024&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Dr Venkatesh Thiru Kudanthai Upanyasakar&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At a young age, this doctor from Kumbakonam has carved out a niche for himself in the ‘Spiritual Lectures’ world&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Debut on Kal Garuda Sevai day, an unexpected 30 days Thiruppavai upanyasam at Sarangapani Koil and a chance meeting with Karunakaraswamy transforms his life&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a young student of ARR Matriculation school, Thiru Kudanthai N Venkatesh showed his devotional flavour by reciting and presenting the meaning of the verses from the Bhagavath Gita at the prayer every morning from his early teens. When he was 15, he won the first prize in an oratorical competition organised in Kumbakonam. By this time, he had also begun writing poems. Following a district rank in class XII, he joined Medicine at the Government College in Erode. Seeing his spiritual interest, his professor motivated and spurred him to pursue that interest. Over the last few years, he has captured the minds of the devotees with his style of presentation and a down to earth way of life. Here’s the story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vuppulUri-gaNapati-shAstrI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/vuppulUri-gaNapati-shAstrI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/vuppulUri-gaNapati-shAstrI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.srivgvp.org/sriganapathi.asp&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LIFE SKETCH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;birth-ancestry&#34;&gt;Birth, Ancestry&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sri Vuppuluri Ganapathi Sastry was born on the Sixteenth of December 1888 in his maternal grandfather, Sri Kalluri Ganapathi Sastry’s house, at Kakinada. Sri.Kalluri Ganapthi Sastry was a great Vedic Scholar and Salakshana Ghanapathi himself. He was a renowned scholar in the Vedas, Dharma Sastras, the Jyothisha Sastra and in the sixteen karmas (shodasa karma). He was a great mystic and a worshipper of different Gods and Goddesses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>आदिवण्-शठकोपे ४२-तमो यतिः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/AdivaN-shaThakope_42-tamAhobila-yatiH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/AdivaN-shaThakope_42-tamAhobila-yatiH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;श्रीः&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;श्रीमते श्रीलक्ष्मीनृसिंहपरब्रह्मणे नमः&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ஸ்ரீ ஆதிவண் ஶடகோப ஸ்வாமி வைபவம்&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(श्रीअहोबिलमठத்தின் दिव्यास्थानத்தில் 42-வது பட்டத்தில் मूर्धाभिषिक्तராய் எழுந்தருளியிருந்த ஸ்ரீ அழகியசிங்கருடைய श्रीसूक्ति.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;இந்த உலகத்தில் இப்भरतखण्डமொன்றே पुण्यभूमि. இது पुण्यक्षेत्रங்களாலும் पुण्यतीर्थங்களாலும் விளங்கியுள்ளது. रामकृष्णादि अवतारங்கள் நடந்த நிலம் இதுவே. ऋषिகளாலும் ஆழ்வாராचार्यர்களாலும் मङ्गलाशासनம் செய்யப்பட்ட देशமும் இதுதான். परम आप्तங்களான गीतादिशास्त्रங்களும் இங்கேதான் अवतरिத்தன. இப்படி இது सर्वोत्कृष्टமான खण्डமாகையால், அப்போதைக்கப்போது இதன் रक्षणத்திற்கு வேண்டிய कृषिயை बहुमुखமாக सर्वेश्वरன் செய்து வருகிறான்.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;परमकारुणिकனான அந்த शरण्यன், இந்தக் खण्डம் म्लेच्छादिகளால் आक्रमिக்கப்படுமந்நாளில், தான் महत्தான प्रयासமெடுத்து स्थापिத்த सनातनधर्मத்துக்குக் குறையொன்றும் வாராமலிருக்கும்படி அணைகோலக் கருதி, தன் திருவடி सम्बन्धமே அதற்குச் சிறந்த அரணாகையால், உலகமெல்லாம் தன்னைப் पूर्वத்திலேயே आश्रयिத்து ஈடேறும்படி செய்யவேண்டுமென்று திருவுள்ளங்கொண்டு, தான் நேரில் अवतरिக்கும் காலம் வருங்காலமாகையால், அத்திருவுள்ளக்கருத்தை सदाचार्यர் ஒருவரைக் கொண்டு पूर्ति பண்ணக் कृषि செய்யத் தொடங்கினான்.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>माधव-शर्मा - Indica</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/mAdhava-sharmA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/mAdhava-sharmA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In January 2024, the founder of the Saptarushi Veda Pathashaala (@sapta_rushi) Shri Madhav Sarma presented a vigraham of Adi Shankara Bhagavadpada to Shri Hari Kiran Vadlamani, who through INDICA has been committed to a manasik yatra of Shankara’s path.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Madhav Sarma garu, based in Vishakapatanam, in Andhra Pradesh, believes that Dharmo Viswasya Jagathah Pratishta (It is righteousness which holds up the universe) and has dedicated his life to the protection and furtherance of Dharma and the teachings of Adi Shankara Bhagavadpada.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>राव-लक्ष्मीनारायणः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/rAva_laxmInArAyaNaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/rAva_laxmInArAyaNaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1965, epigraphist Śri N. Lakshminārāyaṇa Rao, one of the examiners of a young Ph.D candidate, recommended that he be awarded a Ph.D, but also commented, “This candidate thinks he is infallible, like Brihaspati.” Little did he know that this candidate would turn out to be one of the FINEST epigraphist India had ever seen. How I wish he was alive with us today! Why is that such scholars leave this mortal world so early, creating a void which we can never fill?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>शौरिराज-श्रीनिवासः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/shauri-rAja-shrInivAsaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/shauri-rAja-shrInivAsaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SOURIRAJAN, Dr. Srinivasa&#xA;October 16, 1923 - February 20, 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Srinivasa Sourirajan, the accomplished scientist best known as the father of Reverse Osmosis, died peacefully in his sleep at the age of 98 in Ottawa, Canada. His prolific and highly impactful work contributed to the development of scientific pathways that addressed some of the most pressing social issues of our time, including equitable global access to drinkable water and food supply, innovation in healthcare and medicine, and scientific breakthroughs on clean energy. He was a three-time nominee of the Nobel Prize in Chemistry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>श्रीधर-वेङ्कटेशः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/shrIdhara-venkaTeshaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/shrIdhara-venkaTeshaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sridhara Venkatesa Dikshitar (13 August 1635–1720), popularly known as Ayyaval, was a Hindu saint and composer who lived in the village of Thiruvisanallur in the then Thanjavur Maratha kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ancestry-and-early-life&#34;&gt;Ancestry and early life&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sridhara Ayyaval was born in Mysore and was the son of one Sridhara Lingarayar. Ayyaval&amp;rsquo;s father was the Diwan of he Mysore kingdom. When Ayyaval, a staunch devotee of the Hindu god Shiva, was offered the post of Diwan upon his father&amp;rsquo;s death, he rejected the offer and instead, chose to embark on a pilgrimage of the Saivite temples of the Cauvery Delta region.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>सरस्वती-बायी</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/sarasvatI-bAyI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/jAti-varNa-practice/v1/persons/sage-bloodlines/ajJNAta-gotrAH/articles/sarasvatI-bAyI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/tomatosudhu/status/2010783346658590955&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Born in an orthodox Madhwa family, C. Saraswathi Bai rose to become a pioneering cultural force and is remembered as the first Lady Bhagavatar. Restricted by the social norms of her time, early marriage, and the absence of formal musical training, her exceptional talent might have remained unrecognised but for the discerning vision of Tiruvaiyaru Krishnachar, a musician, Harikatha exponent, and Sanskrit teacher at Madras Christian College. Recognising her innate genius, Krishnachar relocated her family to Madras and mentored her, shaping the course of her artistic life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
