<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Gifted&#39; programs</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/MT/gifted-programs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/MT/gifted-programs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1446880401549631500.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There has been some discussion about the removal of special schools/programs for &amp;ldquo;gifted children&amp;rdquo; in the US. This is a topic we have long wondered about: are these really useful? For an India parallel one could think of the IIT &amp;amp; some lesser know programs with a high entrance threshold.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;filtering-and-crackers&#34;&gt;Filtering and crackers&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One thing I learnt from classmates &amp;amp; relatives (&amp;amp; to a degree myself) who made use of entrance into a high threshold program is the obvious. If you enrich based on a cognitive criterion (\approx IQ) then you will get a pool of students who will show markedly above average trajectories. This is simply a consequence of the filter rather than any special training.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Education vs accredition</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/MT/education-vs-accredition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/MT/education-vs-accredition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1460836188093394945&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1460836188093394945&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The divergence between education &amp;amp; accreditation/keys to the cartel has deepened enormously in the American academe. Many from India (myself included) sought that academe primarily for the latter function although for difference reasons. But in the least it offered educational opportunities outside the classroom, such as through technology access, libraries, talks by experts &amp;amp; sometimes peers. However, that role is diminishing over the years &amp;amp; accreditation remains the most powerful thing going for universities despite their capture by navyonmAda.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnet schools</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/MT/magnet-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/MT/magnet-schools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the US there are schools known as magnet schools that enrich high IQ kids. Many H along with east Asians put in tremendous effort to get their kids in there.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Once in those schools there is tremendous pressure on those kids to build shiny portfolios to look like superstars.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Among Americans there is considerable emphasis on the appearance of the package rather than substance inside.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;With respect to the appearance there is again a certain emphasis on trying to look like an all-rounder &amp;ndash; essentially a pseudo-allrounder rather than be focused on your genuine strengths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Science aptitude</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/MT/science-aptitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/MT/science-aptitude/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Hindus &amp;amp; East Asians in such magnet schools &amp;amp; their parents are also under great pressure to look like scientists by interning in real science labs.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;What the system, parents &amp;amp; kids don&amp;rsquo;t realize is that good scientists are mostly born not made &amp;amp; no amount of interning can be useful in a serious way if you dont have that capacity for science. Among other things they just don&amp;rsquo;t realize that for being effective in science you need to acquire a large body of knowledge: perhaps reading is even more important than just hanging out in a lab.+++(5)+++&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Many just don&amp;rsquo;t seem to get it&lt;br&gt;&#xA;that if you have no interest/capacity in Newton&amp;rsquo;s mechanics or mathematics or chemistry of aromaticity you might lack the scientific background to be effective in biology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social media</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/MT/social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/notes/skills/education/articles/MT/social-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1085411901096505345.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In most countries they don&amp;rsquo;t let you ride a motorized cycle, smoke tobacco or imbibe ethanol until a certain age. I believe SM should also not be made available to kids until a similar age. It can be more destructive for females than males. But the current occidentalism flowing into other cultures might not accept such sex differences even if they stare at the face.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Onw has to develop a thick skin in both real life and SM&lt;br&gt;&#xA;but it is much more likely that this can be&#xA;developed in real life than on SM.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;SM offers an opportunity to find truly likeminded people&lt;br&gt;&#xA;unlike IRL where you are usually saddled with&lt;br&gt;&#xA;a relatively limited choice&lt;br&gt;&#xA;which at least for some people in the upper tail of the IQ distribution can find unsatisfying.+++(5)+++&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
